so we have we have this this uh program
I I call it the well I guess it's
confusingly named under employment
underemployed
um unemployed program I kind of change
the name depending on how I feel that
day
um and it's a program that allows people
who either don't have a job right so
they're they're they're changing careers
their
um just happen to be made redundant
right that could be things that happen
um or if they're in a job that is
beneath them right that's that's that's
depending on your your country they're
gonna calculate
um unemployment in various different
ways but most of the major countries uh
calculate include in unemployment
figures somebody who is underemployed so
that is uh your uh you're a nuclear
physicist and your are currently working
at McDonald's right you're underemployed
you should be working somewhere using
your talents and capability that you've
got but it could be I mean I'm creating
a a big one there but that could be any
you know even even short gaps uh
somebody who is uh normally a project
manager who is
working with uh teams or a scrum master
and
um they're they're having to do
something else because they're or jobs
available in their particular context
right that's that's the that's the under
slash unemployed uh program that we have
and um the reason I created it was
because there are so many people that
are in that category and they can really
struggle to afford premium training like
we're talking about right you want you
want to get your your your your PSM your
pspo your Advanced whatever it is
because you think it will enable
um doors to open for you right we all
know that that certification is not the
be all and end-all of of knowledge it's
not a thing
um that that you should rely on right
but lots of recruiters and companies do
rely on it and while they do rely on it
it's perhaps something that you could
add to your cve adds to your story that
would open a open a door and to enable
you to then have a conversation with
somebody and that's where you are then
able to shine
right and part of that uh um um story is
being able to participate in these
trainings gain some extra understanding
and that bit of paper that perhaps
cracks that that door to get into that
interview
um so that you can shine so that's
that's why I created it
um if the way it works is
um you go to my website you book a a
class and instead of paying upfront
which is what most people are going to
do
um you can pick invoice and then give me
a call uh give me a chat chat to me
email me whatever
um and we can have a conversation and
what I do is I just set it as 30 deposit
up front so you pay a little bit right
it's not going to be completely
completely free I have costs too right
so there's a 30 deposit up front and
then you pay the rest when you're ready
right when you feel uh you're when when
you've got that job that you want that's
paying you the the the rate that you're
Worth right then you can pay it back
um I've done this a few times with a few
people I've never had anybody not pay it
back and most people pay it back fairly
quickly so uh I am always happy to help
people
increase their ability increase their
capability and if this program can help
them that's
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else add your scrum or devops
then please book a coffee with me
through naked agility