why is the PSU so popular for product
development teams
um because there's a gap does this
massive gaps
we talk a lot about in the product
development world we talk a lot about
scrum right scrum's not the only process
but it is the predominant process it's
the way most people uh talk about agile
and product development today it's the
way most people
um characterize and phrase it right they
use scrum terminology and the way they
speak it's kind of been been adopted
um but scrum itself does not talk about
where where do you get your backlog from
right it just says have a backlog have
it ordered that's product backlog here
it is what where does it come from how
do you know what you should put in there
how do you know if the things you put in
there and that you've delivered are
actually the right thing and that's kind
of the purpose of the the the the
learnings that come out of the the PSU
and so the professional scrum with user
experience looks at
um kind of two things one is how do we
integrate all of those I ideas
that have come out of the expert an
awesome work done in the user experience
world how do we integrate that into the
product ownership world right product
owners are often user experience experts
or have access to user experience
experts who are able to help them
formulate a a more of a hypothesis
driven engineering practice where
they're looking forward not only looking
forward into the future and figuring out
what it is we need next but also looking
into the past of what we have delivered
and did it actually provide the value we
need or do we need it to be slightly
slightly different so there's a lot of
awesome work in there that's really
important
and but quite often the experts in that
space have to spend too much time
um fixing I'm going to phrase this badly
but fixing the problems that the
engineering teams create because they
don't understand those things so
engineering teams make decisions just
like with lack of security right you
make decisions based on I need to get
this work done not on how do I support
this holistic long-term infinite uh uh
game that we're playing of delivering
valuable product
so by those experts
um encouraging and enabling the
engineering teams to take on the parts
of that work that don't need the Deep
expertise they just need some so skills
right the PSU enables engineering teams
to make better decisions
so that
that
enables them to understand the
additional value that those deep experts
and user experience bring to that story
and the hypothesis-driven engineering
bring to that story as so they respect
that more because they understand how it
fits into their story but also the
engineering team can take
a lot of that lower level work of of
perhaps Gathering the data perhaps
um um and you know actually implementing
the test of the hypothesis
off the plate of the experts and give
them more time to dive more deeply into
the the expertise and what does the
future look like in strategizing and
planning for the future and figuring out
whether we've actually built the right
things
so for me that that value of the the PSU
is in bringing those two worlds together
more closely in in in uh um giving the
teams the understanding of user
experience that they need uh to respect
it and value it
and giving the user experience uh folks
enough understanding of what the
engineering teams are trying to do and
how they can incorporate their work and
engage with the engineering teams so
that um it we have more successful
outcomes and hopefully everybody sees
the value of having these these
cross-functional teams not necessarily
cross-functional individuals but
cross-functional teams where you have
user experience on the team so that
they're able to work closely with the
product owner to help build out new
ideas as well as work work with the team
during the Sprint in order to to to make
sure that the ideas we are building ours
are as valuable and successful as
possible