so so you're looking at your monolithic
system and you're thinking this isn't
working
anymore maybe it's slowing you down
maybe it's getting harder and harder to
maintain or maybe the business needs
more flexibility and you just can't get
that with a monolith whatever the reason
you're considering microservices and
that's great but let's be clear if you
just start breaking things apart without
a solid strategy you're setting yourself
up for a world of pain this isn't about
blindly following trends it's about
understanding how to decompose your
systems in a way that makes sense for
your business scalability flexibility
maintainability all great outcomes if
you can do it but if you rush in without
thinking it through you'll introduce
complexity that doesn't actually help
you at Naked Agility we we don't come in
and do the work for you that's that's
not our approach instead we help you
make sense of your system so that you
can make better decisions about how to
transition where to start what to break
off first how do you avoid turning your
monolith into a distributed mess
we work with CTO's and engineering leads
to improve the way that you work so that
you can map out the transition step by
step allowing you to move towards
microservices as needed without chaos
this isn't just about technology it's
about how you work how you design your
teams how you handle dependencies how
you ensure each service is independently
deployable and maintainable
microservices aren't the goal the goal
is faster more adaptable delivery
without the drag of a massive tightly
coupled system so if you're thinking
about this shift make sure you do it for
the right reasons with the right
approach and if you want to talk through
your options let's have a conversation