so the question is is the EPS immersive
learning experience the equivalent of
having a Hands-On scrum coach
no but almost I think is probably the
right answer to that
um so having a a somebody with your team
on a continuous basis
um is is is really helpful right
somebody to to even even 10 Sprints
later who you're able to get advice from
and engage with is really powerful but
we kind of almost do that with our
immersive class right so what we do is
um each
because each session includes a feedback
loop right the the assignment you get at
the end of the session to try and your
organization is then debriefed before
the next session so you're closing
closing that feedback loop
that includes a little bit of coaching
right because you're you're not just
um and doing it you're getting the
feedback from it
um and and getting coaching from the the
trainer slash cult who's able to to help
you with that but also it's over 10
weeks right typical Sprint length
is two weeks
so you actually get five Sprints worth
of help and you're only taking one half
day
per week
per Sprint out so that's one day ten
percent of your Sprints right in our two
week Sprint that's ten percent
um you're losing right that's you're
losing it as productive time on the team
building your product but hopefully what
you gain back in overall effectiveness
of your team
over five Sprints right continually
coming back closing those feedback loops
trying something new
how many retrospectives do you have in
those five Sprints have five
retrospectives right so you can get
together as a team and each two weeks
each two sessions figure out how much
the training has helped you and bring
that information to the next session so
that the trainer can then adapt and
augment the training based on the needs
of you and your organization on a
continuous basis right that's super
awesome
and in addition oh if that wasn't enough
right the the the we always nickel
agility always offers an hour of
additional coaching per person that's in
the class right so if you're doing a 10
week uh uh uh 10 weeks with us uh with
let's say 12 people in the class the
immersive classes are a little bit
smaller right so you get you get 12
people in the class you get an
additional 12 hours of of coaching and
help so maybe maybe that trainer comes
back for your next two or three
retrospectives maybe they sit in on uh
or even during that time right they sit
in on our Sprint review in a Sprint
retrospective and you're some of your
dailies and you can close some of the
more of those feedback Clips get more
help get that that that coaching is part
of the scenario
um that is being delivered that part is
up to you right you have to want it
because you have to use it and you have
to figure out a how to include it in in
your process but the aps immersive class
is ultimately a a 10 week five prints
five Sprint uh uh Kickstart for for your
organization and moving towards scrum or
kanban or whatever it is you're trying
to do
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility