when you are working on very complex
products one of the the the main steps
developers and Engineering groups can
take is is automating everything I mean
that's that's probably along with
reducing the backat size so making the
things that you're delivering smaller so
that you can you can do more of them and
you're iterating on them right um one of
the
key
things that enable your engineering team
to have the
confidence that they can continuously
deploy to production those small things
is to to automate automate everything
you you should have automated testing
you should have automated deployment you
should have Auto aut as much as you can
automated validation there are are
automated validations you can do
especially if you're collecting telemu
in your product a a great a great
example of that was um the Azure devops
team when they first started deploying
their Cloud version of the product they
they didn't have you know they'd been
used to doing two yearly deliveries and
suddenly they were doing 3we deliveries
and they had H H technical debt they had
poor quality code they had uh um Big
gnarly chunks that were very difficult
to edit
um and they had automation that took a
very long time to run so one of the
there was kind of two big focuses big
engineering pushes that they made in
that team that I I think had the biggest
impacts on me observing their their
their improvements and the first one was
that they
reduced as much as possible that cycle
time right they wanted to time to learn
they wanted to reduce that time to learn
as much as possible and time to learn is
is all the way from I come up with a an
idea for a feature it gets all the way
through being built or some of it being
built being deployed to production or
some of it being deployed to production
and collecting Telemetry and then
feeding that back all the way around to
to to the next Loop that's that's time
to to learn all the way
around so what figuring out what the
biggest
time suck is in that space and tackle
that so for the for the Azure devops
team they they found a number of things
one of those things was their their
testing infrastructure their testing
infrastructure was was for one of a
better expression terrible it
took as I understand about 48 hours to
find out for developers if they made a
code change whether it was successful
their time to self test right their
ability to test uh uh for themselves was
incredibly long that's 40 48 hours to 72
hours and the time to run the the
regression Suite was even longer than
that it was Perhaps Perhaps a week to
get that done because they had long
running regression tests and one of the
biggest focuses biggest pushies they had
was on converting all of those long
running functional tests
into short code tests right
so they were topheavy on their largest
number of tests were these long running
functional tests their smallest number
of tests was unit tests and they flipped
that pyramid over it took them four
years because remember they've been
working on this product for for six to
eight years in a waterfall way and they
built this massive test infrastructure
so it took them four years of doing a
little bit at a time paying back that
technical de
to get to the point where they'd flipped
that that that pyramid over and in fact
they' just removed whole layers of that
pyramid and they ended up with all of
these fast running unit tests so instead
of
80,000 long running automated tests they
had 880,000 short tests and they they
they moved that number from 48 hours to
to find out if a developer had done
something wrong to three and a half
minutes they could run the whole
test Suite in three and a half minutes
on their local machine they could stand
up via command line calls any parts of
the system that they needed in order to
be able to do functional tests locally
on their machine that was one of the
other changes that they made how how do
we enable that so that developers can
just run a command and it's sets up the
bits they need to test the stuff that
they're working on locally so that they
can have a copy of the system running
locally and walk through it and that
they they they build all of that
functionality it took them a long time
to get there but that
investment helped improve their
confidence in their ability not just as
individuals but as a group to be able to
to deploy and build features in the
product and improve the confidence of
their customers right their customers
had greater confidence that this is a
good product it's a solid product um yes
we've seen things go wrong but when
things go wrong they own up to them they
fix them they move forward they don't
make that mistake again so that that
building because it's it's okay to make
mistakes if if you've got a customer
that that you make a mistake and they
throw a throw a tantrum and they throw
their toys out the pram um it's because
they're used to working with vendors
that they have low confidence in and
they have low confidence in you fixing
it so they believe that they have to
throw that tantrum in order for you to
fix that thing so if you need to build
their confidence in you and in your
product and then they'll stop doing that
they'll they'll accept oh something went
wrong you messed up but we know you're
going to fix it we know you're going to
do a good job and we know um that you're
you're you're not going to do it again
right or it's unlikely that you'll do it
again that's confidence and when you're
working in big complex systems like uh
as your devops or or other types of
systems that that you have you need that
level of confidence not just at the
whole product level but at every
individual Team level I as a I working
on a team need to have confidence that
if I'm using capabilities delivered by
another team that they're going to be
solid that they're going to work that
they're going to meet that quality bar
that I need in order to do my work and
I'm not going to be your crutch right to
enable functionality so this is really
really important to have that underlying
attention to detail attention to Quality
shorten those feedback loops build up
that automation automate everything
there should be no manual tests one of
my favorite examples of that is the
Azure devops team they had poor
Telemetry in their product when they
first moved to this Cloud environment
and they were deploying through regions
so they would deploy to a region and
then they would check to see that
everything was working properly they
would check to see whether they
adversely affected users they' do this
all manually and then they would deploy
to the next region and one of the the
developers in intern for fun developed
something they called the Twitter
sentiment bot so this was a little a
little bot that trolled Twitter trolled
Twitter for negative comments about your
product so what they would do is they
would do a deployment to a particular
region and then the Twitter sentiment
bot would monitor Twitter for a couple
of hours to see whether people started
the the level of negativity about your
product increased in any way you're
always going to have a baseline of
people that are unhappy with stuff right
so if it increased in a certain way then
they would automatically stop the
deployment and flag that there something
that need to be look
at that's a crutch right that's a a a
way to automate something that isn't
automatable because of the way you built
your system they eventually didn't need
that bot anymore because they had those
full automations built into the system
but you need crutches while you get
there to be able to push those
boundaries and keep pushing for
continuous delivery keep pushing um to
do things faster keep pushing to improve
your code and improve your quality and
improve your engagement with your
customers and you'll get there
eventually