one of the seven signs of the agile
pocalypse is
chaos and Chaos seems to be the watch
word of almost every
organizations um digital transformation
agile
transformation whatever watchword
transformation they're they're using at
the moment um and it it comes out as as
as kind of two things that res in chaos
one is about the work and then one is
about how we do the work so the one
about the work is really about poor
product ownership results in
chaos right um and it results in chaos
because if we've got no well
communicated
goals then everybody's able to go in
whatever Direction they like if you
think of uh you've got you've got trust
and you've got uh uh no trust trust
autonomy and alignment and where where
do you fit in that story in your
organization so most organizations
create high levels of alignment by
having lots of rigorous project
management things going on they have
milestones and they have dates that you
have to hit and most of those dates are
just somebody's decided what that date
is right there's not a reason for that
date just they've decided it but it
creates this bounded environment within
which everybody moves forward but when
you
remove the the the the the milestones
and the Gant charts and the
deadlines what would you expect to
happen if you don't fill that void with
anything but chaos right that nobody
knows what direction they're supposed to
go what needs to be done when how do we
create that bounded environment in the
agile space is very different from how
we created it in the traditional
management and traditional project
management uh structure so the way we do
that is and we talk about in the product
owner class is Vision value and
validation you need to create this core
strategic Direction so that everybody
understands what direction they're going
in uh talked about it recently in the
evidence-based management class as well
you've got your your strategic objective
that's your um uh your your reach for
your North Star is your strategic
objective and then because that's like a
reach and it's a bit far out it's
difficult for people to see how the work
that they're doing every day connects to
that story so you need some kind of
intermediate strategic goal that brings
that
into it's not a stretch anymore this is
something we think we can work towards
right it's it's progress towards our our
reach our North Star but that gets us
there and then we can start thinking
about what are we tactically going to do
what are our tactical goals what are we
going to do what's our next step we're
going to take towards that
next destination in our journey towards
our North Star our outcome and then we
can start to see how the work we're
doing every day people doing the work
can see how the work they're doing every
day connects to the Tactical goal
connects to the intermediate strategic
goal and helps work towards fulfilling
the overall strategic goal in North Star
and with that connection you enable all
of those people at every level in your
organization depending on what level
they're looking at what level goals they
care about right at every level in your
organization to make decisions the El
that best fulfills the vision and
purpose of the organization because they
all understand and are going in the same
direction but if you don't have that if
you don't provide that and you take away
the milestones and Gant charts and
reports suddenly there's chaos right so
that's one way that that chaos
occurs the other way I mentioned was in
implementation chaos this is the The
Meta information around how you do a
digital agile devops whatever thing you
want to put in front of it
transformation some kind of change in
your organization and this is really
around poor
communication right you you you don't
involve the people doing the
work in the story that you're trying to
tell and you don't communicate that
story that you're trying to tell back to
them in in a way that helps them
understand that reinforces continuously
reinforces the story that we're trying
to get to and what I see most
organizations do is somebody really
senior in the organization sends out an
email saying we're going to move in this
new direction we're going to do this new
thing and that's it they just magically
expect things to happen and what really
happens is every single person in your
organization interprets
that email differently every single
person then takes that interpretation
and over time as they add more
information to that interpretation they
all start going in slightly different
directions so even if from that one
email everybody ended up going in the
same direction they start to fragment
and you end up with chaos cuz you've got
loads of different people pulling the
organization in different
directions so in order to create that
we're moving in this direction just like
the the the the the goals for uh what
direction are we taking the product what
are we actually building we also need
goals on what do we want what do we want
our our organizational culture to look
like how are we measuring people in
order to get them to go in that
direction uh a great great um joke in
that space is if you if you give
developers a bonus for the number of
bugs that they find in fix in their code
all of your developers will end up
writing themselves a very large bonus
right because they can just go add uh
the problem that they can then fix and
get the qos for fixing it if if you
reward firefighters you breed arsonists
right if it's within that same uh the
same package so what what what you need
to do instead is you need to look at how
are we measuring and incen izing people
right because the measures and
incentives that you create in your
organization are the things that drive
behaviors we think it's the goals that
we created over here right but if your
measures and incentives are at odds to
the goals it's going to start pulling
people in a different direction pulling
them in a way that does something
different pulling them perhaps in the
opposite direction because you've not
actually change the system the measures
and incentives are part of the system
within which everybody's operating so
you need to focus on how do
we understand how those measures are
impacting on people's behaviors and
continuously tweak those measures in
order to maintain the direction and
people working together towards that
goal and communicate everything
effectively you can't just say to
everybody we're going to do something
new no you have to change the measures
so they can see that we're doing
something new and then you have to
continuously
reinforce what it is we're doing what
direction we're going why we're going
there how they can help how they're
contributing to the story and you
continually build that picture towards
going in that new Direction
otherwise you end up with chaos chaos of
building the wrong thing or chaos of
just going in the wrong
direction thanks for watching the video
if you enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked
agility