For most organizations,
they have a a a ton of legacy systems.
And legacy systems are are they're
holding back their ability to innovate.
They're holding back their ability to um
move
towards the new features and
capabilities that they're looking for.
Um mostly because it gets in the way. It
adds friction. any anytime you've got a
bunch of engineers
working on anybody working on something
and you put something
in their way, it creates a little bit of
friction, right? And if you have enough
friction,
then most people give up. Most people
are not, you know, the the the the the
sort of person that's going to try and
fiddle with it until they get it
working. They just want it to work. And
if you put enough things in the way,
it's it's the same reason that you put a
lock on your house or an alarm on your
car, it's not going to stop a
professional thief, somebody who's
really trying uh to get around those
things, but it dissuades the vast
majority of people. And that's about
friction. you're adding friction in that
case for a positive outcome, not having
your car stolen. Um, but in in in
engineering work in organizational
systems,
every piece of friction you add in the
way um makes it less likely that people
will bother doing the thing that you
want them to do. So part of
working towards
these ideas around engineering
excellence is that we want to remove the
friction, right? We want to remove that
friction because what that friction
leads to and legacy systems are a huge
part of that friction
is
long lead times, fragile deployments,
and your architectures just don't scale
because
the the the the effort to change the
system to get it to the point where it
can scale is just insurmountable. And
that that friction can be seen at the
engineering level with the engineering
teams um having difficulty. It can be
seen at at management level with
approvals, right? Um why is this going
to take so long? What is this big
investment in this thing that's not
going to provide any value to our our
direct value to our customers? Well,
it's going to provide long-term value to
our customers. In in 6 months, we'll be
able to um increase the number of users
that we have. And it it just often
doesn't fly because there's not a clear
understanding of of what it is. There's
not a clear understanding of what the
problem is and there's not a clear
understanding of how do we reduce the
friction in order to make things
successful. And once you have that
friction in these legacy systems and
there's nothing wrong with systems that
have been around for a long time, that's
that's not a legacy system. I mean, it
is, right? It's a system that's been
around for a long time. But for example,
Windows has been around for a really
long time. 1985
85 something like that. That's a really
long time, right? That's nearly is 40
years. 40 year 50 years of Microsoft.
They just celebrated their their their
50th anniversary and 40 years of Windows
at least. So why why don't we think of
Windows as a legacy system? because it's
continually updated and maintained and
people collaborate on how do we get rid
of these little frictions that come
along. It starts with a bit of
sandpaper, right, getting in our way.
Um, but it turns into a bunch of
boulders and the engine seizes up and we
can't move forward.
So, your legacy systems
are what's holding back your ability to
to innovate, to shorten your lead times,
to improve quality in your products, and
to scale your architectures. You need to
fix them.