the worst trait in unskilled scrum
Masters is probably
their thinking that they're the boss of
everybody thinking that they should be
telling people what to do thinking that
they should be micromanaging thinking
that they should be setting up the jira
environment thinking that they should be
allocating the work and all of that is
just crap has nothing to do with being a
scrum Master being a scrum Master is
about helping teams be more effective
and all of those things I can't think of
an easier way to make a team ineffective
focus on what helps the team stand on
their own be better at what they do
being visibly present
and yeah