there's a quote in um lean uh that's
stop starting and start
finishing um and it it's been around for
for quite some time it's something that
I use all the time with scrum teams as
well it's while it is predominantly a a
lean thing there's no reason why you
can't have lean stuff in empirical stuff
right there's no reason why those two
things can't go together and I think
it's really important for teams that are
doing anything right so we're we're
whatever type of work that we're doing
that we focus on finishing stuff not on
starting more stuff the
traditional kind of um idea is that the
more work or the fallacy is that the
more work we have underway the more that
we're doing which means that that people
people and teams people as well often
have they're juggling multiple things in
what it is that they do and when you're
juggling multiple things you tend to
find that less stuff gets done because
you spend a bunch of cognitive Cycles
context switching so if you think of the
the the work that uh Gerald Weinberg did
in his book systems thinking um you
might be um you might think of the
there's a graph that he has that has the
the number of projects and that are
underway and the amount of time that we
lose to contact switching and it's about
20% per thing so if you're doing two
things at once you're going to going to
lose 20% of your time that's just gone
right and it's it's gone to contact
switching it's gone to your cognitive
load it's gone to um you know you're
you're you're you're in the
shower in the morning and in instead of
the back of your brain solving the
complex cognitive problems that will
help your business be successful you the
back of your brain is sitting thinking
of uh how do I juggle these two projects
or these three projects how do I make
sure that I keep these three projects
worth of stakeholders happy how do I
juggle these these these things and if
the back of your brain is thinking about
how it would juggle those things you're
spending less time and less focus on
solving the actual problem that we're
here to solve that actually provides
your business with value there's no
value to your business in juggling
juggling five things right that your
business doesn't give a [ __ ] about that
all they care about is am I getting the
value that I expect to get um but there
is a big push especially from from from
especially from does leadership really
push this I think there's a little bit
of a fallacy there I don't think
leadership pushes it I think middle
management pushes it because middle
management is under pressure to get more
stuff done and if you're sitting on a
team and you have multiple Masters right
you've got multiple people telling you
what to do then um you're the one who
has to juggle those multiple things
whereas one of the things that we we
talk about in in in
scrum is having a single product owner
and that single product owner is that
that Focus for um um what are we going
to do next what are we working on um and
they become a little bit depending on
the way your organization is structured
this is not ideal right but if you have
that multiple voices in your
organization then the product owner
becomes the funnel that allows the team
to H to work on a single stream right
whereas the product owner has to deal
with all the different stakeholders and
and I'm not saying the team's not going
to help the rest of the developers are
going to going to help with that but the
product owner becomes that final say
that point of uh um that loom knitting
together all those uh different ideas
and threads into a into a single cookies
of story so that the team has has has
focus and can maximize the value and
lean talks about this as well but it
talks about having a definition of
workflow right if you're thinking of
cban a campan strategy you're going to
have that that definition of your
workflow you decide what it's going to
be and you're effectively going to
decide those things as well like
what things do we work on we're going to
limit our work in process for sure right
we're going to do that but then how do
we decide which thing we pick um and a
lot of teams pick the oldest thing
whatever the thing that's been hanging
around the longest is the thing we're
going to pick and then from the options
right the stuff we haven't started yet
we're going to going to perhaps order
that by whatever we decide as the team
right that maximizes the value so you
might order it by you might order it by
age not sure that's the best idea or
order it by value would be best right
have the highest value stuff we're going
to pick next and then we pull Things
based on based on that value and that
need um
so lean focuses on perhaps that idea of
the virtual product
owner for that for creating that Loom
right the virtual Loom to manage the
threads
um whereas scrum talks about it as an
individual a person who's going to going
to do that but the outcome is the same
you have a a a much tighter cohesive
story and focus for the team which is
really important and that's why we need
to um stop starting work and start
finishing work because ultimately the
more work we we we have in progress the
longer it takes to deliver and you can
see that if if you ever um used a a a
cumulative flow um diagram you can very
clearly see see when uh the lines you're
the amount of work you're starting and
the amount of work you're finishing when
when it gets further apart the amount of
uh uh things that you have in progress
right is increasing so the ver a
vertical line from the um uh the
starting line to the Finishing Line I
know you might have other lines in
between colorcoded right but from the
first start to the end that vertical
line I think it's the vertical line yeah
the vertical line is the the number of
items that you have in progress right so
if you you you count the items between
there so if you're getting further apart
then you're you're you're starting more
work than you're finishing and if the
lines are getting further apart then the
horizontal line is also getting further
further apart right and the horizontal
line is your approximate average cycle
time so as you start more things and you
haven't finished
them all of the things that are in the
system take longer to deliver and that's
not what we want we want to we want to
have as short uh um a a time that we're
working on things as possible because
that
increases the the the throughput right
the stuff delivered for the business and
if we're focused on valuable stuff it
hopefully maximizes the value that we're
delivering to the business and we can go
through that process really quickly
which means the business gets
predictability because they know if they
give us a thing onto our onto our H uh
um an important thing and we take it on
immediately they know roughly how long
it's going to take to deliver it right
because it's and it will be short
because we're we're we're focusing on
shorting that that cycle time and I
think that that's that idea
behind stop starting work and start
finishing work and it matters for lean
teams it matters for scrum teams it
matters for all teams stop starting work
start finishing it if you want to have a
discussion about your unique needs or
situation then please book a call or
visit us at naked agility tocom uh we
also have our immersive and traditional
public classes on our website and we'd
love to hear from you