we're going to look at installing a
standard single server and for TFS so
the first thing I'm going to do
is install SQL
Server there we
go this will run the secet server
install have to apply service pack one
afterwards in order to install TFS 2013
now we're going to select a new SQL
Server Standalone we'll add the features
to it now we're doing a single server
everything on the one box and I am
joined to a domain and so we can get all
the the goodness of credentials
so I now have a a warning for the
firewall which I'm not worried about
because it's going to be all in one box
um and it's completed all the kind of
prerequisite tasks that it's uh squl
needs so we're going to do a SQL Server
feature installation um we don't really
need the other uh features at the moment
and we're we're going to configure some
of the
things so in order to do a a kind of
full standard TFS install we need the
database Engine Services and include the
full text uh for search we need that for
TFS we're also going to install analysis
services and Reporting Services now what
I usually do when I installing uh SQL
servers I'll also install the management
tools but which allow us access uh to
configure and operate SQL server and we
don't really need to be able to do much
and because TFS is going to manage the
for us um
but that should give us um all of the
capabilities that we
need so I'm just going to take the
default instance name um that tends to
be um prefer especially if you're just
doing a single server
install as for service accounts um you
want to try and leave it as the default
if you can and these service accounts
are all preconfigured in Windows to
operate as you as you would expect and
in a single server instance where we
don't need communication with SQL Server
from outside of the server this is the
best option and to be honest even on
multi- server deployments this is the
best option as well as long as your
network will support it and it depends
the version of active directory I'm
running uh 2012 hour two active
directory so I shouldn't have any
problems now uh by default there are no
users specifically added um to connect
to TF so I'm going to add the current
user uh which is
myself and I'm also going to add uh the
service account under which uh TFS is
going to run so that
is TFS service I'm fairly sure there we
go TFS
service I'm going to make sure that has
access and I'm going to leave the data
directories and the file stream as is
you may want to put the data directories
on a separate Drive we're going to have
backup set up later um so that shouldn't
be an issue analysis Services um we are
going to install in multi-dimensional
and data mining mode this is the only
mode that's supported currently by TFS
Jeff levenson has a um module for
enabling a tabular mode but you need a
separate analysis server that plugs into
the existing Data Warehouse in order to
achieve that so again I'm going to add
the current user and add a TFS service
there we go and for reporting Services
we're going to install and configure and
we require the configuration so that
there's a database there waiting for us
if we do install only we wouldd have to
configure reporting Services manually
afterward cut
there we're going to use uh install and
configure um if we don't do uh configure
we have to configure it manually
afterwards and this just take a little
bit of time to create the database
that this will do it for
us
so you can check that you have
everything ready to install and make
sure that you have the correct account
setup and then just click
install
e
e e
there we go we have um SQL Server
installed with the management tools
database engine analysis services and
Reporting services
so now all we need to do is make sure
that we have service pack one applied so
let me copy service pack one onto this
machine service pipe one is about a gig
um so it may take a moment to run
and I
that there we go on S pack
here we go let start the update
fantastic now we have a SQL Server
service pack one all installed and
configured so let me close
that now we need to install team
Foundation
server so let me
open my team foration server
dis now we should be able to just
install uh straight forward team
Foundation server and then when the
wizard comes up after the install is
complete we're going to pick the
standard single server
option
for
for e
there we go the installation of TFS is
complete we still have to configure it
it's not really installed yet it's just
the files are there um and we're just
going to pick a trial license just now
you'll get your actual license off
msdn
awesome we can now run a standard uh
single server
install now we want to use the the
default instance
of um SQL
server and if this wasn't a Server 2012
R2 which doesn't support SharePoint
2013 and then it would install
SharePoint 2013 for us just the default
SharePoint Foundation um that will be
supported from service pack one of
SharePoint 2013 but it's just not there
yet now if you want to use remote uh
database servers remote uh SharePoint or
reporting Services then you would want
to use an advanced installation but at
the moment we're just going to take the
kind of
um vanilla version of TFS out of the box
standard single server if I start the
wizard so you have a couple of things
that I need to configure
um let me next there we go so I need a
service
account and we can use the test button
to check whether we've entered the
username and password correctly which we
have and then it's going to run a bunch
of system checks on whether it can
install a SharePoint on this machine
which it should come back and this is
correct it will say h we have two issues
one is we need a minimum of 8 gig memory
in order to install SharePoint
Foundation which I've not got this
machine set to 8 gig memory um the other
one is that um SharePoint Foundation is
not supported in the operating system
we're
using and we just need to check this and
say yes we are happy to continue without
installing um SharePoint
Foundation you can review the
configuration it's going to
have we're going to run the Readiness
checks so it's going to make sure that
the accounts that we've picked um are
going to H be able to communicate
properly that we can set up the server
that we can configure all the PC so
talking to reporting Services that's why
it's taking so long at this point
spinning up reporting Services the tier
and application analysis Services all of
those things are going to be
checked awesome so now that everything's
uh verified here we click the configure
button
okay now that uh TFS is installed
successfully
configured and we can finish up now if I
just go to the URL for TFS a quick test
to make sure everything's working we'll
see that at the moment we get a a popup
box this is actually a security thing
because we're on the server and but if I
go to
and put in
password and we will get TFS up running
so let me close that and you see we've
completed the configuration and we could
go on and configure the build server or
any the other PCS but I'm just going to
close this just now and you'll see there
we go we get this uh
um Internet Explorer security thing and
then we get JavaScript is disabled and
all this kind of Malak so let me quickly
fix
that if you want to fix this open up
your server manager go to local
server I enhanced security is on turn it
off cuz we actually want to be able to
use this
computer and now we go
to and will'll get our connected into
our TFS server and that's everything up
and running we've installed TFS if I
open up the admin tool you'll see that
we have the TFS
RTM
um and we indeed have one collection
with no team projects
currently no team projects we don't have
uh SharePoint configured but we do have
reporting Services configured analysis
services and all of those things and
that will be building the warehouse uh
behind the scenes that will take a
little while and usually 2 to 3 hours to
to get that all configured and this is a
completely blank server so it's probably
done already um but it will work away in
the background and that's your TFS
server
configured if I want to create a team
project which is the main test of TFS
working and it hits pretty much all the
components of TFS so if I open up uh
Visual
Studio I go to Team
Explorer if I connect into my TFS
server and click create team project
now that's going to be a little bit out
of the bounds of the
display let's call
it my first team
project and we will pick the default
Visual Studio scrum 2013 which is the
only you know proper process
template uh we are going to pick git as
the vers control
system and we're going to click finish
perfect now we have my first team
project and we can go back over in our
server and if I refresh
this you'll see we have my first team
project in
here and if I open up the rasure
again oh I did that again
and we
browse my first team project and we can
navigate into that team project and
that's has done we have TFS installed
we've created our first team project and
everything's configured