foreign
so the question was
um why is Scrum so easy to understand
but incredibly difficult to master
and that that's an interesting and
recently contentious one because there's
there's there seems to be a prevailing
idea that if something is difficult and
hard and lots of people can't do it
that it must be inherently broken
and to that I would say I I'm not gonna
win a hundred meters race in the
Olympics no matter how hard I try and
does that mean that that sport is
inherently broken no it just means that
I can't do it I can try really hard and
I could probably with lots of practice
learn to run pretty fast without falling
on my face although that might be
difficult but the reality is that
um
it it it's only difficult
because of our inherent baggage right
um if you think about the the
tayloristic practices of the past and
how they impose themselves throughout
the entire hierarchy of an organization
the entire structure of an organization
and we're we're talking about moving to
something different and scrum's purpose
one of one of scrum's purposes is
transparency
right it's designed so that by
implementing it
it makes transparent
things that make empiricism difficult in
your organization
so it's gonna be hard right because lots
of organizations are not set up for
accepting empiricism right many
organizations have vanity metrics have
have uh uh enforced ways of working that
work for one team over here somewhere
but don't work for all of these other
teams so
um that idea that that scrum is easy to
understand I think is also has a little
bit of a fallacy because it's not that
easy to understand if it was easy to
understand you wouldn't have thousands
of books on the Chrome guide right it's
it's not easy to understand the the
it's easy to read the words it's fast to
read the words
but understanding the theory and first
principles that are embedded in there
understanding the the the like what are
we at what is the purpose
for for each of the events what are we
supposed to get out of it because almost
almost all
um of the events that teams do that I go
see
um are are don't fulfill the purpose
described in the Chrome guide right
um a good example of that is the the
Sprint review
um the purpose of the Sprint review
is to figure out what's next
it's to to to take into account since
the last Sprint review the product has
changed the business has changed
right they might change their mind they
might change direction the market might
have changed
how did those things affect the
transparency of the product backlog If
the product backlog is meant to be a
transparent list of our current best
understanding of what's next
how does what's happened in the last two
weeks affect that
and and very rarely do I find teams
actually walking out of Sprint planning
with an updated product backlog right
with with that information embedded in
there they've they've reordered the
backlog with the stakeholders they've uh
brought in that information they've
asked the right questions what I see
most teams do is they demo the product
ask for feedback they don't get any
feedback or limited feedback or that one
person that shouts and then they're done
that's not a Sprint review right so
that's that's why it's it's not easy to
understand and it's not hard to do sorry
yeah it's not easy to understand it's
hard to do and the outcomes that people
get are so varied because of those
incompatibilities between what people
interpret as The Thing versus the actual
thing and that that I think is
um
it's not it's I was going to say that
that's frustrating right but I don't
think it is I think it's part of the fun
right it's it's how do we how do we how
every company need every company and
every team needs to be unique otherwise
there's no point in them being there
right if I can just get another team to
do it or another company to provide that
product why would I use your company
versus that company it all comes down to
price right it shouldn't be about price
it's about value that's being delivered
how do you create an organizational
structure how do you create a team ethos
a product that is unique and distinct in
the markets so that you build more value
and that that that's that's these unique
interpretations of the scrum guide these
unique uh practices that you add to the
scrum guide scrum's just a little
rulebook right it's like when you go out
and buy Monopoly it comes with a rule
book not a strategy guide you need to
add those strategies you need to figure
out based on the game that we're playing
of Building Products potentially
software
what are the tools that I need to make
that successful what are the additional
practices I need to add to make that
successful what are the choices I have
and the way I do it that makes me my
product and my team distinctive in the
marketplace so that more people want my
stuff than my competitor's stuff that
for me is is is is is that it's it's why
scrum is easy to understand but
incredibly difficult to master because
products are doing businesses
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility