when we don't
deploy very frequently there are a
number of dysfunctional behaviors that
don't have to be there but tend to creep
in when when we're deploying bigger
chunks of work one of those things is
that we tackle bigger chunks of work
instead of taking a big thing and
breaking it down to smaller things um we
try and tackle that big thing and
because we tackled that big thing and
then we deploy it maybe after a couple
of months um maybe after a year that is
unlikely to be edited right we're not
going back around and editing that code
again and again and again maybe in 5
years time somebody will come back
around and add something to that
feature but if we're deploying more
frequently if we're deploying
faster then our deployment window
is smaller than the features that we're
delivering so we're thinking about how
do I take this big chunk of work and
break it down into smaller things that
have
value and if I'm deploying that smaller
thing that has value I'm probably going
to be thinking about well if customers
are using it I can look at the data of
how customers are using it and perhaps
change the way I build it so that's one
advantage
but the main advantage from a technical
debt that's from from a product value
standpoint the main advantage from a
technical debt
perspective is that when I'm writing
that
code I know that I'm going to have to go
edit it tomorrow to add the next
slice and perhaps edit it the day after
that to add the slice after that so I'm
thinking more about how do I make sure
that this code is
maintainable and supportable and
adaptable because either me myself or
one of my colleagues is going to be
coming and editing it tomorrow and you
don't want to I guess there's a little
bit of peer pressure right you don't
want to look bad in front like I shipped
some really bad code and my colleague
now has to go clean up my mess that's
that's not polite right because they've
got to go go go edit it again but even
if I'm doing it myself I'm editing it
again tomorrow I I don't know if you've
ever been in this position but quite
often when you find some some nasty code
something that's written very badly and
you want to go look up the blame tool to
find out who do I blame usually it's
yourself right you're the one who made
the made the mess and you don't remember
so even if you don't want to see
yourself that way as writing that that
messy code then we take a little bit
more care it's it's also worth noting
that if we're doing hypothesis driven
engineering in practices right so that
we can um collect Telemetry and data and
then validate whether we're actually
building the right thing then we're
perhaps only going to invest in the
second
slice if it's worth investing in it if
users are connecting to it if they still
desire to continue to invest in that
feature so quite sometimes it's going to
say quite often but sometimes we we we
actually want to do a quick job on the
First Slice so there's going we're
choosing to incur technical debt knowing
that we're going to be looking at the
Telemetry looking at the outcome and
seeing whether it resonates with users
and whether we continue to invest in it
or we take that chunk back out right so
so this frequent deployments can not
only help
developers tackle technical debt issues
because it just makes it harder to incur
technical debt right we we make it
easier to write good code because if
you're deploying to production at the
end of the
day it needs to be production ready by
the end of the day it needs to be
production ready ready every time I edit
the code it needs to be needs to be
production ready you're potentially
doing continuous delivery right every
every every thing that makes it into
main ends up in production every commit
perhaps makes it into production so
reducing those those those gaps enables
us to reduce technical debt because we
know we have to do a better job it
enables us to understand our customers
needs better because we can see them
interacting with the thing the partial
thing we have built in order to get
Telemetry and feedback and these small
changes help build confidence not only
in with the customer but build
confidence in the the the build
confidence in the product itself build
confidence in our ability to deliver and
continuously deliver those small changes
so when the systems that we're working
on are big and complex and have lots of
interactive
parts that's when we want to be
delivering smaller and smaller changes
so we can see immediately when things go
wrong obviously we need Telemetry and we
need observability of our system to be
able to do that but this is one of the
core practical steps that any
engineering team any developer can take
is make the batch size smaller right and
this works in a lot of cases but in this
particular case if you're delivering
code to production reduce the batch size
increase the frequency of delivery
deployment to production and you will
see an improvement in the code you will
see an improvement in the product and
hopefully that will result in happier
customers