so the applying flow metrics uh for
scrum course is an amazing class about
campan from the proam band.org about how
you would
Leverage The metrics and capabilities
that cban a cban strategy brings within
the context of a scrum team uh we're
going to be talking about how to how to
leverage the different uh data aspects
in in Sprint planning in Daily scrum
especially the other events
retrospective um what tools you can use
around product backlog refinement uh to
help you increase flow how you track
progress towards critical dates uh and
deliverables and to identify
opportunities for the team to ask more
interesting
questions and that's the purpose of the
applying flow metrics with scrum course
um it exists mainly because there are
lot lots of people who are doing scrum
in their organizations and they're
really struggling to uh deliver value at
the end of each Sprint to focus on that
value delivery and a camand strategy
enables you to focus on and increase the
flow of value delivery through your
system um so it really really really
benefits scrum teams I I I would
wouldn't want to be doing scrum without
this
capability um and it it it really helps
teams deliver on that value right and it
and it's really core focus on delivering
value not tasks but actual value to the
customers um so you should be able to
increase uh your your ability to deliver
make your stakeholders happier and your
business happier using these techniques
if you want to have a discussion about
your unique needs or situation then
please book a call or visit us at naked
agility tocom uh we also have our
imersive and traditional public classes
on our website and we'd love to hear
from you