there are lots of
misconceptions about what the
accountability of the scrum Master is
supposed to entail contain focus on um
most of this manifests because of the
difference
between an organizational role which
might include many accountabilities
including scrum Master even if it's
called scrum master um and uh the the
actual accountability as as as what
scrum talks about and what it genuinely
leads to because there's been so many
people that have transitioned from
whatever they did before into scrum
master so they might have been um
project managers they might have been
managers they might have been developers
right and they transition into the the
the role and they have limited
understanding of the the the the the
core principles and philosophies that
underpin scrum and underpin agile um
they end up making some very common um
mistakes so common that that you you'll
see um one of the most common responses
when people say uh oh scrums not working
we did this and the most common response
is that's not scrum and the reason
that's the most common response is
because the thing that they describe
rbe is not talked about in the scrum
guide it's not part of scrum it's not
pro might not even be part of anything
to do with anything to do with agile um
and people will say well but in scrum
you have to great example you have to
have a user
story user stories are not a scrum thing
you have to have a burndown if you don't
have a burndown you're not doing scrum
burnd Downs aren't a scrum thing burnd
Downs come from before or scrum and yes
they might have been encouraged uh for a
while but they're they're they're not in
the scrum guide anymore for sure um user
stories were never in the I don't think
they were ever in the scrum guide I
would need to go look at the history of
that thing but um I'm pretty sure they
don't planning poker not a scrum thing
user H story points not a scrum thing
all of these
things are
mechanisms that people have chosen to
use and might be quite common within the
context of scrum but that doesn't mean
there's something that you have to do
right if it's not working for you stop
doing it or pick something else right um
so one of the most common uh
dysfunctional behaviors that that I see
scrum Masters time after time doing is
focusing on mechanisms and the reason
this goes back to the confidence story
that we have the reason they're focusing
on mechanisms is they have no skills and
abilities and knowledge within the
context of the philosophy's principles
and theories if you don't understand the
philosophy's principles and theories you
can't apply them in new and interesting
ways you're going to look at what other
people are doing and just copy that so
you end up copying planning poker we're
just going to we're going to do planning
poker we're going to do user stories
we're gonna have a burndown we're going
to do those things that everybody else
is doing because I don't understand why
they're doing it I don't understand the
principles philosophies and theories
that underpin the reason this thing
isn't successful for this particular
team or this particular
company competence right move away from
these
mechanical practices that are a choice
and move
towards understanding the principles
theories and
philosophies another great uh most
common um scrum Master thing and is
actually the reason that agile coach
exists even though there's no such thing
as an agile coach is people think the
scrum Masters focuses on the
team it's not that's onethird
of their focus scrum Masters should be
focused on the team the product owner so
the business side and the organizational
structure and capability all three of
those things in equal measure are the
accountability of the scrum master so
focusing on the team means that you're
you you're perhaps creating suboptimal
improvements within that team that then
create an overall dysfunction in the
organization because you're you're not
doing you know all of if you're if
you're working in a team and it's within
the context of an organization and
you're trying to help that team and you
get them to do something that causes
friction with the rest of the
organization right you probably got a
suboptimal change what you should be
doing as a scrum Master instead of
making that change in this team and make
making them unpopular within the
organization because they're not doing
the things they need to do is to work on
changing the organization or perhaps
it's the right thing to do right just
change it and they see it's being
successful and now we can we can do that
but that's a
strategy are you using the correct
or most effective
strategy within the context of your
understanding as a scrum Master of the
theories principles um and philosophies
that you're trying to fulfill right that
will help you make those choices um
there's a whole bunch of uh
stanes uh we talk about stanes of the
scrum master um and and for me the
stanes coaching mentoring uh uh teaching
right these are stanes of the scrum
master and the the ones that we see time
and time again actually I have they're
they're so common they're included in
the advanced scrum master class because
they're so common does the scrum
police right that's not scrum or if
you're not doing user stories you're not
doing scrum or um oh you you the the
team shouldn't be talking to the
customer right all this crap um you've
got the the Scribe of the team so the
scrum Master writing things down for the
team the scrum
master has no in
general I'm using this for to highlight
a specific content context the scrum
master has no need to have permission to
J no no no specific need for that I I've
helped loads of teams that use jira and
I've never touched jira I've never been
an admin of jira um those are not part
of the SC Masters role and that brings
us to jira admin right um being the
chairman of the team being the secretary
of the team being a hero on the team all
of these are very dysfunctional
behaviors that are the
result of a lack of competence within
the context of scrum Mastery right um so
anytime a scrum Master is making
decisions they're not being a scrum
Master right any time they're they're um
hiring and firing although those are
things they might do right it's
absolutely possible for a scrum Master
to also be the manager of a team
therefore they might be accountable in
the organizational context in addition
to them being a scrum Master for the
team they're also accountable for
reports for hiring and firing for
decision making right for for for other
things but that's not the focus of the
scrum master and if those other things
are
conflicting
with enabling the effectiveness of the
team then they become something that
it's expected that scrum Master to try
and
address
right
so this
this idea of the scrum Master the reason
they moved it
from talking about it as a role to
talking about it as
accountabilities is because most people
in organizations have multiple sets of
accountabilities right and not all of
them are scrum related scrum is not your
whole world when you're a developer when
you're a product
owner when you're when you're a scrum
Master if you're a scrum Master you
might also be a manager you may be a
delivery manager accountable for
delivery accountable for other things
right you might be accountable for for
um uh uh uh reviews you might be
accountable for various things if you're
a product owner you're
probably a product manager you're
accountable for other things within the
organization if you're a developer
although you're doing scrum you might
also be accountable for other things in
the organization you might support and
maintain things that are different from
what it is your main piece that you're
working on so
there are so many common
misconceptions and I I feel like these
misconceptions are so common that they
become
fact they become true like you must do
story points you must have user
stories try and move away from those
things try and look at do do your
research right understand why those
things exist and perhaps they are the
right thing for your organization or
your team but also perhaps they're not