so the product development Mentor
program for software organizations is
designed around
helping people that actually build the
products so in scrum we would call those
folks the developers right but that
includes testers coders it includes
analysts it includes product owners it
includes cyber security operations it
includes all of the people involved in
building and creating a product and the
product development Mentor
program is how do
we build in excellence to the way we do
things how do we enable um happy
creative people who are working together
towards a common goal right I I don't
know if you've noticed or I don't know
if you've thought about this but unhappy
sad people don't build amazing
products if the people that work on your
product feel like they're unable to
achieve the things that they're asked to
achieve by the business they're going to
be unhappy if they feel like the things
that they're doing don't add value to
the organization they're going to be
unhappy if they feel like that they know
how to do something better than other
people that are telling them how to do
it in the organization they're going to
be unhappy unhappy sad people don't
build amazing products so how do we turn
that around and enable the people in
your
organization to step up we have to
enable them to step up and be able to
deliver the highest possible value and
that means they're going to have to be
happy and engaged in what it is they're
doing they're we're going to have to
look at things not just around the the
the the the the process like your ways
of work and how you manage that work but
how do you manage dependencies how do
you do devops and continuous delivery
how do you do testing how do you
integrate more feedback loops into your
process for all of those different
process control systems that you might
have within your organization and build
a story and a culture of engineering
Excellence within your
organization because that happy
motivated once things to be successful
wants things to be valuable for their
customers and for them and for your
business is the mindset that we want in
people that are all working together
towards building this product it's not
just enough to have that direction right
although that's quite a lot of the story
they also need the knowledge and skills
they need to understand the theory
behind why we're doing things a certain
certain way so that they can take that
story forward it's not them doing it a
particular way because they've been told
to they understand the theories and
principles behind the things that we're
trying to do they understand why they
need to pay more attention to the
quality of the product they understand
why they need to be trying to engage
with the customers more every developer
in your organization should be able to
engage with customers almost every
developers should be able to engage with
customers and communicate with them
effectively so that we can maximize the
value because ultimately the people that
are doing the work on the teams that are
working on your product are the ones
that are making the majority of the
decisions even if you feel like that's
not true it is true they're making the
majority of the decisions every day
every person on every team in your
organization is making hundreds if not
thousands of micro decisions that will
impact the future of the product the
future of how users use it and they're
not asking anybody because they don't
believe that anybody else would
understand the situation right so the
way I think about it is if I was I'm my
background is software engineering so if
I was making a decision on uh whether I
use an array or a linked list right
linked list might be more efficient for
the thing that I'm trying to do but if
I'm looking forward into the future if
I'm thinking about what is it we're
trying to achieve I'm collaborating
heavily with the business I understand
the goals and objectives of what it is
we're trying to achieve I've been
communicating with customers and I
understand their wants needs and desires
I might realize that a linked list is
not the best
uh solution for this particular problem
and I should use the less efficient
array because it's going to provide us
with more benefits going forward into
the future and that sort of choice
that's just one choice that might have
taken me 20 seconds to make a a and a
couple of hours of
implementation in my the system but that
could have a implication on what it is
we're able to do tomorrow what it is
we're able to do next week um and it
would take a bunch of rework to go back
and make those changes later now we want
to be able to go make those changes
later which is why good testing good
architectures engineering Excellence
will mean we
can but what if we could make more of
the right decisions and every single
person on the team could make more of
the right decisions as we flow towards
the end of our product because the
further we get down that line of of
building our product the more of our
product we've actually created right our
inventory of product is bigger and
making changes to that rearranging the
warehouse right if you've got 10 things
in your Warehouse it's super easy to
rearrange if you've got a 100,000 things
in your Warehouse it's not very easy to
rearrange right and the chances of
something going wrong something going
missing all of those things is is pretty
high how do we create an environment
within which those things are just not
true we're not going to have we're gen
in general we're not going to have those
mistakes because everybody is paying
attention to what it is we're trying to
do we're working together towards that
common goal we're making decisions based
on the best possible outcomes with the
inbuilt knowledge of what's happening in
the future intent based leadership right
how do we create that story at the team
level so that we're all going in the
same direction