oh I kind of like that question what's
the difference between a newbie scrum
master and a professional scrum master I
I feel like neither of
um
I feel like neither of those things
exist right I think that's that's that's
where I would go initially and I would
say that there's no such thing as a
newbie scrum master
you you become a scrum Master because
you've demonstrated that competence
um in in your team to be able to help
them be more effective right so you're
not really a newbie you're just picking
up that accountability of the scrum
Master you are an experienced uh
effective professional at that point
when you pick up the accountability of
the scrum master so I feel like that
that newbie is a bit of a bit of a thing
and really there's the there's no such
thing as a professional scrum Master
that's just a scrum master
right just as there's no such thing as a
newbie scrum Master a professional scrum
Master is is scrum.org's brand of how
they explain things
but if you look at the scrum guide it
doesn't talk about professional scrum
master or true scrum master or certified
scrum Master right doesn't talk about
any of those things because there is
just the scrum master
and I think
um
if we were to look at professional scrum
master and see well what is it it's
trying to create that idea around
we need to approach the role of a scrum
Master From A A professional's
perspective it's it's not just we're not
just playing the scrum master we're not
just uh uh uh decking around as the
scrum Master where it's a professional
role that provides value to the
organization it provides value to the
team it's picking up accountabilities
that that perhaps if everybody on the
team picked them up because maybe
everybody on your team is capable of
picking up the accountabilities of the
scrum Master the the team would have a
hard time getting anything done if
everybody's picking that up so that's
that's one person who the team respects
says well I'll pick up some of these
things and go sort them out so that so
that you can all focus on delivering
valuable product and being as effective
as you can at delivering valuable
product and here's some things that I'm
going to pick up and help up with and
help enable you as a team to do
um the the
something so that we can all get on with
the stuff that we need to do right and I
think that's that's that idea that
scrum.org is trying to sell of the
professional scrum master of
professional scrum is that
um we're doing the thing
rather than going well you know we you
know we we I'm going to be the scrum
Master but in actual fact it's Sprint
planning I'm gonna you know tell the
team right you're not taking on it
you've not taken on enough work this
Mark this Sprint I'm sure you can fit
some more work in there oh Bob have you
you don't have enough stuff assigned to
you I think some more stuff uh you can
take on some more stuff this print right
and and and that idea of well that
that's not
scrum Master right that's that's that's
uh that's uh well I guess I might say
that's a project manager but even if if
you were a project manager and you were
doing that you kind of suck at project
management too
so so that's just somebody who sucks
that's not a professional
if when you're a professional you you
you figure out what what are the things
I can do to help my team be more
effective right help the group of people
that I'm working with or that I'm
managing right it doesn't matter what
terminology you use how do you help that
group be more effective stop doing
things that that are less effective or
try and change things in your
organization are less effective and
increase their effectiveness that's
really all we're talking about from from
a professional scrum Master perspective
is
do the thing don't just
mess about the edges of the thing
actually do it
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility