are teams empowered to change their
process based on what they
learn if they're not then they're
probably not very
agile in order to maximize the
effectiveness of the teams that we have
and in order to maximize the value of
the work that they do get our maximum
return on investment the people doing
the work the teams themselves need to be
able to change the way that they work to
suit the Nuance of the tools practices
and techniques that are best suited to
their context and their context might be
different from another team that's even
doing very similar work ensure that your
teams are empowered to change their
process so you can maximize the value
and the return on investment for your
stakeholders