what does failure look like for a
product owner
um I think I think it's it's very
quantifiable what failure looks like for
a product owner
um if if
you see a product
um that has per quality or
low value inconsistent delivery
probably a sign of a failing product
owner
um if the product owner is sitting there
just writing the requirements
I'm not doing much else they're just
writing the requirements perhaps
ordering them but they're taking orders
from somebody else that's probably a
failing product owner
if if you ask people in the organization
or even on the team what is the vision
of the product what is it that we're
trying to achieve and they don't have an
answer or say well that sits on the wiki
right if people don't intrinsically know
uh what that is then we're probably
failing as a product owner
um if if we're as the product owner not
in control of the evolution and
direction of the product
um I maybe wouldn't put that in the
absolute failing category but we're
definitely not doing very well as a
product owner if we're not able to
influence and control the direction of
the product based on our understanding
of the market right that's something
that we we really do need to be able to
do
um not and that comes to the next one
which is not taking actual ownership of
the product this is our product we're
building this product we are making
decisions we're taking the risks we're
spending the money it needs to be our
product so taking that ownership
um of that is really important
um
and if it's all about perception over
reality then that's definitely a failing
product owner
um do we want the numbers to look good
or do we want to actually deliver value
in the product which brings in more
Revenue brings in more capability to the
organization
um there's a lot of focus on vanity
metrics in the industry and metrics if
you don't know that expression is
metrics that just uh make us look good
like a burn down being on the on the
line right so what does that actually
tell us anything about the product can
you be on that line and uh things still
suck yes of course you can
so let's focus on vanity metrics more on
reality of the product what's going on
what we need to do like uh Satya
um writing down eight billion dollars
for Nokia that's looking at the reality
of the situation
um and understanding it and rather than
Reaching For Fairies and Magic that
we're going to be successful with this
going
no we're done we need to cut our losses
on that
that's what being a product well that's
what a failing product owner looks like
right
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility