automated testing is extremely important
to our ability to use modern software
engineering
to benefit our organization and and
increase our our our profit increase our
margins increase our capability and
deliver better quality higher value
software to our to our customers so
automated testing comes in lots of
different flavors there and I'm
definitely going to stretch the term
automated testing maybe from your tra
traditional
concept um one of the things that
automated testing does is it reduces
human errors right you would think I
used to teach uh a training class I I
still have it on my my um list of things
for manual testers to use as your devops
test tools and you would we had labs in
it you would think that if there was one
group of people
that were awesome at following a set of
steps from a from set of steps and
validating whether that they worked or
not you would think that a group of
testers would be that that magical group
of people that would be able to do that
and it's absolutely not not the case
most of the groups that were doing the
labs failed to follow the steps and
resulted in the this lab's not working
this lab doesn't work right and it's
like yeah it does it does did you follow
all the steps yes yes yes we followed
all the steps and then you sit with them
and they walk through it and I'm like
you missed step four you didn't do step
four or you didn't do the second part of
step four or whatever it is right you
didn't follow the instruction and this
is just a human thing this is not
a an assassination attempt on testers
it's just how humans work right so you
cannot expect somebody to follow a set
of steps and do it the same every time
that's not how humans function so the
that's how computers function so we want
to take those things that make
sense and convert them into automated
tests now that's not we're not looking
for a particular level of code coverage
although node code coverage is probably
bad chasing code coverage is always a
bad idea because you'll just have lots
of people writing terrible tests that
get you good code coverage but don't
actually validate your product right so
don't don't chase code coverage or test
coverage but it is a way for us to get
faster feedback right we want to have
fast running automated tests that we can
validate the changes that we make on a
continuous basis tdd results in some of
those right some tests out of TD are
like that most tests out of tdd validate
that that at least the product does what
the software engineer intended it to do
and validates that we've we've got an
architecture that probably is a little
bit better that's hopefully part of that
that that testing mode but the value in
automated testing is it happens the same
every time you do need to balance this
idea of test infrastructure right
because when we write test automation we
have a body of tests and whenever we
make a change to our product is going to
have an impact on those tests they used
to be a great feature in in azure devops
that had something called test impact
analysis and you could make a change in
the code and it would tell you exactly
which code paths had changed and tell
you which tests were impacted I think
there was a lot of false negatives which
is why it's not well thought of but it
it it was a great idea right a great
idea how do we know what tests we need
to run well let's look at what's changed
and what the tests hit and are we
missing something and which tests need
be rerun in order to to to know reducing
your test
Matrix but because that fundamentally
doesn't work because of complexity right
that's what got in the way complexity of
software engineering we need to run them
all which means they all need to be
super
fast we need we need unit tests not end
to end tests not integration tests we
need unit tests that run really really
quickly and thousands of them in
milliseconds the Azure devops team moved
from long running end to end tests to
fast running unit tests and took their
test strategy their test infrastructure
from 72 hours down to 3 and a half
minutes almost to run their entire test
infrastructure that's what you're
looking to be able to do and that's that
there's something like 60 100 between 60
and 100,000 tests being run to validate
that their product still works that's
the story that you're looking for you're
you're looking for small lean discrete
tests that don't have impact across the
entire platform so that when you make a
change in this part of the system you
only need to change the tests in that
part of the system all the other tests
should still pass because you've not
broken what they're expecting in other
parts of the system and it gives you a
good indication so so having this tight
test infrastructure shifting left as
much as you can can and automating
everything the phrase I usually say is
if it can be automated it should be
automated and if it can't be automated
it should be refactored so that it can
right automate everything you should not
have any
manual
steps between developer cutting code and
production the only thing that I'd say
was a valid place where you put a a a a
a block a human between those things is
maybe an approval but I would prefer for
those approvals to be automated right on
what basis does this human decide
whether we're a go no go for release
well they do they look at this data well
we can automate that they they they they
look at the calendar and they only do it
on these days well we can we can look at
that we can say we only release on on on
Monday mornings right to give us maximum
amount of time to deal with any problems
never release on Friday don't do that CL
strike did that don't do that we can do
all of those things we can automate
everything so that we have that
engineering Excellence modern software
engineering Excellence built into our
entire
story so that we can then spend the time
that we would have spent doing all those
things manually and fixing all those
problems focusing on delivering the
value that's going to generate the
revenue that we need to grow and create
create more that's what we should be
focusing on and test automation is a
huge part of that to reduce the number
of problems that make it through to
production to reduce the amount of time
it takes to detect that you've injected
problems into the system and we can help
you create those strategies build that
engineering Excellence within your
organization and ultimately build better