question was why did I choose the
scrum.org track rather than the scrum
Alliance track and the initial the
initial Choice was kind of not a choice
at all
um I kind of fell into the scrum.org
track right around the time that that
Ken left
separated from scrum Alliance and
founded scrum.org
um a few months after that I
participated in training from Richard
hundhausen
um who created the professional scrum
developer which is now the applying
professional scrum with software
development
um I I participated in love beta for his
class in Australia so I flew down to
Australia to to do that I became uh uh
uh the idea was to become a professional
scrum trainer with scrum.org and it was
funded by my boss at the time Adam Cogan
uh so I can blame Adam for for for that
that choice there
um but I think the reason I've stayed
with scrum.org is because of a number a
business ethos like I don't like working
with organizations
that I feel and this this is very
personal I feel
um don't
um respect the topic respect the people
respect the customer
and I feel like scrum.org do a very good
job of that I feel like
um this this idea that you can you as
the customer right you're coming for
training that you can you magically
forget your your all your knowledge
every two years and the way you get that
knowledge back is to pay two hundred
dollars right that doesn't sit well with
me I prefer the scrum.org model where
um once you've got a certification
you've got it right like your driver's
license or uh your University degree
you've got it you've passed bar and then
if you want to dive more deeply and
increase your knowledge there are other
bars that you can also add to your story
but that's up to you right that's your
choice whereas that idea that your
knowledge is taken away and you have to
re-certify as that's how that one's crap
um and I feel like the investment the
the scrum.org has made in
the idea of community
that we are one group of of of trainers
that we collaborate that we have shared
courseware that we all contribute to so
if you take a class in in uh in Africa
or China or Australia or the UK or the
US you're going to get
class that consists of the same
fundamental ideas it's going to consist
of the same story right
um and that comes through the the the
consistent courseware uh the steward
system have a steward system for
managing that courseware
um and the the constant sharing that we
do as a as a community so for example a
lot of uh we use mural now in the
virtual space right
um and scrum.org provides standard
murals that are as generic as possible
like they don't tell the trainer how to
teach their class they don't tell the
trainer what to say but here's a flow
with the exercises and the knowledge
that we want to want to share in it
um and then I have my own version of the
murals that I share back to the
community and my murals are more
specific right I include liberating
structures trading from some of the
training from the back of the room
content
um I I have created my own ways of
telling stories of doing exercises and I
create those murals and then I share
them back to the PST community so other
psts can leverage them so that
the greater the community as a whole
um the the the the the more powerful it
is in in telling its story right if all
the Traders are better then the whole
story is better and I think that's
really important so it's that sense of
community that I like and I've been a
PST for let's have a look 13 years 13
years now I was back in early in 2010
that I started this journey
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility