one of the really interesting um
articles that I've seen in the last few
years has been from a little
organization that you might have heard
of called the US Department of
Defense um they released an article
called the dib guide to detecting agil
BS um this was sent out to all of their
procurement officers uh worldwide so
that they could tell what whether the
vendors that they were hiring because
they're the procurement officers right
um were actually agile or were just
making it up right because one of the
problems that they ran into was right at
the start um they realized that when
they switched over to Agile procurement
terms so H back in
2013 um the US Department of Defense
updated their main procurement terms to
require iterative and incremental
delivery of any any product or system um
when they move to that model their
vendors just all immediately declared
themselves to be agile right the next
day oh yeah we're agile we do it in an
agile way um but most of them were
lying and something that I found working
with
organizations and I'm going to use the
word that's quite dramatic right um most
organizations that say they're doing
agile are also
lying right I've being dramatic but uh
they kind of are so um the detecting
agile uh BS article came up with a whole
bunch of questions it's totally worth
going reading it uh but there are six
main questions which I think are the
most important pieces of the story this
was the questions to leadership within
the
organization so I'd like you to think
about these
questions from your perspective within
your organization if you asked your
leadership if this is true across the
board in your organization um is it is
it true so there get six questions so
the first one is are teams delivering
working software to at least some subset
of users every iteration including the
first and Gathering
feedback think about that every single
iteration you should be delivering
working product to real
users not uat not a test environment
real production users every iteration
including the first now that's really
hard lots of teams struggle
with creating working product with
getting that working product out the
door and even more like Gathering
feedback it's that's almost as rare as
delivering working product so what what
this is effectively saying is that if
you as a as a team or you're part of the
organization is unable to deliver
working software to production on a
regular Cadence you're probably not
being very agile right um and ideally uh
you want to be delivering on a on a very
regular Cadence so the agile Manifesto
would talk about um from a couple of
weeks from a few weeks to a couple of
months I think is the phrasing it uses
with a preference to the shorter time
scale so you probably shouldn't go two
months without um shipping to production
and then for the scrum guide it talks
about no more than every 30 days so it
puts a hard one month uh uh uh figure on
that 30 days and yeah that that can be
difficult for organizations there's lots
of organizations out there that have
made this change um no organization that
has made this change to
Wars continuous delivery to production
has gone back and decided not to do it
anymore right once you get there the
level of quality that you need in your
product the engagement you get with your
customers these are all things that are
are much much much higher once you get
there and nobody wants to go back uh but
getting there is difficult takes time
investment in in skills for your
engineering teams in skills for
leadership in changes to your business
practices um to make that in any way in
any way viable but is absolutely worth
it and even the US Department of Defense
uh requires that their vendors are able
to deliver working software to real
users every iteration including the
first if your answer to any one of these
questions or the answer of your business
to any one of these questions is no
we're not doing that then you would
probably I probably wouldn't consider
that you're already in the agile space
right you're not already agile you might
be working towards it and you might have
put in loads of effort but unless you
can Mark every single one of these six
questions as yes we do this this is how
things work here then we're still
lacking we're still trying we're still
working towards being agile now this is
just a litmus test dreamed up uh by uh
the US Department of Defense but they
are probably the least likely place for
you to expect something um with this
High a bar to have come from and I'm not
going to um go into a team uh and work
with a team or a company and if they're
not doing these things then I'm going to
say well you guys suck you're not agile
because you're not doing this that's
that's not how we work towards
success uh but I think it's hugely
valuable from the perspective of
self-reflection for you all to think
about the processes and practices in
your organization and are you a how many
of these six questions are you able to
achieve and what could you do to make it
a little bit easier for the teams for
the people doing the work to work
towards this
idea of not being agile BS