do you think that we are in the slope
of Enlightenment in Garner's hype cycle
and I would maybe have to say
not yet I think that's going to be my my
answer I think we're still in the trough
of disillusionment right and I think the
reason the reason I think that is
perhaps I'm wrong right but every time I
uh uh turn on my my LinkedIn I'm reading
the feeds I'm I'm seeing what's going on
every time I look it's uh uh scrum sucks
scrum doesn't work safe sucks safe
doesn't work uh agile 2.0 is the way
forward agile 1.0 is dead
um agile is dead right there's all all
these types of posts there's still a
significant
and I think majority of people are still
in that trough of disillusionment does
that mean that lots of companies are not
already in the slope of Enlightenment I
I think they are I think lots and lots
of organizations out there lots of
people uh um um are in in that slope of
Enlightenment already
um but there are lots of organizations
out there who just just haven't made it
yet there's people out there who are
still
um disillusioned that they can't have
twice the features in half the time
Jeff's book title didn't help with that
right because it sets a level of
expectation lots of people don't even
read the book which is there's a little
bit of bit going on that's not really
what it's about right but
um that that that that that
belief of what agile was supposed to
deliver
um
most organizations have not really
worked out the hard work that is
involved in actually doing it and
getting there and it's not a magic wand
that's going to going to going to solve
their problems so I think I think
there's still a huge number of people in
that uh trough of disillusionment I love
that phrase
um but as as I think I think we're
definitely on that upward turn of that
slope and there's definitely more
certainly the early adopters and even ow
could I say the late major some of the
late majority the early majority sorry
some of the early majority are already
um in in that Enlightenment mode that
they realize that
um it's not all the hype that is the
important but it's the fundamental
change in the way we work and the way we
understand how we do things and that
realization that it's people that solve
problems not tools right
um it's people that solve problems not
bureaucracy
um and putting putting truly truly
putting people first and being willing
to dismantle
um whatever
processes practices or tools
ways of doing things are getting in the
way of people actually doing the work
that they need to do and and helping the
business
be successful right
um I think that's that's that's where we
are right now but we're we're the we're
certainly on the little up up of that
slope I think
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility