[Music]
this
i am going to i'm going to get started
i'm pretty sure
that that more people will drop in i i
have found that in this live virtual
world
um many people forget about meetings
that's one thing
um and they realize late like when they
get that little pop-up on
teams or whatever that the meeting has
started um
and i'm sure i'll be forever clicking
the approve the lobby button
um that i have i should probably
actually turn the lobby off i thought it
would be a good idea
um but as it turns out it's just more
work
yeah there's another lobby admit george
there we go so let me save that
so now everybody should bypass the lobby
if it goes all the way through
so um i am going to stick
uh the link to the mural in the chat and
i'll need to keep
posting it in the chat just because um
things things go missing in um
these chat programs when it's uh live
virtual so let me
so there is a there is a pin i think
there is a pin message feature
but the pin message so that was shelton
was asking
is there not a pin message feature there
is um but
not if we're in our
um webcast because
i think you guys lose access to the
webcast when
uh we we we leave um but i'll have all
of the
the the materials and stuff uh for you
later so um if everybody could join
the mural i am not going to be sharing
my screen um it's going to be all done
through
through mural that's how i teach my
classes as well
uh so next week i'm what am i teaching
next week i have
uh applying professional scrum with
software delivery
for a private customer over in the u.s
and then i have a a public
uh um psm2
in nigeria um so it's in a nigerian time
zone so that's i think that's an hour
ahead of me
in the uk no it's exactly the same as me
in the uk this is the
the downside of international stuff
is i wonder how many time zones
um we have in the room just now yeah
i bet there's a few i can see george is
here so i know that there's some
uh hi george some folks some definitely
some folks from the us
uh some folks from europe uh there's
probably some folks from further
further afield uh depending on how the
time zone fits for people so it's it's
8 00 a.m in pacific time
all the way through to well i've only
got eest here which is
6 p.m what time is a few george
it's six o'clock yep i thought you're
greece
aren't you yeah yeah that was that was a
good remembering
um so i can see there's uh quite a few
people uh join the mural
we have uh seven
seven seven people in the mural uh but
there are
15 people in the call so some people
that haven't joined the mural i will
shove the link in again because i see a
couple of people have joined
oh e est yes est it's
minus five 11 11 a.m that's a pretty
good time
um to be to be focusing on stuff
cool so if you could join
that um mural we're gonna start and let
me
hide uh non-facilitator cursors and
don't show me cursors
and that way um we'll not all see
madness uh flowing around
um oh awesome 10 a.m in mexico which
part of mexico that must be mexico city
yes okay uh um me
espana no moy bien but me esposa
mexicana
uh yeah yeah i remember that that you
told me in one of the actual reflect
festival
my spanish sucks though it's terrible
i've i've known her for six years and
um yeah one of the advantages i have is
she she's she's from cancun most of her
family's in cancun
and if you work in most places in cancun
you kind of know english
so they they go your spanish is terrible
and switch to english fairly quickly
oh it's 8 p.m in india okay well we'll
need to not keep you guys too long
um so we're gonna we're gonna um start
on the
mural with um i'm hoping i've managed to
do this let me
lock that and for those that haven't
been
in in a in a session with me before um
my name
is uh martin hinchowitz i'm a
professional scrum trainer with
scrum.org
um we are going to be uh
i just want to do a little an
introduction to agility right that's
that's really what i want to focus on
um if you've been in one of my classes
you might recognize some of the ideas
the way i talk
at what it is i'm going to talk about um
and i really want to to to demonstrate
two things because there's two groups of
people that are going to come to this
there's people who are just interested
in an introduction to agility and don't
care about the rest of the stuff
right and then those people that are
interested in more of the meta
conversation
how do i run a meeting
online how do i what are the tools and
techniques
that i could use to make those meetings
more effective
now i learned a lot from my
two favorite people um barry and
uh and christian over in the netherlands
um and they use a lot of liberating
structures in their sessions so i'm
going to be using some some liberating
structures as well
and hopefully that will give you the
idea if you obviously if you know the
content
you totally understand all the things
that i'm talking about um
it's an opportunity to help coach
at those in your groups who do not right
um
that's always a a good experience and
and why
often um i find i i have i had
two people last year who are long-term
uh trainers and consultants and agility
come
into one of my classes just to have the
experience of working with a bunch of
other people
talking about some of these ideas and
getting some practice because we only
need a little bit of practice
so i am just making sure that is good
this is good
cool so what what i'm going to do is i
have
and i can see that i missed a question
there so i'm going to have to try and
think of one
i've got an empty box number six is
empty um i got distracted
because somebody joined the call early
um
so let's see right all of these little
red
crosses and green ticks um are
free right there they're available for
you to move around in the mural i'll
summon everybody so that you're all
looking at the same thing as me there we
go there's 14 people
in the mural um there are a bunch of
statements
in these hexagons uh there are a
nine statements because i missed six it
just has a question mark
and i'd like you to read that statement
to yourself
and then um drag over either a tick
or a cross depending on whether you
believe
that statement to be true or false okay
shouldn't it be like true would be a
checkbox
because you got true with the x's and
falses
you you are
see i wanted to make sure that you were
paying attention
oh okay
you get you get a gold star um
so i'll just swap them around but i
think you get the idea i probably could
have done
it even without swapping them around but
you get the idea uh put an x
if you dis if you think the statement is
false
um and put a tick if you think the
statement is true
in the box just drag one over um
they should all go on top they shouldn't
drop behind i think i fixed that
i can see a few people are having fun
with the drawing tools on mural
if you do accidentally and click the
pen on the far left and end up stuck in
drawing mode
at the top of the screen there's a
little drop down appears with a
end um
end drawing on there i'm just posting
the
mural again for those that came in a
little bit
later so we have 20 people that's good
i'm happy with uh
with 20 people i was saying earlier 80
people signed up and i was kind of not
looking
forward to trying to manage breakout
rooms with 80 people
um so that's good oh this is this
this is an interesting group
i think all the all the all the
super knowledgeable people turned up
today
cool so let's see
let me have a have a look uh
we like that we like that we like that
okay so we've got three contentious ones
there
three five and seven okay so it's only
three five and seven that are
contentious
maybe two a little bit right but it's
not not i don't have to worry about this
there's
one person and that thinks that is
false and for that one person if
if we don't discuss the thing you want
to discuss here which is why you put
an x there please feel free to
to ping me offline um but that might be
there might be an interesting
conversation there
okay looks like we have quite a few
ticks some people are still um pushing
things around
let me check the chat awesome so we've
probably
uh got enough people for for for now
hey john say guns
okay so let's let's have a look at um
some of the ones that are contentious so
three seems to be very contentious there
are products
that should be developed with
traditional
plan driven practices and i very
specifically used the word
developed there as opposed to number 10
which is exactly the same statement but
with the word delivered
in it if we are delivering products that
already exist
right maybe we just need a plan and work
the plan
i think we're we're going to get to some
of those ideas and
if we're building products that don't
exist yet
think of the complexity of doing
something that's never been done before
right what's the level of variance
between how long you expect something to
take and how long it actually takes when
you've
never done it before
so i like to think of product delivery
as a production line right that's that's
the the the quintessential
delivery there's a production line uh
the the car plant
in germany volkswagen's car plant in
germany has
one suv drops off the production line
every 60 seconds
right there's very low variance in that
story they're always
optimizing it right they're inspecting
and adapting but there's low variance so
they can have a plan and they can work
it
whereas if they they were building
unique
cars every time so they had to retool
the plant
they had to redo everything every time
they built a car
you're basically hand making all of the
cars
that's a lot more complex
right so that's that's uh i'm so i'm
going to
um bring up a tick and i'm going to make
it a little bit bigger just so you know
it was me
that put it there okay um
and well i'm gonna put the big tick down
there
and a little cross on the three i i do
not think
and i'm happy if people disagree with me
we're gonna get into the details
that there are products that should be
developed developed using traditional
plan driven practices
that keyword is developed
right it depends how much time you spend
in development as well but
we're definitely gonna gonna hit on that
again it just this gives me an idea
of where everybody is um
the other one that's content i think
number five was contentious
uh but then a few people changed their
mind right
maybe they decided to go with the flow
what everybody else was putting or maybe
they just read it wrong that's okay
my my english sucks as george knows
he's been in a class with me um being
scottish
uh bad english is my first language um
so please
please feel free to correct me if i'm
not making any sense
that is definitely something to do um
so the bottom look at number seven it's
is
it okay to ship products to production
every three months
lots of no's but also a few yeses
right that that's that's an interesting
conversation
right how how long can we go
building the wrong thing before we get
into production get it in front of users
and find out
that we're building the wrong thing
what's our time to failure
right there's a lot how much how much
money could you spend
in three months on an engineering team
right depends where you are in the world
what that what that number
is but i guarantee you that number is
proportionally relevant to your budget
right wherever you are in the world
wherever you're running these projects
so we want to find out that we're
building the wrong thing as quickly as
possible
and unfortunately we we use techniques
in the plan driven world like unit
testing
not unit testing that's my brain dying
of
uh uat user acceptance testing
and user accept has anybody ever done
user acceptance testing
like have you ever been given a product
or opened a
tried to play around with a product
that's in beta but you're not actually
going to use
yeah shelton has and do you do what i do
you open up you click around you're like
that looks okay and go somewhere else
right i go back to my day job because
that's what i do when i have to test
a thing that i'm not actually using
which is why i like to test in
production
right i like to make sure that
the product is going to work the way i
work
when i'm doing my job and the only place
that is true
is when you can use it for real not for
pretend
and uat is pretend
so we have to get into production as
quickly as possible
to validate our hypothesis that this is
a useful feature
that's that's why that that question is
in there so i i would say it's
it's it's not okay
to ship to production only every three
months that's
too long too expensive too much waste
right but there might be industries
where that makes sense
okay so what what what is it uh let me
remember when i say rules are for the
guidance of wise people and the
obedience of fools
right and there are always going to be
exceptions
and all we can really worry about is the
the the common cause
ah shelton's brought up um an elephant
in the room i like this one shelton
thank you
um so he brought up this idea that the
internal it projects often has very
extensive uat
because they know it will run ruin their
life i think you mean
ruin their life when it goes live yes
because our quality sucks we're
delivering
crap products to production so then the
the the reaction that the people were
delivering those crap products to
has is they want to protect themselves
so they have uat change control boards
uh what else could you put in the way
of of of getting stuff into production
because you know
that the the developers output quality
is
not good enough to support your product
at pat
i'm not sure what pat p-a-t s-i-t's
site yeah yeah yeah yeah production yeah
all
there's loads of things that you can put
in the in the way to
to make things more difficult to get
into production and and
we do when those things happen
i always look to the quality of the
output
what is it we're delivering and is it of
an acceptable level of quality
right because if it's not acceptable
people are going to put blocks in the
way of us getting it into production
um so i don't see anything else there
that's
super contentious does anybody want to
raise anything
that they think is that they wanna that
they're that one red x and they
think they're right that's cool too
i am not always
uh i'm pretty
usually pretty open to to to questions
there's there are really no silly
questions
okay okay
cool so um
nuclear nuclear electricity no yeah
that's that's a good one um but if
quality is high
enough you could continuously deliver to
production
right the the the the team that runs
azure
deploys to production many times a day
so the whole of azure their management
software that runs azure
is deployed many times per day that
seems like it would pro probably um
have to have good quality high quality
code good tests
then we can look we can be sure of our
quality
uh okay so let's let's go on to the the
the the next exercise that was really
the the the ice breaker
and we want we want to talk about teams
right i did promise um a little bit
about what what the
what the great teams look like but i'm
kinda i'm gonna surf it
i'm gonna surf it from from from you
right because
i bet you've all worked with
teams in the past um you've worked on
teams
uh you've maybe envied somebody else's
team you've seen
sports teams right they generally have
to work together
to get to their goal okay
um so i want to do at this exercise let
me check the number of people again i
think it was about 20
29 okay so um
oh let's let's let's see this is the
largest group
i have done a liberating structure
called one two four
all with okay uh this is a technique
uh that i use and you can use as well in
any of your meetings when you want to
generate
a list of ideas right anytime you ask a
quest
you know how have you ever been um i i'm
not sure how to say your name is a
loud dress
[Laughter]
if you're in a meeting and you ask
at 20 people a question um
how often do you get more than one or
two people replying
probably one one yeah it's pretty rare
yeah it's pretty rare so so but that
meeting's expensive because there's 20
people there
so why are we not able to surf their
opinions as well
so the idea behind one two four all is
to get people
um collaborating and engaged in the
topic
so what we're going to do this is the
the rough flow there are four
four rounds there uh i will i will
summon so everybody's looking at the
same
exercise there's 18 people in the mural
but 29 people
in the in the chat you will not be able
to see what we're talking about
unless you are also in the mural
at least i think that's how many is in
the mural so i've pasted the mural
into the chat again um you should be
able to join just by
clicking in it's not a big mural so it
should run fairly well
uh so there are four rounds the first
round is for
everybody to silently and on their own
write down a list of behaviors that you
have seen in great
teams so i'll give you a minute for that
and then what i'm going to do is i'm
going to create breakout rooms
so hopefully everybody that's here is
paying attention or you might end up
in a room on your own for two minutes
yeah
all right so go into room for two
minutes and you take your two lists
from your two people that are in the
breakout room and join them together
merge those ideas together dedupe it
right so you have one list and then come
up with some more ideas by
uh rubbing our brains together and then
after
two minutes this is the bit that might
not work from my side
is i'm going to merge
the breakout rooms so that you're in
rooms of four
okay so that'll be groups of four
and and then you'll get four minutes in
groups of four to do the same thing
because you'll have
two lists again room one and room two
we'll have two lists
bring them together you'll end up with
one list and then we'll bring it back to
the
to the rest of the room does does the
explanation make sense for everybody
cool i can only um use the
visual of the people that are on on
camera to know
that um things are things are
going good um so if you're not on camera
and you don't know you'll need to
you'll need to go off mute and shout out
as well um because i can only see
everybody else nodding so i'm going to
put a timer on for one minute
right there'll be a little airplane
noise at the end i know we all miss
that that um take your seatbelt off
noise from the airlines so
um that will be the the indication that
the minute is over
and i'd like you to on your own in front
of you write down a list
of behaviors that you've seen in great
teams
you don't need to put you don't need to
put this list on the
mural yet um once you get into
pairs that's a good idea but if that's
where you want to put stuff that's cool
um i have a little hint so i'm going to
open the brevis a minute
i'm going to open the breakout rooms but
just before you do i'm going to give you
a little hint
if you made that list on your computer
as a bullet list or just a new line per
list
you will be able to copy and paste it
into mural and it will create a little
post-it for each
of the the the items so let me just
check the breakout rooms because we had
exactly
an even number of people and then
somebody else joined
uh so they will be stuck with me uh for
the
for the for the breakout room so i'm
going to click open
and you'll get a little notification on
your screen that the breakout rooms are
opening it'll take about 10 seconds
before you start moving off into your
breakout rooms
so i'd like you to in the pair that
you're in
and get your list onto the mural merge
with the other person so you've got one
list um
yep everybody's disappearing
hey most people are off into their
breakout rooms
um i can create a new room
a couple of the rooms have not finished
opening yet so i can see that now you're
still here and
there's a couple of folks um
oh and there's a room that's empty
let me put um
hey
okay so i am wondering what happened
to mal you should have a little pop-up
for your
to join the room if not
do you have a little pop-up do you have
a little uh
ah tell you what we'll just hang out
here then
um because sure that's fine you know
i didn't get anything but anything
all right so let's start getting some
things on to i can see there's some
uh crazy stuff happening on on mural
there
um uh so what were what was your
what was your list
you guys want to talk you and alex and
al
sure
hey mo hey mom so what was your lead
well i
what makes a great team when we had a
little list
one of the things that the the five
things that i
that i mentioned was that i continued my
improvement psychological safety
technological excellence there is
self-organization and a small team
small team cool yeah yeah that's a
pretty nice place
i was thinking about courage respect
among each other
those kind of things mostly
technical parties that's good um
people aspect i was thinking about more
i am going to merge the rooms for the
people that
it's uh merged really badly but let's
see if it will work
i'm going to move 14 people i think
that's pretty close to
good let's see what happens
right so
so 13 ah somebody's disappeared
so let's just close that room then
and let's close that one
because they're not in it
there we go so i think we have groups of
four now
mostly
oh alex is stuck on his own so i'm going
to close that room there we go
so if you're like hi coach daniel if you
are
uh here in the the main room we are
getting ideas
for um great
teams behaviors you've seen in great
teams uh
down on the board
i will stick the board in the chat here
again just in case
there we go the board's in the chat
ah that's a bit weird okay
hmm
all right so does anybody have any
additional things
that they would like to
two three four five six seven eight nine
people failed to move i am gonna have to
talk to the team's team about this
okay i i i've got a little separate
recording so that i can see
so they can see what happened um
because yeah it's a it's a quite a big
problem just helping somebody out by
converting their big list into uh
ideas absolutely no wrong ideas
giving everyone space collaboration what
else should be on there
there's about just about two minutes
left
i guess that's represented oh that's
uh good can you see the mural
are you able to see the mural
there should be a link in the chat i put
it on the linkedin page
as well um
but only for people that signed up for
the linkedin
channel
i can see how many people are in the
mural there are 24 people in the mural
that's pretty close to the number of
people
that are here um so that's good i did
put it in the chat again
i know some people had to drop on and
off that's okay
um
got a lot of uh things on this list
so i added autonomy for you
um i like that argue and forgive
i like argue and forgive on the list um
there's only a minute left oh there's a
massive list let me go fix that
and send it
so i'm just doing a little bit of
pruning
to make sure that people don't put all
of their lists inside of one post-it
because that means we can't move them
around as easily
is that a big list oh no
it's just a big a big statement
okay so there's 20 seconds left i'm
gonna close the rooms in about
10 seconds um because it takes about 10
seconds for the rooms to close
so
i um after i've done that i will have a
little video for microsoft on here's
what's not working okay
oh there's another big list let me oh
what happened
people are probably worried because like
where did my post-its go and it's
because i'm
making them into smaller post-its wow
we've got quite a lot of stuff
right let me close the rooms uh
oh i have to close them each one do i
because we had a little failure of the
breakout rooms i'm just gonna
go through and click these a little bit
of management for me
everybody's on their way back
very interesting
yes i can see people coming back
okay ah peter how you doing
good how are you doing good i hope
there weren't too many people that ended
up in a room on their own
that is sometimes unfortunate when we go
off in pairs but at least when we go
into two pairs
hopefully you still didn't end up in a
room on your own that's that's kind of
painful
um definitely feedback on the experience
at the end
is awesome um i usually max i usually
have in
classes live virtual classes about 20
people
so 29 uh 30 is is is quite a lot
for for for managing here but we got an
awesome list of things out of that
that's quite a lot of things on there
um then we see anything missing i'll
give you a second just to have a look
um across that list there are 26 people
on the mural
a oh of blanks i'm just getting rid of
the blanks
there's a whole bunch of really big ones
so let's make them a little bit
smaller middle
if you see duplicates put them together
and maybe um maybe we
we delete one i don't see too many
duplicates this is good lots of
different words
so it's okay if different words mean the
same thing because
sometimes there's a little bit of nuance
there isn't there
do you see any uh patterns there peter
is mutual respect actually well
that that's why as a as a tool
one two for all is a really good
technique for building that list because
if uh john or
or peter or george just voiced their
list
they might impede your desire
to add things to that list right you get
a little bit of psychological safety
because you write your own list on your
own
and then you share them with one person
um
so i think that that that works pretty
well
cool oh there's some stuff just in fact
there's psychological safety
way up in the corner i just brought that
down
argue and forgive i still like that one
that's one of my favorites
there's a lot of good things in here um
i'm going to we're going to use this
output
as an input for the next exercise okay
but i have um a little a little thing uh
to discuss
first how many of you
are familiar with the agile manifesto
how many of you familiar with that oh
there's a couple people putting their
thumbs up
peter's got his hand up right at least
of the people i can see
oh is that is that kind of
see this is the thing even when somebody
puts their hand up if you can see them
and they're like you know well maybe a
little bit i know a little bit
that's okay right so we're gonna we're
gonna
just go over the high level piece here
so what i have on the screen just now
there we go i summoned everybody to it
is the top level
page of the agile manifesto this i think
is a lot prettier
than the one online because that is a
horrendous website
uh but um the idea
is that um very specifically
because the things that we're doing are
so
complicated and have never been done
before
the only way we can figure out a good
way to do it
is to do it and figure out whether
that's a good way
right there's a little bit of a chicken
in the egg in there trying to figure out
how do we start this thing how do we get
this thing going
so that's the idea behind we uncover
better ways of developing software
or products of developing products by
doing it
and helping other people do it
right um and i want to be
very specific on the statements in the
middle there
the blue and the orange orange on the
right
for those that are colorblind and that's
that that
i am definitely neither the agile
manifesto is definitely
not saying that those things in
orange on the right are not useful
it is not saying that i i've got to
figure out a way to phrase that that
doesn't have a double negative in it
right but it is saying that processes
and tools comprehensive documentation
contract negotiation and following a
plan
are useful things they are useful
okay all it is saying
is that the things on the left in each
row are
more valuable than the thing on the
right
right that doesn't negate the thing on
the right but the thing on the left is
more valuable
so individuals and interactions being
more valuable than processes and tools
processes and tools don't get things
done people do therefore individuals and
interactions are how things
actually happen right
working software is more valuable than
comprehensive documentation
and note it doesn't say documentation is
would your customers rather have the
book
about the product or the product
i think they'd rather have the product
right if you need a book you've probably
not built a very good product but that's
a whole other problem
right and then customer collaboration
over contract negotiation contracts are
awesome right
contracts are like an official working
agreement
between two parties that's all it is an
official working agreement
but if you have to get that contract out
and
sit together and point at it you've
already lost
right you now have zero trust
in that environment
you don't want to have to get to that
point so what would i
rather do than get to the point where
i have to point to the contract i'd
rather talk to my customer
and agree something
right people misinterpret contracts all
the time they are written in words
after all um and words don't mean the
same thing to two people
especially not in the way we work today
in a multicultural
multi-geography world multi-language
world
right words mean different things to
different people
oh was there a couple of questions there
or is it hands left over being up
for from before i can see
um who's got their hand up who had their
hand up first
shelton use your hand out cool karth
sark sarthak and okay cool it's probably
just
leftover hands that's cool
so does that make sense for the edgy
manifesto
cool i know i know most of you have
probably read it and dissected it
but what we're going to do is we're
going to take all of these
um cards that we created
and i'm going to copy them down here so
let me copy them down first
i'll do something about the mess uh
let me resize them all
that's gonna take a second there we go
i've resized them all
and then i'm gonna build a little grid
in the middle
there we go there's a big massive grid
of these cards
in the middle okay
what i would like you to do is
grab a card it doesn't have to be yours
right and move it to where
you think best represents that card
you know like self-organizing i'm gonna
grab self-organizing
and it's not processes and tools
documentation
contract following up it's not any of
those things responding to change maybe
customer collaboration i think it looks
like somewhere pretty close to
individuals and interactions
i guess you're talking to somebody else
that's cool so i'd like everybody
in the mural grab a card move it where
you think
um best makes sense all right
i i am we can put things wherever
put them all around these ideas
okay still got a lot left what's this
one sitting over here let me zoom in a
bit
focus on continuous improving working
agreements
come on we've got lots of cards to move
i can indeed drop the link to my raw
funnily enough that popped up on my
phone rather than on there
your mural oh
now i've got a little message popping up
now that says i can't post messages
because i'm not a member of the chat
it's my meeting damn it
oh there we go turn it off turn it back
on again the age-old solution to every
technical problem
it's funny how often that works isn't it
hey
it's okay to have things on the right
it's definitely okay to have that
i can see there's a couple of things
down following a plan around goals and
direction yeah that's good
some things might go you might think oh
well that could go in two places
right that that's okay just pick what
you think is the most right
it's the pattern that's emerging that's
more important
hey
i'm gonna move that oh well somebody's
still editing it
this is a title that's unfortunately
covered
okay
john what what do you notice
oh heck oh heck of a lot of the things i
moved over to the left right versus the
right
and well i've specifically asked the
question what builds great teams
because hopefully we can agree that
great teams build great products
bad teams don't build good products
right that's that's
kind of and it makes sense doesn't it
right people that are not happy not
interested disrespectful to each other
goofing off right we're not gonna get
good products out of that group
even if we have awesome ideas we're not
going to get good products out of that
so the differentiator between building
bad products and good products
is great teams and building great teams
has very little if anything
to do with those things on the right
processes and tools
documentation contracts plans
not not not super useful in building
great products
they still have value right
because we need to set direction i
there's a couple of uh i
i did go and read the a couple of the
things around following a plan and
they're about goals
right and setting direction that's good
we need those things
i've got an interesting question for you
to think about
where does your spend most of its
time and effort
is it on the left or on the right
my organization that was unfortunately
uh much more
skewed to the right than the left even
in organizations that i
talk fairly well about agility
right i still see a lot of right bias
rather than left by us in this story
that this is a really uh true
that's true i think people for big
companies you know
big names especially in the aspect of
processes processes if they're not good
[Music]
they want to process for everything and
you can't change the process because
that's the way we do things here
yeah someone told me these things
haven't been done
so no
yeah yeah i i worked with merrill lynch
for
a number of years we had a lot of
processes that didn't make any sense for
the work that
i was doing but made sense
for maybe work that other people were
doing but
our work was unrelated
i'd like to give it i'd like to give a
shout out
actually um in
that if they are ingrained
simple and easy then they actually make
like
they make life better so what are the
things that i've been given slightly
insane about
at the moment quite a large uk
organization
is is that the the company's got
i don't know how many how many bits of
it and everyone stores their documents
somewhere
different i'm trying to initiate a
and that should be our team process
because i don't want i don't i don't
hear someone in six months time saying
oh i'm sorry i screwed this up when i
was working on the wrong version yeah i
totally agree
peter and i i would i would have that as
part of the working agreement that the
team
creates right how are we going to
operate as a team
but that document is an i
is an output of individuals and
interactions
right we have an interaction we talk
about what our rules are going to be
we agree as a team to those rules and
then they become our process
but if we find later on down the line
that that process is not working for us
anymore
we need to get together have a
conversation to figure out what the new
process is
so we're not wedded to those processes
to do or die
right like like was mentioned in the
comment you know
they cannot be changed they've been
there since before you were born
type of processes um and i think that's
more what the processes and tools
is is implying that they're valuable but
not as valuable as just talking to each
other and figuring things out
and ma man leo do you have a question
yes martin yes martin i wanted to ask
your view
on the following a plan
agile teams that also do discovery
yeah so um there's definitely a lot of
um uh
i guess controversy discussion arguments
um around that that topic i i don't have
a problem with
any metrics that provide benefit to the
team and benefit to the organization
right um it's when
metrics have a negative impact on
teams abilities to deliver that i would
want to
question those metrics um
and figure out how can we do it better
so okrs
um as they are defined
if you read a book about okrs
is going to talk about something that is
achievable that's realistic
um that that is that measures
valuable things and that sounds
perfectly reasonable
um i know that the azure devops team
at microsoft they they use okrs and they
they did for many years
very successfully and they are agile
teams so i i think it can be a
complementary practice
right but it can also be detrimental if
if
if used to um
i find okrs can often um be used as a
as a as a as a stick uh to beat the team
with
um because they're not meeting their
stretch goals right
when okrs were not really designed this
is my understanding of kr's
not really designed as stretch goals
you're only expected
to meet 70 of your okr
right so yeah so
it's built into the ocr that you're not
meant to meet the whole thing you're
just meant to get
within a distance of it so i
like if it's more like like a guardrail
and
providing direction yeah exactly if it's
useful
use it if it stops being useful stop
doing it
right it's painful stuff
that's the way i look at it but just be
conscious of how it's being useful and
how it might be dangerous as well
because
sometimes these things have effects that
we we
don't notice thank you
so we've talked about
um i think uh
how many people do we have now let's
have a look
i think i'm i i i'm going to i'm going
to give you
an op i'm going to give you an option
okay
um so the next exercise i think will
take about
20 minutes which wouldn't leave us a lot
of time um
for what i think is quite an important
piece
um so i'd like to skip the the
principles exercise that i've got set up
here even though i spent a lot of time
on it when i saw that 80 people had
signed up
to make it maybe support that many
people um but
i i think we need to skip that in order
to
get to some of the additional meat does
that make sense
so this is how it works people that are
on camera i get to
get to uh have their opinions voiced and
then everybody else gets to
live with it that's that's what happens
um
cool so i want i want to talk about
connection
some of you might already be familiar
with connection
david snowden's work um there's a lot of
really good content out there
there's the original hbr uh review
and i think i think i add something
in my explanation of it um so i'm going
to
going to to to walk through my story
i'm going to make sure these are
unlocked of
connection um within the context and
this
that that's why i've got at the top this
is martin's
interpretation of of connection
um and that that's really so i know
um if this is on uh linkedin if this is
on
uh other platforms david might go have a
look
uh and skip to that point and go martin
you're completely wrong and that's okay
um it's just my interpretation and
hopefully that will start a conversation
so the kinetic model really
it talks about um four areas
of our environments that we do work in
okay we do work in these four
environments
um so there's there's a space in the
middle here
that we like to call disorder right
that's where we have no defined
process and that's usually okay up to
about 20
people in your company um and you can
get away with
we're just making it up as we go along
okay but at some point
there's too much going on to support
support that and you end up in disorder
things are not working out things are
not happening when you expect them to
there aren't the accountabilities that
we need okay
um so we're not really really going to
focus on on disorder at all
don't don't be there you know come on
can you summon everyone to the right
part of the diagram yes i can
thank you for that oh there we go ah
there we go
perfect that's probably a lot better yes
please
now i now i know what picture you're
talking about yeah
um so i'm gonna i'm gonna bring in the
first one which is the the simple world
of work simple environment um
the characteristic of simple
right is that we know everything
right we know everything about that
piece of work we know everything that
could happen that's going to happen
everything and it's pretty pretty simple
and straightforward
what might uh shelton be the the
the way to approach that type of work
you know everything about it
what might oh he's got to jump on
another call
always i always pick it so it's the
there's this
expression jdi right and it stands for
just do it yeah right you don't you
don't need a process you don't need
anything
it's uh the things that have been done
so many times that the whole
end-to-end process is so well known that
they're it's just
just yeah yeah you just go look up the
explainer video on youtube and follow it
and you're good to go
right that's that's that's how that's
how we do lots of things
now at least that's how i do lots of
things uh is just look well
youtube explains how how how it works
and then i
i that's it done right so that's that
simple world and we can have those best
practices
right that youtube video is just the
explainer for how to do that okay
maybe there's multiple ones that talk
about the same thing but there's really
one
one good way to do it that's best
practices
lots of organizations bandy about the
term best practices
right but they're only valuable
within this simple world because there
is one way to do it when you know
everything
but when there's a little bit things get
a little bit more
you know confused we end up in the
complicated
environment in the complicated
environment the main characteristic
is that there are uh
some unknowns right most things are
known
right we've maybe got i i don't really
it's just most things are known but if i
was to put a number on it let's say
there's up to a 15
variance between what we think is going
to happen and what what's actually going
to happen
right i just made up that number so
don't don't hold it as a as an actual
number it's just
a normal statistic made up on the spot
um some is unknown but most things are
known
and in that world we can use plan
driven good practices
right we can just work a plan we can
deal with 15
variants right we can just work it think
if you were on a
uh you'd bought a plot of land and you
were going to build 20 houses
right you know what the designs are for
the houses you're going to build because
you've had an architect
design them right so you know exactly
how much wood you need
and your foreman is going to be able to
give you a good
practice on when you're going to need
the electricians the plasterers and how
long
far for each house and how much
materials you're going to need
most things are known and then you get
the weird thing
of some materials were delivered too
early and warped in the rain and you've
got to order more
right that's part of your 15 variance or
that as what quite often happens that
plumber doesn't turn up
right when they're supposed to that's
part of your 15
variant so how do you then deal with
that so you have a plan you maybe use a
gantt chart and you just manage that
plan
right everything's everything's going to
take that time that make sense
so so i i co i i'm going to call out
that that is the world
of product delivery
right anytime you're delivering
something that has already been
designed and already exists
right i don't know if you've ever seen
houses arriving at a building site but
quite a lot of them come flat packed
right they have the the the the the
steep i don't know what they what they
call that thing in the roof the
triangles they're all pre-made at the
factory
you know they they just arrive and
you're assembling
like a massive airfix kit you're just
assembling everything
so that's product delivery whether
you're you're building cars
um and we can use uh prince2
exists a lot in that space
right um i think i can't actually can't
remember what lt
ltps stands for but i'm pretty sure it
sits in that space as well do you
remember what ltps
stands for peter i think you would be
someone who would know that sort of
thing
no no
well i think i tell you what i'm going
to stick it back over there
in 15 seconds yeah yeah google will know
um
so product delivery prince2 pmi plan
driven techniques
right they tend to focus on plan driven
techniques
the the prince2 and pmi institutes do
have
uh some um agile techniques
as well that they introduce into that
story and that makes sense but their
foundation
is on those plan driven techniques right
so they're very useful in that space
and then we move on to this complex
space and in the complex space the
characteristic
is that most things are unknown
some things are known but most things
are unknown
a good example of that is if i
asked you to write a book
on a topic right let's say
uh mao you're gonna write a devops book
okay on devops practices how long
you're not allowed to copy somebody
else's book you've got to write it from
scratch it's going to be your book
the publisher is going to publish it how
long is it going to take you to write it
two years well that but
where did you get that number from
yeah you just took a wild what a wag a
wild ass guess absolutely
just like that whatever yeah yeah i
don't know what's the number big enough
that i feel comfortable
i i know people that the the that have
taken
way more than two years to to write a
book because they get
writer's block or they have to do a
bunch of research
or they find out that something they
thought was true wasn't and they have to
do something else
there's all kinds of things that can
happen if you on your own
were writing a book imagine you were
writing
a a book with three friends
right now now it gets a little bit more
complex because do we all agree
with what should be in the book can the
stories that should be in there
and the ideas that we're presenting
things get a little bit more difficult a
little bit more complicated
so that's where we end up more in the
complex space we're doing that something
that has never been done before that
content doesn't exist
most content creation exists in that
space
all software development is
in that space because we wouldn't write
it right
you know that developers uh are are
notoriously
lazy people right we are we're very
deliberately lazy
i would rather go use a framework that
somebody else has built than build
something myself
i'd much rather do that because i have
less
unknowns i can use something that
pre-exists and has a little bit of
documentation
anytime we've got a cup code we're in
that complex space
and in that space we want to use
empirical management practices
right and that empiricism means that our
practices that make sense
are going to emerge and change over time
right what's right at the beginning of
the project might not be right at the
end of the product or project
right we might have to change and adapt
the way we do things
so i would put that in this category of
product
development right we're building uh
products that don't exist yet we're
developing products
uh scrum was designed for that space
uh the kanban method was designed for
that space and i'm very specifically
saying the kanban method
right not just kanban as a
as a as a generic thing or lean right
lean applies everywhere
but the kanban method sits in that space
um and then we get to the
last environment which i'm sure many of
you have been in
which is the chaotic space right
some people end up there accidentally
because their project's a disaster
although that might be disorder okay
but in the chaotic space everything is
unknown
you have no idea what's going on what
the right thing is what even you need to
build or do in that space we need to
experiment
we have novel practices we're going to
make something unique that we're going
to use this once
and then we're not going to use it again
and
this for me is the product discovery
phase that bit where we don't know what
it is we're going to build yet
right the result of that might be a
business case right maybe a business
case that we have to take to somebody it
might be
um a a bunch of user stories
that we're going to put in a backlog
right that might be the output of that
might just be a hypothesis we think this
product will be useful to our customers
that might be the output of that
and almost all scientific research
exists in that space
right you have a vague idea what you're
going but all the
have you ever noticed that all of the
best scientific
uh uh outcomes have come
from people who weren't studying for
that out they weren't looking into that
outcome they discovered something else
along the way like oh
look that works or this happens or this
works that way
they say oh that's interesting that's
interesting
yeah but that's that's product discovery
that that's
um a product owner might sit in that
space
quite a lot of the time figuring out
what they're going to build next
right it might be a little bit more
informed than chaotic
but um
it still might be in the product
discovery space
so i'm going to i i hate to break your
illusion but
i mean that's a bit of a myth
the scientific additives gravity
you knew what he was up to einstein knew
what he was up to
ball knew what he was up to but the
other really smart ones
do you what he was up to
[Music]
i put it on the bad dude but anyway
let's
um but what i would like you to think
about here
is how much time
does the work that you do spend in each
of these species
going to mute joseph there uh
every product and project that you work
on
will spend some amount of time in every
single one of the maybe except for
simple but it will spend some time in
product discovery
some time in product development and
some time in product delivery
right where i'd like you to i think
peter's preempted there because
he's maybe been here is that peter
dragging one around no not yet
oh i just you're usually the oh it's mal
you're usually the culprit peter
um so what i'd like you to do is grab
one of these little uh auburn dots in
the top right
of this view and drag it onto the
display
where you think your product
or your product spends most of its time
do you spend most of your time in
product development
product delivery
what about discovery right there's lots
of
organizations that spend a significant
amount of time in discovery
yeah just grab a grab a dot pull it on
there
oh that dot went behind let me
let me out whoa make all of those dots
bring to front awesome i'm gonna
unlock that and send it the
back and there's that dot coming back
there we go
i made all of the the dots that are on
the top right are now
uh always at the front
so grab a dot there's more there's more
people than that there's
24 people in the mural one two three
four five six seven eight nine there's
only ten less than half of you
have moved a dot so grab a dot where do
you spend
most of your time
oh i i'm quite interested that there's
two there
in product discovery i'll share the link
once more
absolutely i can let me put it in the
chat
i have indeed put it in the chat
okay
there's a little bit of a pattern
emerging there as well isn't there peter
so this is this is this is the downside
of me picking on people with their
camera on
there's lots of people have turned their
camera off i think that's maybe a
a dysfunction to that that behavior or
some functional outcome
so it looks like we've got two people in
product discovery
that spend a little bit of time in the
chaotic world
um of not knowing what it is we're
building right and we've got to figure
that piece out they might be product
owners
right they're they're they're working
inside of organizations trying to figure
out how do we what's our next big
product
how do we even decide what that is how
do we figure that out
and then it looks like there's quite a
few people that are on or
pretty close to product delivery
one two three four five people are
on or pretty close to product delivery
maybe
your guys are just fine using plan
driven techniques and managing to plan
right because you spend the majority of
your time there
your variance is going to be lower right
if your variance is low enough that you
can manage it
maybe that will work right i i work with
a number of organizations some
professional services organizations
and if the customer comes with a big
list of
here's every feature we want our product
to have
maybe we're building rebuilding an
existing product
maybe we spend quite a lot of time in
product delivery
maybe we're doing a migration from
on-premise
office to cloud office
right that's that's just a migration
exercise well-known
ideas we just want to create a plan
who'll be migrating when and work
through it
but if we are and do spend most of our
time in that complex space
we need to think differently plan driven
is not going to manage our risk it is
not going to manage our risk
because that's why we managed to plan is
to manage risk
but if there's so much variance that we
have to rebuild our plan every
couple of weeks
that doesn't sound like we're mitigating
risk that we're
rolling with the change
manlow did you have a question
she's good you get your hand up i can
put it down it's just it might have been
left over from
before that's cool
so i think most of you are here because
you exist in that product development
world
right i mean that's that's uh part of
that
uh story um but in
if we are in that product development
world we kind of need
a little bit of a different thing going
on so i'm gonna i'm gonna try and
compare some evolutions right uh what's
the
what's the difference between
traditional uh plan driven
and empirical in our in our story and i
know peter will come up with some
caveats for
for for for some of the things that i'll
mention and that is super cool
because it all i'm looking at is the the
common cause there are always exceptions
uh i know people have been very
successful in the plan driven world
and mostly because they adapt their plan
quickly to
what's really happening in the world um
but in this example
um i'm going to say we've got a 12-month
project
right it's about 12 million of whatever
monetary unit you like
euros dollars pounds doesn't really
matter it's going to cost 12 million
and a traditional iteration
might be 12 months right we're not going
to have a working
product until the end of the project
and our empirical iteration might be two
weeks
right i know the scrum guide for example
says
one month or less the agile manifesto
says a few months
to a few weeks right um
but the reality is that 20 years ago
when the agile manifesto was signed in
25 years ago when the scrum guide
was first when scrum was first created
or first presented
it was really hard to ship software to
production
it was hard today
it's not hard to ship software to
production or it shouldn't be
right that might be a technical debt
problem and i teach a class called the
applying professional scrum
and we break up into teams i give them a
website to go build
and they have to go build a website in
teams right
and this has only been one team ever
that has done this so it's about teams
of five
i give them a 30 minute sprint
to build working products and they're
going to demo at the end of 30 minutes
to me the stakeholder right and you're
like holy crap build some
a website in 30 minutes right this
one team ever not only
did they have all of their did they
build it in visual studio write the code
but that code was under source control
they had an automated build
and they had an automated deployment
that continuously delivered the product
to azure and just gave me the url at the
end of 30 minutes
right if you can if you can do that for
regardless of how simple your website is
in 30 minutes
what could that engineering team do in
two weeks
right environments setups used to be
a massive problem now those things are
pretty straightforward i know that
somebody here will say
yes but my company won't allow you know
me to use
the the cloud and i have to use an
on-premise and it takes me six weeks to
request a new server
you guys are in the minority now right
agility getting working product into
production every three weeks
really requires a different look at
things so let me grab a couple of things
over here i have i have
uh some little little pieces to help me
tell this story
that i made the other day um and
the first thing i want to talk about
is is visibility right so let me drag
visibility on here
and talk about visibility
what does visibility look like between a
traditional 12-month project
and an empirical 12-month project
right so let's say we're going to do two
weeks prince versus the one year
effort right i used to work with the
azure devops team
they uh deliver they used to eight years
ago they were delivering to production
every two years
right maybe they had a uh uh um
release candidate halfway right
so after a year they had something to
see but then it's another year before
it's actually
shippable right that was visual studio
eight years ago
today they do continuous delivery to
production and deliver
at least every three weeks
all right so so so doesn't matter how
big your product is
the windows team does continuous
delivery to production
right that's that's probably one of the
most complicated products in the world
so what does visibility look like on our
for our 12 months
right we've got high visibility at the
start
then it probably drops pretty heavily
pretty quickly we've got pretty much no
visibility throughout the life of the
project
and then when we deliver our product to
production at the end
we get our lovely gold star right we've
got our product
now visibility might not drop to zero
right but inside of that bubble at what
point
does your customer see working software
right see a working product that they
can go use
it's really not till the end in a
traditional model
i know that we talk about it spiral came
along to help mitigate that maybe we've
got working product in a shorter time
frame every once every six months or
once a quarter
or whatever that is but it's it's still
a long time
if we were to look at that idea in a
two week window i've got my little
pre-made this is so that you don't have
to put up with my drawing
right because my drawing sucks um
so what does visibility look like
i'm gonna i i don't know whether i
should put it down here or put it up
there i'm gonna put it up there just for
fun
right but in that two week window
we get visibility every two weeks
we should have a working product a
usable thing
every two weeks if we're on a two week
iteration
if we're doing a one month iteration it
would be once a month right but
this is two weeks we still get to the
same star
we get to the same place but how's your
customers comfort level now
right they've got high visibility they
can see what's going on in a regular
frame maybe at some point they
figure out that we're not doing the
thing that they need
right so maybe they get an opportunity
to change
so that gets to this idea of change
what does change management look like
in this space what does our ability to
change look like in traditional
probably starts fairly high
right we can change anything at the
start but then we get that contract
signed and maybe suddenly things aren't
so changeable
maybe we're going to put things in the
way like change requests
in the way of people making changes
but in an empirical space where we're
delivering
usable product at the end of every
sprint
we're still going to reduce in our
ability to change
right because we've built stuff
stuff we've already built is harder to
change than stuff we haven't built yet
but if at the end of every single
iteration
we have a usable product that works the
customer is free to change
anything we've not started
anything we've not started they can
change
but in a traditional model we've
effectively
we've not actually started everything
but we're not working on the product
in a logical manner so we have something
that works every
short period of time right
halfway through my life cycle for my my
12 month project
i can't stop and go work on something
else
unless i'm willing to lose all of the
value that i've already added in the
product
because i can't realize it because it's
not a working product yet
so it gives it allows us to maintain
that ability to change what we're
working on
change how things are going throughout
the life of the product
we still get to the same place right in
that story
change management we still get the same
place hopefully customers are happier
because we're talking to them
with our visibility every two weeks and
offering them the ability to change even
if they don't change stuff
so they feel more involved
okay so then there's there's there's an
interesting one
there's this idea of risk how do we
manage
risk in this new world because if things
change so much and we have such a high
degree of variance we cannot control
risk with more
control right because the control is
just going to fall apart
because things are changing too much the
world is changing the world is unknown
we don't know what we're going to build
we don't know if it's going to work we
don't know if that technology is going
to be
put in three months time uh we don't we
don't know lots of things
right so it's high levels of risk
so if we've got 12 million
i'm gonna put pounds in there because
you know
i'm british i think that's worth about
50 euros today
we're pretty pretty soon peter and i are
going to go to the supermarket and have
to pay a million pounds for a loaf of
bread
i think that's in the next three weeks
at that point we will exit stage left
i'm pretty sure that's
i'm pretty sure that's what they're
waiting on um
so we've got this this this risk model
so in
our in in the traditional model oh sorry
i've not locked that yet so if you go
try and drag stuff around it's gonna
gonna move stuff
throughout the 12 months
we have 12 million dollars at risk 12
million pounds even
right on day one of the project your
customer gives you
here's a check for 12 million pounds
right
and then when do you give them the
product at the end of the 12 months
so every week every day every month
between them giving you the money
and you giving them a product they have
12 million pounds at risk
that i think that customer is going to
be freaking out
right they're going to want more
controls they're going to be more
at things on there
whereas if we bring in
our empirical process i know i'm i'm
running over
if you can stay stay but um i know i'm
running over a little bit
um we're only going to be spending
500k 500 000 pounds
for a sprint that's an expensive sprint
right but
yeah it's what it is maybe there's lots
of teams working on it but at the end of
that 500k we're going to give them a
working product
a working usable product that they could
deploy to production
if it had amortized enough value
well what's their risk at that point
zero
they have no risk right their only risk
is they've not got an adequate return on
investment we've given them the product
and the risk is that the product crap
right so they can look at the product
and then decide whether to give us
another
500 000 for another iteration
on the product they're in control
of their risk even if we signed up to a
12-month plan
right if we suddenly deliver something
that is not what they expected
not going to solve their business
problem why would they want to spend
more than the 500k
they never have more than 500k at risk
at any point in time
so it reduces our risk profile and then
the last one
and then i'll uh wrap up is
um value amortizing value
okay oh let's not do that let's do
i'm gonna drag all of these over a
little bit so i can access them
what does our risk are our value profile
look like
well if we don't give them any product
till the end
then they get no value till the end do
they
right no value at all okay this is
zero value all the way between those two
lines
but in the the empirical world
even if the requirements never changed
over the life of the project right of
the life of the deliverable
we're going to get to exactly the same
place but they're seeing
value at the end of every iteration they
would be able to deploy to production
after a month if we had built something
of value
and then the next month they have more
value the next month they have
even more value they're amortizing that
value over time
rather than one lump thing at the end
but what really happens the real super
power
of empirical process control systems is
that
we can change what we're working on at
the end of every sprint remember we're
maintaining that ability to change
so maybe we get to the end of sprint
two and everything after it
is now invalid and we need to work on
something different because the business
has changed
right think of every video conferencing
product
on the planet the minute lockdowns were
announced
what do you think happened to their
product backlogs
they changed yeah they changed and
probably
drastically whole shift in focus
right probably a massive shift in focus
towards performance
first because they're like well we used
to have
x number of people and now we've got x
times 10 every day
okay we need to look at performance we
need to look at sorting out those
problems
so what actually happens is at the end
of every
iteration we're able to do something
more valuable than the things we thought
would be valuable and that's that value
gap between where we thought we were
trying to get to
and where we really need to be in order
to maximize the value to the customer
think of one of the the the principles
in the agile manifesto
is maximizing the amount of work not
done right don't do stuff you don't need
to
that's this gap here is we didn't do
this work we did something better
and that's how we get that super power
of value delivery
in an empirical process control system
so any questions on that
oh i got some stuff moving around i am
going to
lock that
there we go i locked it i'm going to
send everybody a pdf of
of the the mural anyway at the end so
you'll get a copy of it okay
was that was that a good way to tell
that story building up the
pictures cool nope that's
that's the the feedback i need so we are
at four
minutes over um so i'd i'd like you to
think
of um let me summon again
i'd like you to think of something think
of the
what the difference between
what we've been talking about and your
world at work
and how a move towards
more empiricism right more empirical
practices
because it's a dial it's not a bullying
thing it's not your
have empiricism or you don't it's like
this
dial that goes from zero to i guess it
goes to 11 doesn't it peter because all
all good dials go to 11.
um and
um what could you
do within your organization
that doesn't need anybody else
to give you something to do what can you
do on your own
right so that's without without
additional
authority or um
from your organization additional powers
what could you do
inside of your organization to help make
things a little bit more empirical
just be one thing
that that that boy scout rule
right whenever you do something
leave it a little bit better than you
found it
how do you make things a little bit
better
it doesn't have to be a lot it can just
be a little bit
make your teams a little bit happier
make it a little bit easier to do the
work
a couple people adding adding ideas
it's always a good thing to do
oh some people in the chat as well
managing my own time
to take on more value adding tasks yeah
might stop doing things that are not
valuable
do more of things that are valuable
right and that's we should all be
continually looking at the activities we
have to do
in our in our work world and figuring
out which ones are in the
the poverty gap right what are we not
doing enough of
um or in the rigidity graph depth what
are we stuck
doing that we should really be doing
less of because it's not valuable
oh i'm sorry shelton shelton's saying
he's he's shifting
tracking work items on multiple projects
in spreadsheets with operative
deadlines all in a vacuum to using a
backlog with all of my projects as
different work streams so
that's a lot of work right so that's
good moving away from uh some of those
old ways of doing it
increasing um the
more i guess more modern ways of doing
things right we all need to continuously
modernize the world has changed
yeah code would change priorities
so yeah lots of pain in teams when we're
working the old ways so what have we got
on our list
uh managing time i added that one on um
there sharpen the saw
yeah maybe maybe some of your teams need
practice honing their skills right maybe
you do
maybe you can hone sharpen your saw
do work that matters be an example for
others
break down large tasks and getting
feedback um
get all the bas into one room i don't
know what problem you've got that that
will solve but
if it's going to solve a problem awesome
i guess maybe they're disagreeing with
each other
coach to do more research and rapid
prototyping
to test a hypothesis before writing code
yeah
um writing code can sometimes be what
you need to do to test a hypothesis
right i usually say everything's an
assumption
until it gets into the hands of your
users right
so how much assumption risk
right because assumptions are risk how
much risk can you cope with before you
get things in front of them
that can be uh really really difficult
so thank you for for for putting that uh
those ideas in there
um and hopefully you can make some
changes
to the things around you i added some
some
content some references at the bottom uh
the link
that i think is quite uh good is that a
link to the new new product development
game
um i always like referring to that
article um
and it's definitely worth a read um also
links to things like the
the i think the scrum guides in there
somewhere is it bottom left
scrum guide um the kanban guide for
scrum teams the evidence-based
management guide
is in there which i'll talk about more
next session so the next session i have
is in two weeks at the same time and
it's like introduction to scrum
well an introduction to agility so maybe
this is a little bit of prep for
uh some of those ideas there
and i'll try and use as many of the same
techniques maybe with better timing
right that's that's always something
that i try and uh work on
um so what would be super cool oh i can
see there's already some feedback
preempted me
look at that people are keen to give
feedback um
i am interested in i'm dragging things
around
um any uh feedback
that you have so my good friend russell
miller
always says that feedback is a gift
right i'd like you to give me the gift
of feedback
um what are um
things that you think worked well uh
what needs to change
timing i'm already on that one um
i think i i always have that problem so
that's maybe a systemic martin thing um
yep thank you what needs to change
somebody's plonked time management on
there
i am i'm good with that uh
what else do you like not like
any topic so in the unanswered questions
section
maybe what other topics would you be
interested in
because really we can
i am going to feed that back to um
product team there yeah yeah uh
so for for when i'm teaching classes
and uh it's been pretty good
right it's been it's been pretty it has
been
pretty good uh but for it here
it's not been pretty good and i think
part of that is in a free live webcast
people
sometimes drop in and out um and i think
it confuses teams when people are
dropping in and out
and when you try and set up breakout
rooms and it's trying to put people in
breakout rooms but then they've already
gone offline and
i think it gets confused definitely
there are other tools out there that do
that a little bit better
i am a microsoft weenie um so i'll
probably
i'll stick with it and just provide
feedback for the team
um and hopefully they can they can fix
those issues
cool well thank you very much uh
everybody for your time
and for the extra 12 minutes
that you gave me at the end there um i'm
going to
hang out uh for a little bit
um if you need me i think i actually i'm
pretty sure i have a meeting at some
point
ah not for another and until six o'clock
another 18 minutes so i'll hang out here
i'm going to turn off the