so the question was does a client
tell an agile consultant of what they
need or does it work the other way
around
I think it works the other way around
but I think it's more complicated than
that because
a lot lots of clients come with
an agenda
so quite often you come in under a
particular agenda
but the mark of a great consultant is
you
are trying to deliver the maximum value
to the customer right
so you have to figure out regardless of
what they've asked for
what is it that they need
for for them to be successful in
whatever is that they're trying to do
or even is the thing they're trying to
do the right thing that they're trying
to do
and then slowly convince them to do the
right thing so I guess it depends how
long you're going to be engaged with the
customer for what that really looks like
I'm quite often engaged with customers
for a short period of time
um most of my engagements with customers
have either been over uh uh uh two or
three weeks that's generally they want
advice they're like we want to
understand how we do something and I'm
coming in giving them advice and then
they're taking it forward I'm not not
working with them to do it but I've also
done longer engagements but usually for
Professional Services teams where I'm
working with lots of different teams
inside of their organization so it's
like I'm internally Consulting with lots
of different teams and I would come in
and help observe give them some feedback
usually working with their scrum master
so
when when they come they want a
particular thing
right they want to
um usually actually they want to get
better at this agile thing
but that's not necessarily like getting
being awesome at agile what value does
that provide the company what values
that provide their customers it's not
necessarily the right thing but that's
what they ask for because that's the
trend right so you quite often come in
under that that guys but then you've got
to figure out what is it that this
organization actually needs is it is it
is it a a a leadership
um issue where you need to focus on
um that that that whole engagement
pipeline that they're working through
um I did an engagement recently with a
professional services company and
they were they'd built up this this this
great business and
it was I I have a weird name for it I I
call it the death spiral of Consulting
um and it's it's where you get a little
bit too big
um and
you need to feed the monster which is
that your business
so you have very aggressive sales
tactics you've built a great name in the
industry you're very aggressive sales
tactics you bring in
um uh more you have to hire more people
to get the gigs done because you've got
these aggressive sales tactics that
bring in lots of gigs and then
you need to do them now and you get more
gigs than people so you have to hire
more people
and because you have to hire them
quickly because you've told the customer
you can do it you're not waiting for the
top tier candidates you're getting the
people that are available
and then they're doing the gig
and then you need more gigs because
you've now got a bigger head count and
more people so you have more aggressive
sales Tactics get in more gigs and then
oh all our people are busy we need to
hire more people and then even those
level of people are not available at the
next level down and you end up in this
death spiral of taking on too much work
when what they really need is a whip
limit right they need to control their
sales pipeline it's not a free-for-all
it's uh what can your business safely
handle to deliver the level of quality
that your customers are looking for and
I think this is true not just for
Professional Services this is true in
any business what is the level of
quality and brand and uh uh uh
um visual that you're trying to get from
your customer your customers
and what's the maximum amount of
business you can do while safely
maintaining that and then you want to
grow slowly while maintaining that level
of quality so you're hiring the right
people you're
um engaging on the right engagements
right you're not taking any engagement
that comes along because probably any
engagement sucks you're picking and
choosing which engagement at that level
um so I think most customers don't know
what they want
um they think they want this agile thing
or this devops thing
and can you come and install it for us
but you have to figure out what it is
that is the actual
um difficulty the thing that they need
help with and help them with that even
if it's kind of surreptitiously or kind
of around a different way so that they
feel like and and really do get value
from what you're doing
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility