so the question is what is Sprint
planning
uh there's a more important question
there why why is Sprint planning right
uh but what is print planning it it's
it's a time where
um we get together and we we plan what
we're going to do over the next uh
whatever Sprint length we have over the
next Sprint uh two weeks uh three weeks
four weeks three days whatever your
Sprint length is
um we're gonna we're gonna plan the
Sprint right so Sprint planning is about
planning the Sprint kind of makes sense
um but
it matters because it gives us that that
moment that check-in which could be
short it could be a tiny Sprint planning
because we everybody already knows where
we're going already understands what
we're going to take on we're gonna get a
get in a room five minutes later we're
out we're done or it could even be it
could be a check-in an asynchronous
check-in over over slack or teams right
do we all understand where we're going
and the the point is the understanding
do we all understand what we're trying
to achieve this Sprint do we all
understand what's involved in it what
direction we're going what needs to
happen in order to get there
that's the purpose of Sprint planning
and
um it's it's a lot of a lot of uh uh
people come along and say well you know
we do kanban so you know we don't do
Sprint planning and my question is when
do you decide what work you're going to
pull into the Sprint how does that work
get onto that list of things that list
of options right that the team is able
to select from that is an effect Sprint
planning whether you're involved in it
as the team or not right that is Sprint
planning and wouldn't it be better if
you were involved in it and effective
kanban teams are normally involved in it
right there they've got to say in what
ends up on the options what goes in
there what's what's what's ready to pull
into the Sprint
that's Sprint planning right you've got
refinement which comes before Sprint
planning which is how like
building that list of options
and then Sprint planning is really about
just deciding what is the next list of
options
from a kanban perspective from a scrum
perspective the same thing is true you
have you have refinement which is all
the work that you do that's not on on
the current you know adding features to
the product and then Sprint planning is
about
now we understand all of that stuff that
we would like the product to do that it
doesn't do yet
what is the things that we need to do in
the next two weeks
iteration
so we're planning right in the next two
week iteration or that we think we need
in the next two week iteration that
we're going to pull into the Sprint
um and that might be you know here's
here's here's our Sprint goal here's
what we're going to try and achieve this
Sprint like this is the communication
goal the thing we're going to commit to
if you're doing scrum you commit to the
Sprint goal right but that might only be
a small percentage of the work that you
need to do in the Sprint because we've
also got that you know we're we're we
had some live site incidents and we've
got a large refactoring exercise of our
architecture that's going on and we're
doing a little bit of that every Sprint
so we're spending 20 percent of our time
every Sprint doing that
um we have we have some technical debt
that we're working through that we've
discovered
um and we're going to spend 10 of our
time on on technical debt uh we've got
some some bugs some things that that
customers have reported so we might have
some things that they've reported some
defects some bugs actual errors in the
product we're going to bring bring some
of them into the Sprint every Sprint
right otherwise you end up with a
dumbass bug fixing stripe Sprint right
we're going to do a little bit of
everything all the time to maintain our
product
and Sprint planning is about deciding
what all of those things are and what
the percentages are that we think we're
going to be able to take on this print
right so you don't want your Sprint
planning to say oh we're going to spend
100 of our time on our on our on our uh
sprinkle right that would be silly
because what happens when something
happens in the product right there's a
production incident well now we're
screwed right or uh somebody comes
running in from the business saying I
know you're working on all this stuff
but this has happened and this is the
most important thing that to us right
now and if we don't have some being
being
um what's it called when you make it
bigger than it is hyperbole right I I I
if we don't get this done by Thursday
we're all out of business and all out of
a job right do we just go no I'm sorry
we've planned our Sprint we can't take
that or do we create a system within
which we can have those conversations
that we can see well I you know yeah
that sounds really important let's bring
that into the Sprint or
um you know also a customer reports some
little bugs and the customer says can
you please get them fixed because
they're just just annoying and they're
annoying a bunch of our users yeah sure
let's fix them let's bring them into the
Sprint let's get them fixed how do you
create that Urban Flow
of the work that you're doing while
still maintaining Direction and strategy
right so you've got the product goal
which is your overall what's the next
big thing we're working on but the
Sprint goal is what's the next little
thing we're working on and that's what
we commit to and that's what we decide
at Sprint planning so it creates that
Cadence of success Cadence of
achievement right what are we trying to
achieve this Brent yeah we've done these
hundred little things but also we did
this which the customer was really
looking forward to that we had
conversations with the customer about
that we crafted into a Sprint goal and
that's one of the things that we do at
Sprint planning so I feel like
regardless of whether
you're doing a little little K kanban
right or or big S scrum
uh you're you're really working towards
the same idea and can use the same tools
and techniques there's also big kanban
the kanban method which has its own
structure and process and rules that's
that's its own thing
um but if you're looking at scrum
and kanban you definitely want scrum and
kanban scrum is about planning
which is why this starts with the Sprint
planning it's all about planning
kanban is about delivery so bringing
them both together and you actually get
the best of both worlds
you get that planning Cadence connecting
with customers understanding what we're
doing
um and Sprint planning is the thing that
sets the tone for the rest of the Sprint
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility