hey welcome to running a live virtual
classroom my name is Martin nature wood
I'm a professional scrum trainer with
Rhonda dark and I run our company called
naked agility out of Scotland
naked agility is available for DevOps
and agile training
[Music]
okay so I been running a number of live
virtual classes I've run two so far and
I have noticed that em when students
first come in to the class it can be a
little bit difficult and daunting not
just maybe learning scrum for the first
time but also learning new technologies
for the first time so I wanted to cover
the two technologies that I will be
using in my trainings one is Microsoft
teams as I'm using that for video
conferencing and for some communication
channels and I'm also using a product
called mural for digital whiteboarding
so get some of that feel of an in-person
class so first off Microsoft teams
so Microsoft teams is a tool from
Microsoft that allows us to create calls
one of the first hurdles to get over is
connecting to Microsoft teams we do
recommend that you download and install
the app rather than use the web version
it gives a much better experience during
the class the web version is good if
you're just joining a meeting for a
short period of time but we're doing two
full days of classroom activities and
really having the the thick client is
important when you connect open up
Microsoft teams it'll ask you to log in
you should log in with the email address
that I invited you to the class with and
hopefully that will be the same as your
corporate credentials or it might be a B
or as your Active Directory credentials
from your corporation or it might be an
MS a Microsoft account so like the same
thing you log into Xbox or Skype and any
of those things if it's a not one of
those email addresses so might be your
Gmail it might be whatever you will be
asked to enable that as a Microsoft
account and just like Google do this as
well you're able to enable any email
address regardless of what platform it's
from as an account you can use to log
into Microsoft services and so it's just
a case of setting setting that up if
you're coming on under an MSA I do
recommend that you use your corporate
credentials if you can and if you need
to change your email address because
your corporate corporation might block
your ability to log into my teams as a
guest then that please ping me and I
will change your email to something else
and you maybe come in under an MSA
so let's take a look at teams teams is
not the simplest application in the
world it does come with a lot of
features and we're only going to be
using a small subset of those features
but it's useful to get just at some of
the the nuance of of how you connect in
now you might have joined teams using a
meeting invite and when you join using a
meeting invite you're coming in not as
an on earth indicated guest which means
that you don't have access to some of
the tools that we're going to be using
what you want to do when you come into
teams is on the top right hand side of
teams next to your profile picture there
will be a little drop-down list and and
it should say your company name if you
normally log into teams with your
company and I you should change that
drop-down list so that it says naked
agility limited that's my company and
once you've done that you'll see
so just reordering that so here I've got
a live virtual PSF on the 1st of January
2015 for my demo account here and what
I've done is created a single meeting
the everybody in that team will have
access to so what will happen is I will
add you to the team I'll invite you to
the team you'll get an invitation
request via email click the link follow
the instructions and then you'll be able
to come in here as a fully fledged guest
in my team's account now once you're in
here if you click on any of the items
that have this little symbol here you'll
be able to go in and open the meeting
and in the top right hand side you'll
have a join button so even if nobody
else is in there
you will have a join button to be able
to to get in so if you click join
because you're already authenticated it
will just allow you to have access right
away so I'm going to turn my video off
so we don't get confused by what's
coming up here and I'm going to join now
okay let me make myself a little bit
smaller there we go
so once you're connected to the team
you'll obviously see the the carousel of
people's videos you should have both a
short conversation and assure
participants enabled and if you do not
you have not come in under an
authenticated account you've come in
under an anonymous account which can
happen but if you come in under an
authenticated account negative jollity
limited then these buttons will be
enabled for you one of the things that
we're going to do is part of the the
team is ruined to work in breakout rooms
so this is the main channel that will be
open all day this is where when we get
together and we have our big room events
with however many people are in the
class and everybody will be in this room
so most people will set with mute on
when people start talking at the moment
that you can only have nine videos in
and I don't know what you call it
gallery nine videos in a gallery and
whoever's talking will be one of those
nine videos in the gallery and if you
have a particular interest in an
individual you can right-click on their
picture and pin it to the gallery so
that they don't disappear but what I'm
going to do is I'm actually going to go
over here onto the left-hand side and
you'll see the team's button again if
you commit not authenticated you won't
have this you should open team's log in
and switch to negative ility but if I
click on teams I'll go back to the main
view where we're looking at the team the
call will be in this little display here
so whoever's talking will have the the
picture the one picture you can have
there and and then you'll see down here
that this team has two channels general
and team X the general channel has a
little icon to see that the
is currently a meeting underway in that
channel and if you go in click on that
channel you'll see here that you'll have
a big join button because the meeting is
currently under way and the same option
to click through into the calendar item
and start it but because it's already
started you can just join it and go
straight in which is really powerful and
when you're instructed to you have
particular exercises that are done in
teams each team will have maybe teams 1
2 3 4 maybe they'll have names it
depends on the type of class we're
running but each of those teams will be
listed here I'll be creating them during
the class and if I click on this team
you'll see it's currently empty it was
brand new it has nothing in it but we
want to create a space for that group of
people to be able to to interact if
there's not one already you can actually
click meet now and then it's actually
it's helpful if you put in the name of
the team and then whatever else you want
after that and you can just click on
meet no so now I'm in our second team
meeting oh there we go so there's my let
us earn the camera off again otherwise
somebody might freak out and you can see
on the left hand side here that the
other main room has been put on hold so
if I go back to teams again you'll see
that there's two call started and I'm
currently participating in team X and I
have main on hold this means if I just
leave these calls open so I don't click
hang up when I change between calls I
can actually just go here click play and
now I'm in the main room so if I open up
full screen now I'm in the main room
Nariman team X
now I'm in the main room so I can very
easily and quickly switch between those
those rooms we normally run with
multiple facilitators so there will be
somebody to help with this but once you
get to grips with it you went to the the
team room for a short period of time you
pop back out when we're doing the the
main exercises and it's it flows pretty
well and it's a very quick transition
now one of the things that I can do is
you'll see and you've got a little short
conversation at Wendell here in the main
room if I want to send you some
information while you're in that room
and I'm actually able without joining
the room it to go in here and hit time
is up to let you know to come back to
the main room and when I send that in
your team X meeting that you're having a
discussion at this short conversation
will actually light up and you'll see
the times up in the meeting chat on the
right-hand side that's a very quick way
for me to do that you may not notice if
you don't notice give you a moment then
I'll pop in and say oh we need to come
back to the main room because I'll be
able to switch between multiple teams as
well and I typically run this class with
between these classes between 10 and 20
people specifically for the PSF and I
always have at least one additional
facilitator to help make sure you can
switch between those rooms effectively
in addition to that so I went too high
on those two cars no hang up those two
calls they're finished and at the end of
the class you'll be invited to join the
professional scrum at community team
here this is a team that everybody that
has gone through one of my classes is a
member of and and in here there's some
interesting chat but there's also access
to the course where you'll have a direct
link in the email that I send at the end
of the class and but if you use teams to
access this files and data for example
if I open up the PSF you'll see a list
of the course where that has been
available and I make the PDFs available
for each version of the courseware that
comes out so I'm continuously updating
this so if you did take a previous class
you'll be able to go in and get a newer
version of the courseware when it
becomes available and there's some extra
material in here available as well and
if you click on class media you'll have
a folder for your team your class that
only you and the people on your class
will be able to access they'll that will
only be visible to those folks and it
will have additional things like if we
took pictures during the class and if we
use murals and PDF them or other things
then they will end up in that folder
there and in addition to that I have a
folder with all of the presentations
that I do at conferences so sometimes
I'll mention them in the class because
adds value to our discussion but maybe
not 100% relevant for everybody so we
don't do it in the class plus we only
have two days so you can go and see some
of these presentations that have been
done previously and those recordings
online as well on my youtube channel so
that was I kind of walkthrough of how
we'll be using
teams in the class hopefully that was
useful and will help you figure out how
to get things going as quickly as
possible one of the things we do find is
that the first half day can be a little
bit lengthy that when folks don't
understand the technology or haven't
used it before and so just this is just
to give you a quick brief so I think we
need to have a look at the second piece
of technology
which is mural
okay so mural is a digital whiteboarding
tool and it's reasonably powerful we've
been using it quite extensively for
classes both of the classes that I've
run have used it and many other scrum
trainers have used this class as well
and so let me switch to mural is
available in the web there has a number
of pretty straightforward capabilities
as well as some advanced capabilities as
well and I'll be sharing a link directly
to the individual mural with you
and you'll be able to go directly into
that mural so this will just take a
second to load
there we go so this is at the mural that
I'll be using for my class on Monday
well this is the kind of demo make a
mass version of it and in this you'll
see there's an outline on the right hand
side if you don't have an outline
there's a button to toggle the outline
up there and and we'll start on at
preparation where we'll do some
introductions and we'll figure out who
everybody is what we're doing here and
that kind of thing we will also have
slides in combination with this as well
and just to note that if you want to
take notes or you're asked to UM add
data to these pages you can actually
just double click anywhere on any page
and it will put a post-it there and if
you want to change your post-it color
you can change it in here and then you
can add other post-its and if you do
another post-it close to a post-it that
you've changed it will be the same as
the one you just created but if you do
it next table I don't put their next two
other ones that will be yellow and that
will be a purple circle so there's a
number of tools to be able to do that
text shapes drawing images you can do
anything you like on there and just move
them around and do a bunch of things
with them what I'll be doing during the
class as a facilitator this is the
facilitators view that you're seeing now
is I'll be able to go in in here and
I'll be able to summon everybody to that
this point so I'll be instructing all of
the students in the class might be 20
people to all go to the same mural and
I'll see a little icons down in the
bottom for each of the students that are
in here and when I summon everybody
they'll come and see the same thing as
me they'll have follow enabled on me so
you can see that somebody who's left it
open on their computer from the last
class and has anonymous elephant and our
self aunt is now following me so as I
drag around as
move around they'll have their display
moved as well and they'll see exactly
what what I'm seeing so we can talk
about it we can have discussions we can
talk about those and those capabilities
in addition to that this is just the
main mural we're all all of us will be
working there's also a separate team
based at mural just for teams and for
teams to work in for for each class
again it depends on the class which
murals we use this is for the
professional scrum foundations class and
what I'll hopefully be doing is I'll be
setting timers when we have time boxes
so even if you're in your separate teams
meeting you
teams team meeting yeah you'll be able
to see the timer and I would point out
that the timer is javascript-based and
if you switch away from the display and
then back again the timer does not keep
the correct time so if you have more
than one mural open and you switch
between them the timer gets out of sync
with the real world it's a little bit of
a bug in mural but I'm sure they'll fix
it at some point but ultimately having a
timer that you set on your phone for the
time boxes that are described will will
help a great deal and help us make sure
we keep on track and come back and we
don't have to chase everybody so much
quite often we extend the first exercise
the first time box we have a kind of
team-building exercise at the start and
we often extend it just because first
use of the tool people need a little bit
of extra time so I'm going to end that
timer and when the timer is up and it
will actually pop up a little message on
your screen that says time up it's not
super obvious but it's not super hidden
either and then we will go back to the
main room and maybe bring some of that
discussion that we've had back to every
in the organization so um in addition to
that we might do some voting quite often
we maybe come up with five or six ideas
for something and then we want to have a
vote on it
this is something that you can do in
your team rooms as well actually maybe
you can't but you're good edit rights
but you maybe can't do a voting session
that's a good point so ignore me and
that but we might do voting sessions as
a group so I will create a voting
session some thought I'll say how many
votes
everybody gets and I'll start that
voting session and you can see you can
click a card to add a vote and
shift-click to remove a vote and your
voting is anonymous and nobody else sees
your votes until the end and so we can
begin voting and I can add two votes to
one card one boat to another card and I
have no votes left and I can see how
we're getting on and maybe III don't
know it's a little bit anonymous who
vote car but um I can I can call out
that this three votes left from people
I'll give it a set amount of time and
then I will end the voting session and
when I end the voting session everybody
will see what are the stickies what are
the posts what are the items that
everybody's voted on this can be very
useful for facilitating classes and
agile agile training um okay so mural is
fairly straightforward this is the the
mural that I created just as a
playground for students I usually do a
tech check before a class and I take
them through and live this type of
exercise which maybe maybe helps them
really understand what it is what it is
they need to do so I would very much
like to have that many of you in my
class ease
and I'm going to be sending this video
out to prospective students as a short
introduction and commit 23 minutes to to
to get started with both of those
capabilities logging into teams working
out with mural and then coming back to
the main group and all of the murals
will be PDF at the end of the class and
available for all of the students to go
down Lord it's a very powerful tool cool
so um that was really everything I had
for folks that was at teams and mural
I'm I'm hoping that that will make it a
little bit easier for you to get started
and either in one of my classes or
anybody else's classes or training where
they're using teams and mural
[Music]
naked agility is available for DevOps
and agile training and consultant
contact us for a free consultation