so one of one of the key practices that
I think is hugely valuable for for
organizations if they're moving towards
that more frequent delivery if they're
starting to get things in front of
customers as quickly as possible Right
you want to if you want to be able to do
be doing continuous
delivery you're going to
accept that you're going to be deploying
features new features to
production that you're not you're not
you're might be the product manager or
you might be the developers that you're
not ready for customers to use yet right
you might need you might have a feature
that takes multiple deployments to get
to the point where you're happy to be
able to to to have more more have it in
production right even if it's the end of
the feature is much further down the
line you've got 10% you want to do
before um you want
the majority of users to be accessing it
but you're going to be delivering 1% at
a time right just as a as a random
example a great example of uh
this again the Azure devops team do a
great job of this you can go open up
dev. your.com and when you're logged in
you'll see that there's a button in the
top right with a a picture of you or a
blank but picture of you you click on
that and it'll have a preview features
option and when when you click that it
will list all of the feature flags that
are available okay so what what they
effectively
do is they they write all of if they're
writing an update to an existing feature
that's in production it's just going to
go unless they're replacing a whole
feature like they did recently with as
your boards they had old boards and new
boards they wanted they were doing a big
update and they had a feature flag for
that right
typically if you're adding functionality
to an existing feature you're probably
just shipping it right because it's a
smaller change but if you're adding a
net new functionality to your product a
new feature a new capability a new
different thing then they hide it behind
a feature flag feature Flags the feature
flag would then be turned on in their
environment they have a the developers
themselves environment in their
environment for testing would be for
their once they're happy with their
testing they're going to turn it on for
the product group right so the
environment that they're working in
their account has that new feature and
they're going to be looking at the
Telemetry the developers that built the
feature are going to be looking at the
Telemetry so it's off for 99% of all the
users in the system it's on Just for
their own engineering team and then
they're looking at the Telemetry is this
performing is it doing the right thing
is it causing a lot of exceptions
they're looking at all of that data once
they're happy that that's uh good they
maybe open that up to everybody within
within Microsoft that's opted in to to
to see those things so then everybody
inside of Microsoft can turn on that
feature and can turn off that feature
the feature flag's visible if you turn
off a feature flag it asks you why
you're turning it off and if it's okay
to contact you very prudent I always
give a message and I always tick the Box
to say it's okay to contact me and I do
get contact from those teams because
they're interested in like why are you
turning it off oh you've said why it is
but I don't quite understand what you
mean and then they'll contact you and
try and figure it
out what's missing right what's missing
that you need is there a expectations
Gap is there a it's bad right it's not
what I need is it causing errors and
Performing badly on my machine right
those are all could be reasons why I
want to turn it off but at some point
they're going to want to open it out to
a wider audience more people in the
world so what they typically do is they
publish a blog post on their their team
aure devops blog that says here's a new
feature we're working on we're looking
for people to help us kick the tires and
kick the tires is just a euphemism for
try it out and see see if it
works and they give an email address for
you to email with your account account
and they'll enable it for your account
then on your account you'll get that
feature flag and you can it will be off
by default and you can go turn it on
again they're looking for people turning
it off and feedback they're looking for
Telemetry of people leaving it on is it
performing well that's their private
preview so you have to explicitly opt in
to that capability and that means that
you're limiting your audience right they
they'll they have an idea they'll be
able to look across all of the times
they've done this and have an idea how
many people they're going to get
with that number of people they're then
monitoring the Telemetry and looking at
do we have enough people using it is it
because they might have to do another
blog post right or another way to get
people in and do we have enough people
using it do does the Telemetry look good
is this viable for the next stage so the
next stage after that might be a public
preview and a public preview is that
switch that feature flag then becomes
visible to everybody on the service and
they put it out in a blog post saying
this is now available to everybody we'd
like you to try and kick the tires so
people that want to then go switch it on
it's now easy they don't have to email
it's just there they can go turn it on
and see what it's like some people just
Discover It other people they're reading
the blogs and and they find it and again
they're looking at Telemetry do we have
enough people using it do we need to
promote it again do users care do they
use this feature is it performing well
all of that type of data they're looking
at on whether whether they need to
invest more in that feature whether
anybody cares about that feature whether
they just need to stop right or so it's
it's
pivot H uh anti up or call right that's
your your the poker analogy right you're
you're is this feature
viable if they get enough Telemetry and
everything looks good the next stage is
they turn on the feature for everybody
on the server but they leave that
feature flag to be able to turn it off
so they're interested in that feedback
who's turning it off why are they
turning it off can we have a chat with
them and find out what's missing what do
they need right you're engaging with
your customers this is the development
team the engineering team that built
that functionality is continuously
engaging with with real real customers
in production either through Telemetry
or actually talking to them because you
want to find out what's going on I I've
turned off a Fe before cuz I didn't like
it and said I didn't like it this is bad
it's not working for me take the box hit
submit and a couple of days later I've
got a a a communication from the product
manager for that feature the person
who's moning that feature and bringing
it through to basically ask what's it
need what's missing why' you not like it
all useful and do we need to make keep
continue to make changes to it before it
goes goes live so at any point in that
story you can pull that feature you can
just disappear that feature flag and
it's gone for everybody because it's
performing badly because and you can
automate that as well so you could have
automation that checks for performance
and then automatically let's get rid of
that feature if it if it's impacting the
system right that should be it should be
just built into the
system and then once everybody's got it
turned on people aren't turning it off
there's probably a few lards there's
probably a few unhappy people when you
change things right you move their
cheese that's just the cost of doing
business but everything's generally
okay then feature flags on for everybody
you start removing that feature flag
from the system and that features just
in production so that could be a very
long time I know that when the Azure
devops team did their boards the new
boards old boards it took them nearly
two and a half years nearly three years
to get everybody over to the new
boards because they kept hitting missing
functionality they kept hitting some
performance problems and then they had
to kind of old boards rewrite that new
boards again and it took them a long
time to to to to get
from where we need to replace the boards
to it's done it was a very long time and
so feature flags and how you enable
feature Flags so they can be behind the
scenes they can be something that you
give actual users access
to these this is one of the the core
practices that enable you to do
continuous delivery to production while
protecting your system protecting your
users and enabling you to get the
Telemetry you need to understand whether
you've built the right thing in
production