chaos costs money most
organizations that I work with and have
worked with really struggle with
controlling the chaos within the context
of delivering usable working product to
their customers they find that the the
the the work is substandard we've got a
lot of a lot of bugs hitting production
we've perhaps got a lot of rework
happening cuz things aren't aren't quite
what we expect them to be or or don't
meet the minimum standard for our
organization and we end up going down
dead ends I'm going to need to explain
that
but a lot of the time and and and I do
this as well when I'm building products
is you try and figure out a solution to
the problem you've got right you've got
a problem you know where you want to get
to where you want to get to just now and
you come up with a solution that gets
you to that that that thing that you
want to get to but over over time that
where you want to get to does in fact
shift right it could shift because of
different Market opportunities that
arise or it could shift because we we
we're scaling right so we we came up
with a solution that was on par at the
time we we we we came up with a solution
but now it now it's subpar it doesn't
you know it's it's slow we're running
into problems we're we're having a lot
of support calls because of Technology
choices that we made that are no longer
no longer valid uh you see this a lot in
the in the extreme in the Airlines and
car rental companies right they have a
lot of I would call it technical debt um
the choices that were made at the time
that they've never gone back around and
refactored right so they still have
Mainframe systems and they don't have
people who understand the Mainframe
systems anymore so they've get double
problem
not only do they still have those
mainframes but nobody in the
organization knows how they work how to
reimplement them how to manage them
where where to kick them when something
goes wrong and that happens all the time
in technology right the technology moves
forward I I work with lots of
organizations who have solved problems
in ways that made perfect sense at the
time because there was no solution on
the Shelf out there that you could go
get I've got one customer that built
their own sof control system because
they started developing software 30
years ago and 30 years ago building
software at scale there weren't very
many options for Source Control Systems
the ones that were out there maybe
didn't fit their needs so they created
their own one but today that doesn't
make any sense whatsoever right there
are there are plenty of good source
Control Systems out there git is the
deao standard and they should be have
all of their code all of their systems
on G
but you need to invest time and money to
move from what you had before to what
you need now and that's part of this
story of of technical leadership and
Engineering
Excellence we need to be focused on
ensuring that our systems and processes
that our people are are using are as
effective as
possible so that their job is as slick
and easy as possible Right Satia does
good work on this at Microsoft right he
he would rather people spent the best
Engineers the the most skilled people
spent time on optimizing the systems
that we have because then we can come
back around and build all the features
we want because we have these really
slick systems um and it seems like it's
a cost right but actually these systems
that's slickness of these systems that
Control the Chaos are a Value Center
because they are the thing that supports
our ability to deliver new features a
great example is the Azure devops team
they back in
2012 before they they they improved
their systems they were they were
delivering something like 24 25 features
to production each year with 650 people
with an application of technical
excellence and effort right this is not
for free and great technical leadership
within the organization they took that
from 25 features to production each year
to over 600 features to production each
year and that difference was because
they paid back a lot of the I I'm going
to say technical debt some of it was
technical debt other stuff was technical
cruft just buildup of I don't know
sediment buildup of of of rust in your
in your system because things get old
technology moves really fast and we need
to keep up with it and because they made
those changes just one simple thing they
they flipped from lots of long running
system tests to unit tests took them
four years of effort to get there but
they took their engineering team's
ability to see whether what they've done
works from 48 Hours down to 3 and a half
minutes think what that would do to your
productivity if you had to wait 48 hours
to find out if the simplest change had
been successful you'd push bigger and
bigger changes through the pipe so when
you do have a problem it's harder and
harder to figure out what that problem
is whereas if you're able to find out if
it works in 3 and A2 minutes you'll be
running that all the time on on the
smallest changes you make and you will
build a better product that's more
scalable and has less Band-Aids right
you're not out with the super glue and
sticky tape trying to seal over the the
the the gaps for bad choices that you
made because you didn't know that there
was a problem you didn't know it wasn't
going to meet the
standard so that cost of chaos is
because of poor technical leadership and
low engineering Excellence you might C
engineering mediocrity within an
organization you can solve these
problems by having your best Engineers
your best people focus on delivering the
systems the optimizations to the systems
that you need so everybody on every team
has the easiest possible job adding
value in your product