dictatorship vs democracy dictatorship
is absolutely fantastic for um getting
getting what you want
done the difficulty is what you want is
not necessarily what everybody else
wants and it's not necessarily what the
right thing is and what we've kind of
found lots of papers and research around
this is that groups of people
collaborating towards a common goal come
up with better ideas than one individual
specialist alone so democracy V
dictatorship probably more somewhere in
the middle someone someone to to to to
set strategic Direction um and then a
bunch of folks who are going to
collaboratively work towards
it