one of the seven deadly sins of agile is
pride now you do want to take pride in
your work we all want to do good things
we want to believe that the things that
we create are valued but I think the
pride that's the sin part is blind Pride
you're taking pride in something without
actually measuring its outcome right we
talk about this all the time for for for
product owners don't just build stuff
willy-nilly you need to collect the data
the Telemetry the analysis you have to
do hypothesis you have to create the
hypothesis I think this thing if I build
it is going to add
value you create it and you don't just
assume that it's going to make the value
that you think it is that's Pride
talking you need to analyze the data and
figure out if that actually did provide
the value You're Expecting and you need
to stop investing in something that
isn't providing the return that you're
expecting it to do another good example
of that uh is is H Satia uh writing down
the cost of Windows phone right writing
off Nokia for for 8 billion sometimes
you have to swallow your pride and not
sink more money into something that's
not going to provide a return and you
just have to stop um I used to work at a
at a bank um in the UK in uh near
Edinburgh and they created they had this
massive piece of software that basically
all it did was create forms for
customers to fill out but it was the
most
convoluted unusable
unwieldly um I don't I don't know I I'm
trying to think of more words to
describe this Ridiculousness of this
this software um it
was didn't provide the features that
they actually needed but they'd spent 2
million on building it so they must use
it we must continue to use it that's
that sunk cost fallacy right which I
think is very closely related to Pride
while we've invested this much money it
must be awesome so we must use it um and
those are assumptions yeah I think pride
pride is how come we we assume stuff we
assume lots of things the product owner
assuming that the features the ideas
that they have are good ones right the
market doesn't always agree um
developers building
things in a
way that entertains
them rather than that actually focuses
on the value delivered to the business
um I've been guilty of that many times
of working on features because they were
fun not because they provided any value
to the customer um done that a ton um so
you need to be really uh uh careful that
you don't become too prideful make
assumptions about the products and
capabilities that you're building the
code that you're writing the the the the
stories that you tell in such a way that
it clouds your view of what's really
going on right because then all you're
looking at is Vanity metrics you're
you're missing out on what's really
going on so don't be so prideful that
you miss out on what's really going
on thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked
agility