I've written bad code and shipped it
that's not technical debt that's
incompetence right so so within the
context of a competent team there's
known technical debt and unknown
technical debt but there's another thing
that we call technical debt which is
just chipping bad code making poor
choices knowing that they're poor
choices and not doing anything about it
right shipping bad code stop shipping
stop shipping bad code would be the way
you pay that one back but for technical
debt you need to pay it back you need to
prioritize paying back that technical
debt uh think of it more as an unhedged
fund rather than a debt like a credit
card um most debt is secured against
something secured against an asset if
you stop paying your mortgage then the
bank comes and repossesses your house
and gets their money back right and
maybe you get some leftovers because
you've paid some of your mortgage