if it's not in the pipeline it's not in
your process you can tell people to
follow standards you can tell them to
check security you can tell them to run
tests but if it's manual it's optional
and if it's optional it's missed manual
quality gates fail because people are
human automation fixes that at Naked
Agility we help you embed real
enforcable quality gates right into your
delivery pipeline security scans static
analysis linting automated tests no
check no deploy no exceptions because
real quality isn't about hoping people
remember it's about making it impossible
to forget want automated quality that
you could trust let's embed it in your
delivery pipelines