that is an amazing that's an amazing
question so
from my point of view the main
difference between traditional
management and agile leadership is based
on the context context is the king here
and it plays a crucial crucial role so
traditional management
was created for defined problems so the
problems that maybe they are not easy in
the sense we are producing some
sophisticated stuff but they are simple
or obvious from a complexity point of
view so those are things that are
relatively easy to follow you need
instructions you need monitoring you
need someone with knowledge and
expertise how to control the whole
process
so if you face very little or no no
ambiguities you have very little risks
very little unknowns well you can
completely forget about unknown unknowns
you might be lucky to to take benefits
from traditional management such
managers are very important for this
kind of problems challenges in my view
however
why we are talking about agile
leadership and importance of that well
my my view is that we as humankind we've
learned a lot how to improve things
well I mean automation using
sophisticated machines algorithm AI is
helping us to translate problems that
have some unknowns into something that
can be handled by the machine
what does it mean for us for humans well
more and more problems to come are
moving towards complex domain the domain
that is very interesting the domain that
needs creativity and this is the domain
where traditional management might not
be the best tool so imagine the
situation that you are coming to the
rest around the waiter is serving a very
hot soup and now you have a sharp knife
enjoy your meal most likely you may cut
yourself right so this is this is the
metaphor that I personally love uh in
that context when You Face complex
problem with a lot of unknowns uh
traditional management might be seen as
this sharp knife served next to the bowl
with a very very hot soup
so adult leadership changes its approach
it emerges as a response to our
world with a lot of problems a lot of
ambiguities a lot of unknown things this
is the leadership that is focused on
taking the best out of us humans taking
the best out of creativity creating
teams self-managing teams teams that are
making more and more decisions and the
role of the leader because of that is
changing is changing towards creating
right environment
fostering creating right culture and
helping others in that process instead
of controlling and and monitoring