most
organizations don't realize the amount
of waste that they have in their system
the amount of money that they're
hemorrhaging because they don't have a
focus on engineering Excellence this
this this idea within the context of of
of of agile of business agility of
everything being continuous right so
you've get continuous integration
continuous delivery continuous feedback
continuous testing that continuous
nature that things are happening
dynamically enables you to find problems
quicker so the problems are smaller that
eliminates some waste but it also
enables you to collect data and
Telemetry and understand what's going on
a little bit more easily which means
that you can identify problem areas and
do something about them before those
costs spiral out of control I work with
so many customers that have so much
waste I I I've got some Dora metrics
here I think not all of them are Dora
most of them are Dora metrics we use it
to tell this exact point for for for
agile leaders in our agile leadership
classes but we talk about a number of
different metrics right and if we're
talking about a $1 one Euro one pound
budget and how much of that how much of
that pound dollar euro ends up as actual
value delivered in your product right
and and and what what do you measuring
to understand your return on investment
on on that story so these are just four
metrics that I'm going to use there are
many more metrics that you could be
looking at that can can impact on this
um but one of the biggest ones is
innovation rate what percentage of your
time of your people's time do they spend
innovating rather than augmenting
existing functionality or support and
maintenance right so it's net new
capability within your product and this
is is is really it's a really important
piece because it's the reason why
Netflix uh creates a new show rather
than doing the second series of that
show that you you liked and it's because
when you do a second series right you
augment existing functionality when you
do a second series your audience for the
second series is going to be smaller
than the first series unless there's
some kind of information that leads
differently the default is that the
second series is going to have less
audience right so it's going to make
less money than the first series so if
your second series is going to cost just
as much as a first series wouldn't it be
better to invest that money in a first
series to get a higher potential
audience it's a bet right a higher
potential audience return than it is do
a second series of an existing if the
existing Series has enough of an
audience and enough of a demand for a
second series then it's probably worth
it right you'll get your return on
investment but otherwise it's not worth
it which is why you see the rise of
limited series right I think we'll see
the rise of limited features and
products but Innovation rate is around
39% on average that was the the last dor
metrics that I I kind of looked at so
29% of it budget goes on net new
functionality that's new customers new
markets opening out new capabilities for
your product that's not a lot that's 29
cents on the dollar 29 uh cents on the
Euro 29 p on the pound that's terrible
right and that's just one metric so now
we we only have 29 cents of big Roi in
our product or big potential Roi in our
product what about our on product index
that's what percentage of our Engineers
time do they spend or our people's time
do they spend working on the product
versus doing other
stuff right um the average is about 80%
of their time they spend on the product
20% on other stuff so we would be down
to 23 cents on the dollar what about
usage index what percentage of the
features that you build in your product
are actually used by your customer right
the the the industry average is about
35% 35% of the features that you build
are used by your customer that means the
rest is
waste right it's not really all waste
because sometimes you need to build
features that people don't like to find
out what they do like so that would
wouldn't be waste that would be learning
right so some of it's learning it's
difficult to quantify quantify the
learning but certainly a huge piece of
it is waste lots of companies build lots
of features that your users have
absolutely zero interest in right you be
surprised at go ask your engineering
teams what their usage index is what
percentage of the features that they've
built are used and used Often by their
customers so Microsoft has a has a a
measure that they use which is monthly
active users for each feature in your
product what are the monthly active
users if you can't answer that question
you have no idea whatsoever whether your
features are being used or not so why
are you building them how do you know
you should be adding new features to
this piece of functionality right that
that that augmenting existing if we
don't even know what our user base is
why are we adding why are we spending
money on it right it's a it's a it's a
blind BET right that's a bad bet it's
completely unhedged but 35% usage rate
now brings us down to 8 cents on the
dollar so we went from a dollar to 28
cents on the dollar 23 cents on the
dollar now8 cents on the dollar and
we're not even finished yet because if
we're building a application that people
install if you look at things like
Windows right what percentage of us the
user Bas is on the latest version of the
product now the industry average is
about 70% right so 30% of users are on
an older version of the product I have
lots of customers where that's not even
remotely true that it's a much smaller
percentage on the latest version of your
product so that brings us down to six
cents in the
dollar if
your your return on investment for every
dollar you spend you get 6 cents that's
0.06
% return on investment is that a good
investment I think it's not a good
investment I think we need to do a whole
bunch of work in understanding why
that's so low and dealing with the
reasons why it's so low so in in our
example here the biggest the biggest hit
at the start was Innovation rate right
do you even know your Innovation rate
percentage of time on Innovation percent
percentage of time spent on ADD
augmenting existing functionality
support and
maintenance right what are those three
percentages for your business you should
you should absolutely understand that
for every product that you
have the next biggest thing is is usage
Index right what percentage of the
features are actually used by your
customers do you understand that are you
collecting the Telemetry that you need
to understand that so that you can make
decis
decisions on where you're investing your
capital and not letting costs spiral out
of
control agility is part of this story
agility and devops talk about how you
can close the feedback loops get faster
at iterating and
reduce cost not you're not really
reducing cost because you've got the
same people doing the same amount of
work but your costs to Value ratio
should go up right you should be
delivering more value for the money
you're putting in not the