of why is the professional agile
leadership Essentials course a Natural
Evolution for an experienced product
owner
it starts to bring in
um
again as product owners
become more advanced in product
management right as they get more
skilled within the organization as they
get more respected within the
organization as having that that product
management uh feel for them they'll
start to be
um given more accountability right or
have being able to pick up more
accountability uh that's enabled for
them and they start moving into a more
leadership role as well and quite often
I I know people who are product owners
um who are not just product owners they
are systemic leaders inside of their
organization
um my favorite product owner is uh Brian
Harry who is the product unit manager of
the Azure devops team at Microsoft of
the developer division at Microsoft
um and he had some of something like 650
700 people
um that reported to him
um and he's he's the product owner he's
the budget holder he's the direction
maker the strategy designer right even
though he's taking lots of input from
lots of different people he's the one
that has the final say so he is the
product owner but he's also the leader
he's the people that everybody in that
engineering department looked to he was
the one that created
I'm using the wrong phrase created the
culture that everybody worked within but
that's not really the right phrasing
because he didn't create it he created a
system within which uh the culture that
the desired culture thrived right and
that's part of leadership right is
creating the systems that we all work
within that's slightly bigger than just
being a product owner so I think I think
it is a a logical Evolution it's the
next step uh from product ownership
um that allows
um for a better understanding of that
holistic organizational View
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility