welcome to another episode of agile
actually today we're going to talk about
tools creating more of a problem than
they
solve what do you think Simon that looks
like it triggers you
already tools complicating the problem
uh I I love the quote from Grady bo uh a
fool with a tool is still a fool just
and then you got the coroller but now
they're a tooled up fool
um I think it's very easy to fall into
the tool trap I think this this is a
massive thing um how much do you
include
predefined packaged processes or
practices in in that word to as well
because I I kind of I kind of do right
if you if you
have is an interesting one yeah is is
Scrum
tool yeah that's a that I W that's a
good one it depends I guess it depends
on your perspective right scrum could be
a tool from one perspective it could be
a like a collection of tools that are
put together into a technology right I I
I I tend to think of scrum as a
technology rather than specifically as a
tool but you could that there's some
synonymous nature between those two
terminologies right yeah words are fun
right yeah but but for story points is a
tool Yeah well yeah so it's a yeah uh a
device or implement used to carry out a
particular
function yeah all right so if we say
that's what a tool is I I really like
the fact that Ken and Jeff called it a
framework so it's a a collection of um
aspects that help you achieve a
particular purpose
so I think it'd be useful for this not
to get into
framework methodology discussion sure
yeah I think that's that's just Elmo
those right so our little red friend can
just jump out there and right so I think
the the idea behind the
topic is that there's quite
often tool tools should be there to help
enable us to do the thing that we need
to do yeah but quite often they get in
the
way of doing the thing that we need to
do because of some some particular
reason perhaps
because everybody in the organization is
told to use the same tool that could be
a reason for it to get in the way right
but it's not really a generic framework
right it's it's a specific tool and it's
for a specific
outcome and
people have to use it for everything and
therefore you start having it used for
jobs that it shouldn't be used for
right um yeah and then we also have the
the boiler plating of
tools yep
where a tool is configured or locked
down or over
controlled I've seen far too many people
trying to work in an agile way and the
custodians of the tool their job is the
tool and they lock the tool down so you
have very little permissions to uh
change it so your team wants to innovate
or try something differently but you
have to use this tool even selecting
another tool is considered heresy um
varying the way the tool is used for
whatever reason is considered a breach
um and people it then becomes an attack
on someone's St status to suggest a
different configuration of the tool
someone will go off and read a Blog
article or something and then just put
another bit of formula in it and lock it
down and make this a mandatory field and
next thing you know uh you're looking at
a
700% like that's a number by the way it
was proven I did this with a client the
tool we wanted to use to the tool we
mandated to use it was a
700% increase in admin to Ed the
mandated tool as opposed to the
preferred tool cu the reason we wanted
to use a preferred tool it wasn't locked
down uh I've got a another a concrete
example that I can even name I can even
name and shame the organization and it's
Microsoft uh they had on the Windows
team in the old days they used to have
the windows
teams process yeah your devops it used
to be up on up on giop GitHub upub so
you could go go take a look at it and on
the bug work item there was 170 plus
required fields in order to sub required
required Fields you could not save a bug
unless you'd filled out all of these 170
required Fields oh there would be some
nonsense saved in that right cuz only
non not only some nonsense saved in that
role but there's the old adage that if
make something even a little bit
difficult you vastly reduce the instance
of action right yeah that's why we have
locks on our front doors right there's
not a lock that anybody has on their
front door that somebody who really
wants to get in can't get in right but
if you deter people enough and make it
enough difficult then most people don't
bother their butt doing it and that's
the same with with anything you put in
the way that's the the configurations
the complexities in the tool that you're
using anything that you put in the way
vastly reduces the
um the the the instance of people
actually doing the thing you want them
to do which poent maybe you don't want
them to raise bugs right maybe that's
that's exactly why that ties into
transparency right and there's proven
evidence that creating a culture that is
more comfortable raising bugs talking
about incidents and near misses creates
a cult C culture of quality which
results in performance Improvement and
enhancement but what we're talking about
is putting the minimal sufficient
obstacle in the road so that the it just
it's too big right the activation energy
is too great so people don't do it and
typically the way this has worked around
in a lot of the Enterprises I've seen is
they then end up putting default
information in these mandatory fields to
get around that hurdle to make people
use it will just default fill it anyway
which means that you end up with more
noise than signal well this is why in
aure devops there's a template option I
don't know if you've you've if you're as
your developed user you might have
noticed on a work item you can click on
the ellipse and create a template from
the work item that you're viewing and it
will pre-populate a whole bunch of
fields and then you can just apply that
template when you open a new work item
apply that template and it will fill out
a whole bunch of stuff right um but then
you've got
noise then you get noise right if that
if that data I I it's the same reason
that I
always have strong words when people
want to template their work items right
I've got got whenever I add this type of
backlog item I want these 10 tasks to
appear under it and it's but it has to
be a user story Martin it has to be in
user story syn yeah that to has to be
with story points with story points
right and that's that's why that's why
you get get backlog items in somebody's
backlog that says as a product owner I
want or as a system as system for I want
as a systems integrator it's like the
the
those that square peg round hole right
you're trying to fit something into a
format use a tool for a task that it was
not meant to be used for and then it
ends up inhibiting value reducing
transparency because people can't really
see what's going on
a good example that I hit recently uh
same same same idea that OB Fusion that
lack of reducing
transparency is and and there's a little
bit I know this is a tools conversation
so it's a little bit Azure devops but
when you when you put a work item in you
know how you've got the different levels
in Azure devop you've got backlog and
then you've got the feature level and
then you've got the epic level you can
call them whatever you want and you can
have up to seven levels but that's
effectively that's it the out of the box
when when you have a a the caman board
the board's view it's not called campan
board but board's view there boards and
then task board right those are the two
views on the on the board view if you uh
it defaults The Columns to all of the
states that are physically on the work
item right so if the work item is new
approved uh
uh in progress done right that will be
the default column
and then teams can break them down and
make them more columns if they want out
of
that but in a team that I'm working with
at the moment and this is across an
entire group so there's about 13 teams
working in this in this project
somebody's created a dependency work
item right which is which is okay this
is like an external to this group of
people's dependency that we want to
Monitor and track but they've added it
to the backlog level and it has eight
eight states that are completely
different from the the the the the
backlog item state which means the
default when you go to look at the
boards is eight states no there's eight
plus the back right so 13 15 and it just
effectively shits it all out right yeah
and then if you try and move a backlog
item into a column that isn't a state on
that backlog item it zops back to the
start because it doesn't know what to do
with it because that state doesn't exist
on that backlog item but this is the
infu that is a perfect example of a
tool complicating already complex work
yes the tool is getting in the way and
but it's it's there's two difficulties
right there's somebody made a
mistake they didn't know it was a
mistake but somebody did something that
reduced the effectiveness of the tool
made it harder to use the tool for the
majority of people that are using it
they had good intentions but they it
harder but as soon as that is is is
raised it's a very easy physical fix
right you just take that dependency and
move it out of the backlog group and
you're done to 100% fixes the problem
instantly
but how do you get approval to do that
well this is this is an interesting
thing that I'd like to call out a few
aspects of that example the first one is
the the whole lean approach
of a local optimization for a suboptimal
hole right we're solving a very small
problem in a big system and we've just
made it insurmountably worse for
everyone else yep um the second one
is authorization and the need for
architecture and this is something that
is not disgusting a
lot I know we we talk about it in the
PSD my favorite course and my favorite
version of it was the original version
that you and I qualified under back in
the day five day one and we had a good
at least dayong discussion about
architecture and the ilities and the
need for architecture and the fact that
we start at a high level and we work
down and architecture is part of the
planning process and and how you do
emergent architecture yeah it's and
without ending up with that famous house
the Winchester House in America right
because we've we've seen products like
that what you're describing as a
Winchester House process just a quick
pause here uh anybody who hasn't heard
of it get on your favorite search engine
and have a look at the Winchester House
a fascinating story truly tragic um a
wonderful collection of Foles and
Architectural stupidities because it
there was no overall design or intent
with it yeah and so with a tool
particularly Enterprise tools we need to
have architecture in line with the
organizational process yep so we have to
have freedom at the team
level but it's done in such a way that
one team changing something doesn't by
default impact and roll out and it's
trying to find that goldilock spot
between Some central body going
everybody must do it exactly like this
no Freedom no flexibility
and each team coming up with some change
that then ripples out and corrupts every
other team yep exactly exactly and and
I've worked in a lot of organizations
where that that's true that there's some
local optimization and sometimes it's
it's um f founding founded in business
need right the the the sometimes for a
big organiz the example I'm thinking of
is when I worked at Marl
Lynch um they have the the people who
make the real money for the
business are the the trading desk yeah
folks everybody else is supporting them
and at some point some tool that
somebody wrote inside of the
organization got installed on a trading
desk platform on the trading desk
platform that they were using and it
disrupted the core trading desk software
right which is a big no no because
that's hundreds of millions every second
it's not working that that things are
going to be a
problem so they instituted a rule that
every piece of software in the
organization has to be validated on that
platform has to
be but now you've created a a
bottleneck inside of the organization
for for example I was building a small
application that ran on uh call center
people's desktop that popped the the
calls for them right so I I it connected
to a database listed all the the the
customer data allowed them to change and
enter customiz data and then pop the
tappy interface to to to to call that
person so that they could do their sales
stuff for selling right completely
different but we had to go through that
three-month process of getting our
software validated on that
environment and all it needed was any
software going on these machines needs
to go through this process right yes to
firew I
remember a similar discussion when I was
a software engineer at Nationwide
Building Society uh I got pinged a
message from the security team that I
was messing around with certain bits and
pieces of the
computer uh which made sense given I was
doing Biz talk development and if you've
ever done bis talk development um you
will be familiar with this thing called
the gak and
bis got really good at this weird thing
called UNG gaking so the global assembly
case where you put assemblies that you
wanted bis talk to consume and if you're
doing local development you had to do
some food right you had to do some dance
and of course this flagged up and hit
security like this guy's messing with
some really fundamental it's like that
was a monitored folder it's like yeah
it's yeah yeah I'm just doing what
you're pay me for but um and this this
can happen so is a processor tool Martin
this is where we're sort of heading
towards do processes become tool like in
their
manifestation I think processes become
tool like and I'm I'm I'm going to say
this in a bad way if they're used like
tools right so a tool is something that
like a hammer I don't alter the hammer
in order to use it effectively in
different circumstances it's a hammer
right it has the shape of the hammer is
the way that the manufacturer intended
it to be me modifying that hammer is is
not something I can't imagine 99.9% of
people out there modifying their hammer
in order to have a different outcome
right or to use it in a different
circumstance there might be the odd
occasion where tools have multi-purpose
and somebody's figured out some weird
thing that you can use a tool for that
works pretty well but in general
intended use for the tool is the use
that you're going to use it for and if
you treat practices like that whether
it's story points or it's um uh uh
planning poker right that's a practice
how to get story points the the three
questions whichever three questions you
like whether it's the daily scrum three
questions or the Sprint retro three
questions right uh if you treat that as
a tool I.E this is how you're going to
do things this is the only way to get to
this outcome this is the only way to use
this thing then it becomes a tool and
potentially inhibits if you're using it
in the wrong circumstances um the way
you're saying that I'm noticing um a
very strong parallel towards the the
process management tools that we were
talking about
earlier
whenever whenever we become too
constrained in how we apply the tool yep
when when it becomes too locked in it
increases the complexity of the problem
and I think this is one of the reasons
we're both fond of scrum we're fond of
the principles of agility because if you
lean into the lightness of it where we
allow our teams to riff within the the
context and the boundaries of the
framework if we know what the
constraints are and they can use the
framework and they're allowed to
experiment and play with that to find
what works for them when we start
locking things in and over mandating it
we
then start limiting the capacity and
capability of the teams to deliver right
so it's at that point be it a business
process be it a a tool physical virtual
whatever with then making the problem
complex and the interesting thing is
when you increase the magnitude of
complexity very soon it tends toward the
boundary of chaos if we thinking of the
Canan framework right because it become
very very unpredictable and the manner
in which we behave becomes unpredictable
as well right yeah it I
it's sometimes easy to do the same thing
over and over again and then quite often
the processes get codified in the tools
as well right so a good good example of
that for me again I I your devops user
not a jira user my claim to fame is I've
never actually touched a jira instance
ever in my life I think that's a pretty
good uh claim but I do play with aure
devops and there's a a thing that I see
teams doing in Retros all the time
there's a plugin for Azure devops which
is called the retrospectives plugin and
it has columns where you add cards for
uh what went well what didn't go well
what do you want to prove what you want
to keep right so there's those columns
and then in it has a a way for people to
vote on those items to surface what
items do we want to talk about do we
want to deal with and then it has a what
are you going to do about it page and
the idea of that is great right it's
that sounds like it's something that
that you want to do but if you've been
using it for the past 20
Sprints suddenly perhaps it just becomes
a mechanical thing it becomes just a
tool and there's no emotion in a tool
there's no there's no connection to the
scrum values yeah that's what I was
looking for there's no connection to the
scrum values and scrum itself scrum
itself can become a tool for
organizations there's a reason it's
called the scrum guide and not the scrum
rule book right it's not there is an
organization out there that sells um
their scrum study book and I think
they've managed to get the 4 Pages up to
208 and every something yeah yeah yeah
aw massive here here's the scrum rule
book right scrum body of knowledge there
you go you want scrum in a project
managed way
so how do we so we're saying a let let
me stumble around and find the question
here we're suggesting that overly
constraining means that um business
practices tools whatever become more
tool like when they become man
mechanical in operation we want to
maintain empiricism and the ability to
live the scrum values when we're doing
stuff how what what advice yeah this is
my question what advice or what
steps could you think of to help
somebody if they find their organization
is becoming overly mechanical like in in
their use of tools like a your Dev so
they've locked it down too far you can't
get this out or they're using they
weaponized retrospectives or you know
everybody has to complete mandatory this
or that or even the reporting on
retrospective output I
find a topic of concern because you
might shut down openness if you know
that the grand Pooh bar of division X is
then going to have a look at your retro
output well I I yeah and a good example
is also totally outside of the well well
the core agile space is procurement as
well right where where companies have
processes in place and treat everybody
the same when not necessarily is that
true right you end up with that's that's
the reason I've fallen in love with lean
agile procurement because it applies the
values of lean and agile to the
procurement process yeah and if we
create a discussion space we can get
through a lot of a lot of which has
become very structured and template
um I think you and I have both completed
bids for multinationals where it you
know took you to better part of three
working days to fill out uh 700 page
that's a mild exaggeration but not by
much
EX I I on on on my current current
engagement I've probably spent a total
of at least 10
days um on admin stuff yeah um and we
need admin right there is a need for it
but how do we how do we create that
space where we can focus on the value
delivery and reduce the
bureaucracy so but this is this is this
is where I feel
like um there's a word that's used a lot
in the adual state space that is what
we're talking about that people
misunderstand and I feel like I used to
misunderstand as
well um and that's the word
emergent that we talk about the the
processes and practices that we
need emerge over time right we talk
about that in in in case of scrum we
talk about it for for everything whether
it's procurement whether it's anything
your process is software development
your processes and practices and the
tools you need the processes you need
the practices you need all emerge over
time time and I always used to think
many moons ago that emerge means Boop
now it's
here right but emerge also means the
continuous shifting of that thing over
time that a process or practice might
emerge and then go away and that's part
of that emerging the the the what you
need emerges over time and that idea of
the constant
shifting of um processes practices and
tools what you need goes against that
idea of we just have one thing one way
to do it right that's that's that
imposed one way to do it so whether
that's we're all going to use user
stories right or we're all going to use
story points or we're all going to use a
hammer and every problem is a nail right
or or or procurement right everybody's
the same so when I'm filling out the
vendor form I have to fill out a
delivery address even though I'm
delivering it virtually how does that
make sense or um you know whatever
whatever I mean that's a little thing
right but it that's part of that process
so how do you
create those processes that are more
Dynamic that take into account of that
emergent nature of what you might need
over time but businesses are designed to
codify the way you do things and then in
Shrine them and lock them in right
you've tightened up all the bolts and
now it can't it can't move
anymore I think this is um there's multi
Parts in in the way I would reflect back
what you've said is that I think the way
you're describing the process is
becoming locked in is very
taoris y and it's that whole concept of
best practice that
once oh hang on that's just Homer
telling me what time it
is um so it's it's taoris in the fact
that we will achieve best practice and
this is the older predictive way of
doing things um because project
management is an Adaptive thing now if
we lock ourselves into a space of of
best practice or known way of doing
things without allowing or
tolerating processes to e and flow it
means our
organizations are more robust and this
is the difference between robust
resilient and antifragile so if a a
robust organization will be able to
withstand the buffets of a a turbulent
World whereas if we build resilient or
anti fragile organizations they're more
organic and they will be able to adapt
adapt and change responding to various
stimuli which means that they they will
have a process
for deprecating processes right though
as part of their adaptation they can bin
stuff they can bring in a different
process they will be able to respond
more
quickly and this I love the quote that
the whole point of agile is to turn on
the dime for a dime to be able to Pivot
to be able to respond that that ultimate
Essence but because agile's 25 years old
now roughly um it's
now it's now mainstream it's only the
late adopters that are coming around to
it you know there's a few pockets of our
organization uh where it hasn't been
early majority have already hopped on
board with agile and it's now getting
into the the late majority right yeah
yeah yeah but how do we bring in this
concept cep of resilience the the whole
antifragility thing of that uh
empiricism loing the values and in
response to your question like how do we
do that I think it comes down to having
clear principles if we have a a good
business strategy Y and good principles
and then we just let our people be
awesome within the boundaries of
business strategy and core principles
principles not rules right that's
principles not
policies yes and anytime you have a you
have a policy you're enshrining one way
to do something when you have a
principle you enable people to make
choices within the bounds of those those
those core principles and it's it's like
if we're designing
uh a well-engineered piece of software
and you know many moons ago I was a
software engineer so I sort of lean back
to that but those principles of uh you
know for instance solid writing good
code that aligned with the solid
principles allowed you the freedom to
find the optimal solution within your
context within your constraints that
aligned with those principles to make it
more maintainable durable testable Etc
so now that we've moved out of that um
you know some of the object-oriented
space we're moving on from we're into
the world of microservices and
architecture like that and
devops and the the rise in devops means
we need to lean into the principles of
automation of faster feedback loop of
zero touch right but its principles
gives you Elbow Room yeah give you gives
you room to experiment to try different
things to see if a slightly different
way is a better way to do something
right which which for lots of
organizations I feel like it's it's that
and I do I do definitely agree with you
is that that taoris view that that um uh
turn of the century Industrial
Revolution thinking where businesses
existed in in very sparse markets right
so they could they could afford to say
here's the one way we're going to do
things and build a business around that
one way we're going to do things but
today the markets are so competitive and
so
shifting that that there's I can't
remember what it's called there's
there's a name for um when you've got
too many species in an ecosystem all
competing for the same
Niche right that some of those species
are going to die out because they're not
going to be able to adapt to somebody's
going to be better at it same reason
that that that that uh um modern humans
out evolved the Neanderthal right we we
probably killed them off because we were
the more more aggressive maybe more uh
uh uh thinky uh solving problems well we
more successful EV evidence suggests we
interbred with them but um sure but yeah
that that whole emergence that that that
responsive as you were talking I just
kept thinking of that that buzz phrase
that's been around for a while now of
vuka volatility uncertainty
complexity
vka something yeah and it it also
reminds me of um uh back in the olden
days like when you're talking about this
that the the days of sale when the Dutch
French Spanish and English were chasing
each other around the world's oceans
colonizing and pillaging and destroying
the world um
the the British quote for Friday was um
a willing Foe and SEO and it's
interesting that that style of
leadership where once they were out if
they were out in their ship they they
they decided there was a lot of freedom
and
latitude but there was some core
principles that guided it um and so if
we can think of creating a space of
autonomy based upon a direct ction and
principles within our teams and enabling
some clear boundaries and I think this
is the thing most organizations really
struggle with what are the constraints
and boundaries of your tooling of your
process of your communication of your
problem space if we can nail
that then we can do it because according
to the scrum guide the team has
flexibility to choose tools that help
them the most so they should have a
mechanism to choose a different
tool but that sounds hard
Simon
uh I think it was Teddy Roosevelt said
that uh nothing worthwhile in life is
going to be
easy it's hard to come up with
principles because you're you're
thinking about what is the core thing
that I'm trying to achieve whereas it's
much easier to just say here's a set of
rules that you have to follow not why
you have to follow it or what you're
trying to achieve as the
outcome it's also much harder
to uh check against principles it
becomes very nuanced it means you
actually have to talk to people I am
concerned about your compliance or I'm
concerned about how you're enacting this
particular principle I don't think you
are let's discuss this it it means that
our leadership style must become more
collaborative it must become more intent
based
because um you and I could both enact a
core principle say we're talking about
um say the principle of
transparency you and I could both enact
it in slightly different ways both honor
it within terms of our context but it
would appear radically different and so
it would Rec a conversation right yeah
and intent intent based leadership if
anybody's confused by that term um have
a read of a book called turn this ship
Around by David Marquette um that would
lead you in the right direction for for
for what they mean if if you can't be
bothered reading the book because you're
not a reader there's also a 15minute
YouTube video that also yeah and also
yeah um there's a huge like US military
created some good things thinking in
this space no General Stanley mccristal
team of teams uh jao willink and Le
babit with extreme ownership and
followed that up with the dichotomy of
leadership um and David marqu turn your
ship around you know there's there's
some good thinking in this space more
recently there's also a bunch of stuff
around red team thinking as well which I
think brings into that space too yeah
it's it's but it's a lot of it is
principle based and the need for
adaptation well when you're when you're
in the middle of nowhere with no ability
to get help from
anybody rules don't help right you need
the principles to have the freedom to
make decisions within the bounds of
those principles so that you can you can
be the most effective you can at
whatever your mission objectives are
yeah be clear upon your mission and be
willing to adapt I do I do always um
I I I I have a a thing that I I say I'm
actually I'm looking for you to correct
my
saying uh is that I I I was always asked
people when when did they believe that
the military stopped believing in
command and
control um and I usually my answer is
when Napoleon defeated the Prussian
Army um and Napoleon was the
first military
leader who pushed respon on a on a big
scale anyway who pushed responsibility
down the
organization and whereas in the Prussian
Army that he was fighting against the
the the the soldier on the battlefield
had to ask a sergeant who had to send a
runner to the lieutenant who had to send
a runner to the major who had to send a
runner to the general and then all the
way back down the chain to get the
answer to what should we do next well I
I would suggest
there are many many instances of that
still being the predominant way of
thinking um a lot of time you know the
Special Forces definitely have more
freedom you know the the elite units but
you have a look at the history we got a
big danger of digressing here um sure
that's the whole reason that World War I
turned into such a meat grinder is that
it was the people hiding in you know uh
Berlin and
London um put pushing some stuff around
the map and not enabling free thought
you know the the whole reason that um
the disaster of The galipoli Landings
and
the the the failure of that was because
a general decided halfway up the hill
like the Anzac could have taken the top
of the hill fortified and then pushed
through but some clown decided it was
time for a teab break halfway up which
gave time for the Turks to reinforce and
you've got immensely capable service
serviceman on both sides y but then just
basically dug in and I all I'm thinking
about when you're saying that is Black
Adder Simon that's all I'm thinking
about that that arity of of that going
over the top in the trenches oh yes you
forgot your stick ah yes I'd hate to
face a German machine gun without my
pointed stick thank you
Baldrick yes exactly yeah it's and so
let's bring it back to the topic so
tools adding to the complexity so
basically what we're saying and we we
went on a flight of fancy as we tend to
when we both start discussing um what we
arrived at is it is possible to use a
physical virtual or business process as
a tool that increases the complexity
that uh boosts the amount of effort you
and your team have to expend to be able
to achieve sometimes even the most
simple of tasks
because it's just unnecessary unworldly
painful Etc so people will either not
use that process tool and you'll then
end up with stuff off the books what
we're saying from that is the more
efficient and effective way of helping
teams achieve greatness is by tapping
into core principles much harder to do
but it enables more latitude and freedom
within clear
constraints how if if so there's then
maybe maybe this is a good good segue
into that idea of autonomy versus
alignment right generally
alignment um is often fulfilled through
tooling right people people align
through tools and and if a practice is
BL it becomes a tool right how how do
how do we tell the
difference
between
alignment that might hinder the team a
little bit at the lower level CU they've
got something extra to do that is needed
in order to be all going in the same
direction
versus the things that people come up
with for us to do at that
level that just just in hinder for for
for little or
no perceivable value or outcome right
how do we tell the difference between
those two things I I got to fall back to
my natural scrum Master stance and just
ask the team like is it helping right
they don't make it harder than it has to
be this is what we're saying don't over
complicate an already messy and complex
situation ask people if it's helping and
this is where alignment of a purpose is
is so important you know the the
apocryphal story of JFK visiting NASA
and he bumps into a chat mopping the
floor and he goes what are you doing and
he goes me I'm helping put a man on the
moon you how many times have you worked
with people in a team uh where they
don't understand what the business
strategy is they don't know the guard
rails of their technical strategy and
it's to quote Lewis Carol you know and
it's the cheshier C if you don't know
where you're going all roads will get
you there
yeah or are if you don't know where
you're going how will you ever get there
well yeah and the thing is if we don't
know where we're going you you've got
different people and like you've got
explorers who just can't wait to get
over the next Hill doesn't matter
whether it's in the right direction as
long as it's a cool and interesting Hill
and then you've got other people who
will not do anything unless there's a
clear Direction so they just set up camp
and then dig in
so you end up with this basically you
create a diaspora within your
organization where people are just going
off doing random stuff because you
haven't put that clear Direction down
yeah so we need a purpose we need a
strategy we need a
direction we need ruthlessness on value
and this is where we should be using
evidence-based management good
leadership principles to do the hard
work and Define and work with your
people to say what the values of your
organization are what your strategy is
and what principles you're going to use
to get there because then people can
find out whether they want to be in or
out of the boat well even even not just
the values of of the
organization but what does value
mean to the organization what does it
mean to the business yeah yeah it's so I
I I very rarely encounter an
organization that already and and that
we're probably jaded Simon in
that companies that are doing awesome at
this don't call us for help right so
well they've got it in Spades right it's
but the thing is that it's that great
quote from bander Brothers is they
they're going into Bastone the regular
infantry going out and the the power
Troopers going in chap coming out says
you're going to the Germans are coming
from everywhere you're going to be
surrounded he just looks him go son
we're paratroopers we're meant to be
surrounded right
you if if you as a
consultant as a
coach don't are not comfortable and
going helping a client who will need
help you've picked the wrong job yeah
absolutely right so I I know there's
there's a lot of organizations out there
that are smashing this there's a lot of
organizations out there that have really
good
principles that are making it easy for
people to thrive uh I'm reading a year
without pants which is a story about
WordPress great book great read and
WordPress were founded on this whole
idea of just getting awesome people to
be
awesome and and virtually from the start
right so from the start up you know and
and one of their core founding
principles was open source that
everything they did people could copy
and fork and Spike and do whatever they
went with that that fundamental ethos of
a communitybased development flipping it
into a business enabled really super
smart people to solve a very tough
problem in an Innovative and creative
way so yeah great caller great shout out
great reminder Martin that there is some
wonderful examples of this out there
yeah there so but you and I quite often
only see the companies that are not
doing so well at this because they're
the ones that call us that need help so
our view our view is a little bit if we
if somebody asks us how many
organizations do you see that are being
successful the answer is not many
because the the the many that are are
are not the ones that that need our help
right well I've I've had um some very
short engagements where I've gone in and
people have said how are we doing go in
again you're doing great you don't need
me yeah I I I always find if this was
specifically a scrum engagement many
years ago but if if the customer says
we're doing awesome at scrum we don't
know why we need your help right then
you know it's going to be a total [__]
show when you get there um but if they
if if they say well we're trying to do
some stuff we think we're doing okay
we're not really sure whether we're
actually adding value we need some extra
help then you usually they're doing a
lot better than they think they are
because they've realized right that that
that they know they know less than they
know um and yeah there's a principle of
learning that they're demonstrating
right they're open to be
open open to the understanding that they
don't know everything whereas soon as a
company or people in the organization
are of the attitude
um what because that's where you get the
why do we need to change right why
should we change there's no interest in
change because obviously the way we're
doing it right now is the perfect way
and that's where the way we do things
becomes a tool so woody woody that's the
way we've always done it that's the way
we've always done things right get off
get off my lawn is also a right come
that it's so
easy to keep doing things the same way
that we've always done things it takes
courage and openness and respect to do
things in a different way where we might
have friction we might have difficulty
things are not where we think they need
to be in order for us to function at our
best but in doing that in going through
that Journey we discover a new new way
of doing things a new way of working
that can often be more valuable than
what it was before and I think you on
top of all the things you called out it
is going to require work it's also going
to require effort and it's going to
require some architectural thinking of
where do you want to go and how do you
what are the boundaries that we need to
emerge within to together
and
so we we can apply the emerging
principles of agility to our tooling to
our business processes to the way we
collaborate but it's it's going to be a
graft right yeah it's it's super hard
there's a lot of it's a lot harder to do
the right thing for the right reasons
than to do the wrong thing for the wrong
reasons right it's it's easy just to
follow that well this is this is the the
the the board we have everybody needs to
use the same thing or everybody needs to
do story points because then I can look
at anybody's backlog and I know I know
what it looks like right I know what it
should look like I know that pattern in
my head it should have you know as I
want so that and as soon as it deviates
from that oh they're doing something oh
my my favorite one my favorite one Simon
this was from years ago you'll like this
one this is this is Scrum becoming a
tool or a thing becoming a tool um is I
worked with an organization where um the
scrum Master had just been fired when we
got there this was back in when I was
working in the US and we went in and we
were trying to figure out what was going
on and uh the scrum Master had told the
team that they're not doing
scrum and he told them they weren't
doing scrum because they were were not
standing up during the daily and let's
put aside the fact that stand up is not
part of scrum stand up as an XP thing
from 20 years before right um but that's
what the the the the scrum Master had
said to the to to this group whereas
this group had decided as a group the
team had collaborated and decided that
they didn't want to stand during the
daily because they'd be towering over
the disabled person in the wheelchair on
their team which is perfect sense right
and which you know which is the very
definition of self-organization and
fulfills the values of scrum but
somebody coming in and thinking of scrum
as a tool Thou shalt use use it this
way cause that that and that's a that's
a really bad example right but there's
lots of smaller examples that have less
overall impact but it ends up being a
death of a Thousand Cuts of uh uh uh
making we see these puls all the time at
the moment Simon that that I hate scrum
because um or scrum is a cancer because
posts that you see around at the moment
and usually there's a list of here's why
I think this and none of scrum right
none of it scrum right none of it scrum
none of it fulfills the the the the
values of scrum none of it even fills
basic rules of scrum right there it is
it's without this is something I'm very
fond of saying and you know shouting
from the rooftops scrum without the
values is a brutal tool of nanom
management and
oppression I would 100% agree with that
and that's the people hate mechanical
scrum for good reason it's being
weaponized and used to thump them with
whereas professional scrum is founded in
values founded in empiricism and I think
that's the point is that a tool used
badly will wreak davage whereas a tool
used well will help humans achieve
greatness right if I use a chef's knife
in the kitchen there is a probability
depending on the day that I might make a
decent meal right yeah could be dodgy
just depending with what women fancy I'm
following but if I take that chef's
knife away from the
kitchen it's very rare it'll find an
appropriate use in the the lounge room
right
yep and it's that whole thing of using a
knife as a screwdriver or you know a a
hammer
to yeah yeah yeah you know it's but does
not usually end well knife no um so you
might have bent the tip of the knife or
and it'll only let you use Flathead
screws not Philip's head or um oh you're
not jamming it in hard enough oh okay so
probably I I should go and get a sharper
knife at that point
right yeah exactly exactly wonder why I
cut my how did you cut your hand well
you see I to put a screw in what yeah I
think I think that's the overall
essence of of this topic right right
that um to tools things that are tools
and were designed as tools are often
suited for a specific job in a specific
circumstance and using them out with
that often has sub standard or even
negative results from using that that
that that tool that capability and often
we turn things that in other
circumstances wouldn't be a
tool into a
tool by focusing only on the mechanics
of the thing rather than focusing on the
values and principles of the context
within which we're
working right so up yeah that so to be
agile
actually see what I did there um
needs to be founded in
values and we need to
really think about how we're living
empiricism of being transparent and
inspecting and adapting because there
will be an edge case where we will take
a tool of one context apply it to
another and it'll be an innovation
awesome go
you but also be willing to run it as a
hypothesis and go if we try this this
this will happen and if it doesn't if we
don't get the expected results your your
hypothesis has been proven faulty so
just B it so values
principles mindful
application focus on value let your
paper flourish yeah is that that's
absolutely that's what folks should be
doing cool well I I think we've done a
nice little yeah we' looped all the
I think
[Music]
um yeah I think there's a lot to think
about in what we talked about I think
there's a lot to unpack for for many
folks they might see tools in the
practices that they're doing um but just
think about the context bring in the
context bring in the values bring in the
principles and see if it still suits the
situation that you're using it in and
maybe you need to adjust
the way you do things in order to be
more
effective be agile
actually