another question to ask leadership is
are teams empowered to change the
requirements based on user feedback so
this is not just Gathering the feedback
are you actually able to change the
requirements for your product and and I
and I don't mean like little things on
your product backlog or little things
that you want your product to do what if
you find out that a huge chunky thing is
no longer viable or no longer what the
business needs are you able to close
that Loop are you able to take that
feedback and actually action it and make
changes to the requirements one of the
things that happens a lot especially
when you do sessions where you're
engaging with the people who are going
to be your users and you're asking them
what they want um this is especially
important for for business systems but
also for commercial for B2B but also for
commercial um is that when when if I ask
you what do you need in a system the
first thing you're going to think about
is all the things that you need now
right all of those things are too late
all of those things are stuff we should
actually already have in the product we
should already be able to do because the
delay and actually building it to get
you to the point where you can use it is
is going to be quite tough right it's
going to you're you're you as the
business as the consumer of the product
that you're you're asking for you're
Perhaps Perhaps losing money or you're
perhaps losing time or you're losing
something by not having this problem
that's been identified solved right
um but you're going to you're going to
give me this big chunk of things that
you need now and then you're going to go
away and think about what might my
business need over the next whatever the
delivery cycle is so let's say we you
know we are going to deliver on a on a
3-weekly Cadence where we're we're
definitely doing doing some amount of
agil but the business goes away and
thinks about what's going to H this
product's going to last us for the next
few years right it's going to be in
production for the next few years um
what types of things do we think we
might need to work towards in order to
have that that that products support for
that length of time so they're going to
think about what's going to happen in
the future in the business what are the
choices that are going to need to be
made in the business and they'll think
about that big Choice that's coming up
we're going to make a big choice in this
business in in let's say it's three
months time um and it could go A or B
right I'm making it simple it could be a
octopus problem right but A or B and if
we need a we've got 50 things we want
and we've be we've got another different
50 things we
want what what happens when we get to
that decision and users are able to
feedback to us that we've got to that
decision are we able to remove half of
those work items the half that we don't
need what about if we've delivered some
of those 50 work items that are going to
be of value we deliver let's say we
deliver 15 of them 15 things um and we
get feedback from the users that yeah
you're solving this problem just now
this this business problem is resolved
from our perspective that other stuff
that we put on your list you've
delivered the most valuable piece and
the rest is is not as valuable can we go
delete the rest of those requirements or
at least deprioritize them or not do
them right how quickly can you close
those feedback loops can you actually
make those changes in the system quite
often I see teams talking to users I see
teams engaging uh uh uh and getting
feedback and then not being a able to do
anything with it they're not actually
able to change the requirements because
somebody else has locked them in and
we're not allowed to change them or or
because we don't want them to change the
system because perhaps there's a crazy
contract in the way we create a
convoluted complicated change requests
system that's very expensive to follow
um to try and dissuade people from
making changes we don't want those
things we want to be a adapting to the
needs of the customer that we're sing
we're adapting to the market needs and
their Market needs are changing
constantly which means our product and
the things we think we're going to do in
the product need to also change
constantly which means as well that if
you do have contracts you need to build
into the story of the contract that
these things are going to change
constantly make sure that your teams are
empowered to change the requirements
based on user feedback if your answer to
any one of these questions or the answer
of your business to any one of these
questions is no we're not doing that
then you would probably I probably
wouldn't consider that you're already in
the agile space right you're not already
agile you might be working towards it
and you might have put in loads of
effort but unless you can Mark every
every single one of these six questions
as yes we do this this is how things
work here then we're still lacking we're
still trying we're still working towards
being agile now this is just a litmus
test dreamed up uh by uh the US
Department of Defense but they are
probably the least likely place for you
to expect something um Within this High
a bar to have come from and I'm not
going to um go into a team uh and work
with a team or a company and if they're
not doing these things then I'm going to
say well you guys suck you're not agile
because you're not doing this that's
that's not how we work towards success
uh but I think it's hugely valuable from
the perspective of
self-reflection for you all to think
about the process cesses and practices
in your organization and are you a how
many of these six questions are you able
to achieve and what could you do to make
it a little bit easier for the teams for
the people doing the work to work
towards this idea of not being agile BS