the final question for asking leadership
within the organization is going to be a
stickler um I see this in organization
after organization being a difficult
problem uh to discuss and that is is the
full equal system of your project agile
agile programming teams followed by
linear bureaucratic deployment is a
failure how many of of you out there
listening to this are working within
organizations where you're able to
continuously deliver to
production where there is no um human
intervention required between the
developer submitting the pool request
being approved and getting all the way
to production how many of you work in
that sort of environment where there are
no
bureaucratic uh uh things in between you
and production there may be tests
between you and production it may take
time for your product to roll out
because it has to go through a set of
automated standardized checks uh perhaps
does compliance things I do work with a
team that makes firmware for
pacemakers um and you better believe
they have a lot of compliance they have
to meet uh their software after they
create their usable working uh uh item
to ship needs to run a gauntlet of
external tests and validations but they
expect all of them to pass because
they've done all the things to ensure
that it does so it's unusual for
anything in that um um uh story to to to
be a failure that they have to have
manual processes right that little bit
of bureaucracy in their way but only to
protect people's lives it's the absolute
minimum needed to ensure that we protect
people's lives however for most systems
that we work with we want to be
delivering high enough quality to our
business that we're able to remove a lot
of those traditional bureaucratic uh
points in that story for example user
acceptance testing user acceptance
testing um if you have user acceptance
testing in your business it's because
it's a Value Center if your customer
insists on doing user acceptance testing
when you give them product it's because
it's a Value Center for them you give
them product and they find problems
therefore uat has added value for
them why are they finding those
problems they're finding those problems
because the quality of the the product
that you're giving them is not a high
high enough to pass the bar that they're
expecting and that they're paying you
for if it was high
enough then their uat wouldn't find
anything and would become a cost
center and then that's a conversation
about eliminating cost if it's never
finding an issue with your product it's
of no value to them to do it because
your product is high enough quality
you should all be striving to have a
high enough quality product that you
don't need additional checks and
validations if you need to have
something that somebody else wants to
see as part of your process bake it into
your definition of done bake it into the
way you build software so quality is so
high you don't even have to worry about
it you can continuously ship to
production if your answer to any one of
these questions or the answer of your
business to any one of these questions
is no we're not doing that then you
would probably I probably wouldn't
consider that you're already in the
agile space right you're not already
agile you might be working towards it
and you might have put in loads of
effort but unless you can Mark every
single one of these six questions as yes
we do this this is how things work here
then we're still lacking we're still
trying we're still working towards being
agile now this is just a litmus test
dreamed up uh by uh the US Department of
Defense but they are probably the least
likely place for you to expect something
um with this High a bar to have come
from and I'm not going to um go into a
team uh and work with a team or a
company and if they're not doing these
things then I'm going to say well you
guys suck you're not agile because
you're not doing this that's that's not
how we work towards success uh but I
think it's hugely valuable from the
perspective of
self-reflection for you all to think
about the processes and practices in
your organization and are you a how many
of these six questions are you able to
achieve
and what could you do to make it a
little bit easier for the teams for the
people doing the work to work
towards this idea of not being agile BS