if you're an organization uh that buys
lots of training um especially if you
have a a large cader of people in your
organization that are are currently
trying to do the scrum Master
role then the most
[Music]
valuable purchase you could make is
immersive learning and the reason that's
much more valuable for your organization
is that that it gives the people in your
organization the ability to close that
loop on their learning so normally when
you're when you're training you you you
you you learn
something and then you learn something
else and then you learn something else
and then you learn something else and by
the time you get to the end of that
process you've probably forgotten 80% of
all of the things that came before and
maybe when you come out of that training
class there are few things uh a
actionable things right those those
hints and tips and topics and uh stories
and how to there's only maybe a few of
those you can actually try you you've
increased the level of Baseline
knowledge in your organization right
everybody now understands perhaps what
scrum is and what a scrum Master is and
but have they actually
internalized any of those learnings and
how much of those learnings are they
actually able to put into practice and
the key value additional value in
immersive learning is in allowing the
people in your organization to actually
put the things into practice and we
enable that in the form of
assignments so each each uh uh person in
the in the class is given an assignment
it's probably the same assignment for
everybody but if you've got a bunch of
scrum Masters you're coming bringing to
the class they're going to go off into
their teams with their either with their
teams or with their leadership or um um
in in that area in that context and
they're going to try one of these things
one of these exercises so an assignment
might be oh I'm trying to think of what
what what a what a an example assignment
might be uh my favorite topic is
definition of done quality are we
creating enough quality in a product and
one of the assignments might be to go um
talk to the team and ask them about
their definition of
done and if they don't have a definition
of done help them create one and put it
into action that could be an assignment
for a scrum Master to do and if the only
thing that came out of the entire class
was that all of your scrum Masters all
of your teams had a definition of done
and it was actually actualized then that
would be a a a a total Boon for your
entire organization in in enabling that
level of quality uh but that's just one
of the exercises um that we might do one
of the assignments that the teams might
get and not only do they do the
assignment right but they come back at
the beginning of the next session and
they explain what did you do how did it
go what were the problems that you ran
into closing that learning loop again
and um figuring out well you didn't get
the outcome that you
wanted here are some other things you
can try and that can come from both from
the the facilitator of the debrief right
but also from the other people in your
organization who've actually done that
thing inside of your organization if you
bring 12 scrum Masters to a training
class and those 12 scrum Masters all go
and try and do this definition of done
some of them will be successful and some
of them won't some of them will be very
successful and some will only be a
little bit successful right
so why were certain scrum Masters
successful why were other ones not how
do we bring that knowledge together so
that they can they can assess for
themselves what other ways to do things
CU because quite often I I've done a lot
of
um private training classes and you find
that even inside an organization one
person will say no there's no way you
can do this thing it's not possible
within our organization and then there's
somebody over in the in the in one of
the side videos will go we do it our
team does that and we do it very well
and we do it within the bounds of the
organizational constraints and then the
other person like holy crap how do you
do that who do you speak to how can we
get some of that as well and even that's
that sharing of knowledge we've tried
something it works here it doesn't work
here and closing those feedback loops
bringing those conversations together
are
the whole reason that the immersive
learning classes are going to be much
more beneficial to organizations than
the traditional approach if you want to
have a discussion about how immersive
classes can revolutionize your training
experience then please book a call on
our website alternatively you can find
all of our public immersive classes
listed there as well and we would love
to hear from you