so we have a we have a 20 referral
program
and the reason I created it was because
I thought it was a good idea
to effectively reward people for
um
having a bringing other people to the
classes right uh quite often
um it's it's difficult
to get your friends to come along to the
classes our colleagues in your
organization friends or colleagues to
help participate together so that you
can learn together and move forward
together in the organization
uh so I created this referral program
where
um you
the person you you can go to my website
and you can get this code right and the
code allows you to give it to somebody
else and they will get a 20 discount on
any class right hopefully it's the one
that you're going to be on as well so
you can collaborate together in your
organization or maybe you go on
different classes and pull the knowledge
right that's cool too
um but you also get something for it
right not only does this other person
get a 20 discount but you get a 20 store
credit that's probably the best way to
describe it
um you get 20 of the fee that they paid
uh in credit towards a future future
class so in effect uh if you think about
it because it's 20 if they're all in the
same Market you refer five people you're
probably getting a class for free right
it's probably pretty close to that
um so this enables you to get something
out of it as well
um and the more people you refer the
more the more the more cash is in that
pool the more classes you can take
um
yeah I think that's a a great way to
reward people who who like my training
or who want to bring other people in
their organization to the trail
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility