scrum is like communism it doesn't
work this is a phrase I hear often from
folks who have been unable to adapt
their systems of work to incorporate the
core philosophies theories and practices
of scrum they sit and look at the
signals coming from scrum that things
are broken and don't work like they're
supposed to work and do nothing but say
scrum is like communism it doesn't
[Music]
work hi I'm Martin Henwood owner and
principal consultant at naked agility
I'm a professional scrum trainer with
scrum.org a professional caman trainer
with Pro caman and I've been a Microsoft
MVP in GitHub and as your devops for 15
years
in this video we'll explore five myths
from scrum that inhibit its adoption
from language definition inflation to
cognitive bias here are the top five
myths that result in the idea that scrum
is like
communism there's a myth in scrum that
you spend more time talking than doing I
see this quite a lot people talking you
usually people are using old school
terminology when you hear them talking
about that you hear them talking about
ceremonies right rather than events and
one of the main reasons why scrum
doesn't call the the activities the
events ceremonies is because it's
ceremonies we get together and nothing
happens it's a ceremony it's something
we do that's perhaps the same every time
and there's no actual outcome to a
ceremony apart from maybe people have
some jollies and they feel good right um
the reason scrum calls them events and
also not meetings the reason they're
called events is something's supposed to
happen
there every single one of the scrum
events serves
empiricism that's their purpose right
you're going to inspect something and
that adapt
something if you're not
adapting there's no point in being there
there's no point in having it there's no
point in doing it their purpose is to
adapt so for example at your Sprint
planning you're inspecting your product
backlog and your product goal and you're
adapting your Sprint backlog and your
Sprint goal you that emerges through
that con perhaps through that
conversation
right but at the end of your Sprint
planning you should have a Sprint
goal you should have selected backlog
items what do the developers think best
serves working towards the product goal
and you should have some kind of a
starter plan to complete them if those
three things don't exist at the end of
Sprint planning there was no point in
having it that's what it's there for so
that we understand what it is we're
going to take into the next Sprint so
that we can communicate that perhaps
with other people what's our goal for
this Sprint what are we trying to
achieve how do you get the stakeholders
to actually turn up for the Sprint
review well you have to give them
something that they're interested in
coming in providing feedback on that's
your Sprint goal right and that's just
one of the events in scrum every sing
your daily scrum it's only 15 minutes
how does that add up to a boatload of
meetings at most 15 minutes per day
where the team gets together and plans
the next 24 hours that's its purpose
you're inspecting your existing Sprint
back
clog and you're adapting that Sprint
back clog based on what you learned in
the last 24 hours you might have learn
some stuff from actually working on the
product what can and cannot be done you
might have uh a gained more information
and insight from other stakeholders and
collaborating with the business and
doing analysis on what it is you're
going to work on that means that
something that you've got in the Sprint
needs to be taken out because it's no
longer viable or something else needs to
be brought in because it becomes part of
that that story of what it is you're
trying to achieve that
Sprint that's your daily
scrum right it's not an elaborate status
event it's not a time that you're
wasting it's where you're maintaining
the transparency that is required to be
able to inspect and adapt you're serving
empiricism and all of the scrum events
serve
empiricism one of the common uh myths in
scrum um is kind of a a a proxy myth
this proxy myth is you know why do we
spend so much time working on story
points
um when story points measure complexity
and not time and then we have to figure
out how many story points fit in a
Sprint right and I I 100% agree with
that that part is not a myth the bit
that's a myth is that story points are
even a scrum thing in the first place
they're not story points has nothing to
do with scrum it never has apart from as
a practice potentially complimentary PR
practice that teams choose to take on in
order to get to an
outcome when you find complimentary
practices are not adding value you
should be stopping doing them not
continuing with them so if you're in
that position where you find that story
points are not adding value great stop
doing them and choose something else
choose a different way the guy that
invented story points or that is
generally accredited with inventing
story points has a public apology online
for creating them in the first place
because of how they are tend to be used
within organizations as a pseudo proxy
for time to beat developers around the
head with right they were originally
invented as a reasonable way for
developers to sit and have a
conversation
and find out figure out what they don't
know that's the purpose in story points
we can all get together we maybe use
another complimentary practice called
planning poker and all that really is is
we we keep our cards to ourselves right
we we're not going to tell each other
what story point we're going to pick how
complex t-shirt sizes right whatever you
pick how complex this thing is and
you've got one developer that that says
this is a small or a one right you've
got four developers that say that this
is a five or a medium and then you've
got one developer that says this is an
extra large or a 21 right and the idea
is what do they know that we don't or
what do we know that they
don't that's the
purpose of story points and complexity
conversation
it should be used almost solely during
refinement in order to enable teams to
rightsize their backlog items and decide
do they fit in a Sprint do we understand
them or do we
not after that delete the numbers
they're
useless don't use them anymore that's
their purpose for that one context don't
bring them into the wider context
[Music]
one of the common uh myths in scrum is
that is really a a forum for
micromanagement and the the there's a
there's a core test for this in your
team it is it is a myth right but it's a
reality for many teams so is it a myth
or is it not a myth that is a matter of
perspective however I would point out
that it's not scrum so it's a myth in
the context of scrum but it's not a myth
in the context of how lots of
organizations and teams approach scrum
because most organizations approach
something like scrum from their
traditional topdown steering based
perspective and they want to tell teams
what they're going to deliver in a
Sprint so you walk into Sprint
planning and the product owner or the
tech lead or the project manager or
whoever the scrum Master the worst one
but the scrum Master says here's a list
of things we need you as a team to do
this
Sprint as soon as that happens not
scrum we've gone out of the bounds of
the scrum guide who decides what we work
on this Sprint the developers who
decides how we work on it the
developers okay it's not anybody else
because the de developers that's this
this core reason why they dislike that
approach it's the developers that
understand the nuance and intricacies of
the technical challenges of actually
delivering on the work inside of the
Sprint nobody else can understand that
Nuance because they're living it right
they've got skills that I don't have as
a manager or as a product owner they've
got understanding of the product and the
technologies that we're using to deliver
that product the tools and techniques
that we're using their best place to
make that decision now can the product
owner say oh my goodness me we're in a
difficult place because we're not
working through the work that we need to
deliver as fast as we would like yeah
absolutely they can have that
conversation and they can have a
conversation with the developers about
how the developers might choose to cut
Corners into in order to accelerate work
but it must be done with their Ascent if
the developers say no then we can't work
any faster cuz we might be taking on too
much technical debt and most businesses
and for all businesses all technical
debt is a risk to the business and most
businesses don't understand the context
of technical debt enough to make an
informed decision on whether they should
acrew it and how they should pay it back
that's why we have have hired these
technical experts in order to deliver
our product and we should trust their
understanding and view of the product in
order to do that so I would say that it
is a myth that anybody should be telling
the developers what to work on and when
to work on it but I do understand that
lots of organizations don't understand
how to let go of that control and her
are not yet ready for
agile one of the common myths in scrum
is that since we're doing agile we don't
need no
planning um and that is just utter
garbage scrum for example is all about
planning we have Sprint planning we have
refinement which is a type of planning
we have uh daily scrum which is about
planning the next 24 hours we have a
review where we review what happened
based on the plan and adapt the plan
going forward into the future it's it's
all about planning it's all about
getting things right it's not about
planning
upfront it's not about
spending too much time upfront planning
okay but there's a phrase which is often
misinterpreted
which is we should do just enough
planning we should do just enough right
if we do twoo much planning and we plan
a bunch of stuff that we end up not
doing because it gets taken out of the
out of the backlog then that was waste
maybe that was okay waste maybe we
needed to do that planning in order to
find out other stuff and have that thing
removed or maybe that was a little bit
too much was is there a way that we
could have learned the same thing that
we we learned doing that planning doing
something a little bit
less
and the converse of that is if you are
building I'm trying to think what you
could be building that needs lots of
let's say you're working on
Windows and you're one of 2 and a half
thousand software Engineers how many
teams is that metric assloads of teams
right if you you're that many teams
working on one product then you're going
to need to plan right you're going to
need to understand what's happening
going out into the future you're going
to need to coordinate across hundreds of
teams on Direction and strategy I mean
most of that in scrum is done through
communication right Vision product goal
Sprint goal right you've got that
communication chain how do we all get
behind the same thing but
we're trying to
have as
light a plan up front as possible within
our
context so even even if I was working on
the Windows team I would probably have a
a road map I'm probably going to have a
road map for my current 6 months if
you're not familiar with how how
Microsoft product teams
have they've created their own scaling
framework around what they need in their
business um it's often called the
season-based model because they do they
they talk about the spring update and
the fall update for their really big
products uh many of their products do
continuous delivery but they're talking
about long-term view of what it is
they're trying to achieve and that's
that's about 6 months and they look
three seasons ahead so they're looking
18 months out they have an 18mon plan
and I'm using air quotes because it's
probably pretty vague right if you're
looking at that third season out things
are really big right you might have um
uh themes rather than individual things
you're going to deliver you might be
looking at what are the investment
opportunities what's happening in the
market where do we need to to get ahead
of the of the competition going over the
next 18 months and that generates these
big themes buckets of work that many
hundreds of teams might work in um to to
actually you know make progress towards
those big themes but you're looking that
far out you're planning that far out you
know um probably what your goal your
product goal if if they call I don't
think they call it that but whatever
their their theme for uh their their
primary theme for us each of the seasons
they probably know what they're going to
be 18 months out for the season that
we're in you know we're probably got
backlog items and actual things we're
going to tactically deliver for the next
three four maybe five Sprints
maybe and then in the next bucket we
maybe have you know here's some Sprint
goals we might tackle here's some
product goals we might look at
um in that next seasonal bucket and then
the season after
that we we don't have any of those
detail just what's the big theme and you
can you can see how they did that they
did a uh one recently uh I'm saying
recently in The Last 5 Years right uh
recently that was called the creators
update so when they when they were
talking to us the general public about
the products they talked about the
creators update we're going to invest in
opportunities to make our systems and
products and services better for
creators that was an organization wide
uh theme that can es spawn out of the
windows team but think of all the things
that impacts not only does that impact
on Windows the operating system right
but what about offices impact most
people interact with the operating
system through off office so if you're
to hey fever if you're talking about um
pen support right you've got the the the
actual pen touching the screen on the
surface and the number of levels of
capability that it has in that world
you've got so that's that's hardware
that's the surface hardware and perhaps
third party vendor Hardware
collaborating with then you've got the
application that you're actually is
interpreting those signals so that could
be Microsoft's applications it could be
office it could be third party software
and then you've got the underlying
operating system which is providing
support for the I think it used to be
256 uh levels of pressure and now it's
uh 1024 at least uh uh levels of
pressure that you can put on the pen in
order to to to get that you know I'm
drawing on the page type of type of feel
and that requires collaboration looking
forward into the future what do we need
what are we trying to achieve all of
those strategic things happening we just
probably don't store them in a Gant
chart one of the myths in uh scrum is
that we have have no
governance um this kind of leads on to
the bigger myth that just because it's
not in the scrum guide um doesn't mean
you're not supposed to do it um scrum
does absolutely have have governments it
has small amounts of governance baked in
right but in general you need governance
to build your product so it's kind of
correct to say scrum doesn't have a lot
of governance right there's a very small
amount of governance built in but if you
want to be successful at Building
Products if you're for example Building
Products within the healthcare space
then you're you're going to have to
worry about your ability to support
Hippa to support the Regulatory
Compliance that comes from the outside
don't that's governance imposed on your
organization from the outside that you
have no control of um you're going to
have um things that your organization
does internally perhaps uh your
organization has usability guidelines
perhaps they have um uh uh uh like ux
guidelines for here's how our all our
products ux is going to function so that
anybody interacting with our software
already knows how it's going to work
because it follows the same rules um
then that's internal governance that has
been applied to your product you maybe
have a a business um rules that are
another form of governance you might
have particular ways in which you
interact with the market as a business
that's your unique uh one of your unique
selling points your unique engagement
points with the market and they have
those those ways of working have to be
implemented in your systems in that way
that's internal governance
just
because scrum talks about um minimizing
that governance doesn't mean it's not
there right you just you have just
enough governance to support the
business need um it's when you have way
too much governance that you start
running into a problem that's why in
very large organizations for example
Banks right they really struggle to move
towards uh scrum and agile practices
because they're encumbered by the
baggage that they can't put down uh
Royal Bank of Scotland in the UK was the
I think it was the first bank in the
world it's currently the fifth biggest
bank in the world um and they've been
going for over 200 years can you
imagine the the the the procedural and
compliance baggage that organization has
many of it around for no other reason
than nobody's Revisited it in a long
time nobody's challenged it in a really
long time how many policies and
procedures do you have in your
organization that nobody knows where
they came from or what they're for or
who owns that policy or procedure or why
right it's just the way we do things
here those are the things that we want
to challenge we want to challenge
anything that gets in the way of inh
inhibiting our ability to deliver value
those are the things we want to prevent
those are the uh policies practices and
procedures the governance that we want
to reduce to the absolute m
[Music]