foreign
Consulting that is a very nebulous term
that people often have difficulty
articulating what the heck that thing is
uh I have my approach to Agile
Consulting
um I have there's a number of different
parts to it
um probably the main part again is
talking to talking to people
um help people helping people
um understand that there are other
options to the way they do things people
kind of get a lot quite often people get
locked into one framework like scrum or
kanban
um and they don't realize that there's
not there's not really anything making
them do that one thing there's actually
lots of choices in that that story what
are the strategies that you need in
order to be successful at building
products at delivering uh whatever it is
that you're you're delivering as an
organization
um and there's often quite a loose
connection people focus on delivery and
they forget about the business as well
right so a lot of agile Consulting is
helping them understand that this is not
a tool for delivering stuff agile's just
an idea that is a different way of
working for your whole organization
um and how they can start bringing in
some of those ideas into their
organization so it's kind of filling
that gap between that that Ideal World
that training talks about
and the realities of the organization
and where does the organization
currently sit on those those those agile
scales and how do we start moving that
needle so that they gain more ability
right they get more uh faster at being
able to deliver stuff tighter feedback
loops talking to their customers more
delivering more value and ultimately
making more Revenue right that's that's
the ultimate goal of most companies is
to maximize the revenue for the effort
that they put in so being able to
increase that so having conversations at
different levels in the organizations
whether I'm dealing with teams right and
helping teams get better at building the
product that they're building
um or talking to people in middle or
leadership
teams who are orchestrating that across
a much wider audience either their whole
organization or in the Professional
Services environment
um so there's a lot of engaging in
talking with people running workshops
right helping them not just there's
almost two there's two things that
workshops are good for right
um it will run well-run workshops one is
that
um you get the outcome of the workshop
right that's that's one Oak one that's
only one of the outcomes but that's
that's quite important but the other
outcome is do the people that came to
the workshop did they learn anything
that can make their work better right
did they learn how to run workshops
better how to engage with people better
how to converse with people better and
navigate that Minefield uh that that's
often called the grown Zone
um that that battleground of of people
not agreeing right which is which is
very common and how do you how do you
navigate that so so building up those
those skills in people that I work with
and that's a lot of agile Consulting is
finding people in your organization who
are the people that we that need to be
the ones that are doing the work right
because I can't do it I'm outside of
your company I can't make changes to
your company that's not possible it's
not possible for a consultant to come
and say here here's how you should run
your business go do it right that's
that's not how it works the people in
your organization need to be the ones
that make the changes that understand
the ideas and the job of the consultant
is to come in and effectively provoke
change help people think differently so
they see what it is they need to do next
that's that's the hard part right
um but also you know a state of agile
reports I've done those as well like
whereas our organization currently right
lots of organizations are quite large
and perhaps instead of just bringing
somebody in to help them they need to
have a conversation first about what is
the help we think we need where are we
right now and where do we want to get to
right that's an initial conversation
so I've done reports for organizations
where I come in and I interview people
at all levels in the organization create
a a report that talks about the current
state of agility within your
organization what are the opportunities
for improvement and what are the top
three things that are are I see at least
I see is the biggest problem
um and then it's up to the organization
to have a conversation about whether
they need more help or they think they
can do all of that themselves right
um and quite often they do come back but
it can take a longer period of time
right because they go try things they're
trying to build momentum inside the
organization and then a year later they
come back around and say can you come
and help us with additional stuff or
provide some training in a particular
context right
um and and telling those telling telling
those stories inside the organization so
I think I think that's what I would
quantify as agile Consulting you need
lots of tools in your toolbox
um I try and have as many tools as I can
I'm always learning and figuring out new
tools and new ways of doing things
um and then bringing that to the
customer engagement knowledge experience
uh uh methods Theory right as well as
tools and capability what is it that
what information is your organization
missing
that I can provide you to help you move
forward
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility