so I just came upon a nasty situation in
which my primary domain controller in
fact my only domain controller of my
demo lab environment and has popped off
this message box and I have been unable
to resolve it I've tried to activate
Windows it failed and I've tried to do a
bunch of other things so what I need to
do is create our new domain controller
and migrate everything across if I can
so hopefully this is going to work so
this server
let me pop this open this is air LAN
which is my primary domain controller if
I flip over to my new server which is
COBOL it's not currently joined to the
domain so I I do not have DHCP I will
need to set a hard-coded IP address for
this machine so we're going to and now
let me check which ones which network
connect it'd be nice if it let me know
which one was which so let's just get
the status and this has an IP address so
this is Wi-Fi and this does not there we
go so this is private
I have fed two networks one plugged into
the internet and the other plugged into
just the servers so let me just fix it
IP address with one and currently I need
to set the DNS of the server that is our
domain controller so let me join the
domain and here we go
go join this machine to the domain they
don't have to reboot this machine I have
activated so I won't be in the same boat
as I was before and there we go welcome
to the and naked isle I'm com domain so
let's restart this machine for a minute
as my domain administrator and more or
less there we go we are now in and the
domain so what we really want to do is
we want to promote this machine to be a
domain controller within the domain so
now if we go to local server we've got
our server COBOL in the naked LM domain
so now I need to promote this to be a
domain controller so the first thing we
do is when to add roles and features and
the server and I got to go to so we need
to select item Directory domain services
and DNS server and we're going to be
decommissioning the old server moving
all the services across to this server
and so we need to make sure we have all
of the things available we'll need our
DNS server we need to select any
additional features it's already set up
anything that we need when we selected
the options that we want it so it's
going to automatically set all this up
and there we go we can start the
installation going and there we go
installation has completed we still have
at some configuration to do because
although we've installed all the PCs we
need we haven't configured any of them
yet so I'm going to click on this option
to promote at the server to a domain
controller so we're going to M we're not
creating a new domain or a new forest or
any of those things I already have all
of that set up I just want to move
everything across so I'm going to add
this domain controller to the existing
domain so it's pre-selected the domain
and that I was currently on she's
awesome so I'm just going to click Next
and really we mostly want a default set
of options so right now is communicating
with the mid mean domain controller and
figuring out what options I can select
so now that that's loaded you can see
that the it's limited the options that
we have available and we've got dinner
server enabled global catalog we don't
want it read-only
I'm going to leave the default site put
in our password options replicate from
well I can see I need to mean controller
or it can pick the one other one I have
easy enough
I'm going to leave the path default this
really is a demo system but I've made a
lot of configurations so I don't want to
lose the existing to me and that's why
I'm not just setting up a new one it's
fun when you have to then go and rebuild
all of your servers that have sequel
server and whatnot on them there we go
there's completed all the appearance it
checked there's a couple of triangles a
couple of bangs default security
settings are enabled I'm okay with that
a thorat of parent zone can be found
again I'm ok with that
and so we can just go ahead and click
install if you were in a production to
mean you may want to look more carefully
at those things I'm not so I don't care
so because we just installed domain
controller it's going to restart as
automatically if I click close
I think it's effectively just going to
there we go
often do it itself now this restart me
take a little bit longer than normal
there we go
let me Logan is the administrator no no
we're almost there we have a server it
is a domain controller if we still have
a bunch of things that we need to move
across to this it's going to sink in the
background at some of the capabilities
and it should other DNS may not be
replicating yet go to DNS manager
and it has already replicated awesome so
you can see all the the servers that
I've had in the past so I'm no longer
exist probably needs a bit of cleanup um
but it's already replicated the DNS
across but there are a number of other M
pcs - Active Directory that are specific
to a server and we need to move those
across before we can decommission the
old server so the first thing we need to
do is open up our Active Directory users
and computers and if we right click on
our domain and click operations masters
we will see that I am currently the our
ID operational master is airline and
we'd like it to be cool bald so if we
hit the Change button that will change
it over our primary domain controller is
currently airline we change that now
it's COBOL our infrastructure master is
currently airline again change it over
and I were at COBOL for all three of our
operational master roles now in a very
large domain you might have these on
separate servers for performance and
scalability but here we don't really
need that now everything should be
transferred over m to cobol we're going
to leave that for a couple of minutes
just make sure that everything trans
over errors over correctly and then
we'll be able to decommission the old
domain controller so in order to remove
Active Directory we remove idividuals
pick our server
so you can see that we still have the
schema operational master role on this
server so if we right-click and select
run and run MMC for /a and add the
schema snap in there we go we're now
currently we connect to airline there we
go so we're connected to our operational
master and if we click operations master
you can see that it says airline in both
boxes what we need to do is change the
server and see then know both online
connect to cobol and if we right-click
select operations master we don't have
current as airline we want to change it
to cobol so we hit change yes we want to
change operational master has now been
changed
close that no so we've removed the
schema operational master we also need
to remove the domain name operational
master in order to that we run the
domains and trusts we right-click on
Active Directory domains and trusts
select operational master and you'll see
that the current is airline we want it
to be cool ball and we can just change
that over and we've moved that across as
we've moved these over we're pretty good
we can proceed with the removal hit next
and that was it will and we can demote
it
we won't we've successfully it demoted
it's going to restart anyway just force
it there we go
now while this machine is still is not a
domain controller anymore it's still
currently joint the domain I believe we
will check that in just a minute message
we're trying to avoid nope it's a
workgroup awesome
so this server has been and removed from
the domain and we have a new domain
controller and really as there is
absolutely no going back at this point
anyway let me shut down this server
there we go it's off I'm going to open
up my hyper-v manager and I can delete
there we go I've deleted that server
so now cobalt is our domain controller
so on Kobol and if we do I pee don't
fake and this is for so now I can change
let me pick our machine let's connect to
Baltar
take the right password you may need to
login as a local administrator let me
open up Sarah manager up not on Wi-Fi
well let's open up our private about six
before and this is number four is our
new DNS server our new active joyed your
domain let's try something simple
and we're able to find everything in our
domain and I will be who is not on this
machine and add them in so we were able
to query connect to itit rectory so it
looks like everything's doing just fine
and there you go that's how to migrate
Active Directory from one machine to
another and dmort the old machine