my name is Catherine medics and I am a
Christian we did healthy I
like the foundation class that it is
giving our engineering order us towards
a common vision for how work will be
done which means not had before and it
gave them hope to our developers did
they can get solutions to some of the
biggest problems that that they're
forced to
deal with every day I
even as a remastered
really got out of the nuances
refreshers in some cases that were brand
new to me so it's definitely up my game
of those go mister here this
immediately has had a big impact on
health grades we have a common set of
framework for talking about problems
that were solving problems that were
working together we were a little on the
chaotic terms of course and it's gotten
people really excited about other than
risk limited feature enough energy
the organizational change backlog is
really exciting for two reasons one
reduces people on the ground doing work
voice code what's holding them back and
it's had to lose that communication
channel before and now we are building
them of marking the structured she pick
those off and to build that team back up
so we're not only picking out the
impetus so we're building confidence
across the order set we really do care
about whistling the mapping that we want
to fix it two huge things have come come
the creation of the backlog one is that
we have greater insights with little
tighter services
meaning contagious that we now have a
backhoe to fix and we context but the
second rather unexpected to me benefit
was that we have struggled with
the two munication cycles what those
problems world people have annoyed felt
listened to and
now without Merton we have unstructured
system or hearing those impediments
picking them up and making things better
across the board each evening is
incredibly helpful and hopeful
I
wanted Martin's compared attorney
because I'd like them to the first time
with books high-energy
pragmatic and
really interesting and really glad we
did because even the worst skeptics in
the crowd were won over and that's shot
[Music]