so
it's about the student's ability to take
it in really if you give them two full
days you know how long are they fully
engaged in the class which bid do they
remember the bits that resonate right
now
and then which bit are they going to put
into practice straight afterwards and
and while that's great and they're going
to get a lot of information in there the
ability to spread it up so for example
with PSM over seven weeks means you've
got seven opportunities to go and
practice things and do things in your
real work and not see it in this
beautifully clean classroom environment
let's say in your real work environment
the stuff you have to deal with after
the class so you get to see the real
challenges and you get to see the real
um problems and we can address that not
only have you got access to a trainer
throughout that time there's a cohort
group of people you can work with during
the class and who knows even Beyond if
the groups decide to stay in touch with
each other and that will really get get
them engaged with it and it'll it'll be
a bit more
I hate to say the word immersive
immersive in that you're actually doing
it for real and you know it's well named
for that