so who should lead the Sprint review at
why and how I think that's a great
question
um
I'll start with the purpose of the
Sprint review right
um the purpose of the Sprint review is
to get the best possible information
from the stakeholders in order to
maximize the value of the next Sprint
right the product backlog is in the best
possible State it's got all of the
things that we need in it we've absorbed
the the the we've we've brought together
the information from you know what we've
done in the last two weeks in the
product what's happened in the last two
weeks in the business what's happened in
the last two weeks in the market and
we're mushing that together and actually
updating the product backlog so when we
walk out of Sprint planning we have that
updated as up-to-date as we can as
effective as we can put it backlog so we
maximize the value that we deliver
um so then the question of of of who is
to lead it
who on the scrum team is accountable for
for Value delivery for maximizing the
value of the work done by the scrum team
product owner right
so I would normally expect the product
owner to be the one
um leading the Sprint review I mean it
can be anybody on the team I have no
problem with that right but the product
owner is the accountable party uh for
maximizing the value of the work done so
it's in their best interest to make sure
or enable the the Sprint review is as
valuable as possible and quite often
that means they are the facilitator
right they are the ones who are getting
the most out of it right because that's
their accountability they're ensuring
their accountability
so perhaps they should create the the
the
um
the flow of the Sprint review what do
you if you're a product owner what do
you need from your stakeholders this
Sprint
right that's what you're trying to get
to how are you going to create and
organize that event so that you maximize
the chance of you getting the
information that you need
um in the time that you need it having
the conversations that you need during
that event
um so so how do you run it wow that any
way you like as long as you get to the
outcome right I don't really care how
you run it so some teams do demos some
teams don't do demos right because
they're already in production
uh perhaps a flow that I kind of like
um I have it documented on my on my
website but I flow I kind of like is you
need to use you know the product owner
should be should be setting the scene at
the start right what's the current
vision of of the product let's reset
this is what we're talking about is the
vision that's what we're trying to get
towards what's the current product goal
right what's our our current
short-term uh or intermediate strategic
goal that we're trying to get to
um and then what was our tactical goal
this Sprint what was it that were
actually actually focused on that what's
the the outcome that we told the
stakeholders at the beginning the
singular Sprint goal what's the outcome
that we're gonna we're gonna focus on
and then perhaps the team do a a demo
showing you know what it was what's what
we created in the last two weeks that's
pretty cool
um but also we need to get feedback on
that demo that's almost uh more
important than anything else is getting
feedback on that demo
um but then that's if that's the end of
your Sprint review then you're missing
out on a lot of extra stuff because
perhaps we need to have a conversation
about yeah we need to have a
conversation about what's happened in
the business what the stakeholders are
coming to bring information what
information can we get out of the
stakeholders about things that are
coming up in the future things that
might be talked about in the business
changes in the market that we can bring
into our our story
um and all the whole throughout this we
need to be actually updating the product
backlog so I think there's there's lots
of ways to run that but those are the
key information PCS that we need to get
by the end of it so run it however you
like whoever you like can facilitate it
but ultimately the accountability we're
fulfilling here is the product owners
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility