one of the seven signs of the agile
apocalypse is famine and in our context
of scrum that famine manifests as a lack
of feedback a lack of Engagement with
stakeholders perhaps even a lack of
Engagement with your product owner um
and that famine results in a lack of
care and attention if the business
doesn't care to turn up and provide
feedback why should your team
care thanks for watching the video If
you enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked
agility