if you're looking
for um rules on how to make informed
decisions based on the data that you've
collected uh whether it's from
evidence-based management Telemetry data
whatever you're data you're collecting
um I you're not going to find it you're
not going to find something that you can
apply everywhere um there are in Times
Gone by there have been um large
decision- making Frameworks um that
generally apply
because we
lived in a complicated world not a
complex one so if you think about
um complexity Theory right uh if you
think about if we
understand more about a thing we're
going to go do
than we don't
know right that's like playing chess we
understand more than we don't know then
we can apply a bunch of rules we know
what the next move is right when you
when you if you've ever listened watch
uh professional chess game and listen to
the commentary right they know exactly
what the next move is supposed to be and
the only time when
there's B based on the set of exchanges
depending how smart the commentator is
right how far ahead they can think they
know who's going to win and then it's
does somebody make a
mistake that's
how I think lots of modern businesses
are
failing so take for example I'm going to
use an example non technology example um
take for example uh uh
Logistics right so let's say you're a
Hauling Company and you're going to haul
stuff from A to B um in trucks so you
have your drivers you have your trucks
you need to do schedules you need to do
um H procurement for what goes in what
truck and how it's organized in the
truck and all of those kind of things if
you go buy offthe shelf
software that everybody else uses to
right so everybody all your competitors
are using exactly the same
software to to manage this perhaps
you're buy sap right and then having the
poge plugin and the staff management
plug-in and the whatever stuff it has
right then your business is no longer
unique right you're you're um filling a
known Niche with a known business model
that
works and then the only difference
between you and your competitors is
probably quality maybe right like if
you're if you're are you on
time um are you are you on time did you
have the right stuff like the people
errors right are you on time are the
right stuff delivered to the right place
um and then you build a reputation
around that this is a good Hol company
because they mostly do the right thing
this is a bad Hol company because they
mostly do the bad thing and then they'll
go out of business and you'll stay in
business because they mostly do the
wrong thing and you mostly do the right
thing but your business models are
identical your business practices are
identical because they have to be
because you have to fit within the
plugins the business model plugins that
you've brought in for for for for sap
right um
but when we
work in a world
where we
know
less upfront than we discover by
doing right so that's anything where
we're bringing in a creative element
software engineering being creative
um anything where there's a lot of
unknowns so a a a a great set of this is
is red team thinking uh which is a a
military um tool red team thinking comes
from the the the military I don't
remember if there's a us or the British
military probably the US military um but
it's a a military model that that is
applied quite heavily in the agile space
because we're talking about the same
thing we're talking about complexity
we're talking about um fog we've got
this a lot of
unknowns um and how do we move forward
while being able to adapt to any any
challenges surprises or opportunities as
as we move forward and and the world
reveals itself right um that's something
that that that the military do very well
or hopefully do very well um and we need
to do very well at it because most of
the all of the stuff that we do when
we're building software because we're
writing code it's never been done before
if you're writing code that's been done
before you're doing it wrong stop doing
that um but when you're Building
Products that don't exist yet then
we're exploring the unknown right so
think about when the Explorers went out
to go somewhere new they didn't know
what they were going to find when they
get there they didn't know what was
going to happen along the way so they
had to take into account bring all of
the things they needed uh scurvy was was
a was a early explorers had a lot of
scurvy because they didn't have the
right vitamins right so what they found
was they could take citrus fruits which
lasted a long time in storage if you
store them right um and then you you you
you you can Pro provide that to your
crew and they don't get scurvy right
because they get the vitamins that are
missing from the normal normal diet and
that adaption enabled
those explorers that did that to go
further and the explorers that didn't do
that all died so which ones the ones
that came back what did they do they did
this right let's do more of that and
that's what we're talking about when we
talk about agile right when we talk
about agility it's about a being
creating a system for your way of work
that adapts
dynamically to those those those changes
we have emergent everything's emergent
right we have emergent knowledge we have
emergent data we have um emergent
customers we don't know who our
customers are yet and what they're going
to want and then we get some of those
customers and we understand what they
want so we deliver something to them but
it's not quite right because they don't
like what we've delivered so how we need
to keep adapting continuously evolving
our product our business um to fill a NE
a a a a unique Niche that we've created
for ourselves and then perhaps we
maintain that Niche but those nishes
don't exist forever right um it used to
be in the old the old days of the
Industrial Revolution where there
weren't that many textile mills and
there weren't that many textile miles
within selling distance right perhaps
you as a as a tailor and you're buying
cloth you're buying it from the local
textile mill you have no option you're
buying the bulk of your stuff from the
local textile mill and then maybe you
can get some really expensive stuff from
the fari store you know wherever you
manag to get that that really expensive
stuff from but that's not for your main
client tell your main clientele is going
to be the stuff from the factory up the
road whereas today you can get stuff
from any Factory anywhere in the world
for a relatively competitive price so
that that that Market that Niche um that
those factories were in is is largely
gone it's not a it's not a niche anymore
there's loads of competing species
within that within that area same for
for our companies as as competition
grows we either have to become unique in
different ways or um we need to be the
best in that space in order to not have
any of this competition come in and as
we grow as a business this is all part
of this data driven decision- making
right as we grow as a
business we have a
tendency to say well this worked one
time let's write that down and everybody
does it that way that's
bureaucracy that's what we're fighting
against with agility because the next
thing we do is slightly different just a
little bit but slightly different so
this is not optim optimal anymore but it
kind of works but time change after
change after change after change
eventually this doesn't work anymore but
everybody in the company still does it
because that's the way we do
things that's the mindset we're trying
to change we're trying to change to a
mindset
that we we don't keep this longer than
it's necessary we don't keep this longer
than it's valuable any process or
practice we have emergent practices
within our organization any process or
practice ice can be dissolved at any
time because it's deemed to be no longer
optimal or suboptimal every this this
set of story should continually change
if it's not changed why hasn't it
changed because the world will have
changed our environment will have
changed and we need to continually adapt
and that that
that's agile decision making right it's
emergent how we make decisions is
emergent based on what we understand
what we're doing what we're trying to
achieve and the results that we get
based on that decision making so you're
also continuously looking at the data
and analyzing your decision did we make
the right decision are we continuously
making the wrong decision if we're
continuously making the wrong decision
why are we continuously making the wrong
decision and what is our decision-making
process because it needs to change
because we're continually making the
wrong decision so there's not really any
there are lots of tools out there that
you can use actually I had a I had a
quick look uh for for agile decision-
making tools and I I I found a few that
I recognize that I have used in the
past but maybe not used recently right
um so fist of five if you've got a group
of people and you need to make a
decision fist of five great way to to to
to make a decision is that going to last
forever are you always going to do fist
of five in that same group of people
probably not right because it's
usefulness as you start working together
for longer as a team you maybe recognize
more each other's Tails right and then
you don't need that mechanism anymore so
so stop doing it if it's not adding
value stop doing it if anything in your
business is no longer adding value or
it's actively inhibiting value stop
doing it and do something different
right I I see this in organization after
organization where they have a
departmental model and some department
has decided that you can't do a thing in
an organization and that thing that you
can't do inhibits all of this value over
here either makes it slower it makes it
harder for our us to take advantage of
opportunities it it just makes it too
hard to do business so the people over
here stop trying to do those things
because it's too hard usually this is
security right
and that
department has forgotten that they work
for the business the business does not
work for them their purpose for being is
to protect the business right perhaps
that department medal is a protection
model so compliance or or or security or
those kind of things but
they're um protecting the business
within the context of the business
actually functioning as soon as they're
inhibiting the business functioning they
are cost not a value they're supposed to
figure out we need to do this how do we
do this so that you're you you you can
be happy not no you can't do this right
that so that's that's a an example of
that organizational crft right that rust
and building up over time
that rust building up over time and
inhibiting your ability to deliver value
because you're you're stuck in the past
even if the past was only five minutes
ago maybe you're stuck in the past um
so use whatever
tools make sense within the context of
the decision that you're making but
always
check is that tool that we're using so
could be uh fist of five uh dacky
racy uh decider protocol conent consent
decision making lean coffee holoc dely
right there's a lot dot voting round
robin loads of different ways to do
that if we use that and we have a bad
decision or we use it in a bunch of
decision- making and all of those
decisions ended up wrong or the majority
of those ended up wrong then stop doing
it that's the key to this um agile
process to this
um figuring out how to make decisions
within the the context there are there
aren't any rules for you to go look up
there aren't any known practices that
always work um and that's true across
all of agility and all of all of all of
lean um there are certain rules that we
know to be true
right they're but they're not then rules
they're laws right Little's law is a
great example of that queuing theory
it's it's true it that's how that's how
things
work so we make decisions within the
context of that
story
um figure out what the laws are that
apply to your
business and everything
else is
flexible everything else is flexible how
you do business is flexible how you find
business how you engage with customers
as flexible um emergent right how you um
how people do the work is emergent how
you engage with them how you do
everything that you do needs to be
emergent because what you want to be
able to do as a business is when the
market shift
or your environment changes you need to
be able to evolve and you need to be
able to evolve as quickly as possible
because you don't want to go extinct