so one of the worst things I ever heard
about in agile was actually when I was
working in in the US
um as a consultant in Seattle and I came
in to help a team in an organization and
they just fired their scrum master
and what their scrum Master had done it
was be very dogmatic and totalitarian
and had decided that the daily stand-up
not daily scrum but daily stand-up
everybody had to be standing up in it or
they weren't doing scrum
and it just so happened that this team
had a disabled person on the team in a
wheelchair and the team had decided
collectively to all sit down so they
weren't towering over the person that
was in a in a wheelchair for me that is
absolutely the very purpose and power of
agile that every team can do something
differently and that scrum Master sure
deserved to be fired