so I just wrote a post called stop
hiding behind complexity and start
delivering
continuously and the
premise the premise of the
post is
that any any
person in any
organization working on any
software anywhere in the
world but says
our software is too big and too
complex to be able to deliver
continuously is
either I don't know I I'm going to be a
little bit controversial here but
they're either lying they're
lazy or they don't know
how probably they don't know how is the
most the most likely they M think they
don't understand how to get from where
they are right now with their Mainframe
based Mainframe backed old crusty
software to continuous delivery we don't
know how to get there but you can get
there if there was an organizational
will if there was an organizational will
to
improve the the the the the quality of
the product if there was an
organizational will to improve the speed
of delivery of features in the product
right because improving the delivery of
features in the product is not about
adding more people it's
about getting your product in shape
right if you've got this huge lumbering
obese product it's not going to be able
to do the things quickly that you want
it to be able to do people aren't going
to be able to get it to to to do the
things that you want it to do quickly
it's it's lumbering it's the the the the
the 500 gorilla in the room right but it
doesn't have to be you how how would you
as an
individual if you
were not where you wanted to be
healthwise how how would you get healthy
how would you get to that goal that you
wanted of perhaps you want to look like
Hugh Jackman in the Wolverine right how
would you get from where you are right
now to there because it is possible I
mean you wouldn't look exactly like him
because everybody's body type's
different but you're I mean how how
would you get that type of physique that
level of body fat well you're going to
have to work you're going to have to
work you going have to change all
aspects of of your life in pursuit of
that goal right you you you're going to
have to eat differently you're going to
have to exercise differently you're
going to have to change when you do
things how you do things in order to get
to that that that physique you want if
you want your software to get to that
physique physique so that you it's easy
easy peasy to add features to your
product then you you've got to do the
work to not just ensure that it gets
there that's the tough part right if if
you're incredibly unfit getting to that
Fitness point is really hard maintaining
it is easier right once you are fit
let's call it once the product is fit
maintaining it in that position is is
there definitely easier it still
requires investment and effort um and
time to do things but you're you're not
necessarily doing the same things that
you had to do in order to get there it
should should should be easier should be
easy and that's where you see a lot of
um organizations and software struggling
I think the one the one that gets me is
every so
often the airlines
falter right 10 once called it a
scrumble right I know they may not be
doing scrum but it's like a cross
between scrum and stumble you you you
effectively you trip over your feet you
fall in your face because something's
wrong with the way you're doing the way
you're running the way you're doing
something the way you're building your
product and you fall in your face and if
you just pick yourself up and start
running again you you you're in danger
of having exactly the same thing happen
and you see that with the
airlines right they have these old
Mainframe systems behind under the
covers deep in the bowels of their
systems but they don't understand they
don't have people that can understand
anymore I think I think American
Airlines I heard stories about pulling
people out of retire going finding the
last person who could fix the system and
they were in a retirement home and and
having to pay them exorbitant amounts of
money to come out
and take them five minutes to fix it
right knowing where to poke because
they've lost that knowledge they've lost
that capability yet they keep that
system they've lost understanding of a
system and they keep it around which is
massive amounts of risk you you see that
American Airlines has been down Delta's
been down British Airways has been down
and those are the big ones that I can
think of because they hit the news
because they're massive Airlines but the
reason they've been down is because
they've not cared for their application
they they've done a one and done right
you you you you you build it you get to
the end of the project to build it and
then that project is done there's no
more funding therefore the product then
starts to stagnate atrophy and decompose
that's that's that's what happens right
I mean the system keeps doing what it
was always doing but the systems around
it are changing the needs of the
business are changing the the the the
world has changed and then you have to
layer on more and more stuff to take
care of the fact that this core of the
system doesn't necessarily work exactly
like you need it to work but you can't
change it
anymore or you feel like you can't
change it anymore and all all of that is
crap it's all crap you absolutely can
change it you absolutely can fix it you
absolutely can make those problems go
away you can make it so you never go
down again you you you can make it so
that when when what was it it was CR
when crch strike happened right wait
failure of devops let's let's not talk
about that one but when Crow strike
happened I think it was Delta Airlines I
think it was Delta was was taken out by
it and it it took them a week even
though Crow strike fixed the problem
within hours right so
theoretically Delta was only out of
action from the external source for
hours the implication of that
outage the implication was was that that
they really struggled to get a whole
bunch of systems up because they hadn't
didn't have good resilience didn't have
good Disaster Recovery didn't have
didn't have good stories around these
things that were that were practiced and
manageable and able to be delivered
quickly so it took ages of people
running around with their hair on fire
to get stuff working and I think some of
the stuff didn't come up and running for
for for a week more than a week after
after after the the
outage that's that's not good enough
right that's a business risk that's a
Time ball waiting to happen in your
organization don't have those systems
those are not the right systems for if
you're running a multi-billion Dollar
business those are not the right systems
man if you're running a little business
right because risk
is what's it called when it matches your
your your size like if it if it's 10%
risk that something's going to go down
if you're a small business that's a
massive risk to your business if you're
a huge mass massive multinational is the
same amount of risk right it's 10% of
your business
so portional that's the word I was
looking for fix it get off your ass and
fix it and this is this is not just an
engineering problem right because you'll
probably find that there are Engineers
around this system there are managers of
those Engineers around this system that
that know they know the problem they
know what it they'll take to fix it
right they they they know those things
but there is no organizational will to
fix it because it's going to take time
effort and money time effort time and
effort cost money it's going to take
time effort and money to to deliver on
those changes to fix those problems and
organizations don't want to pay for it
because they don't see the value right
they throw their toys out the prom when
something goes wrong and demand it be
fixed and demand it never happen again
but the only way for it to never happen
again is they get out their checkbook
and they write a check is big enough to
make sure it doesn't happen again for
the for the engineers to go fix the
problem to remove those systems to
replace those systems to upgrade those
systems and to continuously upgrade
those systems they don't have a good
application life cycle management right
they don't have it and and that's
why I feel like they're hiding behind
the complexity right oh this is too big
and too complicated and it's too
difficult to do those things with no
it's not it's really not just fix it uh
the windows team went from delivering to
production once every six years with
massive amounts of Legacy code I I know
somebody who worked on the Windows team
who was talking about what they were
working on and they're the ones that
were responsible for up for do you
remember when you used to copy a file or
group of files from one folder to
another in Windows if there was one file
that had an error it would just crap out
the process and stop and you've copied
half the files and you don't have not
copied the rest and you don't know which
is which and they went in and
changed the file copying protocols so
that it had resum ability and it had the
retry button and all of those things
that was that was their
work and the code that they were
changing hadn't been changed since
1985 this was maybe 10 years ago right
so what's that
uh 20 had changed in 20 years that's not
good enough and that's that's why that's
part that's not the reason that's not
the cause but that's why Windows changed
that's why Windows be became this
continuous delivery story because that's
how you build modern products continuous
delivery forces you to deal with those
problems because they magnify they start
magnifying right if you're trying to do
continuous delivery and you've got some
slow moving mainframe system in the back
end that the team can only deploy once a
month and you're deploying many times a
day and you need changes from them
they're not going to be able to keep up
they're just not they're going to be
they're going to become the bottleneck
they're going to become the the the the
the the the thing that you need to go
fix so go fix it don't just look at it
and go yeah I've got a pro I've got
another blog post about ignoring the
signals right that's a signal in your
organiz ation to say there's something
wrong here you need to fix it and yes it
might take investment of money time and
effort as your devops when it was TFS
took about I guess they went to
deploying as your devops overnight
getting it up and running within a
couple of weeks but to really pay back
the the the technical cruft the the long
years of just fire and forget code right
to really start to pay that back took
them almost four years of of of
continuous effort now they're delivering
features and in fact they were ramping
up and delivering more and more and more
features throughout that time but they
still had to continue that effort and
they continue that effort to this day to
to to to start breaking up some of those
monolith pieces that make sense to break
up because there's nothing wrong with a
monolith but break them up so that they
can deliver some things continuously and
other things take longer and what do you
need is a business there has to be a
business need for it and I can I can't
imagine the American Airlines is sitting
there saying we're okay with this
ticking Time Bomb of risk that could
happen at any moment at any time on any
day it could happen on Christmas Day it
could happen on our biggest sales day of
the year and we're okay with that
nobody's sitting there doing that they
just don't want to Pony up the door and
get off their ass and fix the problem no
matter how much complexity you have in
your system you can positive move
towards continuous delivery