gaining an understanding of your
existing process the system within which
you're working is absolutely crucial in
software engineering where we have
really high variance between what we
think is going to happen and what
actually
happens using camman it allows you to
observe your system have metrics that
help you understand your system
visualizations that show your system and
allow you
as the team as the people using the
system to understand the the the
different things that are going on and
look for patterns um places for
improvement places that are awesome and
enable you to maximize transparency of
the work that you're doing increase your
ability to change right because now you
have agreed what all those things are
and set up continuous deliveries