I think one thing an agile coach must
have to be successful is uh a deep deep
understanding of the
um processes practices and tools
um of the the teams that they work with
that are the technologies that those
those those teams that we have to use
right
um understanding being a lean agile
practitioner understanding all of the
different flavors right now you don't
have to understand them all deeply but
all of the different flavors what what
is it that your team is working on what
tools and Technologies are they using
and how are they using are they using it
well do they need help in using it do
they need moved in a different direction
right agile coaching is about a lot more
uh than just babysitting the team