how would you like to be remembered as a
professional scrum trainer what free
things matter most to you
uh uh I guess the first one is integrity
I like to do the right thing I like to
be seen to be doing the right thing
I don't like to be seen to be doing the
wrong thing
I don't like to do the wrong thing not
just be seen to do it right
and but some of sometimes that comes
with hard choices because
it might be easier for me
to market for example Market my classes
in a particular way that I don't believe
is
morally effective probably is the the
like it's not moral
for me to do that
um I could I could have I could have a
policy whereby if a customer came to me
and had a quote from another another
scrum trainer that maybe I know right
that I could undercut their their price
in order to win the the business
but I don't do that I I have all of my
rates published on my website I do give
people discounts right but I have all of
my rates published on my website and
that's generally the rates that that I
quote
um
so people know even my competitors know
how much I'm going to be going to be
charging and they're welcome to undercut
me right but I'm not going to do that to
them because I think that's morally
repugnant within the bounds of
where a bunch of people trying to do the
right thing it's not in keeping with the
with the scrum values right so
um yeah that's the first thing
um
forthright probably
forthrightness that part of that comes
from uh my my ESD neural Divergent right
is that I don't like things to be wrong
and for me I'm I I feel like I'm
reasonably good at separating out the
difference between
the data
I.E what's what's the truth of the
matter versus what my opinions are on
top of that
um so I I I'll work with organizations
and I'll help them understand
not only what's broken
uh but what my suggestion is for for how
to fix it right and my suggestion part
might be right or might be wrong for
them they need to try it and see
but the data is the truth
um
and that's really important to me
um just in general so that's that would
be that would be the second thing
I'd like I'd like
um
I'd like people to think of think of me
as somebody that they they they can they
can come with their problems and I'm not
gonna sugarcoat anything but I'm also
not gonna poop on them does that make
sense like I I if they're doing if they
or their organization is doing something
that is downright Daft for example stack
ranking all of their employees right
that's I've seen that Microsoft did that
many minutes ago
um
the detrimental effects to a business
its organization the ability for people
to function is is is fairly well
documented for those types of issues
so I can categorically say that's a bad
idea here is the effect it's going to
have in your organization
um I'm not going to say that something's
I'm not going to say that something's
good if it's not
but that comes back to that that second
one right of of of honesty and what what
are the what are the facts if you're
doing something stupid you're doing
something stupid nothing I sugarcoat is
going to make it unstippit so what's the
point in the sugar coating when all that
does is bring politics into the story
whereas you can do something with that
data of okay I understand this is a bad
thing and I can do something with it so
I feel like that that ability for people
to come to me
um and that's why I offer
you know 60 Minutes one-on-one
Consulting and ultimately I have I have
people that I work with that keep coming
back for that for that 16 60 minutes
because not everybody uses it so it's
it's it's fine until it's a problem it's
fine right it's like Air Miles
um the the the they keep coming back and
they'll ask me questions they'll they'll
describe a problem or situation in their
organization and I'll give them advice
I'll give them free Consulting right
because because they need help they came
on my training course I built a
relationship with them
um I want to continue that relationship
and I want to continue to help them and
I'm not going to charge them for that
because that's just me helping somebody
out I think that kind of comes from my
time as a Microsoft MVP right the the in
order to be in a Microsoft MVP you're
not getting paid to do the thing that
you do
right the thing you get your MVP for is
not stuff you get paid for it's
basically for giving free advice and
Consulting to anybody who needs it
whether that be in the form of blog
posts or conference talks or just
talking to people or presenting uh the
product and where things are are buried
it's it's where the bodies are buried
right it's it's it's that free and open
transfer of information that is really
important to me if you want to come and
do a scrum.org class then you know
there's a cost for doing a scrum.org
class
um but if you just want to come and have
a chat with me for 30 minutes
go to my website it's free book up book
a 30 minute chat have a chat talk about
anything you like we could talk about
board games if you like I don't mind
what it is
um because I'm always happy to hear from
people and chat to them and I think
especially in this
in this day and age there's there's too
few there's nowhere for people to go for
help
right you can you if you've got good
Google Foo right or bingfu you can go
find uh
um
contexts
on the internet where other things have
helped other people but they're never
the same as your context and while I'm
very good at finding code contacts that
help me like when I'm coding I'll be
able to go find some code and then adapt
it to what I need
I think that's much harder when we're
talking about people and relationships
and practices and how we work in
organizations and sometimes you want an
expert to hear the story and then offer
some advice and I have a number of
people that have literally I met them
coming through my classes whether public
or private that keep coming back and we
chat all the time I've got what one
scrum master in fact he wasn't a scrum
Master when I met him
um he is now and uh we have
multiple chats a week just talking about
things that are going on in the
organization how could maybe he could
maybe do things differently he he talks
about his wins right somebody to talk to
about the things that you've been able
to achieve and what's the next thing I
should be thinking of and was that a
good idea right and I think that's
that's something we all need
so so if there was one thing like the
top thing it would be
um I'd like to be known as somebody who
is approachable even though I'm
sometimes very pedantic right but
approachable and able to separate out
that pedantic nature of
following the scrum guide right that's
that pedantic part of learning something
I.E the teacher mode right you're
learning something you want a teacher to
be pedantic because that's how that
works
and the pragmatic side which is well I'm
trying to do this in my company and this
is my situation which means I can't do
this thing that you said would be a good
idea how else could I work at this and
I'm not going to say well that sucks you
have to do it this way I'm like well
let's figure out within the bones of
your organizational context what is some
way that you can try and make things a
little bit better a little bit more
effective that that's probably the main
thing
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility