Nikita jollity is available for DevOps
and agile training and consultant
contact us for a free consultation
hey this is Martin Intuit I'm a
professional scrum trainer with scrum
dark and I Microsoft MVP I own my own
consulting company in Scotland and I
travel around the world doing consulting
and training but at the moment obviously
not traveling around the world if you're
watching this video at another time we
are all on lockdown at the moment or
covered 19 so I have taken two and
helping some folks out over over the
internet getting some questions coming
in and then just getting online and
answering them my good friend Debbie who
we often disagree about things was
online earlier and I stole the idea for
office hours kind of from her but it's
something that that I had in mind anyway
but I definitely have to give her some
props for that so ultimately this is a
ask me anything session I have a few
questions that I have collected since
last week I'm interested in any
questions you have you can ask questions
in the chat which I have and I can see
all of the the chats that might be
available but also I have a way for you
to ask questions if you are not happy
about being publicly acknowledged as
having asked that question so on the
side of the screen here there there is a
link to a forum where you can
anonymously ask a question in a box and
I will read out those questions and then
do my best to answer them
[Music]
so there's a couple of things that I did
want to mention first I noticed on the
Scrambler Dawg website there was a
couple of things that I thought were
were super awesome and I really enjoyed
the first was an article by Simon one of
our trainers from Canada about learning
scrum using minecraft education edition
so I think this is this was a really
good article I would recommend you read
it and maybe take a look at minecraft
education to help facilitate some some
things that you might want to do the
second one is from Christian probably
needs no introduction from his
Mythbusters series and he's talking
about
the myth that you can't do projects with
scrum which is indeed a myth there's
nothing in scrum that says you can't do
projects or focus on projects or do
anything of the kind it you can do
whatever you want so that's a good
article in CS get quite a few at
comments and it really tackles some of
the and I think Christians been very
good at tackling some of the the I don't
know what you would call it the
evangelical side of scrum Evangelic or
maybe the the the I guess I would say
bible-bashing but it's maybe not
politically correct at site of scrum
where people are saying you can't you
can't do things or scrum is this way or
scrum is that way I think there's
there's a place for focusing on the
rules of scrum which is in training um
and then there's a place for focusing on
the value that you're trying to get
which is in the real world so training
is not the real world it's a safe to
fail small space once you get out into
the real world you're going to have to
make compromises and that's just just
reality
I and a lot of time going around
organizations all over the world talking
to them about those compromises and how
they can maybe have less compromises
that is also important
getting as few compromises as possible
but the compromises are still going to
exist so I find those two articles
super interesting I think there's a
there's a podcast behind this one and
it's it's pretty awesome so let me go
back to me there we go so I have three
questions I don't know how long it's
going to take us to to answer them it
will take as long as it takes but and I
have three questions so far
the first one is um really so I would
summarize it as product owner versus
project manager I think the question was
what's the difference between a product
owner and a product manager or a project
manager I guess a PM versus Pio and I
think that that there's an interesting
piece there because they they're really
not the same thing if you if you look at
look at the scrum guide which went it's
good to mention in the scrum guide it
talks about the product owner as a role
all of the the roles in scrum are that
roles they're not job titles they're
just a thing that somebody does so the
the the product owner and is accountable
for value delivery in scrum if they're
accountable for value delivery they have
to be looking after the list of work
that people are going to work on they
need to understand what all of those
things are in that list of work they
need to present that list of work to
other people in the organization to make
sure everybody has the same
understanding of what those things are
and that idea and that they need to own
that and really understand that is
fundamental to them being able to do a
good job of providing value in the
organization I often talk about and I
think a lot of the other trainers do
that product owner should be fully
fiscally accountable they should be the
one here's here's your budget you have
your budget and you're spending it on
this product but they're not always the
case but that that is definitely a good
idea
so they care a lot about the market they
care a lot about how the product is
going to be used in production they care
about what the competitors are doing
they care about and what features users
need ok those are all things that a
typical project manager doesn't
necessarily care about I'm not saying
that all project managers are like this
just like not all product owners are
awesome
but the traditional project manager is
focused on delivering on a small subset
of items and their focus from beginning
to end is on on-time with the features
that were asked for and at the cost that
was indicated so on cost on time on
features is the traditional measure of
success for a project manager and that
kind of narrows the focus a little bit
to getting the thing done and you could
maybe ignore the idea of value delivery
you could maybe not deliver as much
value as you could because there's that
focus on here's the piece of work let's
just get this done and that that can be
super awesome that's the the traditional
training for a project manager and and
there are many people out there who have
the role of project manager
but also have the role of product owner
even if their organization is not doing
scrum they're not called a product owner
they might have that hat to wear anyway
and and I think that's that's really the
distinction a project manager is looking
at a short time limited endeavor of work
that's on time on budget on scope and
whereas a product owner is looking
holistically and strategically across an
entire product and understanding and
ordering and expressing the vision nor
during the backlog based on that that
body of information so while there are
project managers who are also product
owners and product owners who were also
project managers I think you can see
that there's a very distinct difference
between those two roles and I think
there's a place for product owner in an
empirical process control system but
inside of an empirical process control
system there's not necessarily a place
for our project manager I'm not saying
that project managers are not useful I
am definitely not saying that but inside
that world of empirical process control
that we know less at the beginning then
we discover as we go the traditional
ideas around project management of
having that scope up front having that
big budget up front and having those
resources available is a little bit
antagonistic to that idea of emergent
architecture emergent backlog emergent
budget potentially and it comes from a
good place it comes from those Taylor
istic ideas if you go watch one of my
previous sessions I talked about the the
tyranny of Taylorism and why that has
had a knock-on impact for the last
hundred years on the way we work and the
way the way we do things and I think
that that that led towards that project
manager and ideal we are as we're
switching over as an industry as
everyone's kind of focusing on that
shift over to product owner project
manager still are useful still have a
place in that world and but it's just
the right approach for the right type of
work which is good so that question was
what's the difference between a product
owner and a project manager and if you
have any questions at please feel free
to put them in the comments if you don't
want to ask a question publicly which
obviously putting in the comments is
gonna put your fingerprints all over
that then please use the link here and I
will get an anonymous question to answer
around scrum DevOps as your DevOps
technology question whatever or whatever
you you want technology scrum process
practice these people tools whatever I
will happily have a discussion around
anything so that brings us to the second
question uh the second question maybe
has a knock-on effect from the first one
is I I was asked a few days ago and
apart from the scrum team who else does
scrum affect
why does a why does anybody else in the
organization even even care and I think
that comes back to some of those idea
that I just talked about that and when
you have a defined approach and you know
a bunch of things upfront you can make
all of these concrete plans around how
things are going to happen when you can
do that and you would organize around a
different model and again that comes
from the terroristic approach that was
designed to manage factory workers where
you have a hierarchy of organization
because you have a bunch of people doing
the work those people doing the work
aren't and that the the phrase I'm
looking for it's not aren't smart enough
that's not correct it's they just don't
care about the work because it's boring
monotonous work if you think of screwing
the top on toothpaste bottles so a
hundred years ago that's how the top got
on your toothpaste bottle so and that
that disengagement from the work meant
that you wanted to have a foreman around
all the time and since the work that
we're doing is not cognitive we can have
somebody else plan our work so you have
the manager plans everybody's work and
they just follow the plan and end of
story we're done and then you might need
if you've got a lot of people you might
have a lot of managers and if you have a
lot of managers you might need a lot of
managers to manage the managers that
you're managing that's that's where
those hierarchies came from that idea of
organizing around at factory worker and
we're not in this work where you have a
lot of employees who are disengaging
from the process but the modern look at
things is having a small autonomous
cross-functional teams who can tackle
different types of work so you might you
might hear people talking about that
every team can tackle every type of work
I think that's a fallacy it's not a
reality of the different sorts of work
you might have a team that is slightly
marketing heavy but they're also going
to have representative from other parts
of the organization and the the the lock
n that we're in at the moment of silos
with
a marketing department a sales
department a contracts department
obscurity department whatever your
departments are called is a holdover
from those terroristic practices best
practices that came out of the
Industrial Revolution which were right
for that type of work just don't work so
well for the type of work that we do now
which is mostly cognitive so if you've
got all those smart people who are
organizing themselves around solving the
problem then you don't need that manager
managing the people you need somebody
who would maybe be described as a leader
setting direction for those teams to
organize towards and potentially getting
you know let's find some problems and
get them out the way of people doing the
work so you transition from that idea of
of management to leadership and because
you're making that transition from
management to leadership almost
everything in your organization changes
how you're going to budget your your
your teams your project your your things
that are going on is is going to change
you're probably no longer thinking about
here's a budget for a project it's going
to last for two years and then it's
going to be delivered you're thinking
about and I have a flow of value that I
want to deliver in various categories
over the next few years and in that flow
of delivery things might shift and
change I might need more people over
here I might need more people over there
and I might not do this anymore I might
change direction the market might change
competitors might do stuff I want to be
able to adapt to that urban floor and so
I've still still got a finite amount of
money I have our I have a I have a
budget and but my budget really
translates to how many teams can I have
and then based on how many teams can I
have I will make a strategic decision
how many teams are allocated to each of
the value streams that I have in my
organization and those teams are then
going to do work against our product
backlog you may have one team doing work
in a value stream or you might have
multiple teams in a single value stream
and you might at some point have to move
a team from one value stream to another
value stream because we're doing okay in
this value stream we're meeting what our
competitor market is is looking at but
in this other value stream we're not
doing so well so maybe we have to pull a
team of skilled people off one value
stream and move them on to another value
stream and that can be difficult for
that team they may be shorts and skills
they may not understand a technology it
might be a different type of work that
they're doing
but ultimately that that that's
something they can learn you hired smart
people if you have a team of software
engineers that that have been doing java
for two years and give them a dotnet
project they're going to be able to do
it they might not be happy about it
but the technology is a material you've
hired smart people so that that that
applies across your organization as well
whatever different products you're
building whatever different situations
you were in if you create teams that are
able to deliver value for your
organization and work together
effectively they should be able to move
between different and valued domains
your value streams and the domains
within those streams and be able to
deliver in different contexts that's
that's so the way you build your teams
will be different the way you organize
your people will be different the way
you fund will be different the way you
manage them will be different the way
they are going to interact with the rest
of the organization is going to be
different and that that really all boils
down to everything is different in your
if you look at maybe a company like
Netflix who run as a holic recei that's
maybe one really far end of the spectrum
towards self-organization most
organizations are not going to get
anywhere near that any time soon but
that's that's there is something there
that they get value from and all the way
to the other end of the spectrum where
most governments set where you have very
tight controlled hierarchy and
bureaucracy
hopefully you're somewhere between those
two and moving in the direction towards
holacracy I'm not saying you're gonna
get to holacracy or even if holacracy is
your goal but that's kind of the general
direction we want to move to more
self-organizing teams and a greater
degree of in the way of team ownership
and individual accountability and moving
that that floor along so that question
was apart from the scrum team who else
in my organization does from effect so
you can ask any questions you like in
the comments no problem this is streamed
out to I think four different platforms
so I'm happy for you to ask the comment
ask the question as the comment I am
losing the ability to speak English but
ask in the comments of any of the
platforms that you like and I will get
that question or if you don't want to
see that your publicly being asked the
question then please where is it here
use this link here nkd agility net
forward slash ask which will take you to
a form with one text box and a little
warning that says I'll read out whatever
you put the text box but M
asked me a question in that text box so
that brings me to my final question that
actually came up during one of my
classes and it was I'm on sprint 22
should I be using story points with my
team should we still be doing planning
poker should we be doing all of those
things and I have a very no it's not
controversial but I have very strong
feelings about this I'm super happy for
teams that are just getting started that
need to just roll forward with an idea
that need to pack up process that pick a
practice that's super simple and
straightforward to pick story points
planning poker let's use velocity let's
do all of those things I would be super
happy for a team to start there but I'm
gonna be really unhappy if they're on
Sprint 22 and they're still doing kind
of stuff and it's story points while
easy to use easy to understand
[Music]
that's what happens when you click
buttons inappropriately the the the
teams are um what was I talking about
I was talking about story points yes if
they're still doing story points that I
would consider I'm still a very immature
team story points don't have a lot of
value beyond the team in the product
owner it's difficult to use them in any
other context it's difficult to gain of
understanding of how things are going in
the team in any other context and for
the team themselves there's limited you
sees within what the team are doing the
the different events in scrum for
example when they can use that data and
figure it out is is super super limited
but it is super simple and easy to
understand
so if you've got a baguette a team
that's just started out they're just
starting to do scrum story points
velocity awesome that will probably work
for them however I consider story points
an amateur team technique this team are
still amateurs once they move towards
being a more professional team once your
team is able to deliver a usable
increment working software at the end of
every single sprint and by working
software a usable increment I mean
something that you can put into
production that you could choose to that
the business could choose to is
technically there then once your team
has got there I would expect them to
start wanting to optimize what they're
doing how they're doing it a little bit
better make more process and technique
changes I'd be able to do that and one
of the things I would encourage them to
look at is is look at their floor and
bring in some of the the floor
techniques that you would see any Kanban
team doing so I would expect I would
want them to ditch burn downs ditch
below velocity graphs story points I
would I would kind of get rid of all of
that and focus instead on a flaw
does the the Kanban guide for scrum
teams I wish was developed core
co-authored by Daniel Vacanti who was on
one of my sessions last week but he had
bad audio and Daniel and I are teaching
a professional scrum with Kanban class
in the Edinburgh British summer time
times on a virtual online class very
summertime in a few weeks so we'll be
teaching it online that is where we're
going to talk about a lot of those
techniques that we expect professional
teams to do and but you can download the
Kanban guide for scrum teams and that's
all open source get all the information
for free so what I would be wanting
teams to be doing is they want to be
looking at they're controlling their web
work in process so having a fixed number
of items that they have in total in
progress at any one time so that's
reducing the batch size of that and they
want to be looking at work item aging so
how long things take to get across that
board how lonely sit at sit there for
and looking at their their throughput
how many items are they delivering per
unit of time so rather than looking at
story points delivered per units of time
looking at items delivered per units of
time mean that in order to game the
system the team has to reduce the size
of the items and that's awesome I want
them to game the system in that way so
we're putting our set of metrics in
place that allow us to positive spin the
data but in a way that is actually
providing value for the organization so
we can reduce the batch size of
different items including story size
make them smaller they're going to flow
through our system better
because we get we need to do less work
for each item so if things are flowing
through our system better we're actually
going to get more things delivered so
rather than focusing on getting more
more story points we're just focused on
getting more things delivered so if the
team are continuously taking on big-ass
chunky backlog items then their low is
gonna suck if they want to have better
flow write those things down make it
make me bat the game and that works
works really well so bringing those
Kanban metrics into a professional team
will allow that team to get better at
delivering software scrum is not the
be-all and end-all methodology that
you're going to use for forever it's a
framework that allows you to build your
custom most optimized for your people
and your business and your domain
process around that idea so you're not
meant to be just focusing on we're just
going to do scrum its scrum and what
else are you going to do to help
optimize that process I've seen many
teams that are doing what looks like
pretty good scrum but they still suck at
delivering working software at the end
of every sprint it's just difficult for
them because they start a whole bunch of
work they didn't really understand the
work before they started it they're not
doing enough for Fineman they don't
understand the things they've not broken
it that it can be a real mess so if
you're on sprint 22 and you're still
doing story points I would be looking to
the hem scrum master to encourage the
team to get a start upping their game
getting more advanced ideas in there so
I mean I'm I'm I would consider a team
on Sprint 22 to be looking at and
newest delivery I would want to see a
completely automated deployment pipeline
and to end that sure you're a lean
manufacturing floor in the software
world is your DevOps pipeline from the
time the engineer commits code til it
gets into production what does your
pipeline look like and how ultimately
does it it should be completely
automated and then things like so I put
upping the engineering game looking at
feature flags instead of branching so
moving to a single branching model
feature flags that's on the engineering
side and then on the process side
starting to bring in some of those
Kanban measures monitoring your floor
optimizing your flow over time while
still maintaining that planning cadence
that scrum offers for your business so
every two weeks you can get together to
shift and control strategic direction
but your process is continuously
delivering our software and value into
production potentially on a continuous
basis you can be planning tactical
direction on a two-week sprint while
delivering and testing and validating
your software and ideas in production
and twenty times a day but that's that's
going to work just fine and that's going
to be even more awesome than delivering
it just once every two weeks so if you
look at if you look at the scrum guide
to bring it up again you'll see that it
says at least once per sprint you should
be done it doesn't say you can't be done
20 times a sprint that's that's where
you want to get to and that's that's a
difficult progression so that was the
three questions that I had so I answered
it was the difference between a product
owner and a project manager or at least
I talked about it for a little while if
you had another follow-up question
please ask me apart from the scrum team
what
else's affected in the organization and
you should go take a look I did a
presentation for agile by example
conference that was recorded it should
be in my channel I think it's right at
the start of the conference's I spoke at
at list and in that when I talk about
what Microsoft had to change as they
moved towards their agile evolution some
teams inside a Microsoft spent the last
eight years moving from traditional
waterfall like everybody was doing all
the way through to being nimble agile
team of about 650 people working on one
product and that has progressed through
the rest of Microsoft so I did a
presentation on the changes inside of
Microsoft which is super funny I mean
they're they're they're now the poster
child of some of those success stories
on being able to make those changes that
quickly and I talked about if you're on
Sprint 22 so that's 44 weeks into your
scrum story should you still be using
story points with your team and I said
no you should be looking at the Kanban
guide for scrum teams and bringing in
the floor metrics that you need to
monitor your work cool so um if you're
interested next Monday which is the 20th
of you know with the lockdown I'm
forgetting what eve not what day it is
let alone what month it is on the 20th
of April so on Monday I will be teaching
professional agile leadership class in
the Edinburgh time zone again which is
British Summer Time or GMT +1 and I
would love for anybody that wants to
come along and it should be on my web
site it should be on LinkedIn and should
be in various places
I would love to see you there
please ask any questions use this link
to ask anonymously ask in the comments
and I will answer them at the next
office hours okay thank you very much
Nikita glt is available for DevOps and
agile training and consultant
contact us for a free consultation