a critical skill
um to master as an agile consultant is
really understanding that you can't
possibly understand the customer's
context there's just no way you can do
that in the short period that you engage
with them and so you need to leverage
your experience with previous customers
and make suggestions
right that may or may not work within
the context of the customer and you're
probably going to get it wrong more
often than you get it right you need to
keep iterating on that on that idea and
figure out what's what works well with
that customer you'll also find a bunch
of stuff that work well everywhere right
it's just people you'll find stuff that
work well but yeah don't assume you know
the customer's context