if even large organizations are
struggling to deliver value to figure
out what products they should build and
how to maximize their effectiveness in
the market what chance do small
organizations have with smaller budgets
and less quantity of people to be able
to focus on this task and the reality is
is not about scale it's about your
ability to engage the people that you've
got in
um creating those products of the
highest possible value
traditional management practices inhibit
the ability of you to get the most out
of the people that you have because it
tells them what to do it tells them
where to go it tells them what to do and
it tells them how to do it
we need to start looking at these
whole process differently we need to
reorganize the way we structure
organizations in order to decentralize
democratize and engage the people that
we have in maximizing the value that our
organizations can deliver and that
doesn't come from
um rules it comes from principles
principles so that everybody knows and
understands the direction that we're
going and what we're trying to achieve
and we let them figure out how they can
leverage their own skills that they
understand in maximizing the benefits
for our organization that's not
something we can know as Leaders we have
to enable the people in our organization
to figure out how best to leverage their
capability for our benefit and for that
they need to be engaged they need to
care and they need to want the
organization to succeed if they're just
turning up for a paycheck and they don't
really care about your organization
you're not going to get those outcomes
thank you