[Music]
[Applause]
hi
my name is martin hinchowitz i'm the
owner at naked agility
and i'm a professional scrum trainer and
microsoft mvp i'm running a professional
agile leadership essentials 27th till
the 30th of july
over four half days from 9 00 am to
12 30 at cest which is
8 am till 11 30 british summer time
professional agile leadership essentials
is a
hands-on workshop that uses a
combination of instruction
and hands-on exercises to help managers
and
other leaders who work directly with
agile teams
understand how best to support guide
and coach their teams to improve their
agile capabilities
so join us on the 27th and 30th of july
for four half days 9 a.m till 12 30
[Music]
cest
you