it's critical that we start investing in
the competence of the people that we
have of hiring the right people of um
keeping the people that we have that are
competent in supporting them in
experimentation and learning and
figuring things out because without them
we're not going to be able to create uh
uh uh the value that we need we're not
going to be able to create um the the
the products that are going to lead to
us being successful the thing I always
think about was an epiphany of mine many
years ago and that's that unhappy sad
people don't build great products they
build mediocre
ones do you want to build mediocre
products if you want to build great
products you need to find great people
you need to find people that are happy
you need to create environments within
which you encourage people to be happy
you encourage them to learn you
encourage them to care about what it is
you're doing and the products that
you're building and the first part of
caring is self-care and self-caring
within the context of the work
environment means caring about your
knowledge and your capability and your
competence and doing something about it
just like if you care about your health
you eat well and you go to the gym
if you care about your competence you
learn and you
practice that's why it's so important
that we have this focus on competence
within organizations and stop hiring for
a lack of it