If if you're still
deploying manually, you're you're you're
not you don't have modern engineering
practices, I would suggest you have
massive amounts of business risk. Uh
there's there's no good outcomes um to
deploying manually. Uh if you want
stories about that, look up uh the Night
Capital Group uh which is a company that
went out of business in a day from a
failed deployment, from a failed manual
deployment. Um this happens in the
industry. And
while the bigger organizations can
absorb smaller failures within that
context, if you're a one product
business, um it's it's almost impossible
to absorb that that that failure
depending on how you're you're the
outcome the impact of that. H for the
night capital group. Um they ended up
deploying
there's a whole story around it, but
they ended up they had eight servers,
eight production servers, and they ended
up deploying with a feature flag enabled
on one of they forgot to deploy to one
of the production servers cuz there's a
manual person following a script. Um and
they repurposed a feature flag that used
to be used for a a training scenario
that they were exploring, like an
exploratory training scenario. and they
were they were a venture capitalist
group. So they were they're not venture
capitalist stock trading company. So
they're trading stocks. Um and the
feature flag enabled on this one old
server that wasn't updated to the new
code. Um, it updated it to buy high and
sell low
because there were they they had in the
past they had some kind of exercise
training, AB test, whatever they did
around that in in in the test
environment. Um, buy high, sell low, bad
idea. Um, and they couldn't it took them
long enough to figure out what the
problem is that they went bust.
They used up all their money. They had
$450 million in the bank at the
beginning of trading that day. Um, and
by I don't know, certainly by the close
of business, I think by lunchtime,
they'd run out of money. They they
they'd lost all all of the money because
their software was acting erroneously.
And that's massive risk. How a a
business that has that much at stake
when they're doing a deployment is
completely incompetent.
if they're using manual deployment
processes. This just mental. I I I I wor
I worked with a bank many years ago
and they had ma not just manual
deployment processes but they had five
production servers. This is for a real
time banking system.
Real time banking system. They had five
servers. They had five people in the
team and each person in the team would
log into the server and write their own
code and deploy it directly to
production on the server. Right? And
this is within the last 15 years.
These sorts of things
risk they're unprofessional.
They they they risk your business.
They're they're not the risk of the
engineers to take. They're probably not
even the risk of the managers to take.
Um, if you're a scrum master, that's a
big squirrel burger right there. Um,
it's a whole bunch of squirrel bers. So,
if if if you want to
have any movement towards modern
engineering practices,
um, let alone engineering excellence,
just modern engineering practices, you
need to be using
automated processes. You need to be
using automated builds, automated
deployments.
That's non-negotiable. That's table
stakes in this story. It's not an
aspirational thing. It is table stakes
because it makes you vulnerable.
People People make mistakes, right? You
would think
my my favorite reason the the the the
moment in time when I lost
any belief that a human can follow a set
of steps repeatedly and successfully um
was when I taught a training class for
testers. Testers using the Azure DevOps
test tools. And this was many years ago.
So it wasn't the Azure DevOps test
tools, it was TFS test tools. But yeah,
um Visual Studio Team System, but you we
had we had labs
in our training and in a lab you work
through the set of steps and when you
get to the end you've completed the lab
and you've done all the things and
you've seen how it worked, right? All of
the labs worked,
but every five minutes in that training
class, I had testers. This was for
testers, and the people doing it were
testers. Testers saying, "The labs don't
work."
I followed the lab and it doesn't work.
And I would sit down with them and show
me where it doesn't work. And they've
missed a step. They haven't done
something. They've missed one of the
things in the list.
If there was one group of people in the
world that should be able to
successfully manually follow a set of
steps and confirm whether that set of
steps works or not, it would be testers.
How many false positives are we getting
in in manual testing, right? That that
that that they just missed a step
perhaps in their own test, right?
This is why you can't rely on humans to
do these types of repetitive uh um
complex repetitive
tasks. You need automation. This must be
automated. Everything must be automated
and automated in as fast a way as
possible. So you want to have h um
automated builds.
I recommend both uh Azure DevOps um
pipelines,
Azure pipelines, right? That that
feature of Azure DevOps and I recommend
uh GitHub actions, right? But Azure
pipelines is is is is great. It's
fantastic. Um
you need those pipelines. You need those
um I'm going to call them gates. Just
cuz they're gates doesn't mean they're
not automated, right? A gate doesn't
have to be a manual thing that blocks
your ability to do something. It can be
automated. But pipelines, gates, test
automation,
that that's how you automated
deployments.
You want to automate everything. If it
can be automated, automate it. If it
can't be automated, refactor it until it
can be automated. End of story. You
should not have any manual processes
from your developers committing a line
of code to it ending up in production.
You might have approve an approval
button or I'm going to read through it
and then approve it. Right? That's fine,
but all of the steps are automated.
That's human in the loop,
but not human doing the loop.
And what you'll find is if you get there
to that minimum bar,
the only way to peel away the pain is
you're going to do lots of automation.
You're going to do lot you're going to
go through that process lots of times to
build it out. And what you realize in
doing that is you can do it lots of
times. So if you want to go from monthly
or yearly releases to continuous
delivery to continuous daily, weekly,
hourly releases into into
an environment where at least some
subset of your users are. You need to
automate. You need to use uh build
automation. You need to use test
automation. You need to integrate it all
together. Deployment automation. Get
your stuff deployed in an automated
fashion. Otherwise, your business is at
risk.