as your devops was built for agile teams
by agile teams but there are many ways
you can use it to support your agile
practices here I'll show you how to use
as your devops to support your scrum
process from the perspective of
scrum.org and the teams at Microsoft
that created it the focus will be on
using the scrum framework coupled with
value focused hypothesis driven
flow-based
practices
[Music]
hi I'm Martin Henwood owner and
principal consultant at naked agility
I'm a professional scrum trainer with
scrum.org a professional camand trainer
with Pro camand and I've been a
Microsoft MVP in GitHub and aure devops
for 15
[Music]
years would it surprise you that there
are no metrics in the scrum guide would
it further surprise you if there were no
user stories story points planning poker
or burndown charts that were part of
scrum these are and always we optional
practices that many people found value
in their way of working but that you
don't have to
have just because you use a tool or
practice in a previous context doesn't
mean that it will fit a future context
the practices that you use and how you
use a tool to support your team's
practice practices and behaviors will
add or detract from achieving the
outcome and impact that you're trying to
achieve scrum is just a container for
other practices which can be helpful or
unhelpful I'm generally pedantic when
teaching and pragmatic when implementing
so everything you see here would be
guidance based on the common cause not
just rules to follow with some
pragmatism for Azure devops he's own
idioms
it's important to realize that everyone
and every team will have dumb ideas that
sound good at the start the most
effective teams are the ones that are
able to let go of an idea when they find
that the evidence does not support it so
let's take a look at how we can use
Azure devops within the context of
professional scrum for teams that build
software
products so in order to
understand
how I've got this set up in aure devops
we're going to take a look at how Azure
devops constructs what it is we're going
to be looking at so in as your devops
you have a an organization you can see
my list of organizations on the left
hand side here and inside of each
organization you have a set of projects
so here's a number of uh projects that I
have listed when you create a new
project you uh are able to select uh
what process process to use now I've got
a bunch of custom processes here uh to
select from I've created one based on
the scrum guide here which I'm going to
show you a project that's created with
that one um and the way that's
constructed you will all be able to see
this even if you can't edit it but if
you open the organizational settings on
the bottom left and go to um
process process you'll then see a of all
of the processes that are available so
out of the box um there are core
processes of basic agile scrum and CMI
those ones are locked you can't edit
them uh but you can create inherited
processes you H createed process based
on it and this one here I'm actually
going to make that one the default CU
that should be the default set as
default process is my custom process
that I've created based on the scrum
guide so what I've done in done is I
have gone and I have disabled epic and
feature I don't want those things I
don't want any hierarchy in my backlog a
product backlog is a flat list of things
to be done and epics and features and
user stories are
just states of a product backlog item
they're things that product backlog item
can be um so if you check on the backlog
levels I can't remove epic and features
on the back log levels I'll show you how
I've disabled them but I've disabled the
work items um so they can't be created
and on here at the same backlog level
here I've got backlog product backlog
item um and I also have bug which I've
put at that level as well I know that
that you'll see there somewhere else you
set that um I have tasks too if teams
want to use tasks uh but in general it's
whatever they want to do um each of
these backlog items so if I go back to
the work items and I open up the actual
work item um has a set of fields I've
add one custom field you'll see that in
a moment um and I've added um one custom
State and removed an inherit an existing
state uh so I don't want it to say
committed I don't think that reflects uh
new scrum guide I know it used to say
committed in it and it's a little thing
but in progress is is a much better
State and because I have bugs and put at
backlog items at the same level I've
also made exactly the same change uh for
bug as well so that they're they're
they're going to be the same at the same
level so that's the custom uh process
that I've created so I'm going to click
on my scrum demo and open up my um
project and what you will um most likely
be concerned about if you're whether
you're an engineer you you're going if
you're an engineer you're going to have
want to have access to all of these
other things as well um but for most um
people that are not engineers and
Engineers we're going to be talking
about boards so I'm just going to click
on that and open
boards so by default it's just going to
show me all the work items and you can
see when I click new work item I have
bug impediment product backlog item risk
uh task and test case those are just the
basic work items I've removed feature uh
uh and um epic okay and in asure Ops
there's a bunch of tools built on top of
the basic work item tracking system so
what we're going to take a look at is
how we can do some of the things that we
would normally expect to do as a scrum
team within the context of azure devops
so first off um there are some uh
Logistics that we want to set up uh
before we get started so this is where
um you're this is something that maybe
your admin will do I prefer that every
everybody on the team has permission um
to do the things that I'm going to show
you but in the context of the project uh
there are two things that you definitely
want to configure one's area path and
one's iteration path um these are very
confusing brand new possibly
terminologies um but area path is the
breakdown of teams and what that looks
like and iteration path is a Time based
uh uh uh breakdown so I'm going to open
project
settings just going to pop open there in
the top right there we go so we're going
to the project settings and you can see
the name of the process remember scrum
2020 there as well um and on here on the
left hand side uh there's project
configuration so I'm going to go into
project configuration first um and you
can see that my uh current Sprint setup
which may or may not be a good idea uh
but what I have is um a season-based
model set up here so I have two halves
to the year I have the the first half
and the second half of the year and
inside of that half I've got um the 11
Sprints the 11 3we Sprints that make up
that half and then I've just started
adding a couple of Sprints in here and
you'll see that each of these Sprints
has a start and an end date um that's a
a subset of this uh higher level item so
I've said it up like that might be a bad
idea but that's what I've
done I then have three team well I
technically I have four teams um I have
a camman team which this is the area
path and this is the team that it's
assigned to I'll show you where that
happens in a second uh so I've got scrum
Team 1 and scrum Team 2 and cand team
one and then I've got scrum demo which
is the top level uh uh of uh this setup
so that's my areas and iterations that I
have set up I then go to my team
configuration just to validate the that
things are all in the right place and
this is where um you can see the epics
features and backlog items by default
when you create a team it's backlog
items and features I'm going to take
that features out and now that will not
be shown uh for this scrum team at all
um down the bottom here you can see uh
how am I going to work with bugs I
always pick bugs are managed with
requirements I have a blog post uh
called the the bug as a task
anti-pattern blog post uh that I'll put
in the comments that you should go take
a look at and make a decision right I've
decided that I want uh bugs managed with
requirements you can also choose bugs
are managed with tasks um and you can
also choose we're not going to manage
bugs on the back logger boards at all
we're going to keep them separate um
don't recommend that either bugs are
just backlog items that we need to work
with and deliver and and do stuff with
but in this context you can see at the
top here I've got the context of my team
um and what I've got is I've got
iterations that are assigned to this
team so this is
irrespective of um the the iterations
that we've created this is which ones
are assigned to this team uh so I've
gone ahead and I've assigned uh
iterations 1 to 10 to this team and you
can see the dates don't don't overlap
there um and then if I click on areas
you'll see I have one area assigned to
this team it's the default area and it's
for scrum Team 2 which matches the team
name so that's very straightforward and
very uh very simple in there if I were
to
switch to the kind of parents team that
is looking down uh across everything um
I have the main area path which is the
same as the project name uh here and
I've got sub areas are included so this
team will be able to see all of the sub
areas and in the iterations instead of
adding the individual Sprints cuz this
is like the higher level overview I'm
adding the seasons so if we're planning
the seasons uh we go to this level if
we're planning the Sprints uh we go to
the lower level um and I'll show you a
little bit how how that works maybe if
that works out so now you have an
understanding of hopefully of where to
go look to find the configurations where
to set up some of the things that will
manage the way your team looks each team
has its own area inside of this project
um and you can control what columns are
available on your backlog what columns
are available on your boards uh what how
how things are laid out um per team the
states on the work items are the same
across everybody so if we were doing
reporting across bunch of scrum teams we
would use the state-based
transition if we're doing reporting on
one scrum team uh we would just use the
column uh based transition
uh so I'm going to just go to the
backlog first for this uh team which
team I am scrum Team 2 perfect that's
the one I want to be looking at and the
first thing that we're probably going to
look at is is
refinement how do we do refinement in
Azure devops well refinement is all of
the work that we do against the product
backlog items as opposed to the ins
Sprint work which is against the product
itself right that results in the
increment we're all everybody on the
team the product owner the developers
perhaps other people um involved in this
story are going to be doing both of
those things all of the time uh some
people will spend more time in
refinement and less time in delivery uh
some teams we'll spend more time in
delivery and less time in refinement and
that's and perhaps it will change over
time that's just the way it is so during
refinement you're going to be um looking
at these back log items you're going to
be understanding what's coming up next
right how far into the future are you
looking um you might do some some
long-term planning you might do some
dependency management around these items
and your main friend here is the tagging
system this is your your main friend we
want to be able to manage this backlog
by filtering the items um filtering is
hugely important
because it allows us to group items that
might not be together in importance but
are together in another context another
type of slicing so for example um in
here um I have a bunch of tags uh
already added to these items uh so I
have a bunch of items that are um
associated with a particular product
that we're integrating in um so these
are these are integration points I have
uh uh some
different categorizations of work that
might be um have have have more
importance for certain groups of people
in here as well um so they can filter by
by their um slice um I have some work in
here that is to do with a particular
feature that we might be working on um
and I have some external stakeholders uh
to our team we've got some external
stakeholders to our team and some of
them are running projects that go across
the entire organization and a bunch of
different products our product might
have some work in it that we're doing to
support them um with our product and
they want to be able to see what's going
on ask us questions we want to
collaborate on those items so we want to
be able to filter on those items as well
so I'm going to show you how I can H do
some of those things in here uh right
now this is my backlog um this is an
ordered list no two have the same order
number and I can drag and drop these
around and put them in a different area
if I have a really big backlog don't
have one of those practice lean
inventory control but I can select a
bunch of items and I can move to a
particular position like in send to the
top or send it to um somewhere where
we're going to then do some fine grained
uh uh checking don't have that many
items that need to do that if you can't
actually grab it and drag it and scroll
you probably have too many items in your
back that's probably a good limus test
there uh so here I'm going to be um
filtering so over on the right hand side
here there's a filter button you can see
that highlighting I'm going to click on
filter and I'm going to do refinement
and we want to filter um by the thing
that we're looking at so uh the the
project manager who's running this cross
cutting uh a project who's been feeding
some items into our backlog is asking us
can we collaborate on some items can we
figure out if we can you know they need
to be different break them down do we
have the right thing we want to have a
conversation uh so we're going to get in
a room do a little bit of refinement and
I'm going to click on tags and I'm going
to find Project a there it is and I'm
going to filter by those items and we're
going to have a conversation about them
um it will show the actual order
relative to right so this is number 11
on the total backlog number one and two
are not part of this project right um if
I turn the filter off po take filter off
and take like uh the where's project
there's five project a I'm going to put
it way down here and then I'm going to
filter by project a again there we go H
you'll see there's that 24 10 and 24 cuz
I just moved that item further down so
now we can have a conversation about
relative uh to the rest of the backlog
where are these things um I can't drag
and drop these things around anymore it
won't actually let me do that I'll drop
it and nothing will happen um but I can
have a conversation around these items
we can open them up we can edit them we
can break one down into smaller ones we
can delete that other one we can we can
do anything we want at
this uh we might do some forward
planning um we might assign them to
different Sprints so it's quite easy to
do that on the right hand side I have a
planning panel um if I click on more
actions view options I can turn on and
off uh planning down here planning um is
quite useful um so I might say that uh
these two are in Sprint 7 uh these ones
here I probably can't oh I can do that
there we go are going to be in Sprint 8
and these two are going to be in Sprint
n um and that's through the conversation
uh We've we're working with the whole
team we've taken a guess at what these
things are so this is not they're not
actually going to be in that Sprint the
team still has to have a conversation
during Sprint plan
uh but I might be looking out a little
bit into the future seeing what's going
on figuring out um figuring out what's
happening now my filtering is way more
powerful that than that um I'm going to
take off uh uh project a uh what I might
have is I might say well I want to see
feature a and here's uh Feature Feature
A here and I want to say and uh comply
check there it is there's only one item
in feature a for comply check but if I
take off itay you can see the rest of
the comply check uh uh items here so you
can create multiple slices you can do
ORS or ands in how you view these slices
in your backlog um so that you can
decide what it is you're doing what
you're opening up what you're editing um
and what you're doing in here and you
can tag people and have conversations
and track uh those things as you're as
you're going through this is a really
powerful tool for for storing the result
of your refinement you still have to do
the
refinement so the first event uh that
you're going to do as a as a scrum team
is Sprint planning um and when you're
planning your Sprint um just as in
refinement you're going to need to look
at the contents of your Sprint you're
going to need to have a conversation
about what your Sprint goal is going to
be you're perhaps going to store your
Sprint goal somewhere and then you're
going to have a conversation about what
what do we need to do to fulfill that
Sprint goal and then what other sorts of
work are we going to take into the into
the Sprint as your devops is going to
store the outcome of that conversation
but you still need to have that
conversation facilitate that
conversation as a team um we might
decide that in order to um facilitate
this next uh uh Sprint the most
important thing that we can be working
on is the group of work that results in
feature a um we think we've got enough
together to be able to to create some
something viable value that we can ship
in our product and we think it fits
quite snugly into our Sprint with lots
of other room for other things that
we're going to do um so I'm going to
filter to feature a and here are the
items um that we're going to do we can
see there's a couple of items that are
left over from the previous Sprint
Sprint six was the last Sprint our our
current Sprint that we going to be
working on is Sprint 7 um and what I
actually want to do is move all of these
items into Sprint 7 so I'm just going to
drag and drop and you can see that's
updated that uh iteration path so you
can see there's uh What uh 1 2 3 4 5 6
sixish items um but we have 11 items
total in the Sprint that's fine these
are the things that are going to be our
Sprint goal we're going to commit to our
Sprint goal if anything happens that's
unto we're going to focus on the Sprint
goal and other things drop away this is
our one most important thing that we're
going to do you might have multiple
things that you're going to do in a
Sprint but pick one as this is the one
that we're going to prioritize over all
other things if we have to make choices
hopefully everything goes great and we
don't have to make choices uh but not
everything always goes great right um so
those have been moved into the Sprint I
can actually now click on sprints on the
left there and it should default to
Sprint 7 which is our current Sprint and
now I can see just the work that has
been assigned to the Sprint uh these
things should be approved I've not
actually done that yet so I'm just going
to edit that state and move them uh to
approved State
cuz approved there we go I've just moved
them all to approved that works cuz why
would you bring stuff that's not
approved into the Sprint right that's
data cleanliness uh problems creeping in
um and we you'll see that a few times as
we go through I'll always try and fix it
as I go um because the demo Gods right
um so we do have a couple of items that
were brought over from the previous
Sprint this is totally fine if you have
a flow focus and you're modeling the
flow of work Sprint planning is the end
of the Sprint is not like a a hard
deadline you're going to have activities
you're going to have H changes that are
going to take multiple Sprints to be
able to deliver and if you're 3 days
before the end of a Sprint and there's
the next most important thing that's the
product owner there we have a
conversation the next most important
thing is a six- day task um sure we can
start it and that's totally fine and it
will just flow into the next Sprint that
is predicated on us having awesome
engineering practices where we can hide
that behind feature Flags so we can
still continuously shipped to production
we still have a usable working increment
at least for the Sprint review um while
still continuing to do work but maybe we
take that cut of the usable working
increment if that's how we're working we
take that cut uh prior to starting that
work and that's the version that we're
going to show at the Sprint review and
then we're going to start some more work
that is going to lead into the next
Point that's totally totally fine do it
as you as you see fit as long as you
have that us working increment that's of
value to somebody to show at the Sprint
review um all of that is is is okay it's
okay to do
that uh so here I have these items uh we
can reorder them inside of this at
Sprint backlog um that will affect the
product backlog so just be careful with
that and we can maybe create some kind
of plan to complete these items um if I
add I should be able to add tag tags on
here
tags
tags uh and oh joy that's uh there we
go I don't know why I did that joys of
JavaScript o
lovely uh so we'll be able to see what
features we've got I should be able to
filter these by tags so there's the
important stuff for feature a and then
there's all of the stuff that we're
going to be working on um during this
Sprint great we're going to create a
plan uh to complete those items that
could just be a whiteboard plan that we
agree as a team or if you do want you
can create subtasks for these items um
you can do that uh by clicking on the
taskboard here um and in the taskboard
you'll see the items pinned to the left
and you're able to add uh tasks to this
board you don't have to do tasks I
generally don't recommend using this
board apart from for planning purposes
um it's quite useful for that in general
I'm going to be focusing on the flow of
value through the system um but during
Sprint planning um I might indeed uh use
some of these
ideas the second event that you're going
to hit and you're going to hit it loads
of times is your daily scrum uh when you
get into your daily scrum the probably
one of the better views
is the board view so you're going to be
looking at this board and seeing what's
happening with the flow of work trying
to identify if there are any issues in
your board and you can remember if I I
marked all those items as active and
I've hit the whip limit um because I'm
silly and I haven't Built My Board very
well at the moment but this is just a
the default board if you remember the
states on the work items new approved in
progress done if you're using um flow
metrics then the flow metrics that come
out of the box in Azure devops uh if I
do this uh the flow metrics start at a
particular time so H you've got cycle
time and lead time now we all know that
lead time is a special type of cycle
time and they're all cycle times if I do
into approved to leaving approved that's
a cycle time but those words have been
defined within the context of azure
devops for their reporting and if you
put on a cycle time um graph cycle time
graph is between uh these two oh that's
actually not in tall it's between these
two points okay so when it moves into
impr progress um the cycle time timer
will start when it moves out of impr
progress T cycle time start timer will
finish and this line over here is the
lead time so as soon as it crosses into
new your timer starting that's not
always ideal uh I do recommend using a
tool called actionable agile I'll cover
that in another video uh but it does
allow you a lot more flexibility in how
you want to report on this data and how
it gives you more insights into what's
going on but for this video I'm going to
show you the outof the Box uh
capabilities so one of the things that I
we would expect to do as a team is have
perhaps a more interesting board a
little bit more planning going on um a
little bit more decision rather than
just using the out of thebox States
these are the minimum States uh that
work goes through I highly recommend not
adding more states to the process but
instead just uh columns to the board if
you have a state that has to be true
across that every work item will go
through that State and you want it to be
applied to every team then add a
customization but don't do a
customization for like blocked that
should be a tag don't do a customization
for on hold or any intermittent states
that a piece of work might not enter the
states on your board should be a card
should flow from left to write through
all of the states ideally um so this
should be the common cause and then we
can deal with exceptions separately
preferably using tags I'll show you that
in a minute but what I want to do for my
for my daily I'm going to be looking at
the things uh that are in progress
you'll remember that I had some stuff
that's approved that we haven't started
yet if we've not augmented this board I
would probably move all of those items
to impr progress as soon as they hit the
Sprint but I don't want to do that that
seems to me a little bit um basic so
what I want to do instead is I want to
take this in progress column and I want
to split it into multiple columns so I'm
going to do that now so if you go over
to the the little Cog on the top right
this is for my for my
daily um you're going to see lots of
options now we can customize uh the
fields that are available on uh the work
item so we can add additional Fields uh
we can customize add some style rules
that can apply apply either to the color
of the card or titles we can apply style
rules based on field values on whatever
it is we want uh we can add tag colors
my favorite one is I've always oh uh I
don't have a block I haven't added
blocks to anything uh but I'm going to
add a blocked color make it like some
really bright red um that's going to be
my um that's going to highlight any
blocked items on my board give you a
visual indicator um you have some
annotations subtasks can be added on
here as well I've got that added I'll
show you how that works um for creating
creating the plan or changing the plan
um and what we're going to do is we're
going to add an additional column so I
want to take H impr progress and I kind
of want to uh split it I want to H what
am I going to do let's split it into
um options I guess so let's change this
to options because we want things to be
coming into our Sprint and then we're
going to pick from those options and
then we're going to replenish those
options uh during Sprint planning right
that's our that's our a general cycle we
can replenish any time but that's our
general cycle uh so this is going to be
in the in progress State there you can
see the mapping of the states on the
work item to the name of the column so
what I'm going to do is I'm going to add
a new column going to insert right and
this new column is also going to be for
in progress for both work items but what
are we going to call it
options um let's call
this develop I can't spell let's just
call it develop I definitely can't spell
so you'll see that as well throughout uh
develop and then we're going to put a
new one to the right called
validat y um and develop is going to be
split into doing and done columns but
validate isn't yeah that's what I'm
going to do so now uh obviously this
would not be done arbitrarily your team
would get together and have an agreement
on what this is uh but now I have my
options column so what I'm going to do
is I'm going to move um all of those
items that I wanted in this Sprint into
the options column um yeah that's what
I'm going to do for this one I actually
have a idea for how I would set this up
but again that should come out in the
wash so I'm going to move all of these
uh state to in
progress so this is me starting all the
work at the beginning of the Sprint not
always the best one for flow um but you
can plan around that so see everything's
jumped over uh into options so now we
can say um I'm going to pull this into
doing for develop and we're going to
have few items in there I'm going to
push a few items in here just so the
board looks a bit nicer just for fun um
and then as things move across the board
I've got my options which is my Sprint
backlog um I'm going to pull things into
develop um and I'm going
to do something in there okay and then
things are going to move into develop
done I we've done the work and we we
think it's finished and then at some
point we're going to pull things from
done into validate and somebody's going
to do some validation could be any
member of the team is going to uh maybe
the basic Val validation that we do is
we check against the definition of done
right let's double check let's double
make sure um that things meet the
definition of done if it does meet the
definition of done we then push it into
done and I don't know if you saw that
but as soon as I pushed it into done the
states changed to done so the columns
here if I I'm just going to take an item
I'm going to highlight it uh let's
highlight it as
blocked cuz I just want you to be able
to see it there we go so I have this red
this is the red card right um it's in
approved in this column and when I move
it into options it moves to impr
progress right as soon as I move it into
develop the in progress doesn't change
cuz these three columns are all an in
progress uh
validate oh see this is how why you test
stuff I put that let's move that back
fix that validate column I did that
wrong P approved in oh in progress yes I
know save that there we go now I can
take that column and put it in validate
and it ends up in progress there we go
perfect oh um and it's still in progress
and as soon as that moves over here it's
then marked as done okay so now I can
look at this board during uh my daily I
can see what's going on I can see the
work uh flowing across the
board the next event Instagram is the
Sprint
review uh there are some data points
that you might might want to look at in
the Sprint review most of those I would
get actually from actionable agile again
um but there are probably some things
that I'm going to look at I might jump
over to my uh Sprint and I'm going to
say what of these items is done and I'm
going to I'm going to cheat I'm going to
change the tag to that uh not project a
feature a and we're going to mark all of
those things as uh
State
done there we go and then I'm going to
so during this Sprint we managed to get
all of the things uh for our
[Music]
um spring goal completed so they're all
marked as done we're all good to go
that's what we're going to show the
stakeholders and separately we're going
to do uh perhaps we're going to do a
demo um we're going
to show what was created against what
we've got in here but then the next part
of our Sprint uh review which is
arguably the most important part is we
need to figure out whether our product
back clog still
reflects transparency of the future
still reflects the work we have to do
next so we're going to have
conversations with the stakeholders uh
that come to our uh Sprint review um
with the team we're going to collaborate
on what's happening in the business
what's happening in the market uh what's
happened in the product what are the
choices that we've made we're going to
put that all together in a big Melting
Pot and we're going to go update uh the
product backlog which it looks like I
have uh oh cuz it's got a filter on
there that's why there we go we're going
to go update the product backlog so the
product backlog is not going to include
any of the items that are already done
it's going to include the items that are
still to do and since these are in
progress I might like to actually just
stick them up the top there we go and
now we're probably definitely going to
do these things they've already been
started I'll perhaps show you how to not
have to have them started and then um
I've got some uh work here that is
coming up next this has been approved we
need to go refine these items um we need
to have this conversation during Sprint
um review where we talk about um what
needs to change here and I want would
like to see um physical changes in the
product backlog during that event
because the next thing we do after a
Sprint review is we're going to go into
the Retro and then we're going to go
into next Sprint planning and who's
going to update the product back Club
between those items probably no nobody
so this is the last moment we have to
get those changes in uh so I'd be
opening these items I'd be making
changes we'd be talking to the
stakeholders about it does this still
reflect what it is we need to do is
there changes that we've learned maybe
the stakeholders gone and talked to
additional people in the organization
and they want to bring in some changes
those these are all maybe there's a
whole body of new work that needs to go
in here we can start creating it uh uh
uh now um so that we have the best
possible product backlog for going into
the next Sprint planning and if there's
a bunch of stuff we really don't
understand perhaps they need to be able
to go on a list of we're going to need
to get together with these stakeholders
and discuss and refine uh uh more things
into the P backlog during the next
Sprint um because that's work that
happens all the time refinement happens
all the time but what's the important
stuff we need to update here to get get
straight into the next Sprint um feed
back or core changes anything like that
should be in
there the last event in scrum is our
Sprint retrospective I'm probably not
going to spend as much time in aure
devops during my retrospective we might
have a conversation about things that
happened during the Sprint things that
were left over things that were
difficult we might need to go look at
some items in the product backlog and
discuss why were they so difficult what
did we not understand and we might do
some root cause we might do some
analysis on that uh but in general we're
probably going to be having uh separate
conversations people processes tools
relationships all of those things are on
the table for the Sprint retrospective
and that doesn't have a lot to do uh
with the contents of aure
devops so I wanted to show you a board
uh that was done a little bit
differently so here I have a board um
where I have the the backlog um on the
left hand side so I have a column for
backlog so that's the new state and then
if you remember we had the approved
State and I've renamed the approved
state state to Discovery and set it as
doing and done so I have that doing and
done uh uh in here I've colorcoded these
items cuz they're too big so I've got a
field called uh item size and it has
unsized right size and oversized with
unsized being the default so if it's uh
oversized then it's going to highlight
that we need to do some some refinement
work and that's where in this discovery
column doing um I wouldn't expect to see
anything with this orange title any
further this needs to be broken down um
refined a little bit more this might
split into multiple items um before we
uh start bring it into that that
Discovery Discovery done column this is
where we might do some uh usability
analysis we might do some user studies
we might do paper prototyping we might
do
um all of those things in this column if
you're doing a lot of those things you
might split it out into multiple columns
for um how you're going to process that
work um and then it moves into analysis
at the beginning of the Sprint so if you
remember our uh timer starting for oh
that's not the right one that one our
timer uh for cycle time is between these
two lines within this box um so cycle
time uh starts here at analysis whereas
uh lead time uh starts all the way over
here and that's for the buil-in uh um
stats hopefully this gave you some ideas
about how you can use as your devops to
support uh your scrum environment if
you're more interested in uh uh the
board and the columns I have a cand
session which goes a lot more in depth
into that story as well if you do have
any questions put them in the comments
below and get in touch if you need any
[Music]
help