once you've defined and visualized your
workflow the next most important thing
you can do in a cand strategy is to
actively manage the work within your
workflow that means that you are not
just a bystander to the process right
the people that are participating in the
process are not just sitting there
looking at a piece of work going yeah
that's not working very well and not do
anything about it the the the the core
practice here is to actively manage that
means that if we're finding that we've
got too many things going on in a
particular area perhaps we should reduce
our work in process if we've got lots of
folks sitting about uh uh doing nothing
in a particular area because we don't
have enough work perhaps we should
increase the amount of work actively
manage your whip you want to
avoid uh uh work piling up anywhere in
your system so if you're if you're if
you're viewing if you've got your
visualization of your caman and you see
lots of things piling up before another
another group another team another H H
process right what are you going to do
about it you can't just sit there and
watch it pile up that's not going to
help us maximize the flow maximize the
the amount of value that we deliver we
need to do something about it we need to
go and figure out what the problem is we
need to change our system in order to
make it better um
so making sure we don't have stuff pile
up uh making sure something doesn't sit
there for ages that's part of actively
managing your work as so many teams that
I work with where we start looking at
this data and the first thing I'll say
is why is this thing been active for 250
days right and it's something that's
either fallen through the cracks or it's
some kind of bucket piece of work that
exists forever or it's just something
that's taken a really long time because
it's got blocked or we didn't understand
it or any of those
things why is it still sitting there how
can we make it go away how can we move
it towards completion I if we have a
history of things taking a long time
then we need to do something about that
if if items on your board are blocked
how are you visualizing and indicating
that they're blocked right that was the
first practice but what are you going to
do about it are you going to just going
to sit there and go yeah we've got all
this block stuff let's move on and work
on something else no no you need to
actively manage the blocked items how do
we unblock them how do we unstick them
how do we get them moving through the
system again it's it's kind of like
having having a pipe if the pipe gets
clogged right with whatever it is that's
clogging the pipe it's difficult for
other things to move around it because
our attention is is continuously pulled
in different directions so we want to
actively work to get rid of those
blockages right anything that's blocked
anything that's slow moving and getting
old sitting there and any thing uh that
is piling up right something that's
stuck and usually things pile up behind
blocked stuff right all of those things
are required for you to be actively
managing your work in a caman strategy
if you're struggling to implement a cban
strategy we can help or help you find
somebody who can click on the link below
and get in touch