one of the big struggles within the
context of software projects is
estimation um most organizations try and
do some form of estimation either
they're using um absolute estimation so
we're we're talking errors here um or
they're using some kind kind of relative
estimation tool it's really difficult
because we feel like we need estimates
to understand what we're going to do we
actually
don't
but what we do
need is the ability to forecast out into
the future with some kind of probability
right so the the
the when we're talking about software
delivery where we have really high
variance it's still really difficult
there is there is no tool when you have
more than 50%
unknown that you can use to accurately
predict the future right accuracy is is
not a thing you can have so what's the
best we can get right we want to be
looking at probabil abilities and
probabilistic
forecasting so what we tend to do is use
some kind of
forecasting simulation tool to look
forward into the future based B on what
actually happened so we're never
actually effectively estimating an
individual item within our backlog we're
just saying that we can deliver let's
say in the next 30 days we'll deliver
another 50 items with a with a
85% likelihood that that's going to
happen that leaves wiggle room for
things not happening the way you think
and it doesn't require the people on
your teams to spend spend a significant
amount of time estimating it doesn't
require any actual numbers to come out
of the team it still
requires the people doing the work to
analyze the work and break it down into
smaller chunks right that's reducing the
batch size of each individual item that
is still required that is something you
want to spend time on because it builds
understanding within the context of what
it is that we're delivering in right we
want to understand the thing we're
delivering and that understanding is the
main
impactor of our ability to execute on
those things so in in this new new world
there isn't really estimation but we
still have confidence and we put an
actual probability on our confidence I
usually encourage teams and departments
and organizations to look at about an
85% confidence level um being that what
70% of all startups fail so probably
relates a little bit to 70% of all ideas
are going to be unsuccessful right so
what's your confidence level of being
able to deliver as long as it's higher
than 70% it's probably a good bet and we
can figure it out from there