so
in order to be an associate trainer for
naked agility ultimately you you you
need to be able to to co-teach with
somebody who is already an associate
trainer or myself who can who can vouch
for you right
um but what we tend to be looking for is
is not
trainers we're actually our associate
trainers are not are not just trainers
our associate trainers are
um consultants and coaches and trainers
because the reality is the the
thing that makes our training powerful
is the stories that the trainers have of
the circumstances that they've run into
and things that companies have tried and
why something that that a purist would
say this is how you should approach
something why that might not work for
you right here are circumstances where
it's worked here's circumstances where
it hasn't right and and how in different
Industries because because you get those
questions in training you get people
asking those questions of but in my
specific circumstance
that's not going to work and the trainer
needs
the competence and background knowledge
and expertise to be able to bring that
person around to understanding why
that's why that might be an
organizational dysfunction rather than a
uh uh you know they can't do it the way
that they need to do it in order to get
the benefit they want because of some
organizational constraint that perhaps
needs to change
and and that can be really difficult for
trainers that are just trainers and have
never been a a coach or a consultant
um I myself spent
10 years as a software developer and
then 10 years as a devops consultant
right
um helping organizations get get better
at delivering software so I tend to work
with software teams
um so I just just brought on
um another another trainer
um Joanna from scrum.org
um she has a PHD in robotics and has
been coaching uh uh software teams
um a bit of scrum Master for many years
before she became a PST a professional
scrum trainer
um so that's the type of person that I
like to work with
um I work with Russell Miller who's also
a PST
but he has developed and built
components for fighter aircraft in the
US Military
um he designed control surfaces for
aircraft and project management project
managed uh uh and developed products
within the the context of Lockheed
Martin right these are organizations
that are going to test your ability to
figure out how to do Agile even within
the most horrendous constraints
which are the circumstances our students
find themselves in right so you need to
be able to have answers for those things
you need to be able to have here's a
place you can start that I have seen
work oh you're within an organization
that says you can't do Agile because we
don't do Agile here here are things you
can do without using the word agile or
using the word scrum that will enable
you to get a little bit a little bit
more benefit demonstrate that you can do
something a little bit better make the
metrics look better right and then
they're more likely to listen to you
um it it's it's
yeah I think it's it's it's really
important that all of the trainers that
we have have the competence expertise
and experience to be able to
um
debate with the students on the merits
of agility within their specific context