imagine was what is the hardest part of
working with a brand new scrum team I
guess it depends on whether you're
talking about a team member joining the
team or like a scrum Master right your
coach working with a brand new scrum
team it's probably both pretty similar
it's
it's what we think we know
I think it's it's the same is true when
you work with any group of people new
that you you it's
um I always this is one of my my tests
right I I ask teams people companies I
asked them
um how they think they're doing it's
grammar agile or whatever
and if they say we're awesome at it I
know it's going to be a complete car
crash
um and if they say well you know we're
we're we don't think we're doing that
well we really need some extra help uh
we're trying to do different things but
we're hitting stumbling blocks you know
it's going to be absolutely awesome
right because they've got they've got to
that point where they realize what they
don't know
and that's that's in a big inflection
point for for teams
um
so when you're working with teams new
teams
um the the the the biggest Gap is what
they think they know
they they think that they have to do
user stories they think that they should
be doing planning poker and story points
um they think they should be doing
estimation
um they think they should be doing burn
Downs they think they should be
monitoring their velocity and all of
those things are nothing to do with
scrum right they're they're barely
mentioned in the scrum Guide Burn Downs
are mentioned I'm not sure velocity is
but burn Down's mentioned as a EG here's
a list of things you might do
um so they're not intrinsic to the to
the process at all they're strategic
choices you might make right
um and trying to help them understand
the difference
between that and like the the the the
the fluff right so
the core the core thing that that we
need to understand as as individuals as
teams as uh members of teams
is that
we're trying to create we're trying to
leverage empiricism right
it's a scientific method we're gonna
we're gonna we're gonna do something
very small we're gonna get it to the
people who are gonna use it and then
we're gonna analyze their usage and
maybe get maybe they're gonna tell us
feedback we're going to analyze their
usage and then we're going to change
what we do based on that that Loop
that's that an empirical empirical Loop
and
that knowledge that understanding seems
to be fundamentally missing from from
from most teams that are doing scrum
right
um they they they they don't they they
never learned or never understood the
the foundational elements and they're
just looking at
the mechanisms
in scrum and just following mechanical
mechanical scrum
um so trying to get them to understand
that all of the mechanical parts are
just
so
the bollocks you need to make sure you
get the the the the the empiricism
feedback loops shortening the time to
Market getting that getting closing that
feedback loop closing that time to learn
right those are the things that actually
matter and whether you're doing
focusing on on kanban or scrum or kind
of an Ann scrum or lean or whatever it's
our devops it's all fundamentally the
same thing that we're trying to trying
to trying to achieve those underlying
foundations if we understand them
everything else is just right what would
we like to do in the way we do it in
order to be successful and
bringing those foundations in when
people have already built houses on top
and is much harder