naked agility limited is a professional
company that offers training coaching
mentoring and facilitation to help
people and teams evolve integrate and
continuously improve to allow us to
focus on reflecting and practicing in
the classroom our training courses
leverage a flipped learning approach
that delivers some or all of the theory
as self-study the course content is
divided into Learning Blocks each with
presentations and lectures in the form
of videos reading material and writing
activities that are provided for
self-study complemented by half-day
virtual sessions delivered online using
Microsoft teams in Europe these live
interactive workshops create a dynamic
and interactive environment where we
dive into the Core Concepts through
group activities interactions and shared
experiences all with the guidance of an
expert professional from trainer
professional kanban trainer or Microsoft
MVP obtaining new knowledge through
self-study materials and having an
in-depth Rich engagement in the class
allows students to enjoy learning that
sticks students will complete the course
ready to take the globally recognized
certification exam included in the
course fee as part of our learning
experience for every participant we
provide a 30-minute learning review
60-minute coaching session and accessed
future courses at a 30 discount we
recognize the positive impact that a
happy and motivated Workforce that has
purpose has on kind experience we help
change mindsets towards a people first
culture where everyone encourages others
to learn and grow the resulting
Divergent thinking leads to many ideas
and opportunities for the organization's
success
and all participants gain complementary
access to the premium professional scrum
space in our public Community the league
of extraordinarily and agile
practitioners I hope to see you there
click the link below to find out more
[Music]