one of the myths in uh scrum is that we
have have no
governance um this kind of leads on to
the bigger myth that just because it's
not in the scrum guide um doesn't mean
you're not supposed to do it um scrum
does absolutely have have governments it
has small amounts of governance baked in
right but in general you need governance
to build your product so it's kind of
correct to say scrum doesn't have a lot
of govern
right there's a very small amount of
governance built in but if you want to
be successful at Building Products if
you're for example Building Products
within the health care space then you're
you're going to have to worry about your
ability to support Hippa to support the
Regulatory Compliance that comes from
the outside don't that's governance
imposed on your organization from the
outside that you have no control of um
you're going to have um things that your
organization does internally perhaps uh
your organization has usability
guidelines perhaps they have um uh uh uh
like ux guidelines for here's how our
all our products ux is going to function
so that anybody interacting with our
software already knows how it's going to
work because it follows the same rules
um then that's internal governance that
has been applied to your product you
maybe have a business um rules that are
another form of governance you might
have particular ways in which you
interact with the market as a business
that's your unique uh one of your unique
selling points your unique engagement
points with the market and they have
those those ways of working have to be
implemented in your systems in that way
that's internal
governance just
because scrum talks
about um minimizing that governance
doesn't mean it's not there right you
just you have just enough governance to
support the business need um it's when
you have way too much governance that
you start running into a problem that's
why in very large organizations for
example Banks right they really struggle
to move towards uh scrum and agile
practices because they're encumbered by
the baggage that they can't put down uh
Royal Bank of Scotland in the UK was the
I think it was the first bank in the
world it's currently the fifth biggest
bank in the world um and they've been
going for over 200 years can you imagine
the the the the procedural and
compliance baggage that that
organization has many of it around for
no other reason than nobody's Revisited
it in a long time nobody's challenged it
in a really long time how many policies
and procedures do you have in your
organization that nobody knows where
they came from or what they're for or
who owns that policy or procedure or why
right it's just the way we do things
here those are the things that we want
to challenge we want to challenge
anything that gets in the way of inh
inhibiting our ability to deliver value
those are the things we want to prevent
those are the uh policies practices and
procedures the governance that we want
to reduce to the absolute minimum thanks
for watching the video If you enjoyed it
please like follow And subscribe I
always reply to comments and if you want
to have a chat about this or anything
else agile scrum or devops then please
book a coffee with me through naked
agility