what you need to do is you need to fill
that vacuum and as a new product owner
this is the key part for you to
understand as well as for you to be able
to engage and communicate to other
people in the organization up up down
sideways whatever it is do you
understand the vision of your product do
you understand what it's trying to
achieve if you don't that's step number
one figure out um what the what the
value is in your product what's the
vision right what is it you're trying to
achieve where are you going what's your
North Star right once You' figured out
that once you figured out that and you
can communicate it right you have to
learn to speak in front of people and
engage people in that story because you
need to engage them in that story then
you need to think about the value that
you're going to deliver are the things
that you're delivering in the product
actually serving that Vision are they
working towards that Vision what is it
that you're trying to to to achieve