it depends what type of coaching we're
talking about if
um we're talking about coaching an
individual
um then the absolute top thing they need
is permission
you don't you don't coach without
permission that's just rude and comes
across man it can sometimes comes across
quite dickish right
whereas the the I think I think what I'm
thinking is the the coaching stance is
when are you when are you coaching the
team
like as a group the whole team rather
than one-on-one coaching the team versus
uh
um you know telling them telling them
stuff teaching the team and I think
um three things you need to learn are
are to listen you need to listen to the
team and not just listen to respond but
you need to listen to understand one of
the problems that the people on the team
have what are the problems in their
interactions with themselves between
each other
um outside of the team how how do you
understand the dynamic right so
listening to the team is is is really
important
um
another top thing
I think is the understanding of what is
it that the team are doing
um for me I would maybe put that one
first although I thought of the other
one first but I would put this one
probably pretty high on the list that
as a scrum master
you're leading
therefore
you lead from credibility you don't lead
from
mediocrity right you need to you need to
be credible within the space that you're
leading people
so do you understand what it is they do
how they do it what the trials and
tribulations are what does good look
like for the type of work that the team
is working on
um and and and how
what does good look like and how can you
engage with the team in a way that
enables them
to do more of the right thing and less
of the wrong thing thanks for watching
the video If you enjoyed it please like
follow And subscribe I always reply to
comments and if you want to have a chat
about this or anything else agile scrum
or devops then please book a coffee with
me through naked agility