so there's no such thing as a junior
scrum master I I I wrote this post
because I see and continuously
see a lot
of multiple things so I see a lot
of
organizations thinking that the scrum
Master can can be or teams right
thinking that scrum Master can be anyone
in the team and going well they're just
facilitating a few meetings so we will
just who's who's who's the least
productive on our team okay it's this
junior person I we'll pick them as the
scrum Master you go do this stuff and
that that that does that person and
themselves are complete disservice let's
tackled that one first right so that's
that's the first part of why why I I
wrote it the other part is on the scrum
Master site
that there is a
belief in the industry that if you want
to get into
it then a good way to do it is to come
in through the scrum Master because you
don't need to do anything
Technical and that for one of better
expression is total BS you you do need
to be Tech you need to be technical
within the context of the
team just like if you were wanted to
coach a
professional soccer
team you're probably football in my
words you're probably going to want to
understand the rules of the sport you're
probably going to want to understand the
Nuance of not just the sport itself the
the the the the the league tables how
you move between the leagues right the
the mechanics and the mechanisms of not
just the sport but the leagues and how
do you navigate your team
through through that story how how good
do the individuals need to be how well
do they need to work together how if how
do they they they they they thread that
needle of becoming a high performing
team in that league and perhaps going to
the next league if you can and maybe you
don't want to go to the next league so
maybe maybe you deliberately need to to
to lose a game right because you don't
want to go to you don't want to be
pegged High have to go to the next
league and then you'd be the bottom of
That League rather than the top of this
one all that kind of stuff the the the
understanding
of what we're
doing how we're doing it why we're doing
it and how we're going to get to where
we're we're going from a strategy
perspective so that's not the the in in
scrums perspective in in the perspective
of a of a of a scrum team
the the product owner is going to take
care of the the the what right I I I'm
pushing it off to the product owner the
whole scrum team takes care of the W but
the product owner has the has the
accountability um and we've got this
what that we're looking at but we've
also got
the the system that we're using and that
system that we're
using needs to be as effective as
possible so no matter what whats come
through the system we're able to deliver
them as quickly as possible and the
system the system coach the person who
is most focused on the system itself and
encouraging people to reflect on the
system itself and figuring out how the
system itself needs to change in order
to uh maintain that and how the systems
around that system need to change so
that could be things in the organization
or things and other teams that that
would enable us to be more effective if
they changed but is that good for the
overall system or just a a local
optimization which might be good for us
but negative for the rest of the system
how do we fit into that whole story that
that's not a that's not a junior who who
figures that out right that's somebody
with deep knowledge and understanding of
the type of work that the team does so
in my case that's usually engineering
teams they have deep technical knowledge
in the type of work that the product
owner does so the context of the
business right because the system has to
operate inside of a bigger system the
system of the team has to operate inside
of a bigger system that is the whole
organization so understanding the
systems of the organization and how we
navigate
that and then they they also need to
understand the the
the things that we see most which are
the the the the the tools and practices
around how do we actually do those
things so I I think too many people look
at the outcome and look at the tools
people used to get to the outcome and
they focus on the tools but they don't
focus on how did we pick that tool how
do we get to that tool and does that
tool continue to support our needs over
time
and that's the perview of the the scrum
Master they are they are a system system
mechanic there they're a mechanic for
the system and if you're going to be a
mechanic for a system you want to
understand the systems and that system
is made up of the way the team works the
capabilities of the team the knowledge
of the team is made up of the knowledge
of the product owner and what they're
picking and what direction they're going
and that informs what knowledge the team
might need in the future and we're
looking at the organization and what the
organization understands about the
system what the organization system is
it's just such a
big ball ball ball of worms that you
need somebody with significant expertise
significant history to be able to do
that so that's why I I use the phrase
there's no such thing as a junior scrum
Master there there is no such thing as a
junior Scrat Master just the same as
there's no such thing as a junior CEO or
a junior CIO the might be somebody who's
new to that role but how did they get in
that role they were selected they were
picked for their their
demonstrated skill and ability already
they they they they are didn't arrive
fully formed right that's um a little
bit of a misnomer I
I I think I think a good example is that
idea of a of of a of a of a gunny or or
in in in the military right a gunner
Sergeant there's no such thing as a
junor Gunnery Sergeant right you you you
have a person who demonstrates skill at
different levels and is promoted through
the ranks right and then they get to
that they're now a gunner Sergeant they
may be new to the role of gunnery
sergeant and have to learn things about
that role but they bring with them
significant skill and expertise in what
we're doing already they they already
you're not going to make General
Sergeant if you don't understand the
organizational structure if you don't
understand not just the the hierarchy
right but also that network of how you
actually get things done inside of the
context of the organizational structure
so there really is no such thing as a
junior Sun scr Master there's no root to
scrum Master for or should be no root to
scrum Master for somebody who doesn't
have any skills within the context of
the team because they're going to do the
team and the organization a disservice
they're not competent within that
context so my my advice for for people
who I I I'll use a concrete example I
had somebody set up a a meeting to have
a chat about becoming a a srum master
and they worked in accountancy they
worked for an in firm and they wanted to
to get into the like the idea of the
scum master that they'd heard about and
they wanted to get into that and my
advice to them was to to fight find a
team or a group inside of the world of
accountancy right so you already know
the context you hopefully you have some
skills in that context and and make them
try you
work while you're doing the work with
the team to enable them to be the best
team te anybody's ever seen within that
context and by pursuing that goal you
learn the the the the processes and
practices that are required within that
context of an account team doing
accounts what what are the actual
processes what are the systems that make
sense within that context how do I
educate the people on that team in that
group and The Wider organization on
those practices and convince people to
and that will build your skill and
eventually the people in your team and
the people in the organization will look
to you for those things because you have
demonstrated competence in them right if
they're looking to you for those things
you are the scum Master right you are
the coach you are that that that person
and you arrived at it almost you you
know you became it fully formed because
you've demonstrated that capability but
it took a long time to learn the things
you needed to go over that line and
become that thing and then yes you're
you're you're uh new scrum
Master but there's no such thing as a
Junior scho Master