so there's no way
for an external
party to come in and give you a solution
recipe something that that you can no
recipe is the wrong word but there's no
way that somebody can come into your
organization and just tell you how to do
your stuff it's the reason that the the
big
Consulting companies don't affect any
change is the reason that the the big
Frameworks for agile or devops don't
actually tend to change anything in the
organization um apart from cost durin
your bank account that's big Consulting
companies too um it's the
reason that most
organizations struggle to incorporate
the story that they're trying to they're
trying to work towards a new story right
and the reason that they struggle is
because they're trying to buy it
in rather than adapt it it's like if you
wanted to be a
gymnast
and are you just going
to hire
somebody to do the gymnastics for
you but you wanted to be the gymnast
they're the gymnast you're not the
gymnast
so there's a fallacy
in
Consulting that a lot of Consulting is
just Contracting right you're hiring
somebody in to do the job you've got a
butt on a seat doing that job for you
and if that job inside of your
organization is a business critical job
which anything that's around the the the
the purpose of your organization
anything that's around how your business
does business is critical to your
organization then you're Outsourcing
part of your organization and now why
would anybody in your organization learn
how to do that thing because there's
somebody else doing it who doesn't want
to share it cuz they're a
contractor and if they keep that
knowledge they keep their job if they
share that knowledge they lose their job
and that for me is the big difference
between Contracting and Consulting right
although a lot of people sell Consulting
when actually they're doing contract
acting and that's that um the purpose of
a
consultant is to provoke
change that's probably the most
interesting way to say it is the the
purpose of a of a consultant is to
provoke change the consultant shouldn't
be doing any of the work within your
organization if you hire a consultant
you're not hiring them as an agile coach
that's a contractor you're not hiring
them as a development lead or a project
manager that's not a consultant that's a
contractor right there's somebody in
your organization doing the work what a
consultant is an
advisor who provokes change they are
somebody from the outside who maybe has
additional deep Knowledge and Skills in
that particular topic who doesn't come
in to just tell you how to solve the
problem even if they know how to solve
the problem right they might give you
advice but they're not going to solve
the problem for you but they help enable
you as the person inside the
organization or group of people if it's
a team to
understand the
theory so that you can make the
decisions for the organization so that
you can make the changes in the
organization and because you understand
the theory and the
principles you're able to then make the
future decisions as well that are better
than the previous decisions if that
makes sense the whole idea of
Consulting is to help organizations
change by provoking the people inside of
the organization to do things
differently AB