evidence-based
management is the
application of evidence-based practices
at the Strategic and tactical levels in
an
organization it involves using data to
inform but not control the actions and
behaviors that have been shown to impact
outcomes so what that
means is that um we're going to we're
going to collect a bunch of data within
the
organization the way we measure
people informs the way they
behave so when whenever you're working
within an organization and you find
somebody's working against you or
somebody's not um being as involved as
they you think they should be involved
and you're wondering why there's
probably some organizational measure or
metric something being levied against
them um levied on them that that enables
that behavior that enables ensures
encourages that that behavior in in that
person so the best way to figure
out why somebody is doing something in a
particular way that maybe you feel has a
negative impact on the way your things
need to happen
is to figure out how how they're
measured right uh uh that that can be
difficult but if you can glean that
information you can figure out why
they're behaving the way they're
behaving why they're taking the actions
that they're taking um and we want to
try and have more behaviors and actions
that impact our outcomes positively
right we want to deliver more value to
our customers we want to
um what other outcomes might might your
business want well they might might want
more Revenue um they might want more
value for their customers um they might
want uh uh to save money uh what else
might be good impactful outcomes for our
business we might we might um want to
increase our capability within a
particular market right being a little
vague but um it's difficult without a
specific instance to have a specific
outcome that you're trying to achieve
right so once once you've figured out
what your outcomes are you need to
figure out what metrics are going to
help you measure progress towards those
outcomes so I mean these can be super
tactical things that help you move
towards those outcomes it can be leading
or lagging measures there's all kinds of
things uh that come into that but
evidence-based
management is that
application of practices within the
context of that data to help you make
decisions and I one of the reasons I
very specifically uh said inform but not
control is that the data is not always
going to result in a specific action
right so um what's a good example of
that uh let's say I had a metric for my
for my team or teams I've got a group of
teams I'm working with and my
metric
um is number of live site incidents that
last or exist for longer than two
sprints three Sprints let's call three
Sprints right so we're running a live
service we're going to have outages and
issues and things that happen in the
live service when those things happen
we're going to create livesite incidents
right um or or Liv sight incident
mitigating actions right things we're
going to change in the product in order
to not have that type of Liv site
incident happen again so we've done our
analysis we've we've come up with these
ideas and then we expect our our metric
is that we expect teams to clear those
off off um within three
Sprints so if I expect them to clear it
off within three Sprints I maybe want to
have a measure a team dashboard and I'm
going to have a measure that says uh uh
what is the number of live site
incidents that have been existing for
longer than three Sprints and what is
the trend of that number right so is it
trending up or is it trending down and
you may see your list of teams and you
see the numbers and they're all good
apart from this one team that has these
four outstanding Liv site issues that
have been there for longer than let's
say they've been there for six or seven
Sprints
right that doesn't mean there's
something wrong in that team these are
indications these are flags pieces of
evidence that you use to inform your
decision making so you'll probably need
to go ask them how it's going and maybe
there's a team that that they're waiting
on something else to happen they can't
fix their thing until some other third
party that they don't control and we
have no well limited influence over um
we can go shout at them right that's
influence uh but we have limited
influence over um needs to do something
so we can't make them do it they're
going to do it in their own time it's on
their backlog it keeps getting pushed
and we we can't resolve our issue until
they've resolved their stuff that they
need to do
so the team that data looks bad but the
team's doing fine they're they're
chasing it on a regular basis they're uh
putting pressure on that other group on
a continuous basis um it's just taking
time to get to get resolved so that's
why it informs but does not
control
um but we're making decisions B based on
the evidence we're collecting a bunch of
evidence we're extrapolating what we
don't know or don't understand right the
evidence is going to have gaps in it and
then we're making an informed decision
based on our understanding of the
current situation and that's
evidence-based management right um in a
nutshell