this is one of my favorite questions so
the question is how do you define a
definition of done if you aren't 100%
sure what the solution is going to look
like and I would say easy because the
definition of done has nothing to do
with the solution absolutely zero to do
with the solution that you're trying to
create the definition of done is the
level of quality that each thing needs
to meet in order for it to be an even
viable solution right so let's let's
let's let's use an analogy because
that's always always great for these
things let's say uh you've decided to
quit quit quit your job in this it or
whatever Malarkey you're in at the
moment and you are going to go open a
bakery right you're going to go open a
bakery in this Bakery uh you've decided
that your your new products that you're
going to ship in this Bakery are donuts
and baguettes
right donuts and baguettes have very
different recipes one's made with sugar
and one's made with salt right um so if
you have these two different products
that have different characteristics you
could say that you're you're you have a
different recipe for each one you have a
different um characteristics you would
like each one to be right let's call
them acceptance criteria in order for
you to accept your your dut is in fact a
dut it normally has to
be
round it has a hole in the middle or no
hole in the middle if it's filled with
something right it should be fried and
dusted with
sugar right Donuts very tasty right the
other tasty thing is baguettes if a
baguette looked like a donut that would
be a bit weird I'm not going to fry my
baguette and dust it with sugar right
what I am going to do is I'm going to
create a a a
long tubes of dough tubes that's not the
right word long rods of dough that then
go in the oven and you need to cut it in
a particular way to get that kind of
twisty thing that you see on the top and
they to be golden brown um and they're
not sweet right those are those are
maybe some characteristics some
definitions of of of acceptance criteria
for for uh baguettes make sense so far
okay what needs to be
true for both of those products in order
for you to ship it the
customers not specific to any particular
thing thing you're shipping in your
bakery what needs to be true for both of
those
things I would
suggest um kitchen is clean at time of
preparation that would be good you could
swap that out with Meats local Health
standards right all ingredients are
fresh at time of
preparation right you don't want to be
making with moldy or or or per quality
products right the better quality of the
product input the better quality of the
output
um and each batch is taste tested before
it goes on the
Shelf before it goes on on on
sale there's your definition of
done and those three things have nothing
to do with what your Baker is
creating a bakery in fact I would
suggest that those three things should
be true for any Kitchen in the world
preparing in any type of food right once
your bakery decides to add some meat
products right let's say you want to to
have some kind of pie uh steak pie or
something you're going to sell as well
suddenly you might need to add an extra
thing to your definition of done and
that might be heated to the appropriate
temperature right because you want to
cook the meat you don't want people to
get salmonella and all of those nasty
germs you need to kill the germ terms
but that new definition of done cook to
the appropriate temperature still
applies to donuts and still applies to
beet right so all four of those things
can then be true for every single thing
you create in your
kitchen that's the definition of done
it's about quality of the product how do
we ensure that we don't make our
customers sick that we don't make put
ourselves out of business
that we have happy and successful
customers that's your definition of done
so it has nothing to do with what you're
making in your kitchen so let's apply
that to to software world right what
needs to be on your definition of
done for you to be sure that you're
protecting your
customers that you're protecting your
brand that you're protecting your
business and you're protecting
yourselves what you need needs to be
true that would be your definition of d
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked
agility