one of the seven signs of the agile
apocalypse is chaos chaos oh my chaos is
everywhere in teams um it manifests as
not having a plan of not knowing which
way we're going not having goals and
what would you expect when everybody
doesn't have the same goal this they're
not working together towards a common
goal you end up with chaos everybody's
pulling in different directions and this
applies not just just at the team level
but all the way up your organization why
would you think everybody would be going
in the same direction if they don't all
understand the goals of the organization
the goals of the product and how the
work that they do every day contributes
to those goals