hmm
uh does scrum allow you to do twice the
work in half the time at such a [ __ ]
marketing
thing isn't it right that that's uh
that's how I want to sell lots of books
phrase
um
does it do that no
right that's not what you're trying to
trying to achieve when you say twice the
features in half the time right you're
talking about 400 percent
increase my math is right at 400
increase in in in in in output and and
it's and and it's an output focused
measure right
features is output and scrum is not
output focused it's outcome focused
we want more value not more stuff if we
could deliver 10 of the stuff that I
deliver but a hundred times the value
I'm
it's going to be better
right so
that that's just some yeah it's terrible
terrible phrase and probably has done
quite a lot of damage to to in the
industry or at least
um it seems to have have damaged that
but also Woody actually talks about in
the book
right that's the that's the title of the
book it's like when you see agile books
that have the word best practice on the
front and you're like oh but there's no
such thing as best practice in the agile
world it's you know emergent practices
yeah but you your your your publisher is
not going to sell a book that says
adequate practices on it right they're
gonna sell a book that says best
practices because that's marketing
um so so I when you actually look at the
contents of the book how he explains
um what he meant by twice the features
in half the time I think it gets a
little bit better right it gets a little
bit better and it is definitely a book I
have used
leverage successfully with people in
leadership
to get them more friendly more on board
with the process especially if they're
very opposed right because it's got that
cover is covers a good lead right
they're gonna the opportunity pick up of
that book and so I have I I have
leveraged it I have bought copies of the
book I have a box somewhere with with
copies and I will go leave them near
executive bathrooms and customers I go
uh and then they're gonna that's that
that book that they pick up and just sit
and have a read of and
talk you know it talks about the the
Udo Loop it talks about Jeff when he was
a fighter pilot and just those
compelling stories about where some of
this where he felt some of this stuff
came from and being able to do that but
no the title of the book is just it's
it's [ __ ] you're not getting twice
the features in half the time you maybe
twice the value and
half the features I don't know maybe
that makes sense I don't know but it's
it you want to be focused on outcome not
output