so
the difference between a a an agile
leader and a traditional manager
is that a traditional manager tends to
focus on
um telling people what to do right on
creating a a walls so that people can
focus
but in actual fact they reduce
communication
um they reduce the capability of the
organization to make decisions and
reduce the capability of the
organization to respond to the market
it's not it's not their fault as
traditional managers it's the system
within which they're expected to operate
right so they're they're just following
the the the conventions of the
organization that they're in
but the the agile leader I think in
those organizations challenges those
organizations pushes them towards
thinking differently and enabling people
to make the decisions that they need to
make