so what do people love most about the
four day trading format it's not two
full days I think that's what they love
most right I don't have to sit in a in a
meeting or in a room
for eight hours that that just sucks I
feel like the four four half days
is quite a good intermediary format I
think there's a there's a better format
coming which is either
um going to be four half days over two
weeks or eight half days over eight
weeks right
um but I think the
four half consecutive half days gives
you enough time to absorb the content do
a bit of a bit of reading right
[Music]
um
think about what it is that we've been
working on and then come back the next
day with more better questions I think
that for me is the core value of the
four half days over the two full days I
actually I still do two full day classes
and I really struggle in them to to
um to pay attention the whole day right
because it's it's that's that's a long
day but also
um to really understand and rock the
content right you kind of need that Gap
um so having that that four hours and
then you've got the full 24 hours Gap
and then uh um another four hours does
seem to add value to the class
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility