one of the core practices of caman is to
Define and visualize your workflow this
is really important because it sets the
groundwork for us all all the people
that are participating in the work in
the system as all
agreeing what is it that we do and how
do we currently work so there are lots
of pieces of information that we need to
pull together uh to figure figure this
out so one might be like what goes on
our board that might be a great question
to ask what types of work goes on our
board um another question might be what
are what are the current what are the
stages that all of our work goes through
not a specific piece of work but all of
our work goes through that would
generate the columns within your your
cambam board but also asking additional
questions like why do we pick this item
how do we pick the item from this column
when we go to select things and what
you'll find is that for most teams most
groups of people they don't have any
level of agreement on what that is why
would you pick something lots of lots of
people will pick stuff because they
think it's cool because it fits they
think it fits their skill set but the
important questions to be asking are how
do we pick this so we maximize the value
value of what we're delivering is that
the right thing to select in order to do
that is that the right business decision
and answering those questions and coming
up with a set of rules for our team
right these are our decided rules on how
we're going to select things why things
move uh from one column to another what
are the defined States what are the
types of work um and how are we going
to control the amount of work that we
have in progress are all part of
defining our
workflow and
explicitly setting policies that's all
part of this defining and visualizing
your workflow
and bringing all of those things
together allow us to have a way of
working right it another way of saying
this another way of saying Define inv
vision ize your workflow is what is your
team's way of working and does everybody
on your team agree that that's the way
that they should be working
um this definition is absolutely
fundamental to figuring out um how work
flows through your system right you'll
probably have heard folks talk about
having a stable system right you need a
stable system well you can't have a
stable system if every member of the
team decides ad hoc how they're going to
do all of the things within the system
we don't have a system we've got to make
it up as you go along system and that's
never going to generate stability so
having a stable system means we've
decided what it is we've written down
how we're going to work we've debated as
a team and decided on certain things and
then we visualize that so we can all see
what's going on if you are struggling to
implement a cband strategy we can help
or we can help you find somebody who can
click on the link below