what is evidencebased management I think
the easiest way to describe it is just
bringing science and empiricism to
leadership all right how do we how do we
make decisions as Leaders what's the
data that we're using to inform our
decisions and when we make decisions
what is the impact that those decisions
have on the organization and how how are
we measuring that um in most
organizations that I see a lot of that
is done by either gut feeli right so
there's not really any data or it's
there's a lot of vanity metrics in the
organization um the the represents us
looking good but doesn't necessarily
change the way we do business so
evidence-based management is an attempt
to address that and help organizations
understand their business value right
that's the the the key thing there is
the business value are we focused on Val
delivering value to our stakeholders our
customers and how are we measuring that
value and it really really talks about
um uh two two categories with four key
value areas that you we we we feel like
um is a good idea to measure right um
the the at the top we've kind of got
market value um that's a obviously
that's key right if we don't have any
market value we're we're we're not going
to be a sustainable business um and the
two sides to that is value we already
have our current value um so that's in
our product and our services and things
that our business does right now and the
other side of that is unrealized value
right what's the value we've got left
sitting in the table markets we haven't
uh uh new markets New Opportunities new
things that we haven't new customers we
haven't got yet um so trying to
understand those two and although
evidence-based management comes with a
set of um I guess you could call them
example metrics in each of these in in
each of the key value areas uh the
reality is that you need to find the
metrics that make the most sense for
your organization within those
contexts I just like to see us having
metrics in each of the key value areas
so we we were talking about market value
so current value and unrealized value um
but there's also our capability as an
organization our ability to actually do
stuff right um so the the the the top
two are about doing doing the right
thing are we moving in the right
direction are we uh focused on filling
those gaps perhaps in our our Market
capability um and then the bottom half
is our organizational capability so that
kind of kind of sits in two key value
areas so it's four total and that's time
to Market which is our how fast we can
go from IDE into Market get stuff in
front of the customers to test our
assumptions right because we assume that
something is going to provide value but
until we actually get it in front of
customers we're not really sure um we
just you know we have an assumption and
and we want to test it um and the other
side is ability to innovate right right
how much time do we spend um delivering
new stuff and what are the things that
impact our ability to spend time
delivering delivering new stuff and I
think those four together if we as a
business have a core understanding of
our current value our unrealized value
our ability to innovate and our time to
Market that gives us a holistic view of
our ability to deliver business value
and then once we've decided on what
those metrics are and we're we're we're
able to monitor our organization and
maybe maybe you only do that quarterly
right uh collecting a this large set of
metrics we're then able to see how the
decisions that we make the changes that
we make to our
organization actually impact on those
metrics that we've decided to to to look
at so that that is what evidence-based
management is we're going to use
evidence to manage our organization
right so this is something that a
manager would use um at the the
depending on you know whatever whatever
you're you're the top of um the pyramid
for right it could be a product it could
be a service it could be a whole
organization a whole company um how are
you measuring these things and how do
you use that data to inform the
decisions that you make an
evidence-based manag agement is just
bringing that story together and saying
yes we have metrics yes uh uh we're
we're looking at them we're monitoring
them in a regular Cadence and we're
making different decisions based on
those metrics and seeing how that shapes
the direction uh that we end up going um
and I that's because this is something
that that so many organizations don't do
you would believe the number of
organizations that I go into and they
have no goals they have no strategy and
they have no way to measure it
um it this this can be a competitive
Advantage right if you able to leverage
empirical uh uh hypothesis driven
database decisions to shape the
direction of your organization to the
market and the market niches that you
are able to
find that that can be the competitive
advantage that you need to be successful
if you want to have a discussion about
your unique needs or situation then
please book a call or visit us at naked
agility tocom uh we also have our
immersive and traditional public classes
on our website and we'd love to hear
from you