one of the great things about immersive
learning is that we
specifically give students the ability
to adapt their mental models it's not
something we force upon them or we can
actually you know you can lead a horse
to order but you can't make it drink
right you have to want to change your
mental models but the new format because
they're doing things in their
organization they're seeing how it works
they're seeing the benefits and the
negatives
they're hopefully able to change their
whole mental model so that they make
different choices in the future and
they're able to assimilate these core
agile practices into the way they do
things