so the the the question is what is a
scrum master
and I think that's really interesting
because I I think of a scrum Master as a
guide
right so so perhaps scrum guide would be
a better name however that's taken by
something else right but they they
they're there to
um they're they're somebody with with
deep
technical understanding of what agile is
the the the the different agile
practices of empiricism of lean I'll
lean agile practitioner right and
they're there to help guide the team so
that they have the knowledge tools and
skills to make the best decisions they
can within the context that they're
making those decisions
so it really helps if the the the the
scrum master has understanding of that
context right I usually think of it as
there's three contexts that this scrum
Master should understand there's the the
business context right because they've
got to help the the product owner
build the right product and they've got
to help the business understand why they
need scrum in the first place like what
does it mean to them he has to be able
to speak their language
um she also needs to
um really understand the technical
domain of what it is the team is doing
right what are they doing why are they
doing it if it's this is if this is a
software context then I would expect
them to understand what devops is how
devops functions why devops what are the
different tools and practices that a
team could be using to help improve the
way they do things because not everybody
knows right that's uh not true and the
other one is organizational change
context so understood standing uh beta
codex understanding taylorism
understanding
um uh follett's work understanding how
we can organize around solving
particular problems so that they can
have those explanations and
conversations with the organization and
with leaders ship and with teams and
people on the ground and people high up
in the clouds right we've got to have
the conversations everywhere in order to
have everybody understand why is it that
we're moving in a particular direction
and I think all of that stuff being
missing is why we're seeing a lot of uh
scrum Masters being let go in
organizations because they're not able
to demonstrate to the organization the
value that they're providing because
they are absolutely essential
to uh to a team in an organization's
ability to deliver
it may be that you you you you work on a
team and you're thinking oh but but we
don't have a scrum master and we're
doing great right you probably have what
I would call a virtual scrum Master
right you've probably got a a Gestalt of
the team understanding within the body
of the people doing the work of the
business of the organization of change
of the product of everything and you're
able to create that idea of a scrum
Master without it being physically
embodied in a person but there are lots
of teams out there who who don't have
that capability and there'll be lots of
teams in your company who don't have
that capability you are in fact unusual
in your ability to have all of that
understanding and knowledge and content
and be able to create that entity of the
virtual entity of the scrum Master most
teams really struggle
so the scrum Master is essential to
helping
um teams
focus on the things that improve their
effectiveness because if a team is more
effective everybody gets more done
everything is better other teams even
focusing on the right things right if
you if you are working with software
teams if you are a software team then
shortening that feedback loop between uh
coming up with an idea and all the
engineering tools you need to get it
into production as quickly as possible
is something that's going to improve
your effectiveness at delivering value
to the to the customer
are you there yet how do you get there
how do you even know that you need to
get there you need the scrum master that
has that knowledge has that
understanding and that knowledge and
understanding is critical to a team
being as effective as possible
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility