agile is not a a a a new thing by any
means what one could absolutely argue
that is a very old thing um that prior
to the Industrial Revolution although
it's not
totally to do with that but prior to the
Industrial Revolution um things were
done in uh small uh H Mom and Pop uh uh
uh shops all over all over the world
right your your local cobbler made your
shoes and your local cobbler understood
fundamentally your needs as an
individual because they knew who you
were they knew who you were they knew
your life story and they created Goods
just for you um and as we kind of kind
of scaled up we lost that human
connection between things and and a lot
of people blame uh uh Frederick Winslow
Taylor right talk about taylorism I do
as well um he he's not strictly at fa it
wasn't his
intent uh uh uh to dehumanize the work
environment it was just the outcome of
of the practices that he pushed and how
they were they were interpreted right um
so agile's a thing that has always been
true for most of human existence that
the way you get stuff done is you figure
it out you don't know how to do
something you go try some stuff and
figure out what works best and what
doesn't and ultimately it's an
evolutionary story because the people in
the world that were able to do things
better perhaps survived and those that
were not able to do it did not those
that adapted to farming and new farm
equipment and were able to to increase
the yield of the crop um they prospered
those that
weren't able to do that or couldn't
figure it out did not right that that's
that's fundamentally how evolutionary
theory and how um humans interacting um
with the world around us if we're
successful we're if if we do well at
something we're successful if we don't
do well we're not so agile's not a new
thing but um even as far back as the
kind of kind of 1900s late 1900s um they
were talking about harnessing the
aspects of of of people the so social
aspects of work in order to maximize the
ability for us to deliver value um and
if you want to go look up some of the
the the theory and stories around that
it's Maryanne fet you want to be looking
up um she was a a contemporary and
perhaps a little bit in opposition of
Frederick winow Taylor at the time um
and her stuff was largely lost by the by
the
1930s but there was really a Resurgence
of this idea right this fundament that's
the thing with good
ideas is they'll keep coming back even
if we forget
them um and in the '90s
XP came along in the software world
because it was it was very obvious that
um it it wasn't working right we
actually weren't able to to successfully
and repeatedly build high quality
valuable products without copious
amounts of waste um we had lots of uh
unhappy people I think Ken wber talks
about it as hateful work right the work
was hateful we we hated the companies we
worked for um we hated the work that we
were doing the managers hated the work
that they were doing it everybody just
hat cuz we were dealing with complexity
and everything would always go wrong
right because we're trying to control it
and when you try and control chaos much
like a lion tamer uh you might you might
get eaten and in fact the likelihood is
that you're going to get eaten at some
point if you keep trying to do it that
way and that happened in in Project
after project after project um when I
started out in the software industry
right when I graduated University and
started out in the software industry um
there was talk of this idea of a project
called a Death March and a death march
project is a project that every single
person on it already understands before
we hard we've hardly started uh the
project and everybody already
understands that is Dead on Arrival
right it's not going anywhere it's not
going to be successful we're not going
to be able to do this it's not going to
cost what they think it's going to cost
it's not going to be done in that time
it's not going to have the features that
they think it's going to have Death
March um but we have to do it anyway cuz
that's what we're paid to do and
somebody bean counter higher up in the
organization has made the decision so
the the the this Resurgence um that kind
of culminated in the 90s with XP right
that was really the the start of the
bigger Resurgence although it had been
been mulling around before that and then
scrum um eventually culminated in the AO
Manifesto in 2001
and the the manifesto
really codified a little bit that's
probably too strong a word but
def how' to describe it I would I would
say it defined the principles right but
that's probably too strong codified the
principles suggested some principles for
a new way of working one that focused on
dealing with complexity and the unknown
with empathy and with connection to
people right bringing that social aspect
that that maryan fet wrote about nearly
100 years 100 years before so um that's
really what the
intention of agile
was however it was kind of predicated
right on
competence the the the the the there was
an assumption
of the inherent craftsmanship and
competence of the
participants that we're we were going to
build on um however the demand
especially like I graduated University
in 2000 first job 2001 is um and the
demand for engineers for product
managers for
leaders um that had the both the
competence and understood some of this
new way new way of working that we were
trying to maximize the value of of what
we're getting far far outstripped the
supply in in the market and really it
still does and part of the reason it
still does is we didn't focus on
competence of who we needed to do the to
do to do to do these things to make
these changes to fundamentally support
them from a from a leadership
perspective from an engineering
perspective from a from a from our goals
and Discovery and what direction we're
going perspective right that's Engineers
product managers and and and
leaders and because we didn't focus on
that level of competence it's largely
starting to fall
apart right um that that that
realization it's like the the the it's
not quite like the dot bubble bursting
that was a money thing this is a
competence thing this is this
is of
the hundreds of thousands of people that
are currently in roles where they're
expected to either uh participate
in
craft or um o over overview oversee
probably oversee is the wrong word right
but but um lead
right the the level the level of of
competence is a tiny percentage of
people in in that in that space right it
it's it's starting to show in
organizations where organizations are
looking
for they're looking
for what are we getting for our money
because we're paying perhaps a lot of
high price salaries for for for for
engineers for product managers for for
leadership um we're not getting we're
not getting the return on investment
that we're expecting and we kind of need
to get the return on investment
otherwise it's not worth spending that
money that's how business functions
right in in in uh in our world so if we
can't justify the cost we're going to
have to get rid of the the the the thing
that's costing us and that that at the
moment is people and it's what it's
looking like is kind of not the
engineers and not the the product
managers um but it's the it's the
leaders it's the the the scrum Masters
the coaches the uh
those those folks that just don't
necessarily have the level of competence
that's demanded to fulfill the role and
be successful I think that's the way I
would describe it to fulfill the role
and be
successful um they maybe had enough to
convince the people that were hiring
them that didn't necessarily understand
what they needed that that's that that's
that they they could do it but as it
turns out they they they couldn't do it
um yeah it's it's
it's systemic at the moment and that's
what we're seeing in the industry
there's a there's a wide wide ranging
General
reset of our understanding of what these
things are um what are the competencies
that are
required and most people are coming up
lacking
um so that's kind of
what we intended to do when we were
originally talking about agile back in
2001 I I just started so I'm uh uh
commenting on what what they were
thinking at the time um but the outcome
has not been that it's been a
commercialized uh watered down lip
service um based based result and that's
where we're at right now