so how
what should a scrum team do
within their first four weeks that's a
really interesting question because if
if they're intent
is to as a team is to try scrum
then what I suggest they do within their
first four weeks is try scrum right the
the the there are all sorts of great
reasons why we shouldn't do some of the
things in scrum there's reasons why we
shouldn't have uh as much Focus as we
would like on the topic right because we
get multiple things that we have to show
progress on there's lots of good reasons
why
um we CA we can't have a single product
owner it has to be multiple people
there's lots of good reasons why
um
we can't have a a single unified backlog
because we're working on too much stuff
and there's a reason why we can't have a
product goal because you know we can't
decide what it is we're working on
and I think all of those are just
excuses for not being able to find Focus
you know commitment right to to to to to
change dare dare to change the way we do
things
in order to try something different and
see if it works for us
so my advice for for teams just starting
out in scrum and is do that right just
do scrum a great
um I have a great set of exercises that
I do with teams I have a scrum startup
exercise that I do happy to share it
with anybody that's that's interested
um and what I basically do is I teach I
teach scrum and then provide the startup
exercise they see what scrum is supposed
to look like again the EPS is great for
that right
um and then have them have the people
that are doing the work that now
understand scrum create organizational
change backlog
right that's something you can do in the
first four weeks if we're going to try
and do scrum do it and write down every
reason you can't
right write down every friction that you
hit write down everything that that
needs to change in your organization in
order to be able to do this thing and
make that list open and transparent to
leadership so that they can see what's
getting in your way because quite often
they can't it's very opaque to them make
it transparent right that's the very
essence of scrum is increasing
transparency so we can see what's going
on and perhaps do something about it
stop moving my advice