and I do that both in the technical
space and in the agile space if you want
to have a chat you can go to my website
and book a coffee and we can talk about
agile we can talk about the things that
are happening in your organization and
if in half an hour I can fix your
problem that's great we've had a coffee
we've had a chat and you get something
to try that might result in success
right I I don't I don't do that for d
direct renumeration I do that because I
like helping people I like other people
being successful I want organizations to
be successful in agile because that
helps all of us all the employees of the
company the entire thing the entire
ecosystem and that's charity