if you want to be able to ensure that
your software performs well and creates
a great user experience you're going to
have to put in a lot of effort in making
that happen it is not going to M you're
not going to magically has have awesome
software with an awesome experience and
F and and fast and responsive without
actually putting in the effort to figure
out how to do that and performance
engineering has a huge impact on user
satisfaction and and the business goals
you're trying to achieve right without a
focus on performance engineering and
this is also shifting left right towards
where the the the the team is doing the
work without without that you're
not you're not going to be able to build
you're not going to be able to build a
product that suits your customers
customers are going to leave because it
doesn't perform well or customers are
going to leave because it doesn't do
what they need it to do or customers are
going to leave because it's it's it's
buggy and doesn't you're not getting
things there fast enough right so
performance engineering where we're
looking at how
quickly users are able to do things and
that some of that some of that could be
user experience based taking steps out
of the process and some of it can be
does the software actually function at
speed does it function at load and while
some of these things can be load and
stress tested um I'm going to quote um
one of my favorite product managers and
Brian Harry who said there's no place
like
production no matter how
much
testing you do prior to production
you're going to have problems that only
exist in production you you can't
simulate real users it's not possible
you can only uh synthetically simulate
users so no matter how much of that
stuff you do you're going to have
problems when you hit production they
can be performance problems they can be
the way people use it problems right the
order that people do things or the
amount they do this particular thing is
different from what we had in the
simulation and that's where you run into
a lot of your your your Major
Performance
problems
My
Philosophy is that we want to get into
production as quickly as possible so
that we can figure out the impact of the
changes that we've made
and
analyze the load and stress test
within the context of real usage real
users using it for real and this is this
is the story of of testing in production
which doesn't mean you're not testing
before production holy moly no don't
ship stuff that's not tested to
production that's a bad idea right but
we need to get into production as
quickly as possible which means we need
to automate and create fast Sleek
automated testing for all of the normal
stuff that we need to test right does
the software actually function the way
we expect it to and then we want a ring
based or audience-based deployment model
so that we can control the exposure of
these new capabilities and features and
we do load and stress testing
effectively in production so what that
might look like I'm going to use an
example because I I I love the way that
they've done this so I I've worked a lot
in the past with the Azure devops team
at Microsoft um as your devops seeing
how they do things has been really
really really enlightening because they
they've got quite a big product it's
quite a big scaling problem they've got
millions of users and what they
effectively do
is they have some some of the rings that
you're deploying to are physical Rings
like
environments but even once you've
deployed a new capability to all of your
production environments let's say you
have
six areas around the world you've
deployed to them all those features that
are deployed might not be accessible by
people right so they're not impacting
production in any way they're off
feature flag is
off but
then they the team that owns that
feature that's deploying that feature
wants to ensure that that feature is
load tested stress tested is the right
and you've also got is the right thing
right is the right thing resonates with
customers provides the right capability
but also works load tested stress tested
and we agreed well I agreed uh that we
can't do load testing and stress testing
very well not in production so what we
need to be able to do is we need to a be
able to limit the number of users that
are accessing this new feature and then
expand it over time so there's various
ways to do that what they would do is
their first ring that they would create
and this is actually a ring for each
feature
so they they're creating an
audience-based deployment model per
feature if it's big enough right you
might have features that you just ship
you might have changes that you just
ship you don't do this with everything
this is expensive right but what they do
is the team will go ah we want to start
getting real users into kicking the
tires on this feature it's just us so
far just internal people so what we're
going to do is we're going to publish a
blog post so they publish a blog post
that says we're working on this new
feature it's it's it's going to provide
this capability here's what it Curr
looks like and if you would like to help
us kick the tires send an email to this
email address and we'll we'll with your
account name and and your your either
org an account or just org or just
account depending on how they're how
they're doing it so you give them the
data of who you are and then they enable
it for you so you can then go in the
tool you would then have a little
feature flag that you can turn on and
off so you can choose to turn it off and
when you turn choose to turn it off when
you choose to turn it off it's you get
asked for a comment and it goes to the
the team right so they can find out why
you don't like it right why you're not
using it it's slow it's this it's that
and then they can go look at the
Telemetry but that's that's a very
private preview right people have to
actively opt in once they have enough
data to say that they think this is a
good feature they think it performs well
at least with the small number of users
once we have enough telemetry they then
open it out and they'll turn it they'll
have it off for everybody that's using
the service but with the feature flag
enabled for everybody so everybody can
go turn it on and they'll do another
blog post that says we're now ready for
more people to try this you don't have
to email us anymore you can just go
switch it on go try it out and tell us
what you think so that encourages a
bunch of people to go turn it on and
then they get a bunch of telemetry for
people using it and either people then
continue to use it or they turn it off
because they don't like it right maybe
it overrides the existing functionality
and they don't like the way it is
because something's missing so they got
to turn it off they're asked what the
problem is they type in I don't like it
because it's slow I don't like it
because there's features missing I don't
like it because I don't like my cheese
being moved whatever the reason is
right and that's they then collecting
more Telemetry and if they get enough
data they maybe go to the next stage or
maybe they need to do more things more
iterations on the the the capabilities
improve the performance maybe they need
to turn it off because it's not
performing well and then they need to do
some performance improvements and then
turn it back on again eventually if
they've got enough Telemetry they'll
turn it on by default for everybody with
the option for people to go in and turn
it off so everybody gets it forcibly
turned
on and then we're collecting data and
Telemetry from the people that turn it
off to find out why they don't like it
why why do they go turn it off what do
we need to do to get those folks on
board once they have enough Telemetry
they see there's not so many people
turning it off there always going to be
people that don't like what you're doing
right so you can't it's not a unanimous
thing they then have it on by default
you can't turn it off right they maybe
disable the option to turn it off see
what complaints roll in for people that
want to be able to turn it off and then
eventually they get rid of the feature
FL and it's on for everybody in
production that's
a modern software engineering
implementation of continuous delivery to
production and then an audience-based
roll out and expansion and testing story
to allow you to do load testing and
performance testing and stress testing
in
production that takes discipline that
takes
effort it's definitely
has a cost right there's a lot of things
that had to happen there and things that
had to be organized and things that had
to be
done but aure
devops using that capability that they
built into the system using that story
they created a massive following from
their users that their users expected
Excellence expected new things expected
those new things to work and and as
those new things rolled out cuz you have
an expectation if you op opt into a
private preview that there might be some
you know things that don't work quite as
well or we don't know yet right so
you're not testing in production with
users that haven't chosen to be part of
that test story right you're soliciting
for people to come in and help you and
because they want to help you one
they're more forgiving and they'll give
more feedback right because they're
choosing to be there and that's how you
create a a story of performance
improvements and enhancing user
experience in a progressive modern
engineering Excellence Manner and this
is something that naked agility can help
you build within your teams build within
your product don't expect it to be
magically overnight these things take
effort they take discipline sometimes
mistakes are made but with uh a focus on
delivering high quality usable working
product continuously to our users we can
build some of the best products you've
ever seen