how will a psm-2 class challenge your
sub assumptions the most I I think
fundamentally people's assumptions about
what they think a scrum Master is what
they think a scrum Master does how they
think a scrum Master guides the team the
number of times that we have to hit on
those myths of of what scrum what what
people think scrum Masters are right I
mean
um let's discover Masters or jira admins
that's a good one
um so realizing they're not a jira admin
they're not there to solve the team's
problems right get Get impediments Out
The Way of the team is apparently the
scrum Master's problem is like oh no
they're they're there to cause the
removal of the impediments
right which which means they probably
don't do the work themselves they're
helping the team do the work themselves
and effectively doing themselves out of
a job right you want to be invisibly
present that's a great phrase that I
love from the from the PSM too is being
invisibly present right
um you're there you provide value
um you help a shape and guide the way
people are organizing around the work
but then if you're off for two weeks
um
the work still happens if you're
away for two weeks the retrospective
still happens the daily scrum still
happens because the people on the team
understand the value that it provides
rather than just being told to do it by
the scrum master and I have to turn up
and be told what to do right
um that for me is the biggest
transition from
um
scrum Master into the advanced scrum
Master world
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility