a really interesting question so
um the question is
is
digital delivery of training of live
training classes
um as effective as in person
and
there's there's really there's the the
SE are just answering the question right
which is no it's not
right I mean that that is ultimately in
in person is higher bandwidth
um and it's more engaging right
but but the other part of the question
is which would you rather participate in
and is it better and I would say yes it
is better and I would rather participate
in a digital delivery than I would in an
in-person delivery and there's a couple
of reasons why
so
I believe
that using techniques pulling in as many
techniques as you can I I use techniques
from Trading from the back of the room
from liberating structures at my own
Creations based on you know mushing
those things together
um using those techniques you can get 90
of the way
to an in-person delivery right
but in the in the digital space you get
some added benefits
um
that I think were only just getting an
idea of how big those benefits are
for me personally one is that I like
teaching training courses where I have
people in the training from all over the
world
I'm I taught a training class uh today I
was teaching an APS today and I had
um one person from the US a bunch of
people a couple of people from Europe
some people from India and somebody from
from Asia from Asia Pacific right APAC
um all in the one class right so you've
got different different accents
different understandings different
interpretations
um different ways of looking at the
world all coming together and
influencing and cross sharing with each
other
right so there's there's more more of
that
I like digital delivery better because
it is more accessible to people
um I'll teach our our training class and
I'll have 10 people
um book from from Africa
right I'll have uh 10 people in the
classroom Africa a couple of people from
Europe a couple people from the US
um and and that's a training class
those folks in Africa might not have
been able to participate if we were
doing it in person because it becomes so
much more expensive
right we've we've when you do it in
person class you've got to have a room
availability you've got to get all the
people
into the one place you've got to fly the
trainer in
and teach the class you can only it only
really makes sense if you do two full
day classes which I don't teach anymore
because I don't think they're as
valuable so you have to do two full day
classes because it's not economically
viable to do four half days and you've
got a trainer on site for four days
right and
it gives that flexibility to the people
in your team because you're able to then
do four half days
so they can take a little bit longer to
absorb the information they can absorb
some information try it in the afternoon
we could do longer times but that seems
to work pretty well as well
um
you don't have to fly people around you
don't have to pay all of those expensive
things
um I I just think it's it's
fundamentally fundamentally better
um
the other thing the next thing that I
think is is hugely valuable is how are
your teams currently working
and that's that's that's my my kind of
that's my mic drop one right is if your
teams are currently working in person
and go to the office every day
and sit five days a week together in the
office and and build products then
absolutely you're going to get bigger
benefits from flying a trainer in having
an in-person class doing it over two
days and everybody's working in the same
way that they currently work
but that's not how
most people in our in in in in my sweet
spot of Industry right which is it and
software teams
they're virtual
they're sitting at home even if they're
even if they're hybrid right and
everybody has to come in two days a week
does everybody on your team pick the
same two days to come in no they don't
right so all the meetings all of the
conversations are all done on teams or
Zoom or whatever platform you've got
they're all online so you have your
teams have to figure out how to engage
online how to collaborate online and how
to discuss and get the most out of
online because even your customers are
not coming on site anymore to talk to
your teams they're wanting a virtual
call right so if we if I teach a
training class over four half days
online
the the students learn not just the
content of the material but the meta
information around how does Martin run a
class online
what are the tools and techniques that
Martin is using to run the class so that
we might be able to use them as well
you know I've heard of this liberating
structures thing but how do I do an
impromptu networking with breakout rooms
in Microsoft teams
well you're going to experience that in
my class and then you can go use that
with your customers so I I think they're
learning more than
um they would do in an in-person class
because they're learning about how to
engage how they work
that's that's my favorite part