Another ghost of Agile
past is burndown charts.
You know, I always, always had
a problem with burndown charts.
There was just something niggling at me
that there was something wrong with them.
Everybody seemed to talk
like they were the holy grail
of monitoring a team.
But when you start thinking
about just-in-time planning,
Just-in-time planning doesn't just extend
to the product backlog,
it also extends to the sprint backlog.
And if we do just-in-time planning,
how could you possibly have a burndown
that reflects the team,
the work that the team's working on.
Think about it. The way a
burndown works is it goes
from top left to bottom right.
It goes from a list of all the stuff
that we need to deliver burns down
towards that trajectory
of we've delivered all the stuff in it.
In order to do that we have
to understand all the stuff
that's going to come
into the sprint backlog at the start.
This is why you see lots
of teams and organizations fixated
on that once you've brought things
into the sprint backlog
you can't change the scope.
Crap, right?
The idea that you can't, that
if you're going to remove something
from the sprint backlog
you have to bring in something
of equal size
and all of that stuff
that is really really just smacks
of traditional project
thinking right we've
got scope we want to maintain
that scope we want to control that scope
so we're gonna have this burndown
that we want to be on this line of that
and it's just just a crap.
The worst way to do burndowns is
if you are burning down hours on tasks.
That's probably the worst form
Because it implies that we've built all
of the tasks with all of the hours
at the beginning of the sprint.
And I don't mean all, right?
There's at least one person
out there is sitting there thinking,
but Martin, we don't plan all
of this stuff, but maybe we
get 90% of the way there.
I'm saying 90% is crap.
I'm saying 70% is crap.
I'm saying 50% is probably
crap, right?
We discover more by doing
than we could by thinking up front.
That's the fundamental
context within which Agile sits.
And anybody that thinks
that they can build products
that don't exist yet
and have a higher than 50% probability
of the things you bring
in being the things you need is,
I don't know what they're smoking
but it would be great
to get some of that stuff.
Because it's just not how the
world works. How the world works.
When we have that high
degree of probability
that things will be different,
low predictability
in what we think's gonna happen
and what actually happens,
we need a different
way to manage the work.
We need to manage the work empirically
and in any empirical process
which Scrum is founded on empiricism, most
of Agile is founded upon empiricism,
in any empirical process you're not going
to know what it's going
to take to do something.
That's the first part.
So if we're thinking
we can create a whole big list
of hours at the start and then burn down
and see that we're on that trajectory,
that's not gonna happen.
So a solution for that
that many teams have tried or many teams
that I've seen have tried
is to do burn down
in story points so instead
of burning down the hours they burn
down the story points
so it's slightly less granular
or go even more less granular
and burn down in stories right so you get
that more jagged line rather
than a smooth line but the real and
that's a little bit better at least
if we're 50% way through the sprint
and we're 50% delivered value
that's probably the best
that the burndown is going to
get right in in that world where
we've brought 10 things into the sprint
and we're gonna deliver 10 things
if we're halfway through the sprint
and we've delivered five
of them things are going good
if we're halfway through the sprint
and we've delivered three
of them, things are not going good,
right?
That's probably, there's a
lot of assumptions in there
that things are of similar size,
there's all kinds of assumptions in there,
but that's probably the best
of that world.
But the reality is that all
of those are predicated on the idea
that you've decided what
that thing is up front.
You've decided how many
of those things you're going
to bring in up front.
And whether it's hours
or story points or stories,
that's not how it works.
Most teams have a higher
degree of volatility.
They're not just thinking about the value
that they're delivering in the sprint,
their sprint goal.
They're also thinking
about how much technical debt
do we have to pay off?
How much refactoring
do we maybe have to do
as we're building this product.
They're thinking about that,
those little bugs that keep,
you know, that steady stream
of small, inconsequential
but valuable defects
that keep coming through the system
you don't want them building
up so you've got to take some of them on
and responding to the business
and the business needs something
and be able to respond to it
or production issues
or there's too many ors the reality
is you are much better focusing
on the flow of value
through your system and maintaining
a steady consistent flow as much
as you can within the bounds of the work
that you're doing, than
on trying to meet some arbitrary
top left to bottom right graph, burn down.
That's just ridiculous,
and it is one of the ghosts of Agile past.
If you are being haunted
by these ghosts of agile past,
we can help you exercise them
or find a coach, consultant,
or trainer who can.
Don't let these phantoms undermine
the effectiveness of your value delivery.
The longer they linger,
the more they'll haunt
your team's progress.
Send me an email to martin
at nkdagility.com
and we will help you get to
the bottom of it.
If you want to have a discussion
about your unique needs or situation,
then please book a call or visit us
at nakedagility.com We also have
our immersive and
traditional public classes on
our website and we'd
love to hear from you.