the flexibility that you gain by being
able to move things around ad hoc I I
can move this one team from here to here
I can move this one project from here to
here I can merge projects I can split
projects um that overrides in most cases
if you need it um the inflexibility on
how the data is formed right that that
that it's not quite as high fidelity as
as as some folks would like that they're
able to do it when they before is is is
is enough so I think I think flexibility
SL inflexibility depends on it's going
to be based on what it is that you're
trying to achieve what's the outcome
that you're doing um what's your goal
and and figuring out which is the best
method within that context um and doing
the best we can within that context