foreign
if you could teach just one thing about
scrum
what would it be
I think it wouldn't be scrum at all that
would be the first principles right it
would be empiricism and complexity
that's that's what I would teach and in
fact that's probably what I spend the
majority of my time in the EPS in
um when I'm just talking to people
um engaging with leadership that's what
I spend the majority of my time talking
about is empiricism and complexity
and
if you have those fundamental ideas of
empiricism and complexity of the the the
understanding the realization
that
no matter what
way you choose to do stuff it might not
always work it might have different
outcomes depending on the current
circumstances the prevailing wind right
then
um you realize why
people realize why things don't always
work out for them they realize why
things are different they realize why
things are difficult they realize why
you you don't always get a successful
Sprint no matter how hard you try you
realize why you can't normalize
normalize your your your your number of
story points delivered per Sprint you
realize why story points becomes
ultimately been effective right
um beyond the team you realize
why for a lot of those things you people
and teams can take those ideas and run
with them themselves
and I I don't believe that that scrum
should be forced upon teams I think they
should choose themselves how they work
and if they want to take and use
principles of scrum then then I'm here
to help them
um but if you want to use other stuff
I'll help them with that too
but they should be making those choices
with a clear and concise understanding
of complexity and empiricism so that
they can ultimately make more of the
right choices and less of the wrong ones
and I think that's hard and I think
that's that's missing in a lot of the
I don't know a better word than
boilerplate
teachings of
um you know the the the the mechanisms
in scrum doing mechanical scrum is is
not useful at all people have to
understand why each of those things in
scrum is in place why it provides them
with value why taking it away what's the
result of taking it away what what
happens what what doesn't happen
um and why we want to keep those things
I think that's so important
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility