one of the seven deadly sins of agile
it's sloth and this manifests in a
number of number of different ways with
with teams with
organizations uh with leadership all
over the place um one of the most common
um elements is just not bothering our
bothering our ARS actually doing the
things
um that that that we say we're going to
do right we say we're doing agile but we
don't deliver working product at the end
of the Sprint we say we're doing agile
um but we have long convoluted
deployment processes which are not in
control of the developers we say we're
doing agile um but we don't have an
ordered backlog right all of these
things
are places where we say we're doing
something but really we're just kind of
lazy and ly through our teeth in order
to not have to do the work perhaps it's
because somebody in leadership in the
organization has decided that thou shalt
do Agile and your product is not
particularly suited to that model
because it was built in a in a
traditional maybe it's got Mainframe and
all kinds of crazy stuff in there maybe
there are other reasons why it's not
viable within the the the confines the
structure of of of your organization the
system that you're in um but I would
much rather teams and people were honest
and
transparent with their companies and
their organizations about what they they
can and cannot do what isn't is not
agile and