from Masters love asynchronous
communication
um asynchronous communication is
something that has been become more
popular uh since lockdown right we're
able to collaborate with people in a
much more Dynamic manner we don't have
to wait for people to reply we don't
have to all be in the same place at the
same time all the time we can have these
back and forth communicate with people
engage with them on a constant basis and
it provides a much more uh uh compelling
way to facilitate communication without
imposing too much on people's time
because everybody's trying to get work
done as well and they can reply as
needed
asynchronous communication