empiricism is an interesting uh Beast
ultimately empiricism is this idea
um that all knowledge comes from
observable data right that's that's
Science is based on empiricism and it's
been adopted into the agile way of
working and many other ways of working
in business that really you should have
access to all of the data you should
make deliberate actions that you think
will affect the data and then you
monitor the data to see whether those
outcomes have actually come to pass and
then you repeat that experiment a bunch
of times and if you are able to repeat
it and successfully get the same outcome
then it's probably a thing that you
should be doing otherwise it might just
be something that worked that way for
one time