when we're building products um there
are are
are really two main parts of of the
consideration that we have we need to
think about product management and we
need to think about product development
so product management is deciding what
we're going to go build right um product
development is figuring out how we're
going to go do that and they need to be
able to complement each other in a way
that we're working together
towards a successful working product but
product management leads the product
development the product management sets
the direction the strategy the the goals
that we're trying to
achieve um the high level goals
strategic goals and product development
focuses on the actual delivery of those
goals and delivery of those outcomes now
that doesn't mean that there's no
product management in product
development or there's no product
development in product management
there's there's definitely a a bleed
over between those two um two topics
they're not they're not a distinct thing
that somebody hands over from here to
here right um they're they're an
integrated story and I think a good
analogy for that is the evidence-based
management story that helps at least it
helps me
think about not only how they interact
with each other um but how they
complement each other and how they need
each other right product management and
product development in order to to be
successful and working together to be
successful so the way evidence-based
management breaks this down is is um
you've
got two sets of metrics at the at the
top of the diagram which is Market
talking about market value so in the
context of market value that's where
we're talking about product management
we're focusing on two things we've got
our current value in our product um the
stuff that's there that um maybe we need
to maintain maybe we need to remove
maybe we need to augment in some way
right that's the the features and
capability that we have in our product
right now and all of those features and
capability in our product night right
now should all work right that working
usable product we have increments that
work and our current increment our
current product is our current value
right that's what we've currently got
that's part of our market value um if
you're if you're not in a consumer
facing world then um think about your
your the market that you deliver to is
inside of your business it's not
necessarily doesn't have to be outside
of your business doesn't have to be a
commercial Market it could be an
internal Market inside your business
right um and then the other side of that
is the unrealized value and that's where
I think
a lot of product management maybe
doesn't Focus but should focus is in
this unrealized value area which is the
stuff that our product could do that it
doesn't do yet right the net new
functionality that we want to bring in
um the net new functionality that we
want to bring into the story so that um
is going after new markets new users um
new
we want more people to be using our
product than we're using it before
because you're always going to have a a
decline in the people that use your
product um if the features remain
stagnant right even if you add uh new
capabilities to an existing feature
there's there's still that uh um tail
off that we're keeping our existing user
base happy and our existing user base um
is always going to juice over time if we
don't do anything right we might still
be bringing in new customers but the
existing people are going to going to
going to tail off that's how I I I think
about it I think about it a lot like um
Netflix uh creating new content right if
you if you have a an existing show um
the viewership for that show is going to
decline over time right it's not new
anymore people that have watched it are
not necessarily going to watch it again
although some people do and it's going
to decline over time that's a little bit
more drastic than a than a product that
people use in a business right but the
idea is that you're not you're not
gaining a lot of new customers and when
you to do when you do a second season of
an existing season you know the
viewership is going to be less in the
second season it's always less but does
it maintain high enough for you to
justify the investment right what we
really want to be doing is focusing as
much as we can while supporting and
maintaining our existing investment in
our in our product in our story in our
existing customers we also want to be
aggressively going after new markets and
new customers that's that's product
management leading right where are we
going what are we trying to achieve
what's our Direction what's our strategy
for for building a a more valuable
product right value creation we're
creating more value that's that
unrealized value and those two together
um unrealized value and current value is
that agile product management um story
that leads to market value right that's
what we're measuring market value
and the the activity is product
management but then we've got the the
the product development which is
supporting that story um and product
development is our organization's
capability right that's our ability to
deliver the things that we identify that
need to be delivered and perhaps input
to those things as well right provide
part part of the feedback cycle that's
what I mean by the bleed over right uh
product development is going to have
good ideas too that we might want to
implement um but that's broken into two
sets of sets of metrics in in in product
development one is uh ability to
innovate right that's our how much time
can we spend on net new versus
maintaining and supporting existence
right so that's how we're measuring that
amount of time that we spend on net new
and then the other side of that um to to
balance it off is time to Market how um
quickly can we go from an idea to
getting in into production so ability to
innovate and time to Market both talk
about product quality talk about
engineering Excellence um talk about
those stories that's our our agile
product development product development
is about building high quality usable
working products that are of value to
somebody right that's product that's
just product development agile product
development um is just the newer
practices in that in that story um so
we've got this uh product management
leading looking at the market looking at
the Futures looking at it um what
customers are going to need in the
future what our stakeholders are going
to need in the future and trying to
anticipate those needs by running lots
of little experiments some of those
experiments will be implemented uh by
product development right so we can then
get the results uh but
ultimately delivering usable working
product enables us to to to maximize
that value return because we're closing
those feedback looks so we've got
product management leading with Str stry
and Direction and vision right Vision uh
value and validation is is is product
Management's focus and then in
order to get that value and validation
we need to actually build something we
need to actually create something that
we can then put in front of our our our
our our users our stakeholders to then
gather feedback and actually uh see
whether is it actually valuable are they
actually using it the way we expect is
it actually changing the number the way
we would like and that's how agile
product management leads but is
supported by product development and
product development supports that story
of uh uh collecting that data that
Telemetry that um additional information
that product management can use to
figure out whether are we actually going
in the right direction do we need to
stay the course do we need to Pivot or
do we need to stop