how important is devops in the
continuous delivery of value to
customers well it's it's imperative
that devops
is
exactly the same thing as agile but from
a different perspective
so the agile piece uh looking at how we
work together
and comes out of that view of the the
looking at the people and how the people
are working together right
um the devops side is coming from the
perspective of
well we've got all these cool ideas how
do we actually get them over here to the
customer right how do we take the idea
and actually deliver it and they're
they're kind of part of the same
capability that we're trying to achieve
you you'll find people out there talking
about devops and agile is part of that
story and you'll find other people out
there talking about agile and devops as
part of that story right
um and I feel like they're all talking
about the same thing that any argument
between that is irrelevant and devops is
intrinsic uh to to to Agile it's the
implementation of the same practices
that we're talking about empiricism and
shortening feedback loops right
um in the technical space
um devops has become more than that
right and that's where you get that if
you had a Venn diagram devops and AD
you'll have this massive overlap
um so
I think it is absolutely
um imperative for teams to focus on
devops practices focus on that lean
delivery of usable working value
continuously to their customers
so that they can get the feedback that
they need to feed into the other
processes as well to help us build the
best product we possibly can for our
customers because really without getting
our working product in front of our
customers we're not we're not we're not
going to get there we're not mitigating
any risk we're not testing our
hypothesis right that we're well this is
valuable yeah okay but is it is it
actually valuable to the customer you
have to get in front of them so those
those for me those devops and agile
practices work uh intertwined together
are effectively indistinguishable from
each other
um and both need to be there obviously
if you're not working in software right
devops is not the bit you you that
snuggles in there
um for delivery
um but if you're working in the software
world devops is that those techniques
that snuggle in uh along with your agile
to get that product into into production