so I guess I guess the number one tip
for Effective Sprint planning is make
sure everybody on your team
already understands
what's in the product backlog what's
likely
to be brought into the Sprint as much as
possible right there's all I put a lot
of caveats in there I did put a lot of
caveats in there did it deliberately
because again there could be surprises
there could be things you don't know
that you discovered during Sprint
planning
there could be all sorts of reasons why
you have to deviate from the happy path
but the happy path is uh that number one
thing for making you as effective as
possible is as much as as possible the
entire team should understand
the things that are in the product
backlog before they bring them into the
Sprint that would be my number one tip
for Sprint planning if I was to bring in
a number two tip which I'm gonna
uh then it would be that that have a
clear well understood product goal as
well
right what what is the context within
which we're making decisions that's
really the purpose of the product goal
right
um we're making making holistic
decisions during Sprint planning about
what direction we're going to take the
product in next
right and a clear understanding of the
product goal is key key to that
understanding uh it's key to being able
to effectively or make those choices as
effective as possible how do we make
more of the right choices less of the
wrong ones we need more understanding we
need more uh uh uh visibility and
transparency of the Strategic direction
of the product uh the current tactical
direction of the product
um or intermediate strategic Direction
which is the product goal but also
that's how we craft the Sprint goal
which is the next tactical thing we're
doing in order to reach our intermediate
strategic goal
um so having that that clear and make it
as transparent everybody on the team
needs to understand it product owner
needs to understand it
um and its impact stakeholders need to
understand it as well right otherwise
you're going to get to the end of the
Sprint and you're gonna have unhappy
stakeholders because you went in the
direction that they didn't
didn't think you were going or didn't
understand you were going right
don't do that
um and if so yeah well uh if teams don't
or aren't able to
um
to do those two things uh they're pretty
they're pretty much
screwed you're not gonna build great
products right unless you actually
understand where you're going I I think
look everybody should be should should
look up team
in the dictionary everybody should have
to look up team in the dictionary right
it means a group of people working
together towards a common goal if
there's no common goal there is no team
if you have a a list if your Sprint goal
is a list of things you're not a team
you're just a group of people who pick
some stuff and happen to discuss it
together that's not a team you're not
working together towards a common goal
um so make sure that you you you have
Sprint goals
you have product goals and that they're
not just lists of things
right and make sure you have it at least
for Sprint planning
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility