naked agility is available for DevOps
and agile training and consultant
contact us for a free consultation
hello welcome to my stream this is
episode six and I'm here with a
gentleman called russell miller
who i have known or an incredibly much
longer than you would think a long time
russell wouldn't you introduce yourself
hi I'm Russell Miller I live in Atlanta
Georgia USA I'm a product development
specialist and scrum dad or a
professional trainer cool and we spent a
little bit of time working together this
week we facilitated a virtual live
virtual classroom on Monday Tuesday of
the professional agile leadership labor
is anything you want to say about the
course itself of course is geared toward
those who want to see agility grow and
thrive in their organizations and want
to know how leaders can positively or
sometimes negatively influence that yeah
for me the courses are trying to move
people from the ideas of management of
people to leading people so you're no
longer really managing people anymore
you're creating environments within
which people can thrive yes and we're
also disciplines that those things
aren't needed once you move to more
agile ways of working because they are
very much needed they are very much
needed organizations have definitely
functioning without somebody if we're
focused on delivering value in a product
it's difficult to spend the time that
you need on making changes to the way we
deliver that product the way we interact
with people and you need somebody with
that dedicated focus yes oh so we had we
had a good time we had sick
students so we broke them into two teams
and the course is very exercise driven
so we kind of went back and forth what
do you think kind of worked well in the
class fear I think that the students had
the ability to give communicate their
own experiences especially in their
group but also in the larger in the
larger group and it's good to be able to
express some of your thoughts because
that's actually a bit of a learning
exercise you know you when you express
your thoughts you have to formulate them
and helps you really more with a greater
focus examine your own experiences and
then you can get feedback on those
experiences so that was that was good
for the students when we do have a
smaller class size of SIG's you can get
a lot of your specific questions
answered so that was a big positive for
this I mean we'd love to have you know
20 people or tween and you know give our
agile goodness to as many people as
possible but for this for the students
who attended with a smaller class size
that was really beneficial for them I
thought it was super great - since we're
relatively new in the world of live
virtual training scrum board
it's good for the students to be able to
join quickly from the comfort of their
own home or office those are a highlight
of some of the pieces yes there's a
little bit of a delay that's why I was
waiting there I was waiting for for your
voice to finish so we um we spent quite
a lot of time working together in the
class as well as having since we were
working in two teams we had two trainers
so a trainer could go with each team and
make sure that they didn't fell feel
left out and alone and I think that is
the the difficulty with live virtual
classrooms the
students don't feel the love from the
trainer and have difficulty getting
getting attention on the upside to that
because of the electronic means students
can can summon the trainer to their to
their breakout area regardless of which
tool you're using all the tools have the
ability must al most of the tools that
we're using him I'm sorry all other
tools that we're using have the ability
to to summon the instructor or one of
the instructors to the small group and
so that's a bit of a positive because in
a larger classroom setting the students
may be inhibited to you know to ask for
help they may look up and see the
instructor talking to somebody else but
through the electronic means since
there's only one way to summon the
instructor I think people are less
inhibited when they want some some
attention to ask for it so it's a bit of
a it works both ways and both in the
negative end I see it more as a positive
we just tell people if you need help
here's the way you can help and don't be
bashful
so it's quite a lot of delay in the
audio that was my wait there between for
some reason it's the video is in sync
but the audio wasn't which seems a
little bit weird to me usually it's the
other way around but that's the way the
cookie crumbles sometimes so I'll speak
in sure I really I really enjoyed that
aspect of making sure that the the
students had somebody to talk to and
it's difficult with the the facilitating
the exercises and I think that one of
the things that that were was very
difficult for me and was getting
attention back from the breakout rooms
from the exercises you find that as well
that was the challenge we have a blinker
that says come back but hurting the cats
isn't always as easy as is in a live
classroom in a live in-person classroom
yes exactly
I think it's a bit a neat is that
five-second Billy something like that
it's a super fun so um I am just working
around it as we are in need to do and so
I think definitely having the two
facilitators for the exercises is going
to be much better I'm actually teaching
private PSF for 20 people with four
teams on Monday
which is going to be interesting I've
managed to organize a couple of extra
trainers but we'll see how that goes
with two people in the room but
something that I think did work well um
was we were using Microsoft teams as our
technical environment for for running
the the event and we were able to very
easily create team-based breakout
and have a call continuously running in
that breakout room and then easily
switch between those two things I was
shocked
hell I expected it to be a hurdle and it
wasn't yep III thought teams worked very
well with that better than I was
expecting
being able to switch between things um I
know that I had a lot of problems with
neural and I think you you didn't you
had everything was super snappy and fast
yeah zero zero zero problems so and what
what I did find
after some significant googling after
the event was that this I have a surface
book one and surface book one has a
performance problem if you have a attach
a second monitor there is also 60 Hertz
so I've actually moved my 60 Hertz
monitor off to another machine and I'm
using much cheaper not very good monitor
but that I can set to 50 Hertz and I'm
not having the same performance problems
on my machine that I was having with
with that I'm gonna try and upgrade my
machine at some point but it's difficult
to do in lockdown because there's
nothing left the whole world is buying
electronics yes and I found that am i
gay webcams impossible to get I managed
to get my microphone upgrade I got a a
te X microphone which was fine and I got
a stream down
or manipulating the the inter inter
swimmy webs but ya know webcams and it
can be difficult to get some of the
other other pcs and I think even my my
microphones I can't get I wouldn't be
all to get another one if I wanted in my
life pays to be prepared
at least we have sound and a consistent
internet connection this time last time
we did this we tried to do it on Tuesday
or was it Wednesday it was Tuesday and
it was a complete cluster with internet
not being very good I think we left it a
little bit late and we had Netflix
traffic in Europe but it was still the
problem I need to work on why my Skype
over here which the system is not
particularly taxed 60% usage which is
not too bad but we'll need to only to
see overtime if I can if I can fix that
and repair it for these types of chats
are there any other things and feel free
to talk for a little bit longer because
we have a seven or eight second delete
anyway so may as well talk about that
longer and then I can just wait tree
what what saw any other things that you
felt you wanted to add to the experience
during this well a couple of things that
I think people should should should bear
in mind if they're thinking about either
delivering live virtual training because
we have a lot of the world that we live
in and the product development space
especially software probably development
space requires some specialized skills
and specialized training and so there
are a lot of trainers in the world that
are trying to learn how to deliver their
great training content virtually and
then there are students who are trying
to up their skills especially those who
have been economically impacted by by
the worldwide economic impact those
people are you know some of those find
themselves suddenly furloughed or laid
off or downsized and people are trying
to up their skills and they're looking
at their backlog of training and so a
couple things I think are worthy of
consideration that after having
delivered several of these are more more
at the forefront of my mind than ever
um students that travel to my in-person
classes if they travel from outside the
city in which I'm delivering those
people incur often airfare costs lodging
costs or their employers and meal cost
and those are zero for live virtual
training I think that's a big big deal
I've had people travel as I view I mean
on multiple occasions I mean a lot of
vacations people travel internationally
even to attend courses that I'm
delivering and not only do you not
expend the resources the financial
resources to make the travel trip but
you don't have the long time that you
have to it's not really a waste because
you're getting training at the end of it
but but it's you would like to be able
to have a transporter and just go from
wherever you are to the training locale
and not spend 4 6 8 10 12 hours travel
maybe even you know one-way sometimes so
that's a huge advantage and you don't
spend that travel time away from your
loved ones or family or exercise routine
or favorite pastime so these are not
insignificant advantages and some of the
training that we're doing live now and
we you know we don't know what the
future holds but it may not be the same
say maybe some ways may be better but
some of the training that's now offered
virtually once we go back to the the old
old way of working you might not be able
to get it virtually so you might
consider it's much you know if you need
some training and have the resources and
the time then you might want to get I'm
serious you might want to get some of it
now because you don't have to incur the
expense and effort to travel to a
location so it's my sincere belief
Martin
I totally agree and I have I it's
sometimes a little bit different
training in the US than it is training
in some other parts of the world just
because I think I trained in 32
different countries over the last 10
years
I'm usually about 12 countries a year on
average and that means 12 different
languages 12 different cultures although
I know the culture for example between
Atlanta where you are and Seattle is
very different as well but at least
there's less of a language barrier
everybody supposed to speak English and
usually it's bad English but ok that's
generally an American thing
but aha yeah um but I found that that
when you're dealing with radically
different cultures like I could be
teaching one week in Saudi Arabia
another week in the Netherlands another
week in Norway and people's attitude and
outlook and the thing the way they react
to things can be very different as well
even things are an interesting one and
that I've mentioned information in my
class II sometimes that when I'm in
Norway we have an expression in English
where you might say you don't want to
look like you've got egg on your face
and I think that translates to American
as well that's a common phrase but that
doesn't necessarily translate to Norway
to Denmark to Sweden to Saudi Arabia
while Saudi Arabians they're British
anyway that was a British colony it
seems to have but that's saying but for
example in Norway it's it's you don't
want to look like you've caught your
beard in the mailbox which so who knew
and another one is everybody's on the
same page which is a common English
expression in the Netherlands it's
everybody's noses are pointed in the
same direction so you kind of have to
learn a lot of debt do you have to learn
a lot of different is it idioms I think
that might be the right word yes
they're different videos that people
talk about things in different countries
and what it means because words can make
a big difference to how thank you how
you interpret the the material that
we're presenting and even though a lot
of the work that happens inside of the
class is interactions between the
students rather than just interactions
between the like a one-way communication
between the trainer and the students I
think there's still a lot of things that
we need to take care of in in that
setting I guess my question for you
would be how you we had a in our class
we had two Germans one two from Slovakia
it's the back here I think no we're
split and well it's not Slovakia I've
got my countries mixed up as I am apt to
do and my brain has died but we had two
from Eastern Europe - from Germany one
from Leeds in the UK which is kind of
middle England and one from London but
who wasn't from anywhere near London
just just worked there how did you find
that different group of people I found
that that particular mix of students
worked well and you you you touched on
or circled around something I think is a
bit of an advantage to the training
whether it be live or sorry live and in
person or live and virtual is that you
get to expand a little bit of your
cultural horizons and I don't mean just
for the entertainment value I mean it
causes you to reconsider some of your
outlook and your the way you approach
situations if you're if you're
constantly and people from your own
culture then you don't really have the
same reason to to examine your own
stance and your own perspective but when
you when I find fun I find that I'm
around people from other cultures I'm
more conscious of what I'm thinking I'm
more conscious of my idioms and I'm more
conscious to the way that I look at the
person you know artists are those who
have art training realize that you have
a you might have a still life but there
are multiple perspectives from which you
can draw or sketch or paint that's still
life and so I find that when students
are or people professionals are immersed
in their own culture they don't have the
same reason to take a different
perspective and that's one of the things
that when I teach people about the scrum
master role if I could segue just a
moment is that one of the things that I
try to get students to understand about
the scrum master role is that it's not
only about the specific accountabilities
of the scrum master role but we need
someone that has a different perspective
like you suggested that the people doing
the work need the perspective of someone
in a different position in the
organization looking down not down but
up at the work from a different point of
view and that's one of the powers of the
scrum master role is because that person
often has different daily activities
than some of the people that are on the
development team creating the increment
that that difference of perspective
provides a lot of valuable information
that often scrum teams don't appreciate
they don't understand why oh well you
need it the scrum master
to do this or this or this well yeah he
or she does but here she also needs to
have a perspective that's that's
different focusing on different things
in their minds and so I think that's a
powerful thing that students who attend
to class with multiple cultures
represent get a little bit of a benefit
from learn I totally agree and that I
taught classes in Africa in Middle
Eastern Eastern Europe UK and us as well
and I even talked I manic I awesome
class I might as a teach a class in can
couldn't you kinda can't get better than
that that was good
and I think that we're I think it's
going to be difficult to put the the
training Jeannie online training genie
back in the bottle and the feedback from
many of the the students is that while
they might prefer an in-person
experience from students that have gone
through both an in-person class and an
online class because of the quality that
is required by scrum the darg and the
pursuit of that quality by the trainers
the the the students are not seeing a
discernible quality decrease from the
interactions but again absolutely we
were worried that the the the quality of
training that you could deliver remotely
would be substantially less but I think
the the ideas behind that are behind
that notion that it would be sustained
alas I come from maybe five five or more
years ago where some of the technologies
that are available to us like mural
which we were using in the class was was
not as mature not as able to provide
that experience for students the video
conferencing technology necessarily
wasn't I mean it was there but it
potentially wasn't as good as it is that
no I mean it's this in most cases apart
from obviously our problem with Skype
here and delije it's it's generally
generally flawless you made the comment
that during the class you felt like some
of the students we're in the same room
as you because of the the quality of the
video that they were able to push you
bring up a good point Martin students
are not only learning about scrum and
agile leadership and in our professional
scrum master courses and product
ownership and using scrum and user
experience design approaches but they're
also learning about some very modern
very very modern technologies for remote
work and for people who you know work
two days a week or three days a week
from home these technologies that we're
using so it's a bit of a I'm going to go
off and get some leadership training but
I'm also going to go off and and for a
bonus I'm going to get some experience
and training using electronic recording
tools and learning how to break a larger
team out into multiple groups so so
you're getting I always want to look at
the value that we're delivering to
students and that's a value that again
before I began delivering this training
I wasn't really perceiving that as a
value I was more focused on trying to
maintain the quality of the experience
and and now I'm realizing that there's
some some bonuses that students are
getting
that I had originally thought about I'm
still trying to fix that delete but I
will see you have it I can't get it and
I think to to go but I yes I agree and I
think I also agree with what you said
before about the the this is a good time
for people to think about live virtual
training I know that the the number of
people now unemployed in the US is
incredibly high part of that is the
system within which your economy
operates and in the UK there's more
people who are our load then then made
unemployed and part of the furlough
rules in the UK are that you can receive
training while you're on furlough and
your company can pay for it and that's
the one thing that you're allowed to do
so it's even a government recommendation
that you do or put people on training
that are furloughed to just keep keep
people doing stuff keep people learning
and figuring out what's what's what's
next and I think things like like the
agile leadership is good for that that
cater of middle management that maybe
feel like they have difficulty in
justifying their existence maybe more so
at this time when the teams are all off
doing something separately and you just
end up in meetings all day and I think
that that I don't know I just think that
there's this space for for people to
learn a lot a lot more during this time
not that they have to
yeah you bring up a good point Martin
one of the powers of the agile
leadership training the the major upside
to that agile leadership training is you
got two or three things going on in
organizations that are moving to more
agile ways of solution or product or
service development and one of the
things that the teams are beginning to
get a taste of what we call self
organization in other words getting to
use more of their influence because
they're closer to the work and so when
teams began to to get a taste of that
then they have some newfound needs some
some needs that they didn't have before
and so teaching leaders how what those
needs are and and a little bit about how
to meet those needs is powerful but in
addition the teams themselves sometimes
fail to appreciate if I can be blunt the
contribution that that managers at
various levels sometimes crowd
appreciate that the contribution that
managers at different levels in the
organization have have to contribution
they have to offer or contribution they
have to make and so we want to teach
both of those things we want to say look
you have to a leader to a person in a
management level in the organization you
have some new responsibilities that
there's some care and feeding that these
teams and individuals need that that's
different but also there's an
opportunity there to to also try to
communicate back to the larger
organization not only their needs but
also the the upside of okay great they
have these needs and we want to meet
those needs but what is the goodness and
the upside what's coming out of these
teams like the identification of
organizational impediments for example
that that and the the view now that
scrum masters have across the
organization of I say some synergies and
also some some impediments and how do we
get that goodness out you know that
information that rich flow of
information that we the teams are
getting now that maybe they didn't have
before how are we how do we
read that across the organization so we
talk about communities of practice for
engineering practitioners and and
designers and scrum masters and product
owners but we really we really the same
concept of sharing of information needs
to happen at the in the middle
management layers and so that's an
opportunity as well agreed and I think
that and it's also the the nope
I was practicing active listening and
the thing that I thought I was going to
say is now it's now gone there are there
are a lot of teams in organizations now
that are being forced to work remotely
when they would have preferred to work
co-located and I think not that word
co-located is very important here
because it's really it's really just a
metaphor for people working closely
together it's it's trying to say that if
you're in the same building but on
different floors then that's not good
for you being able to work together
effectively and I think online on
technology modern technology can kind of
allow us to have a level of colocation
as long as everybody in the team that's
communicating digitally is in the same
time zone that we're may be able to to
to practice some of those colocation
skills from this perspective because
there are a lot of people who work from
home as well there are a lot of people
who don't want to live in the big city
don't want to commute into work I don't
know what it's like in cities in the US
but London commutes can be three hours
plus to get from your home to wherever
your offices and people do that because
they have to not because they should be
doing that yes and people don't have to
be in the same exact time zone but I
think it's when you haven't you know six
hour time shift or greater or maybe five
that you begin running into the
challenge just especially if you have an
even larger time shift so I'm liking the
idea of having a select number of people
in a video team meeting when working
remotely maybe they're on mute maybe
they're sometimes on mute but having a
small group or even with some of the
technologies you can have an even a
larger group and what research has found
is that a line of sight is a is a lack
of line of sight is a barrier for
communication so in some ways depending
on how you set your groups up you can
actually have improved line-of-sight
over in person work yeah I think I think
Microsoft did a study that with the
judicious use of modern technology that
you can get and higher levels of
communication and colocation bonuses for
for teams that are working together and
they were using ridiculous levels of
Technology because they can and they
have lots of money to figure it out and
and and do that but for most of us
there's the the tools like Skype and
zoom when they get the security problems
fixed and teams and I don't know WebEx
and whatever else you want
to use there's a plethora of choices out
there that can help us get closer
together while we're far away one that
I'd noticed the families are using
something called house party which
allows you to see when people people
mark themselves at home
ie I'm open for for a chat and you can
you can just have a room with many
people having a chat talking about stuff
and it handles the multiple people
talking at once problem very well
whereas other tools are not so concerned
with that because you want one person
talking at once they handle that a room
as a party and you can kind of drop in
and out of different channels and groups
very very quickly I think it's only on
the the the thorn but it seemed to work
at work pretty well and I think there's
going to be a lot more apps sitting that
space
I actually I have I have M because I
used to live in the u.s. I lived in
Seattle for three years I started using
Amazon for for books and audible books
and stuff and super super early on at
that time because I couldn't take all of
my physical media across the ocean with
me so I've ended up with all of my
accounts or US based which poses some
problems for example I have to buy my
xbox in the living room runs off our
proxy effectively a proxy so that it
thinks it's in the US so I are you
legitimately in order to buy us stuff
you have to have a US credit card which
I have you have to have a u.s. address
which I have so it's it's perfectly
legitimate I just can't get access to
that content because I travel so much
and actually if you think about it
apart from now I was spending 300 days a
year travelling regardless of where I
physically lived my my my time was spent
in in hotel rooms so I think that the
and the thing that I noticed was I have
I have some channels on Amazon that have
advertising and it's all American
advertising which is something laughable
you you can't have the the funniest
thing my wife and I talk about it all
the time when the adverts come on is
American drug adverts and and when they
talk about all of the crap at the end
that is going to basically kill you or
deform you in some way we're sitting
there thinking there's no way we would
ever take any drug advertise in the news
but and there are now a lot of adverts
about social distancing about companies
providing services and new either new
companies or existing companies
providing services around that and
that's the ability to take advantage of
opportunities when they arise is kind of
the whole purpose of this thing we're
trying to do in the first place yeah I
am another thing that if I could just
segue a bit to suggest is that there are
some downsides not downsides some some
things students should know if they're
considering online training and the
camera in your laptop will will work if
you have a better camera by all means
use it it's not required to have a
better camera than the one in your
laptop if you have a second monitor and
and do intend to take some live virtual
training then by all means have the
second monitor hooked up because it does
add a lot to the experience if you don't
have a second monitor it
not a insurmountable barrier by any
means there there is technology that
will allow you to use your tablet or you
know iPad or Android tablet as a second
display so if you don't aren't already
using that and don't have a second
display otherwise then then look into
that but prior to prior to taking some
virtual training your your earbuds with
the mic will likely work adequately for
a live virtual training if you have a
headset then that's likely better
because headsets and oftentimes have not
always but oftentimes have a little bit
of features that help with canceling out
external noise so these are some things
for those who are considering laboratory
training that you might want to - to
think about and especially think about a
little bit before your training because
if there's some things you decide you
want to purchase then you can't get them
quite as easily now so you might want to
make the purchase now even if you're
considering some of these things are
quite reasonably priced these headsets
are not expensive if you buy a small
display small monitor you can get those
not an exorbitant cost and those are
readily available the larger ones are a
little bit more in demand but some of
these things you might consider putting
on your if you have the resources your
you're ordering backlog but it's just
proof or thumb and hopefully for most
folks there their company will be
helping them out with some of these
purchases certainly I had trouble
getting a second webcam and just because
there are none available anymore because
everybody's and bought that and the
ships were coming from China anyway with
the stock and there was a shutdown for
about three months in China so there's
going to be unduly a procurement delay
there
that is more unusual and but for example
I have our video camera I have a
doorknob EP is a Canon yes I have our
Canon video camera that I bought many
years ago and that has an HDMI out and
then I bought a dongle which was
available to be able to plug it into my
computer to use that as a second camera
and that's the one that I'm on just now
and is significantly better quality than
the one that's built into my laptop and
that type of thing is definitely well
worth it and I would agree on a second
monitor so that you can have the video
the pictures of people up all the time
and then do work on the other or the
other screen I think that would be be
important cool so um it's giving you
enough time to interject there I don't
know how bad that I think the delay is
pretty short for me to you because you
react to things that I save very close
to what I'm when I'm saying it it's just
the reverse that is not true and I will
need to figure out how to fix that for
future sessions was there anything else
um that we wanted to add to to our list
of things today a bit of encouragement
to them those who are reviewing and in
two ways and two aspects I should say
the the training at participating the
training is usually a very stimulating
and invigorating activity so for those
who find themselves suddenly remote
that's an upside but the encouragement I
want to give to those who are watching
who are suddenly remote is there a take
advantage of meetup groups in your local
area and often those meetup groups are
now having virtual
meetups so use this as an opportunity to
network with your peers or groups of
people that you that you haven't taken
advantage of in the past person I say
that because personally in the Atlanta
area there are a lot of meetups that
I've had interest in but not the time to
travel to them and so now that I'm now
that we're everyone in Atlanta is sudden
well not everyone uh everyone except
essential services or suddenly remote
then I'm getting to spend some time
learning about communities that I
couldn't learn about in the past meeting
people I couldn't meet in the past
because I didn't have the time to
physically go but now that those people
are meeting virtually I've made several
very enriching professional connections
just in the last few weeks
via meetups that have a live virtual
component yeah most of the meetups in
Scotland that I actually found
definitely getting to as well because
I'm in Glasgow and many of the meetups
are in Edinburgh and it's it's not the
easiest thing in the world to get
between the two and especially at the
moment but they've gone all online I
spoke at one of the meetups and I did it
as a live stream for them which they
have now continued to do live streaming
the event which I think is is is good as
well and they've found that they're
actually getting more people coming
because it's a live streamed event and
they're getting more people from much
further away they're getting people from
other countries dialing in because they
just think the topics interesting you
know my local meetup has topic a and
this one no that is that that's much
more interesting than than the one that
I was thinking of going to and you're
getting that that higher levels of
diversity which i think is super super
good and
we I think we're pretty close to time
don't want to ramble on too long we can
always do this again sometime we've got
some more classes that Russell and I
have planned to do together and I know I
have I have a public PSM in Oslo
obviously I'll be doing remotely a
public PSM Oslo a public PSK that I'm
cool teaching with Daniel Vacanti from
the UK time zone and I think I oh I have
our pal E in the Mexico City I'm knowing
which will be interesting between my
private classes do you have anything
coming up Russell that you want to add I
have some public classes here in the
Eastern time zone in the US and both
professional scrum master professional
scrum product owners so those who live
in the Atlanta area or select other
cities in the Southeast United States I
didn't be happy to have you reach out my
LinkedIn connect is Russell a Miller so
you can message me through LinkedIn
that's a good way to contact me or you
can also find me on the scrum org
website those are two methods people can
use to to reach out oh absolutely and I
think that we both are going to be
working together and over the next few
months and hopefully we'll have even
more learnings the next ones that we're
working together on is going to be our
professional scrum foundations but not
the next one I'm doing which is on
Monday Tuesday because you're busy so
hopefully that will be yeah that's the
way it goes and hopefully that will all
work out well and we'll both know a
little bit more about how to do this
crazy thing
a live virtual classrooms when we get
there okay thanks very much Russell for
for for coming on Martin it was a
pleasure to get to help you facilitate
that professional agile leadership
course that was great to to do that and
I'm looking forward to our upcoming
collaborations awesome so I will speak
to you
[Music]