so the reason that I believe that an
agile coach is greater than a
professional coach is that an agile
coach will have deep
technical knowledge in understanding
um agile and its practices lean and its
practices uh flaw
um all the theory behind these these
these very technical practices that they
can leverage in helping teams and
organizations be more effective by
bringing something bring something to
the story that they didn't already have
um whereas a professional coach is
helping the people in the situation
understand and deal with things that
they already know right they already
know how to solve the problem and
they're helping them work through it and
agile coach brings more