there are lots of reasons why companies
come to us to help them with an Azure
devops migration um mostly it's
knowledge so we've done a lot of
migrations I've done hundreds of
migrations I've done um migrations up to
Azure devops I've done upgrades to
servers over the years beta servers
included um I've written code to move
data in a custom way from one
environment to another environment and
I've written an support code that allows
you to standardize that process as well
so the main reasons that that that
companies come to us is uh we've got a
department or a product that we've sold
to somebody else so we need to get it
out of the rest of our stuff and move it
over here that's one um we created one
big project um I think I coined the term
many many years ago one project to rule
them all right so they created one
massive project um and they actually
realized that they need to split it into
two so take one thing and split into two
or they created 20 projects and they
realized that they're all interconnected
and they should all be in one one bucket
um those are probably the main ones I've
sold part of my company I created too
many things and I want less things I've
created uh not enough things and I want
more things so moving that that data
around um but
also we we don't know what to do right
we this is our current state of what
we've got we want this how do we get
from here to there because it is really
complicated to do some of the migrations
and upgrades that people want really
depending on their context um so we do a
lot of migrations where there's many
many steps to get all the way to Azure
devops because the servers that they
environments are on are crusty and old
and that's the best reason to do it
right if if your servers and your
environments are crusty and old then
your teams that support them are not
able to support them right um so you
don't want to be running them yourself
you certainly don't want to be running
all of your Cod your organizational
asset which is your code um in a in a a
crusty falling apart barely
functions uh doesn't get any support
anymore right because the environments
are old um version of of anything um so
if you can get it get it up to the cloud
get it into that um fully supported
fully maintained environment where in
this case Microsoft do all the updates
do all they take it Forward they
engineer the proc product they do the
support and maintenance and uh load load
and everything Disaster Recovery just
everything they take care of it um and
it cost you what $4 per user per month
to get that it's a total no-brainer um
so getting up to the cloud doing those
things um we've also done a lot of
migrations from TFS to git um from G to
TF sorry GitHub GitHub TFS to GitHub
GitHub to TFS um I even did migration
once from Azure devops to TFS I assume
somebody in the
organization went without permission and
took all the stuff up to your devops and
there's no way back from Microsoft's
perspective um so yeah there's loads of
reasons why companies ask me to do
migrations some of them are good reasons
some of them are not so good reasons and
sometimes we we'll we'll push back quite
heavily and say look the this is not I I
get a lot of calls for backup right you
don't need to back up as your devops
Microsoft back it up for you they have
Disaster Recovery they have copies off
the tape they have all of that stuff for
you and they're all the isos compliant
for uh uh uh uh the level of recovery
that that that you're you're paying for
so there's no need for you to do that so
we push back really heavily on that but
we've also done it because the customer
really insists that they want want a a a
backup and sometimes you're you're
you're going to do that um so there's
lots of good reasons lots of bad reasons
to move data around and is your devops
um but it's irrelevant people want stuff
done the way they want it done um and
sometimes you need to do that and uh
yeah we help them out doing that