I don't know if you've
noticed but unhappy sad people tend not
to be engaged in what it is that they're
doing and one of
the E metrics for whether you're going
to have success in the future is the
morale of the people that are doing the
work that could be could be people
actually building the products it could
be the people designing the products it
could be the people managing the people
people that are designing the products
if if if we're sad and unhappy we don't
do good work as humans no matter how
much you encourage them to just be
professionals and get on with it so we
want Happy engaged excited people and
and part of what
makes us as humans happy and engaged and
excited about topics is if we have our
intrinsic needs met so hopefully
hopefully you're paying people enough in
your organization that they're not
worried about extrinsic needs right like
the paying the mortgage or the rent or
putting food on the table right th those
those are things that hopefully the
people within your organization are are
already a to achieve which means if if
ER you've read uh Dan Pink's book drive
um the intrinsic motivators that really
encourage us to do the best work work we
can or autonomy Mastery in
purpose
and autonomy
being us feeling like we're in control
of Our Own Destiny and we decide what
we're working on um Mastery means we're
we're good at what we are do what we are
do we're good at what we do we're being
um valuable right we're learning and
understanding and then uh purpose
right we the things that we do matter to
to others they provide value in the
space and we can see the value that
those things
create
so part of the thing that I think is
most valuable about this idea of the
longer term um mentor and training
immersive
programs is that that
because we're provoking discussion
within the
organization right we're provoking
thought leadership within the
organization I found that the people
within the organization start becoming
more engaged and animated in the the
particular topics right they start
talking to other people in the
organization about the things that
they've been not just the things they've
been learning but the things they've
been discing discussing the things have
been discovering they start H figuring
out who in the organization can I go
speak to to have a a conversation on
this particular topic they're starting
to get engaged and excited and animated
about what it is that they're trying to
do because they're starting to see how
the work they do every day connects to
the overall purpose of the organization
even if the organization doesn't yet
understand the purpose that it's trying
to achieve so lots of organizations
don't have that that overriding goal
that North Star that they're working
towards um are working with a few
organizations at the moment that H the
leadership hasn't even thought about
that oh to make more money right which
is which is not what everybody can get
behind because it's making somebody else
money but the
the
even knowing especially this is
especially true for the product
management Mentor program the things we
talk about helps those FKS understand
the need for those things so their
initial purpose becomes how do I engage
with my organization and help them
create that that those those those goals
and vision that that that this is what
we're trying to achieve that North Star
and in not the current the I've got a
current um Mentor program that's
underway for for product management but
I had a a previous previous one that
ended perhaps two months ago something
like that
um for an organization in the UK and
about halfway through the program I got
an email from the
CEO uh effectively
saying I I I
I've not an exact quote but to
paraphrase what he said he said I i'
I've I've
never had a training program that we've
purchased as an organization cuz it was
sold as a training program never had a
training program that we've purchased as
an organization provide the level of
Engagement and
excitement and potential
change than the mentor program did for
for product managers so it it it
highlighted it was highlighted to him
because um effectively one of one of the
weeks everybody was in Poland
so from a time scale perspective I think
it was afternoon
session um so in Poland it's like two
hours two hours later is it two hours
later or is it 3 hours later not Poland
Romania was Romania I think it was so
it's it's like two hours two hours later
and um so the product managers had had
their day in the organization then
they'd had this class into the evening
so I take four hours of their time into
the evening and then there was a dinner
organized with the CEO and all the
product managers and some other folks
and the product man the the CEO was
expecting all the product managers to
turn up tired and grumpy and you know
all of those things that you expect when
oh they've just spent four hours doing
this thing they've probably been in a
PowerPoint presentation for 4 hours and
they'll be tired and grumpy but when
they came to the dinner they were
engaged in talking about the topics that
we'd been talking about during the day
they were engaging the CEO in
discussions about what it is that they
would like to try and do how it's
different from what they've done before
how it might impact on the value that we
create in the
organization that engagement and
excitement was enough to prompt the CEO
to email me directly and say well this
was this was great this was great I've
never seen this before this is this is
fantastic and that obviously for me is a
great outcome as well um and we've
actually done follow on mentorship
programs for their engineering teams as
well where um we've taken their
engineering teams into a similar type of
program same same model uh we did a 10we
uh uh product development Mentor program
uh with two of their four teams in the
organization and we've already started
to see Improvement in the teams
Improvement and what it is that they're
they're they're doing in the
organization and their ability to
deliver and support the business
so I've
seen way more instances of success with
this type of format than I ever saw
before um with uh uh the traditional
training uh uh four half days or two
full day format that has been delivered
in the past um I've really only seen
that work once really successfully in
hundreds of trainings um at least I've
seen it right that doesn't mean it's not
been successful for people um but me
being able to see and engage with this
group of people over um 8 to 15 weeks or
perhaps longer depending on the program
um and just have that continuous we're
working towards getting things better
engaging re-engaging talking about those
topics um has produced some some
fantastic results already from every
single instance of uh uh of of running
these programs every single instance has
created actionable outcomes for the
businesses that have purchased it