in order to craft
a Sprint goal A team's going to pull in
a bunch of information with the
Strategic direction of the product the
current tactical direction that the
product owner is looking for the
um current things that are happening in
the engineering of the product and they
pull all of those things together and
figure out what is the next most
important thing they can work on what is
the next most important thing they could
show the stakeholders that would provide
them with value
and then once they've got that context
that will then enable them to have a
discussion about what items they're
going to select they're going to pull
from the product backlog into their
Sprint