fake it till you make it fake it till
you make
it oh but that
yeah bake it till you make it has its
limitations you can if you have some
knowledge and you're missing something
right you're missing a small piece you
can uh uh uh fake it till you make it
you can do the thing like learn as
you're going and figure out how to do it
better but if you were for example I
wouldn't want my neurosurgeon faking it
till they make it I wouldn't want uh uh
my I wouldn't want my plasterer that I'm
hiring to do the walls of my house
faking it till they make it hire
expertise but those experts should be
coaching and helping those that don't
have skills uh or don't have the skills
but want them to make them better