building a road map to get you from your
legacy engineering practices or legacy
products to modern well-built
products, modern engineering practices
is is a it's I guess it's a little bit
of
it's going to be a very high level road
map.
It's difficult to put structure
around the idea
of building
a a culture of engineering excellence.
Changing changing culture, changing
systems is more of an art than a
science. You bring science to the story,
right? Because you're you're going to
have data and telemetry. You're going to
bring things like things like OKRs,
right, which have here's what we're
trying to achieve, the objective, but
also here's the key results. Here are
the things that you're um that you're
going to
meet, right? Measure and meet to be able
to say whether you've been successful in
that thing. And we want to be bringing
that hypothesis
driven story to all of the things that
we do within the context of our of our
of our road map. So it's ultimately a a
transition from legacy to modern is a
road map of of hypo hypothesis. I think
that's the plural of hypothesis
hypothesis.
Um we we've we've done it before with
organizations. Um I'm working with an
organization just now to to to start
moving them. their own team foundation
version control TFVC
um moving them to git um modernizing
their tooling building out the DevOps
pipelines
and it's not something that you can just
plan up front and say it's going to work
because you don't know what you're going
to run into along the way there's too
many unknowns
um and it's unknown unknowns is is is
very very big so we want to
take one thing at a
And what I tend to recommend, it seems
like a little bit of an oxymoron, but um
take your biggest, riskiest, nastiest,
most difficult product, and that's your
pilot, right? You want you want to move
them from um TFVC into Git. You're going
to have to fix a bunch of stuff to do
that. You want to build out your your
automating pipelines. You're probably
going to have to um move things around.
let's call it move things around in
order to get your automation pipelines
working. And then um you're probably
going to want to look at bringing in
like what other stuff are outside of our
scope of our our scope of automation our
our current view of our automated
pipelines that we need to get to
production. Right? That that's that's
the story. One of one of the key
things that I always run with with a
with a customer
is I I get everybody together who is
involved in impro approving
that your product gets deployed to
production, right? Who are all the
people that need to be involved in that
story from from product developers all
the way up to somebody in management who
ticks an approval box or approves
something or whatever, right? All of
those people and ask them to write down
everything that needs to be true
in order for them
to be happy to ship that thing to
production, right? Everything that needs
to be true. So that could be a
particular measure. It could be some
piece of data. It could be something
they look for. Um it could be something
that has to be done. We just need to yes
this is done. True. Take right. We get
all of those things together. Those are
all the things that need to be in your
development process. And ultimately as
many of those things as humanly and
inhumanly possible need to be automated.
You want to automate everything. You you
shouldn't have you should not
you should not have any manual tasks
between developer committing a line of
code to your repository and it getting
into production.
And that's manual tasks i.e. people
following scripts or doing all those
things. It should be
topic automated build validated test
approvable request as automatedly as
possible as short as possible provable
request trunkbased development then kick
off your automation to deploy to some
subset of real users right I'm usually
pretty clear on when we're deploying to
production a new version of our products
production we're probably not talking
about deploying those new things to
everybody at once. You don't want to do
what Cloud Strike did, Crowdstrike did,
and take out half the world's internet,
right? That's not a good place to be.
You want to do like uh uh uh uh Windows
or Teams or Azure DevOps or um Google do
and you do a a a phased audience-based
roll out. I usually call it ring based
development but audience-based uh roll
out. So you have a that that part of
your transition road map
from legacy to modern is figuring out
what what does our
new in our new model what does our
branching structure look like? What does
our automated deployments look like?
Where do they go? Who sees them? who
interacts with them? How do we get as
quickly as possible to some subset of
real users? Not everyone, some subset of
real users. Uh a good example, although
it's still a really big sample set, is
when Microsoft ship Windows. Uh they
ship Windows daily to everybody inside
of Microsoft that takes the internal
build, which is not everybody. That's
going to be thousands of people, right?
Um, and then weekly they ship to a bunch
of people in the insiders group, which
is up to 17 million people
before they roll out to 900 million
people, right? Everybody using Windows,
900 million machines. They roll out to
17 million machines, not 900 million
machines.
And that phased roll out allows you to
understand, get telemetry, shorten that
feedback loop when you know you have a
long tail for your customers taking
taking parts of your product. This is
your short tail. That's your long tail.
And
understanding
how to do that, planning around figuring
that out is that's your transition road
map, right? that that's how we get the
information to be able to understand
what it is we need to do within the
context of your product or at least
what's the first step we're going to do
within the context of your product. And
if you're on TFVC, it's getting onto
Git. If you're already on Git and you
don't have automated builds, it's
automated builds, right? If you have
automated builds and you're in Git, it's
automated deployment if you don't have
that. If you don't include testing in
that matrix, that's the next step.
Bringing in the automated testing. So
there's a clear road map of what's the
first thing to tackle, what's the second
thing to tackle and keep going down that
line. And as you're going down that
line, you're building a story of both
engineering excellence and technical
leadership within your organization. And
you need to do that in a way that that
scales across your organization. So that
means
when you when you build engineering
excellence within your organization,
it's it's an it's an ethos. It's a
philosophy of how we do things within
the context of our organization. And
it's all about adapting to change,
adapting to surprise, adapting to the
things that happen as we go in a way
that's that's professional and um um
provides the outcomes that the business
your your your end customer is looking
for. So if if if you want a stepbystep
path out of legacy pain, you're you you
don't have a paddle there. There's
there's no real way to do that. But what
we can provide you is the compass to
help you um orienteer your way through
your legacy pain. Right? What's
every step of the what's the next step
of the journey? We do the next step of
the journey. We look at the compass and
the map and we figure out what's the
next direction we're going to take.
What's the next thing we're going to do?
And that continuous l iterative uh uh
path is what's going to support you long
term um and map right your migration
journey.