so the question is what's my favorite
devops Consulting outcome and and I
really have to go to
actually one of my
favorite and longest customers
um they were building a piece of
software
uh there
I'm gonna try and not name them but
they'll know who they are when I'm
talking about them
uh they were building a piece of
software that was massive multi-billion
dollar
products
so ultimately leadership didn't care
about efficiency so much right when your
profit margin is in the four to five
billion dollars and you've only get
650 people working on it your answer to
a lot of problems might be can't we just
hire a bunch of people to solve that
right which is not always the best way
to to solve a problem
and we were in the position that
um it was a very fragmented product so
there was 80 to 90 teams
working in 13 locations in nine
different countries
they all did their own thing so each
team picked their own source control
system ran their own source control
system locally
there was everything you could possibly
imagine there was uh
um there was git but not very much of it
there was team Foundation Version
Control there was subversion oh there
was just everything there was even a a
source control system that they built
themselves right because when they
started building this product there were
no good source Control Systems out there
and they still had people in the company
using their homegrown Source control
system lots of fun
um and in order to
build this product because it was one
product that was deployed to a machine
right so you've got one not one
executable but it
for one I'm old right it was burned onto
a CD and then you know that's your your
install right so it's one install for
your for your product
um
in order to to get that to exist
they had to run a bunch of builds to go
pool that
code from all the different locations
right pull it into some central location
then actually do all of the builds that
they needed to do and that was hugely
complicated because every team did
different stuff right so you had
different tools different capabilities
it was a multi multi-hour Fandango to go
do it and what they ended up having to
do was about this is about about 10 000
builds a day
in order to to to create one working
version of the product
so they had a a a a
set of 20 between 20 and 40 build
servers uh the all in order to build
this product had to be the most
unbelievably powerful machines you could
possibly imagine as many cores as you
could possibly fit as much memory as you
could possibly fit it was just a
monolithic product
um and it it ten thousand builds a day
to have a nightly build of the product
which needed a team of people to run run
this
um so I I started working with them that
was the state they were in kind of when
I started working with them and and my
my overriding advice was you need to
simplify this process you need to make
it easier faster slick because it's just
too hard to find out something's wrong
to find out you've broken something and
one team breaks another team right all
of those things
so I did a a state of agile state of
devops report for them which is
basically uh um here's the here's what
did I how did I phrase it here are the
opportunities for improvement right
um that you have in your system and if
you only fix three things here's the top
three things right and the top one was
that that build problem get them all
into one source control system uh one
set of builds and those kind of things
and that effort because they've got to
go do it right I'm the consultant I'm
there to help them do it and I also help
them with a whole bunch of other stuff
as well right but
um day to day they're the ones that have
got to go do it I don't understand their
code I don't know where all the bodies
are buried and who they need to
politically talk to in their company to
get stuff done they need to go do all of
that so I was there a little bit of
coaching uh mostly Consulting on other
stuff while they're doing that and then
coming back around and having
discussions and being part of me all
that kind of stuff and it actually took
and this was a record in this company
four years
uh to get them onto One Source control
system which was team Foundation we got
them all into Azure devops One Source
control system all on team Foundation
version control everything on one set of
branches and everybody working in the
same uh the same area so they'll be able
to clone the same clone uh uh um what
was it called create the same workspace
uh in tfvc and I'll work together and
not poop on each other still had lots of
branches still had 80 90 active branches
but at least they were all related to
each other and you could do the
branching and merging properly and all
that kind of stuff
and um but that was the first stage to
getting them onto uh getting them over
onto git optimizing their processes you
know
um
doing all of the other things that need
to happen in order to have uh I I
there's a phrase I love it it's called
onees
if you've not heard this phrase one
engineering system it's from uh first
time I heard it was from Microsoft and
they're one es strategy is part of the
reason that Azure devops exists in the
first place and that it's a cloud
platform and that's that they had this
problem internally and they wanted to
you don't want
an A person who works for you
to go work from one team and they move
to another team and suddenly have they
have to re-figure out how everything
works they have to re-figure out where
to store their work items they have to
where all the work requests are how they
build their code where they build their
code where the code comes from all of
that stuff shouldn't be that should be
like that's the default stuff that we
all understand
and then the actual build that happens
is different for every product in every
platform but it's in the same place
right between those lines is different
but the wrapper the how you get it to
done how what you need to install all of
those things should be part of the the
organizational standards and that's what
one engineering system was all about was
getting everybody onto one platform
everybody onto one not way of working
that's the wrong phrase but one
engineering system
that can do all of the things that
everybody in the company needed to do
so that nobody's confused about where
their crap is and where they need to go
to go change stuff and do stuff and
collaborate with each other and that was
the ethos of of of azure devops and it
it met it absolutely fantastically
um which is why I I love that tool that
is my go-to tool is is your devops
although I use other tools as well
um but just that that that vision from
Simon guggenheimer of of that one
engineering system of that Elm devops
experience is just phenomenal
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility