um
that's a good good question I don't know
if you like the answer so the question
is how did I know
I was ready to transition from a devops
practitioner to a devops consultant
and I feel like I
didn't it just happened to me that's
that's for for me personally I feel like
it just happened to me
um I worked predominantly in the
Microsoft space I was awarded a
Microsoft MVP in 2008 I think 2008 and
that kind of gets you access to a
different group of people and I got
noticed by people who were Consultants
people who worked in consulting firms
and then I was hired into a a consulting
firm so I I feel like
I don't know if it's the right answer
but I feel like you don't make that
decision somebody else makes it for you
you need to be you need to be noticed
right you need to you need to be good at
what you do
and you need to do something in that
space that somebody who's in the
Consulting space notices you and says oh
that would be great if you were able to
leverage those skills to help people
rather than just working in one job for
one company right because I think it
takes a little bit of a different
mindset to help many at many companies
than just just your own company
but I have also met
um some of the best two of the best
devops Consultants that I worked with
were actually hired from straight from
University into a devops consultancy
but they were hired out of a competition
right so the devops consultant say I
worked for in Seattle uh went to the
local University and ran a competition
with all of the students in computer
science and then they picked the two the
the the that looked like they would make
the the most effective devops
Consultants
and both of them are now I.T directors
in multinational companies in in the US
so I think I think that that level of
expertise demonstrate your expertise
and you'll get noticed write blog posts
right demonstrate uh uh that you that
you know stuff build build things in the
devops space and people will will see
you hopefully
um and think you're doing good stuff and
then want you to come and come and help
them out some more and that's that's
kind of how you know you're ready is
people want your advice people want to
talk to you people want to know you
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility