that's a good question why is becoming a
scrum Master a great career option
I I feel like the
scrum Master is the first next step for
a team member
on Elite on the leadership
track right on the the like like the
gold shirts in Star Trek
right you're you're you're you're you're
wanting to move forward you're wanting
to take on more more
um accountabilities you want to
demonstrate to your organization
um that you can you can
um
lead right that you can bring a team
Along on a on a journey and I think for
for that you have to demonstrate that
leadership before you get the position
and
um if you're a team member you've been
working every TF team for a long time
perhaps you've had a focus on
um excellence in whatever it is that you
do right because your background might
not just be coding right it might be
testing it might be operations it might
be a documentation right whatever that
is
if you've had a focus on
um excellence in how can I help my team
be more effective
right just as an individual as an expert
on that team then I think it's logical
that people on the team are going to
look
to you
for some of those answers right if
you're the knowledgeable person about
about Automation and how can we get
better at doing this thing and make what
we're doing Slicker so we add more value
to the customer and then that's you
demonstrating that leadership ability
that hopefully every member of your team
has right but if you stand out perhaps
they'll be looking to you more and
you'll kind of naturally fall into that
scrum Master role for the team the the
accountability you're picking up that
accountability that's perhaps lying
around
and um
once you're once you're there and the
team respects you and respects your your
your your ability to to help them become
more effective then that will be seen
hopefully in the organization
um and for me that that leadership
leadership track from a team member
starts with scrum master and then into
wherever wherever those go in your
organization right every organization is
different for how that flow is
um but it's that step on the leadership
ladder
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility