so the question is what does what does
openness mean in the scrum values and
why does it
matter and I think openness is really
important it has a number of of of
aspects to it but it really comes it it
comes down to that serving of the the
the transparency right the values are
trying to in order to have transparency
we need Trust
right without trust we've gotten nothing
so how do we get trust because trust is
an output not an input right to the to
the to the story it's just it's a result
it's a thing that we can observe and see
that we have but you can't magically get
it just cuz you want it so openness
openness serves that by um being be
being being open well I guess partly
open and transparent in and of yourself
right but just telling people people how
it is right there there are things that
we need to talk about there's things
that need to be in place there's um
stories that we need to tell inside of
the organization so that everybody
clearly understands what's going on so
are we expressing things are we are we
hiding things right that might be the
opposite of openness are we are we is is
it easy for everybody to to find and
understand what's in the product backlog
is it easy for people to find and
understand what our working practices
are is it easy for people to find and
understand how how we as a team do
things or we as a group do things if not
then how are we being open right um and
also just just if you bring that back to
the emotional context right are are are
we being open and saying to people when
we don't don't like something are we
being open and saying to people when
something's affecting us in a way that
maybe they didn't know or
recognize that openness
enables us all to have a conversation
because we're talking right we're not
we're not hiding or resenting uh
something that's happening in the
organization we can actually have a
conversation we can talk about it
whether it's a physical thing that's to
do with do with scrum or the way we work
or it's an emotional thing to do with
the way we interact or communicate with
people and just being um being being
open right that's that's part of that
building up to
transparency thanks for watching the
video If you enjoyed it please like
follow And subscribe I always reply to
comments and if you want to have a chat
about this or anything else agile scrum
or devops then please book a coffee with
me through naked agility