I think it's very difficult for aspiring
agile
leaders to get
the time the space needed to have a lot
of the conversations that really need to
be had in the leadership space in their
organization and the the the p e is a
fantastic class that enables that that
space to have those
conversations but doesn't necessarily
always result in
space that to actually do the things uh
differently that you want to do or
practice the things that you want to
practice and that's where taking this uh
uh the the the the traditional Pali
class and exploding it
[Music]
into a a a six week immersive
class enables more more time for
people's thought processes right to to
adopt some of these new ideas for people
to try things in between the class
specifically the assignments would be
would be something that they they're
going to definitely try they might try
other things that we talked about in the
in the in the course but the assignment
is a specific thing here go try this go
figure out this how does this happen in
your
organization um and then bring that back
around into a a group of their peers
whether it's a public class and there's
leaders from lots of different aspiring
leaders from lots of different
organizations or it's a private class
where you've got the leadership for your
organization in that private class um
that that coming back around and
debriefing those those assignments and
also being able to if you did try other
things being able to ask those questions
at that point this is I tried this uh we
looked at this idea and it didn't work
um we tried to do this level of
Delegation how do we do this differently
so that we can get more Buy in from the
people that are doing it and that
collaborative experience is really the
the the why the pal immersive class is
such a great fit for people who are in
management or leadership positions
inside of their organization and they
want to ad adopt those agile ideas that
they see
organizations out there people out there
being able to do and getting so much
value from how do we get the same value
in our organization from those
conversations how do we change the way
we do things to enable the people in our
organizations um to to take more more
accountability um to to take more
ownership of the thing that they're
working on to be more invested and
connected with the work that they're
doing um and the pal E class is um an
experience that allows you to understand
how all of those things are connected
together and perhaps reflect on the way
your organization currently does things
and how that might inhibit the ability
for teams U to maximize the value that
they deliver to to stakeholders your
customers uh your stakeholders your
leadership if you want to have a
discussion about how immersive classes
can revolutionize your training
experience then please book a call on
our website alternatively you can find
all of our public immersive classes
listed there as well and we would love
to hear from you