so the question was why am I going the
immersive trading route
um
because I want to do the thing that's
best for not just the students but their
ability to make changes in their
organization I I got into this training
thing for the same reason that I got
into the devops thing back in 2010 it's
that I I I saw that people and
um
organizations where where we're
struggling right people were struggling
and organizations weren't getting what
they needed so the organizations were
blaming the people and suddenly you've
got this vicious cycle and
um
devops helped Grease the wheels give
people more because you automate you
automate a lot of stuff away again I was
working with Azure devops and more from
a technical perspective and how do you
improve the flow of value delivery so
that then we have time to look
holistically and figure out what's going
on
and in doing that I think I said before
I I very quickly figured out that it
wasn't it wasn't actually the tools that
were the thing that was helping people
it was the different practices that
people were using and that led logically
towards
um the same this this idea of of agile
and scrum and kanban and those kind of
things as well
so this is that logical progression of
um we're we're using double Loop
learning in and of ourselves right our
our our the outcome of the training
styles that we've got is not the most
optimal for how people retain knowledge
learn and use that knowledge
people are much better in that practical
world so closing that loop again and
saying well we need to change How We Do
training
um and part of that was moving to the
flipped ish flipped learning experience
um and this is the the next progression
and I know that there are our trainers
out there that have been experimenting
with uh different learning formats and
this is starting to pull that
information together and what are the
best learning formats and not the best
that's probably the wrong word or what
are more effective learning formats for
people and how do we incorporate it into
the way we do things the the harder part
for us is that it's
um as a trainer right and as a business
owner is that it's actually going to be
less I'm going to have less time
to be able to do other training classes
right so instead of it being four half
days or four half days spread over a
couple of weeks or or you know four half
days spread over two days right it's
going to be
um eight half days so spread over
um eight weeks so in the time that it
takes me to deliver this I could have
delivered in the old format to food
classes but for me this is a better
experience for students if the students
are going to learn more and be more
effective then this type of training is
going to be more valuable
and it's providing value to the customer
that's the most important thing rather
than uh uh you know if if we just focus
on a revenue extraction model rather
than a value creation model then we're
not going to be able to I don't know
we're not going to be able to affect
change we're not going to be able to
have people look favorably on what it is
we're doing right we're not going to
have people
we both need to get something out of the
experience if companies are realizing
that they're not getting anything out of
the two two field days and even the four
half days is starting to not provide
them with the value that they'd really
like to get they're going to start
buying buying that trading and they're
not gonna they're all going to be able
to provide that to the people in their
organization and I think this is part of
that story of we want to deliver more
value to our customer even if it means
that it takes more time to to get there
and I think that for me is that that
that that piece from both sides both the
business side right because I'm running
a business as well as from the helping
people site it actually benefits both
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility