and what circumstances is agile
Consulting appropriate
so I guess first we have to quantify
what is agile Consulting
right we probably have to quantify that
first for for me agile Consulting
is almost always what I do with
customers
I find that
the only the only reason businesses
think they need agile coaches
is because of a systematic lack of
leadership within the business they've
lots of managers
but not so many leaders
so they need somebody to come in and
fill that servant leadership Gap and
they hire in external people but
unfortunately
that's a Core Business practice
and you don't Outsource core business
practices
right because that's what makes your
business successful so those those those
contractors that you hire in to do to to
to to be long-term agile coaches
actually end up hurting your business
because as they change out as they leave
you're upsetting the people that are in
your business because they're not that
that as permanent a fixture they're paid
differently they're not included in the
training right they're not included in
lots of things that you would you would
be doing as a team as a group
um so I I I feel that there's very well
there's maybe a Kickstart value in agile
coaches right but in reality in a
long-term business the value is in
creating agile coaches inside of your
business finding the people inside of
your organization who can help support
your organization and make that move
from management to leadership so that
they can help fulfill your business
desires right and internal Core Business
need
um so I I feel like any organization
that thinks they need an agile coach
probably doesn't they probably need some
Consulting agile Consulting to help them
understand what they need to do
in order to make their business more
successful
right and and that's that intrinsic
difference is agile Consulting is not
thinking I need to be here for for six
to 12 months in order to to you know
have my income for the year it's it's
I'm I'm here for the next two weeks I'm
here for a week I'm here for a month I'm
gonna I'm gonna figure out how to solve
solve your problems providing Solutions
right like things to try they're not
maybe the end solution but they're where
do I start because because businesses
have that question they have that
question what do I do where do I start I
don't understand this thing what where
where should I go from where I am right
now and and agile coaching doesn't often
provide that answer because the agile
coach
um
is is looking at that systematic slow
engaging with people type of model
whereas Consulting is more the you know
we want to figure out what switch to
flip that's probably the best
explanation is flipping switches
um so there's some really good
um data out there talking about how
um
the traditional transformational model
in organizations is actually it's it's
not working it all it results in is lots
of feeble implementations of agile
fragile implementations of agile and
um um The Continuous need to maintain
that external help and support because
we actually never changed our business
right we didn't actually change anything
so as soon as that crutch of that agile
coaching is removed the whole thing
collapses and falls back into a
terroristic commanding control control
mass and there are a whole bunch of new
techniques uh uh there's open space
agile
um open space beta talking about how do
we enact change in our organization over
a very short space of time change as
flipping right you're going to flip a
switch something will be just different
right in the way we do things and how do
you figure out what those switches are
well you can have Consultants come men
and help you figure out what those
switches are but the reality is the
people in your organization already know
what those switches are isn't I think
that's the art of Consulting isn't it
coming in and telling people
what they already know right that's
that's kind of the art of Consulting and
the people in your organization already
know what changes need to be made you
just need to empower them and I think
one of the core reasons organizations
need Consultants rather than coaches is
Consultants are going to help them
understand what it is they just
fundamentally need to change