most
organizations really
struggle
to enable the people that are doing the
work in their organization to understand
where they're going and what they're
trying to
achieve um I I remember working with a
with an organization in the US this is
just an example probably about 80% of
the no must be more like 90% this is
anecdotal evidence from me Consulting
with organizations um probably 90% plus
of organizations teams groups that I
work with um have no idea what value
means to their business um they have no
idea what the Strategic direction of
their organization is and they have no
idea what the current goal is for their
organization can you imagine that you're
trying to trying to do work trying to
decide what to build trying to decide
what direction to go and you've no idea
what that direction is that's like being
being uh dropped in a field in the
middle of nowhere and told to get to the
nearest Village and you have no idea
what direction that Village is you're
just going to have to come up with a
search pattern and you're going to have
to go try and search whereas what you
really need is a map and a compass and
that's what those things are right that
is what this idea of uh uh um
vision and value is for an
organization it's the map and the
compass where are we going how are we
going to get there are we going in the
right direction how do we measure how
we're going in the right direction
that's that's why I talk about
evidence-based management right how do
we measure we're being more successful
than before we made that decision um
that's why I talk about hypothesis
driven engineering practices um how do
we ensure that the ideas that we have
actually have a valid story to them
right are we making the difference that
we thought we were going to make with
the investment we thought we were going
to do um
and that's why it's so important for
Senior Management and leaders to grow
their product management and product
ownership capabilities in in their
organization to to to
understand how important that story is
for organizations to to to have not not
just to have h a a goal and a vision
right but for it to be articulated in a
way that every single person in your
organization understands what that goal
and what that vision is and how the work
they do every day contributes to it
because if the work they do every day
doesn't contribute to what it is your
business is trying to achieve then you
probably shouldn't be
doing right and if we don't know what
direction we're going how do we know
where even the big things that we're
working on are supporting that goal and
vision that we're trying to
achieve you need to have a North star
you need to understand as a business
what are you trying to achieve and be
able to communicate that to everybody in
your organization in a way that makes
sense to them it doesn't matter if it
makes sense to you right it has to make
sense to them because they're the ones
who are doing the work they're the ones
who are doing making the decisions every
person in your organization is making
lots of little micro decisions every day
within the context of um the context of
whatever it is they've been hired to do
right so software engineer
are making engineering decisions uh
Architects are making architectural
decisions uh project managers are making
project decisions
uh delivery managers are making delivery
decisions uh every single day they're
not going to go ask
you whether they're making the right
decision or not in order for
them to be able to understand what it is
that whether their decision is a good
decision or not right let's say they
just have two options you never have two
options you have like 50 options but
let's say you've got two options um and
depending on the
future one is right and one is
wrong maybe they're both right but one
could be right one could be wrong we
don't know yet depends on the future but
if I am making that decision and I
understand more about the context I
understand more about the impact that
this choice is going to make on the
future I can perhaps make a better
choice if I don't understand I'm just
going to randomly pick whichever one's
my
favorite right because that's what
people do what do I think based on the
limited knowledge I have is the best
thing I can do so if you look if you
look at something like um David
marquette's turn the ship around right
it talks about intent based
leadership what do you intend as a
business how do you communicate that
does everybody understand your intent
because if they don't understand your
intent they're going to make bad
decisions you want them to make good
decisions because they're going to make
the decisions because in order for you
to make the decisions you have to
understand everything that they
understand and you're hiring incredibly
technical people these days right in the
in the in the old days of um big textile
factories um
management
leadership management could make better
decisions than the people on the shop
floor because the people on the shop
floor were large a largely uneducated
Workforce and you could maybe talk you
even the four four people foremans were
um probably not highly educated they had
anecdotal knowledge right they didn't
understand the theory they just
understood the mechanisms of what's
happening on the on the floor um you
needed to go up to management levels to
get people to understand what it is
we're actually trying to achieve as the
business what's the thing so so they
didn't make any of the decisions at the
bottom but they weren't doing highly
technical work that required lots of
decisions when you're doing Simple
Things when you're doing let's say
you're when you're doing complicated
things you can document them into
simpleness right that's probably a good
way it's terrible way to describe it but
anyway you you can you can take a
complicated thing you you can write a
bunch of documentation create a bunch of
rules create a bunch of uh if this
happens then this happens and you can
provide standard operating procedures
right so you can you can provide those
uh for people and they can just follow
them and we're going to have good
outcomes right because by following that
standard operating procedure we're going
to have the same outcomes every time um
but in the world of
complexity when uh we are dealing with
surprise and um surprises and surprises
can be good or bad surprises and
opportunities right um those vary too
much and we can't create a standard
operating procedure because we will
perhaps not be able to maximize the
value that we create because we're just
following the standard operating
procedure and lots of big organizations
definitely fall into that trap of they
have a a sop for everything this is how
we do things here this is our
bureaucracy our red tape or uh whatever
you call it locally um and it inhibits
the ability of the people in your
organization to make better decisions
than the person who decided on the
standard operating procedure which may
have been 10 years ago in a different
Market in a different part of the
business for a different context and now
it's applied to everybody and everything
equally across the organization and in
some cases it's a good decision in other
cases is a really bad decision we want
to make more right decisions and less
wrong decisions and that means everybody
in your organization has to understand
what it is you're trying to achieve and
in order for them to do that you as the
business you as leaders and management
within that business need to grow your
understanding of
um how you communicate and engage with
everybody in your organization to ensure
that they understand what you're trying
to achieve in what direction they're
going and that means you can't just go
install okrs and have everything be
perfect you can't just write something
in your vision statement and have
everybody just follow it they need to
understand understanding is not a
Boolean proposition it's not something
that you can standard operating
bureaucrat your way into it needs to be
something that is personal that is based
on empathy that is based on engagement
with people and for that that's why we
have a product owner that's why we have
product ownership capabilities and in
order to maximize the value that your
organization creates you're going to
have to help everybody understand what
it is you're trying to achieve