according to the chaos report from the
Standish group small projects of under
50 participants are 30 percent more
likely to be successful with agile
practices and large projects of more
than 50 people are over 200 percent more
likely to be successful
hopefully this short video will help you
identify the key differences that make
this possible
my name's Martin henshawott I'm a
professional scrum trainer with
scrum.org professional kanban trainer
with Pro kanban and I've been a
Microsoft MVP in devops for 14 years
so we have the traditional model the
empirical model and we're going to look
at that within the context of visibility
right how much visibility do our
stakeholders have we're going to talk
about change operational risk and
realized value
so let's focus on visibility
at the beginning of a product life cycle
in a traditional model we're going to
have high visibility we're creating that
documentation we're showing the customer
liaising with the customer and what it
is we're going to going to create
and then at the end of the product cycle
we also have high visibility right the
customer's got a delivered usable
working product that solves their
business problem right that would be the
expectation at the end of that that time
period but in between those two points
we largely go dark right there might be
touch points with the customer we're
going to show you the documentation uh
we have little demos that we might do of
different parts of the product in
isolation but they don't really get a
holistic visibility about what's going
on where we are
we're just telling them so we tend to go
fairly low visibility not to zero right
but fairly low visibility and then at
the end of the product cycle it jumps up
as we deliver a usable working product
however for visibility in an empirical
model we're actually going to start in
exactly the same place and we're going
to end in exactly the same place right
we have high visibility at the end
because they've got a usable working
product we've got high visibility at the
start because we've got documentation
potentially right but
at the end of every single iteration
we're going to be providing
the customer
with a usable working product right
that's how we mitigate risk it's the
minimum bar for an empirical process a
minimum bar for scrum is a usable
working product at the end of every
Sprint
so in fact during
each iteration we've got that low
visibility
but we jump back up on a regular Cadence
as we're delivering
usable working product to the customer
so they get these many touch points
where they're able to make assertions
change direction and have a different
understanding of what's going on
now let's look at our ability to change
our ability to change I would quantify
that as our
the implications and our ability to
accept change into the system right
we're creating product so as we build
more product we have less ability to
change because each change has a bigger
and bigger impact
and in a traditional model our ability
to change is very high at the start and
at the end it's very low right we have
if we finish the product we've spent our
12 months working on it we've delivered
the usable working product we've
deployed it to production we know no
longer and have an ability to to change
it unless there's more funding more
budget
but very quickly as we get started
building the documentation the more
documentation we build
the more impact change has right a small
change could have a massive impact on
all the documentation we've created
so our ability to to change drops very
quickly and then we start actually
Building Product and perhaps we build
the entire database first or we build
the database and then the mid tier right
and then the uh uh interface that
customers are going to interact with and
we're building it constantly and we've
kind of started everything so our
ability to change drops again it never
drops to zero right
um but throughout the life of the
product it stays very low so it drops
very quickly and then stays very low
across the life of the product
our ability to change in the empirical
model again starts in the same place and
finishes in the same place right we've
got a Time limited uh product cycle but
what happens during that product cycle
is our ability to change remains higher
right higher it's still going to drop
right because every time we deliver a
usable working product the things that
we've already built are harder to change
than things we haven't built yet but
because we're building in those vertical
slices creating working usable product
that the customer can deploy to
production each of those vertical slices
allows the other uh uh 90 right at the
end of Sprint one the rest of the
backlog the stuff we've not created yet
can really can change anything they want
with very little impact right because we
haven't built copious amounts of
documentation we haven't built copious
amounts of product yet so they can
change anything they want
so the idea is that the ability to
change is still going to drop Sprint on
Sprint but it does remain much higher
all the way through the life of the
product and obviously ends in the same
place now let's look at operational risk
an operational risk in a traditional
model we're going to start high
operational risk right because we've not
delivered anything and then when we
deliver our usable working product at
the end of our product cycle 12 months
we're going to have a zero operational
risk because we've deployed a working
product for them
I know there's an assumption there but
uh let's let's assume the best
um and then over the life of the product
we've actually got very high operational
risk if we're six months into our
product cycle what operational risk for
the customer have we alleviated zero
right no operational risk so it needs to
remain high during the life of the
product and then right at the end we
deliver that working usable version of
the product right so we alleviate all of
their operational risk in one big chunk
in an empirical process for operational
risk again we start high and again we
finish low but every Sprint we're
providing a usable working product
so the operational risk gets a little
bit less
at the end of Sprint 2 it gets a little
bit less again because we've delivered
usable working product that solves their
business problem and we end up with that
straight line from top left to bottom
right
right every Sprint we're alleviating
some of that operational risk now in
reality we should alleviate it quicker
if we as a team are focusing on
delivering the most valuable
things that that customer needs to know
first
so that operational risk
might might be more
of a curve
but let's assume it's a it's a straight
line let's take a pessimistic view that
each Sprint we just alleviated that
Sprint's operational risk
finally let's talk about realized value
the delivery of value to the customer
so in a traditional model and we have
zero value at the start of the product
cycle we deliver a working product to
production at the end so we have our our
usable uh working product that perhaps
we delivered our 300 features that the
customer asked for and and
how do we how do we get there well we're
only delivering to production at the end
right the customer can only use the
product once it's in production it only
adds value once it's in production so in
fact we're not delivering anything
during the life of the project and then
right at the end they get their usable
working product obviously it always
works with their 300 features in it that
are exactly what they asked for and uh
they're they're happy because they got
that realized value at the end
but maybe there's a better way
because what did we learn a little bit
earlier in this discussion we learned
that 35
of those features are used by the
customer at the end of that product
cycle only 35 percent right that's like
90 100 110 of those 300 items are
actually used at the end of the product
cycle that's not particularly great so
what could we do instead
using an empirical process there's
actually two ways to draw this graph one
is that we're going to start at zero
value just the same and we're going to
end at those 300 features
so this assumes that we're doing an
empirical process inside of a
traditional organization or working for
a traditional customer the customer says
here's these 300 features we've added
them to the contract right and then
that's what we're going to build and
we're not going to very low variance of
change right because we're going to put
barriers in their way like change
request boards and uh cost you know
having to do a business case to make a
change all of those things we're gonna
we're gonna just deliver those 300
features
but at the end of every Sprint we're
actually able
to deliver them some value right so at
the end of each Sprint
here is some value here's a product that
you can deploy to production that solves
some of your business problem right not
all of it but some of your business
problem
and every single
old Sprint we're delivering a working
usable product along that line
right so the customer is able
to get value from it sooner so if you
think about the the realization of value
at the end of Sprint three they've got
three Sprints worth of value
how much of their business problem is
alleviated already and we're not at the
12 month Mark 12 month Mark where one
quarter of the way through the product
cycle and we've we've alleviated one
quarter of the business problem right
they're adding value as we go along so
they've had the value for longer is what
I mean it's not sitting on a Shelf
because we're able to deploy to
production
but there's indeed a superpower there
because only 35 percent of those 300
features are used so we actually don't
want to build those those 300 features
we want to build a different 300
features right even if we just get to
that 300 mark
so what happens is at the end of Sprint
one
we remove things from the backlog that
we no longer need perhaps the customer
has realized that they asked for stuff
they don't need perhaps the Market's
changed and they no longer need that
perhaps a business decision has been
made right there's a branching decision
this way was one set of 100 features
this way was another set of 100 features
so they added them all to the backlog
but now they've made that decision and
it's this one so we can delete these
hundreds right so we delete those things
and we don't build
some of those things and we take it in a
different direction right we add more
value
sooner in the product cycle as we go and
perhaps we hit that Mark of the same 35
percent of value much sooner perhaps we
hit it in month five
right we could stop there and have
delivered the same value that we would
have delivered in a traditional model
but at
5 12 of The Price my Math's not good
right 5 12 of the price
but what often happens is in the product
cycle we continue
to build features
different features based on the needs of
the business based on collaborating with
customers and stakeholders and we add
way more value to the product
that's if we're using an empirical
process within an organization within a
structure that is accepting of that
level of change
and that is what we want to get from an
agile process so even using an agile
process inside of a traditional
organization we get value we maximize
visibility we maximize our ability to
respond to the changing needs of the
customer we minimize their operational
risk and we continually deliver
value that that customer can amortize
over time right
those are the superpowers of agile even
within a traditional organization if we
can change the organization as well we
can get even more
well thanks very much for listening if
you're interested in uh uh reading a
little bit more in depth into this story
of agile
um I really recommend the new new
product development game it's a harvest
Business review article from 1986 it's
available free online and I also
recommend Stephen Dennings book the age
of agile
if you would like to get in touch with
me please use this QR code right here uh
to book a 30 minute free consultation
with me and we can figure out how we can
make your world a little bit better