question is what's the the biggest
contribution
from a product owner that you know of
and I think I think they're they're I
think there are a lot of great product
owners out there
um great product managers
but the one that I always think of
when I think about great product
management
um is that is is kind of two people in
the same organization both kind of
product owners in the same product which
is confusing because then there's two
product owners right but I'll try and
explain
um and that's that's effectively Brian
Brian Harry
um who was the product unit manager for
uh Team Foundation server for the entire
developer division at Microsoft back in
the day
uh when I was getting into all of this
stuff he was he was the man
and he
um realized
as the single responsible person for
about 650 people
um working on on this products
that a two yearly release Cadence kind
of sucks right
um so that his was the first team in
Microsoft and to start really on mass
start moving towards a greater degree of
agility and
his
the way they came up with within the
context of Microsoft for for doing that
stuff
is almost the model that was replicated
across the organization right it's never
going to be identical right but that's
that's the the when if you hear
Microsoft talking about their
season-based model
um which they do talk about they have
the spring release and the fall release
right this kind of cadence of of bigger
things that they're working on
um of product goals maybe right that's
really what they're talking about is
this season-based model
um where they have that that Urban Flow
of of of work and ideas but Brian Harry
worked on that very much supported by my
other favorite gentleman uh Aaron Bjork
um who was in effect if you're not
familiar with if you're not familiar
with TFS and it's now called as your
devops right that's effectively at what
it is back in the day uh Microsoft was
doing two-year releases of Team
Foundation server and uh visual studio
right kind of can I can go together
doing two yearly releases and what they
found was that the the the the Cadence
for closing the feedback loop
um was actually
four to six years because they were in a
two yearly Cadence it's two to three
times whatever your delivery Cadence of
usable working product is
that's that's ultimately your your
feedback Cadence because what they found
was that that
um you know they would do a beta halfway
through
to get feedback from people
but they'd already
as soon as you you've shipped that beta
you're now working on
this stuff that you need to do for lunch
and the feedback you get on the beta you
can't actually fit it in here because
you don't have anything you don't have
any time left you're all booked
right you've booked out that time for
the stuff you need to do to get it to
production so then you start thinking
about well maybe we can fit it into the
next yearly release and they were able
to fit some stuff in there but what they
also often realized was the closer they
get to that production release they've
already
by the time they finish the beta they're
planning for the next two yearly release
right
so they all they've already booking out
this time as the feedback comes in on
this product
so the earliest you can possibly get
that feedback from the beta into the
actual working product is is is is two
years down the line right or two and a
half up to two and a half years down the
line but in actual fact some staff might
not make it into that time box so it's
the next time box which is another which
is four years four to four and a half
years down the line which is just too
long right it's just too long so what in
realizing that this leadership group uh
in this this organization in this part
of the organization they realized that
they had to do something different and
he led the way in his organization in
making those those changes largely
leveraging the respect uh uh for his
um
I don't know his choices his his wisdom
within the organization the respect and
the rest of the organization for his
wisdom allowed him to maybe do things
that other people weren't able to do or
hadn't been able to do in the past and
he is Relentless this this guy he'll
work 20-hour days no problem at all
um he's just one of those folks that has
that that Outlook
um and he him along with Aaron Bjork
um effectively changed the way Microsoft
do business changed the way Microsoft
approached Building Products
um and changed the whole ethos I mean
not without support right
um somebody else has to come along and
water those ideas and help them grow and
that was Satya who was able to uh uh
come along into Microsoft and then start
encouraging a lot of these ideas uh but
the kernel for these ideas was pre-satio
it was uh the Azure devops team and they
moved to three week three week
continuous Cadence so it in in fact the
product owner who that's that's how I
see the product unit manager right fully
fiscally accountable
um person in your product structure
um they're the ones that are actually
best placed to enable changes in your
organization anyway they're the ones
with the money they're the ones with
well if I'm going to spend your money
building this product I need to be able
to control this and this and this in
order to be most effective at building
this product they're the ones who need
to have that argument it's not your
agile coaches or add your Consultants or
any of these people like what what the
hell do they know about your business
right that's that's that's the attitude
internally
but one of the core purposes of that
that agile coach and consultant is to
help them that person who can make that
change who who does have that respect
inside of the organization who does have
that fiscal accountability make those
changes and that that was the
that huge I just think it's such a huge
contribution
um that Brian Harry and Aaron Bjork made
to to this idea of of Building Products
inside of Microsoft right but Building
Products in general because the whole
ethos of azure devops is about
devops right it's about shortening those
feedback loops what tools do we need to
support that idea and yeah that for me
is the the most powerful powerful story
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility