so the question is why did so many of
the early agile Transformations fail
and I think a better question is just
without the early part on it right why
why do so many agile Transformations
fail because the early ones failed for
the same reason as as as as they do now
and
that's the the people who are doing the
implementation
are not involved in the process of
deciding what we're implementing
right that that that's why that's why
that's why it fails because your your
leadership decides we're going to do it
this way
and everybody else goes okay but that's
the wrong way and suddenly they're
resistive and unhappy because they feel
like it's imposed upon them
um if you know that that old if I'd been
asked I would have right said to do
something different and you get that
through through organizations and it can
be agile Transformations it can be
digital Transformations it can be
um just we're changing something right
the the the the the
in that
top down command and control
triangle model
Alpha organizations right where where
you've you've got the people at the top
are the ones making the decisions and
the people at the bottom are the ones
doing the work and all the decisions are
made at the top and we steer the rest of
the organization based on those
decisions you're always going to get
into that situation where
um the the the people that you need to
do the stuff don't want to do it because
in this context they're smarter than you
are
they have more information they have
more understanding and they perhaps have
more skills in that space so they're the
ones that should be involved in driving
it so I I I I I think there's been a lot
of good work done
um by by
um uh open space agile
um and specifically as well on top built
on top of that open space beta to allow
um
methods systems are we a a mechanism to
be created a practice to be created that
allows you to involve everybody in the
organization and making those decisions
if you involve everybody in the
then even though
it might not be the decision that they
would have made if they were sitting
there on their own right because they
were involved in making that decision
they feel like their voice is heard and
if they feel like their voice is heard
they're more likely to get behind
whatever the ultimate decision was
because it's a collective decision right
decentralization and democratization of
the the the ideas
and then they'll be supporting and
helping with the transition As you move
forward rather than getting in the way
and hindering because they just don't
care because you didn't ask me anyway
um that's what I think is is is why
agile Transformations fail
and I think it's just as true today as
it was in the the early days it's just
in the early days there was a small
number of high profile agile
Transformations and and today there's
there's there's hundreds of thousands of
actual Transformations going on