to be an awesome agile coach you really
need to be part of a community
especially a community that doesn't just
listen to you or doesn't just have the
same ideas as you you don't want to be
in an echo chamber you want to be in a
group of people that are going to
challenge the way you think challenge
the choices that you've made that's
going to say no what you've done is not
good enough in order to be effective at
agile and to help you realize and grow
your experience to be able to deliver
the most value to your customer thanks
for watching the video If you enjoyed it
please like follow And subscribe I
always reply to comments and if you want
to have a chat about this or anything
else agile scrum or devops then please
book a coffee with me through naked
agility