so what are three top tips
for a new agile consultant
um
so I think
the first the first thing is understand
the domain
within which you're working
if you're going to be Consulting on a
particular topic
um like for example going into an
organization that builds some kind of
software product
and helping them get
shorten the feedback loop and get better
at delivering that product then
you want to understand what it takes to
build products
you want to have a keen understanding of
the context within which the teams the
people that are doing the work are
operating because it's the people that
are doing the work that are actually
moving the business forward
um they're directed by directed that's
probably two stronger words
um well it might be depending on your
level of control but they're directed by
above like what direction are we going
what's our goals what's our objectives
but
um they need to
um be intrinsically understanding of
that that context that's the first one
is understand the context of the people
that are doing the work
um
what would be a second thing
listen
probably a very powerful skill
is is is listening to what the people
that are doing the work are saying
and how that what differs or relates to
what leadership sing and what customers
are saying I often do
um interviews across all levels of the
organization when I start working with a
team or with a with a company to really
get an understanding of of what it is
that's going on and and it's incredible
the different stories that are told from
the same perspective from people at
those different levels I remember an
organization where the the the
engineering the leadership was like yeah
we're awesome we do continuous delivery
we've we test everything we've got
automation we're brilliant
um and the people doing the work were
like oh my goodness me we've get no
automation life sucks we're doing
everything manually it's a struggle
every day to get out of bed and go work
on this big pile of crap that we're
delivering
um and and and that that fragmentation
was through a lack of transparency
right and even I spoke to some customers
for that team they managed to get a
couple of customers and they weren't
external they were internal customers to
the organization but they were like yeah
you know we don't tell them about every
problem that we have we actually keep a
separate list of problems because we as
the customer see the engineering teams
as totally overloaded and running around
like with their hair on fire so we feed
them things that we think of as
important right they're creating a
separate backlog of work and
prioritizing it as the customer because
they see the struggle that the
engineering teams are under yet
leadership is like everything's awesome
and we're great right so that that that
that that
listening to people talking to them
finding out what's actually going on at
different levels because everybody's
story is different
um and at every level in the
organization and if you get that
difference in story you know there's a
fundamental problem with transparency
so that's perhaps your first Focus for
organizational change and organizational
shift
and now I've got to come up with a third
one see you need to you need to be able
to articulate what people don't want to
hear
so
I remember before I was able to do that
I went into an organization that had
just gone through a massive reorgan
restructure
um in order to try and Achieve agility
and they'd ended up with a test Silo and
an engineering Silo and an operation
Silo right same old crap
and I was sitting in with the CEO and he
turned to me and said
do I need to pick this apart and do
another big reorg
and I was afraid to say
yes what you've done is wrong
it is not going to achieve the outcome
that you want to achieve
and you're gonna need to redo it with an
eye to cross-functional Vertical slices
value stream right focus on those things
and I was afraid to say that because I
was a lowly uh wet behind the ears
devops consultant back in the day
um and this was sitting in with the CEO
of a large multinational company and I
felt I couldn't couldn't couldn't tell
him he was wrong
um I've since learned and in fact that
that
happens that that that story is one of
my catalysts for
um just saying to people when you think
something's wrong they can always
disagree with you they can always not
like you
um but you need to you need to say you
need to if something's not right and
you're a consultant you're hired because
you have more information
right you've got you've got more insight
uh you're hired for your expert opinion
give it
um even if they're not gonna like what
you're gonna say
so that was three things
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility