so there's a quote from Lau which is if
you do not change direction you may end
up where you're heading and I think
that's that's
absolutely absolutely a thing we have to
be concerned with we want to be
continuously asking
ourselves are we going in the right
direction and that that can be asked at
at many levels right I can be a a a a
developer building um product and I'm
writing code and am I writing the right
code am I taking this product in the
right direction am I making the right
architectural choices am I making the
right security choices right because you
don't want to head in that that
direction where you end up at the end of
a product cycle you're shipping your
product uh to a bunch of a bunch of
users and the there's security flaws and
there's usability issues and there's cuz
we've not been heading in the right
Direction and and that's also true at
the at the product owner level right are
we building the right features in our
product are we going in the right
direction to to maximize our ability to
to to provide benefit in the market and
thus have lots of people use our product
and it also works at the organizational
level um are are are are we as a
business focused on the right Vision are
we going in the right direction and
quite often lots of organiz ations head
off the
cliff and don't change direction right
they forget to look at the data they
forget that the world is ever changing
and ever
Dynamic um and that where you thought
you were going might not be the right
place for you there's a great example
it's a product I use uh called it used
to be called zoom. a nothing to do with
uh Zoom the video conferencing tool um
but it allowed you it was BAS basically
a an AI um assistant that would help you
with booking your meetings so you could
add them on on teams you could add them
on whatever chat platforms you've got
and I could just message it and say uh
you know set me up a meeting with uh uh
with Satia at 3:00 on Thursday right and
it would go off and it would email Satia
and say you know we've got this meeting
to set up um how would you like it to to
be you want to pick your pick your valid
options and it would figure out from
everybody's valid options what's a good
time uh uh to host that meeting and then
it would just book it right it would
book it straight into your calendar and
and and book it um but they they
realized that that's not how people use
their product most people that used
their product just went to the website
and booked through the website right
they they they literally went new
meeting here's who I want to attend
submit and that would go off and do it
so they weren't going going through the
chatbot so the chatbot was largely
irrelevant to their business outcome to
the thing that they were delivering that
people were using was largely irrelevant
um so they actually changed their whole
business strategy in order to fit how
people were using their product right
they're taking advantage of an
opportunity that arose instead of
heading in the direction that they were
heading they pivoted maybe not far right
but they pivoted over to a different
direction and they actually renamed
their entire organization they they they
reasserted all of their interfaces and
stuff around this this this is the
Paradigm that people are actually using
in our product and
that's something that lots of
organizations don't do um what's a good
example of things not happening that way
are the oh I'm not going to remember the
dude's name
um but the the the the the dude that was
doing the high jump and he was doing the
high jump everybody at the time was
doing the high jump one leg
first right um and he started doing it
he was the first person to start going
backwards doing the back flip over the
high jump and he was winning gold medal
and totally outing all of the comp like
going far higher than everybody else for
10 years
before everybody else went oh actually
we maybe we should do it that way maybe
maybe that's better he seems to be
getting better results why does it take
10 years because this is the way we've
always done things we're going in that
direction and we like to keep going in
that direction that's our comfortable is
to keep doing the thing that we've
always been doing and perhaps keep doing
the thing you've always been doing is
going the wrong way if you want to have
a discussion about your unique needs or
situation then please book a call or
visit us at naked agility tocom uh we
also have our immersive and traditional
public classes on our website and we'd
love to hear from you