foreign so the question is what's my
advice for becoming a scrum Master
outside of software engineering
I don't I think that's a that's an
interesting topic because
in order to be a scrum Master be a
successful effective scrum master I
believe that you need to be able to
um understand fully the work that the
team is doing so it makes the most sense
for a scrum Master to be somebody who
has been part of a team doing the thing
that they're going to scrum master has
been in that domain has been part of
those those organizations and has worked
their way to that advanced position
which is the scrum master
um as a change leader in the in as part
of a team right so if you want to be a
scrum master and you're not currently in
the ite software world then what
probably makes the most sense is to be
part of a team doing what you like and
enjoy doing anyway
right I was speaking to somebody
recently who has an accounting
background and wants to be a scrum
Master to accounting teams to help
accounting organizations get better at
doing accounting right and that's really
what what you want to be and being an
experienced team member doesn't mean
that you're awesome at the thing the
team does right you don't actually have
to be awesome at coding to be a scrum
Master for a coding team
but you have to understand
the coding you have to understand the
ramifications of devops you have to
understand the ramifications of
automated build automated testing of uh
what it means to be a software engineer
or means to be a tester right in that
space so if you want to be a scrum
master and your background is accounting
what better place to start than joining
an accounting team in an accountancy
firm and then working slowly to help
improve the way they work and at some
point that team that you work with
is going to be seen to be more
successful than other teams in the
organization and somebody's going to
come along and ask why why is this team
more accessible successful why is it
doing better why are are people on this
team happier than the other teams that
we have in our organization and they're
going to come and ask and your boss is
going to say well I don't know but if
you go speak to Bob right he's he's been
leading that those ideas and maybe maybe
Bob can tell you a little bit more about
how that works and then you build a name
for yourself you're given more
accountability and responsibility within
the organization and you can do it at a
higher and higher level across across
the arc for me that's that's that's
leadership right that's the leader who
serves from the scrum kite