if you want to be an agile coach one
thing you must be is agnostic in your
practices while you may have a favorite
mine is Scrum you need to ensure that
the team the people you're working with
are able to choose the most effective
practices that work for them and that
means sometimes not picking the one that
you like you want to encourage and
enable them to understand the principles
that
underpin the the lean principles the
agile principles and perhaps the scrum
principles as well to enable them to
make better choices thanks for watching
the video If you enjoyed it please like
follow And subscribe I always reply to
comments and if you want to have a chat
about this or anything else agile scrum
or devops then please book a coffee with
me through naked
agility