in order to be successful organizations
need trust and Trust comes from the
virtue of
patience your organization needs
patience and tolerance with the people
in the organization who are doing the
best they can within the context that
they have and hopefully trying to create
the best possible product if they're
trying to create the best possible
product um and something goes wrong
there's a failure um things don't go
like we expect or we create something
that doesn't look like we
expect sometimes that's just a fact of
life right not everything's going to go
the way you want it not all of the
outcomes are going to be what you want
everything that we create when we're
building products is something that may
or may not work out may or may not be
successful um and we're we're taking a
BET right we're saying we think this
feature this capability is going to be
successful or we think these practices
are going to work for us as we're trying
to do things in the organization we
think this new tool is going to work and
we don't know any of those things are
true until we actually get to the end of
that process or at least someway through
that process and we have something
usable that we can validate um with our
with our customers with our us ERS with
our with in our world um to be able to
um create good outcomes so businesses
need to be patient with teams leaders
need to be patient with people um
product owners need to be patient with
the product right with the people that
are building stuff in the product are we
getting to where we need to go if we get
um uh
frustrated and create a blame cult
within our organization we are not going
to be successful cuz we're going to
erode the trust that is the foundation
to empiricism and one of the key things
we need to build trust is patience if
you are having difficulty getting the
most out of the Seven Virtues of agility
then my team at naked agility can help
you or find a consultant coach or
trainer who can it's essential for you
to find help as soon as you can and not
wait you use the links below to get in
touch because you don't just need
agility you need naked agility