well I think so the question is what is
the most valuable lesson
you'll you've learned as an agile
consultant and and I think you could
take the word agile out and it's just
the most valuable lesson I've learned as
a consultant in whatever flavor right
I've ended up working in and that's that
quite often the statement of work in
fact almost always the statement of work
Bears no relevance to the problems that
the customer actually has
and that's where
you have to try and tread carefully
because it is is your business is my
business as a consultant in delivering a
statement at work or is it maximizing
the value that I bring to the customer
right
and quite often Consultants will deliver
to the stem to work right here's the
contract this is what we've been told we
have to do and we need to deliver to
that contract
um I find that that's a losing
proposition because you can quite often
and this happens a lot have unhappy
customers
because you've delivered what they asked
for but it's not what they need right it
doesn't actually bring any systemic
lasting change to their to their
organization and things go back to the
way they were as soon as you leave
because there's not that that change
because the statement of work didn't
include it or a scope for it
um a great example of that was
um
I was on a train uh
in in England somewhere and it had Wi-Fi
on the train and the Wi-Fi was
absolutely horrendous absolutely
horrendous
and I I think I tweeted at the the train
company and that's using my mobile
signal when I could and basically said
your Wi-Fi is completely unusable on the
train completely unusable and the answer
I got back obviously from their
marketing team right because that's
where Twitter goes uh was well we're not
contractually obligated to provide Wi-Fi
so
of yours right that was pretty much the
the answer that came back from them it's
like it's not in the contract so if it
doesn't work we don't care right and
that to me
is is is that idea taking to a little
bit too extreme right of just following
what's in the contract I I quite often
don't like having contracts at all with
with with customers because because of
that I want to be able to dynamically
and adaptively figure out what it is
they need when we get on the ground and
get engaging and for most customers I
work with I just have a a a variable
contract an email contract right can you
come and help us out yes I can come and
help you out what dates can you come
these dates okay I'm there right and
that's enough for me to go go book
flights right pre-covered book flights
uh turn up on site and and help them out
and then invoice them afterwards and I
never never had a problem never been
burned I'm sure now I've said that it
will probably happen right but
um never had a problem uh for the big
large customers right they come with
their own contracts that they like you
to sign and then do EAS and all of those
things I just assume NDA right for for
every customer I work with
um but but
those bigger organizations of bigger
contracts lock you in to delivering
something that the procurement we need
right in the organization is going to
hold you to regardless of whether you're
delivering value to the customer so you
have to deliver enough value that the
people that you're working with will
happily just tick that box and say Yes
Martin delivered right what what what
what's in this statement of work when
actually there's no relationship between
what's in the statement of work and what
was delivered but we delivered what they
needed at the level they needed that
provided them with the value they needed
to not worry about what was written in
the contract
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility