you
oh my name is Martin Henchy wit special
scrum trainer with scrum dark I want
little chat today I'm
some of this information comes from some
well-known sources I'm going to
elaborate on those saucy
party
you
Hey
80% 81% all development shops see
they're agile
that's based on Forrester Research that
of that 81% around 80% and 82% I think
and our say that they're doing however
the reality that almost 81% of them are
lying that's the thing that we find
anybody out there who is a trainer a
coach a scrum master at will know that
these things are almost never
so how can we tell the real thing
from what might be considered
I do have some very concrete measures we
can use they are not mine they come from
another organization which I will
describe I just find them interesting
enough
you
only 22% of organizations and short
iterations
that's iterations of six weeks or less
the manifesto does say that we should
have
six weeks or less or get stuff in front
of our customers six weeks or less the
scrum guy you would see at 30 days our
last one
but if you don't have short iterations
and
are the only ones that do then the
likelihood of you being
and only 16% have an order backlog this
is one I do not understand if an
organization is going to spend
honey
getting there
having a team of software engineers
working through a body of work why would
you not want to make working on the most
sixteen percent have an ordered backlog
you'll probably find that
we have something they would call a
backlog at all
only 13% do retrospectives closing that
feedback loop it's super important and
how do we make sure that don't do the
same thing wrong all the time tight
act or not just what we just did but how
we did it
it better store so this data that I'm
using here and comes from Forrester
Research I have a slide which with the
the original data for that I found it
pretty interesting
feel free to and have 50 yourself
because really the reality today with
organizations is that while it looks
like
hey they're doing the right thing it's
secret is we're all a mess in sight I
don't know any service orientated
organization I'm actually I'm thinking
of
thank where I've heard of our consultant
developer going in and really liking
what
behind-the-scenes things tend to be a
little bit interesting
you
let me check at the the I can do
something about the sound
you
so I'm not sure if I managed to actually
fix the sound or do something about it
hopefully that's ah
one comment on why it's so hard to
change it's it's a cultural thing we
like to as humans we like to do really
the same thing we get stuck in our way
of doing something and unless we feel
that we're empowered to make changes
through that process then um it's it's
very very difficult I just googled why
has changed so hard and Dilbert and I
had a plethora of choices for em but
what constitutes
so there's something that we all know
and love this is the the tyranny of
terrorism and being very specific here
I'm trying to avoid the term waterfall
for for very specific reason
look at them as I go through but
ultimately you'll see this process
reflected in many organizing
fireman's through to designing through
to implement the verification and
maintenance you might even see in
organization that they have HR
department they have our sales
department they have our IT department
they have an apartment as completely
separate entities and there's a very
good reason why we ended up in that
position it's not necessarily good now
but for the time when those ideas came
about it was the right way to approve
but times have changed we have more
understanding of how humans interact
with work we have more understanding
about the complexities of a lot of the
world and most people know do a
cognitive work so let's have look why do
we work that way so we need to kind of
go back in time a little bit go back to
three at nineteen eighteen ninety before
eighteen ninety people generally lived
pretty close to where they work they
whenever they had a problem they just
rallied around and figured out how to
solve it supportive innovation I need to
work very very close to their family and
and if you were doing a job you did the
whole job not just part of the job so
you can see there the the cobbler on the
right the apprentice learning how to
make the shoe and the reality is that
that cobbler probably knew the person
who they were making the shoe for the
knew what their job was how they were
going to use the shoe that product and
the cobbler can make that shoe with that
person in mind they probably made that
person's previous
and they know that that person can come
back in and whenever they've got a
problem with the shoe so they get old
they can they'll know all the experience
that that user that person has had with
that work and that's a very powerful way
to build products that have a very high
Happiness ratio with theirs but how do
we scale that it can be very difficult
so in just after the 1890s the
Industrial Revolution kicked off into
food and it was a time of lots of money
was made but you can see in those
pictures that there are people doing
very individual tasks I would struggle
to even understand what these folks were
making something around for sure with
boats in it it could be clocks it could
be parts for cars it could be um washing
machines it could be any sort of device
we don't really know and it doesn't
really matter for the individual sitting
at their workstation they only need to
do the one thing I usually use the
example of Charlie and the Chocolate
Factory
and Charlie's dad's had a job before he
lost his job to a robot and his job was
screwing the top on toothpaste bottles
like a very
ask and when we do menial tasks our
brains disengage from the work so what's
what's that's the difference here is
that on the Left we have the cobbler
making the custom shoe for the
individual person that they know that
they interact with they understand the
whole process whereas on the right we
have the factory floor where the
individual users don't really don't
really even care don't even need to know
what the thing is that they are creating
they probably have some idea it's
probably difficult to work in a factory
and not know output is but do they
really understand how their piece of the
puzzle contributes to the overall thing
they're just doing exactly what they're
told
so there were two really big thought
leaders at the time the first was a
gentleman called Frederick Winston
Taylor and he has a comment that I think
you'll find very in keeping with our
understanding of how current management
practices like that think of this is the
foundation of current management
practices hardly a competent worker can
be found Tudor does not devote a
considerable amount of time to studying
just how slowly they can work and still
convince their employer that they are
yes
if you think about that position of
distrust that people are trying not to
work and that's a very common mental
practice for management for project
managers for the way people manage their
people in the world today
other are not saying as everybody there
are lots of progressive people out there
but is a very common mindset and they're
starting to change but it's changing
very slowly
they were invented something called the
scientific management method
and it was based on the knowledge at the
time so what they did was they developed
standard methods for performing each job
best practices they divided workers into
appropriate ability based groups for
each job so and you know they're going
to have the steelworkers
the for one of a better expression the
project managers the coders the testers
the operations having them all as
separate ability based groups they
understand that so they should all work
together on that one task you saw in the
pictures of the factory floor and the
they have everybody that does that one
task together so they can deliver those
standards they train the workers in
those standard methods because there's
no no thought we need to remove thinking
and we're just going to plan their work
so they do it the way we tell them to do
it and and we're going to create a bunch
of wage incentives to
you'll see some of these things in maybe
the current management practices of your
organization
hopefully you work in a more progressive
organization but Taylor had somebody who
came after him kind of a disciple
somebody who looked up to his work and
that was a gentleman called Henry Gantt
and Henry Gantt and came up with some
things we know and love today apart from
the Gantt chart but he created the tasks
and bonus system of which payment he
created our basic wage based on expected
low performance so if we think from a
position of distrust of our employees
they're gonna try and work less so let's
pay them like we expect them to work so
pay them last for their work and then
we'll give them bonuses if they manage
to meet the expected professions
that we we sent a vice by default and
also if we're going to have all of these
folks that need told what to do because
we're removing thinking then we need
managers to manage them
the Pyke's t of the work you might need
more managers and you might need
managers to manage the managers but the
manager should be motivated based on
getting bonuses on the outcomes of their
staffs so if you think of well I worked
in Merrill Lynch I had to fill out a
bunch of status reports at the end of
each week which I would give to my dev
leet who elected them together for all
of their direct reports and passed it on
up the chain everybody had a head count
they were accountable for that head
count and the amount that was delivered
they also henry gantt and came up with
this thing is is unknown i like to call
the modern school system and you may
hear folks refer to the modern school
system even today and when they refer to
it they're referring to this something
little bit like this picture here let's
that was like my class in school
although this was a lot further ago and
but everybody in a modern school
everybody sits in rows people do the
same thing at the same time there's no
talking you gotta put your hand up and
incentive based learning and reward for
fulfilled tasks these are techniques
designed a factory workers the modern
school system was designed to do that
was thank decree remove thinking and
just do it you're told
just follow the set of tasks you've been
given it doesn't matter if you don't
understand it
[Music]
so many of us grew up in the system many
of our kids are in more of a hybrid
system where teachers are trying to push
away from this idea of rules but they
you know they're they're struggling
against a system like we are that
defaults to the old way you go to those
places in the Netherlands where they
have changed the school system to be or
in keeping with what we expect
group Isis learning together presenting
the stuff that happened in the modern
workplace so really there's no
difference between the modern school
system and that management scientific
management
nostril revolution in the factory floor
these two folks optimized for output and
not outcome you're our coach or a
trainer at following this you'll know
that's already and but I find that
knowing why something is a certain way
help us combat some of the the eight
years and in 1908 and this was the first
Harvard Business School I think this
might be the graduating class of Harvard
Business School and and loads of the the
leaders of the time the the people who
would be managers at the time or who are
going to be managers at the time and
flocked to these and
schools doing MBAs so this was the first
MBA and we know those ideas have lasted
for a long time in the 50s this this new
way of working started to emerge and
become more prevalent across the board
not just as part of option align process
so dividing people into specialist
skills marketing sales contracts
development testing and all of our
separate things
and and create things sequentially in
hand things between the different
sections that doesn't think you know the
complexity of the work
then round about the 1950s the US
military complex who is I think still
the largest buyer in the world it's it's
they have a lot of employees
a lot of people that work with them a
lot of consultants and because they wear
such a large buyer and their their power
to push vendors and consulting companies
towards this model that they wanted to
use was immense and most people couldn't
escape it and if you work with any large
consulting company they probably work
with the Department of Defense
especially at the time and if you work
with the varmint event you must do this
this new staged process so we adopt it
and eventually it just becomes part of
their procurement Sassy's that's also
the Chairman processes that we know and
love
and that I struggle with when I'm
working with customers I even had an
engagement with a with a customer and
because it was uh I think it was I
remember the the big consulting company
I was working with and I was doing a
short engagement like a day's worth of
work and they couldn't figure out how to
pay me their procurement processes so I
basically handed me a stack of cash
because they just couldn't figure out it
wasn't worth the effort of going through
the process I didn't get training
engagement at Royal Bank of Scotland in
Edinburgh because they couldn't get the
procurement process done in time it was
just not possible yes that seems to be
the way things are and a lot of our
larger organisations with a little
bureaucracy bureaucracy comes with these
different departments and separating
people into that work so if we fast
forward again to the current modern
times and this stuff was applied to
software development and it didn't work
out so well
expediency is that off but I've got an
interesting article so um the largest
organization in the world with the most
employees in the world as realized they
made a mistake this particular
organization and as 2.8 million
employees largest employer and a 739
billion dollar budget they are in fact
the Department of Defense in the US and
they have realized that they've created
this monster that is the sequential
working process and it's gone through
all companies are in the world so in
[Music]
2010 they brought in a bunch of agile
folks so I believe I believe Jeff
Sutherland was there Kent Beck was there
a few other folks I don't know what
everybody that was involved and they got
together to rewrite how can we change
our procurement rules to take advantage
of these new thinking and new ways so
they pulled it all together and and the
new procurement rules which mandated
short iterative cycles of delivered
value to to the customer which is on the
defense at went live in 2013 but as you
can imagine and now that the procurement
rules have been changed
agile then becomes a buzzword of
software development and therefore all
projects now declare themselves to be
agile and so the department events
created this document called detecting
add ups that is for their procurement
officers to really understand what it
what it is they're looking for in a
vendor when a vendor says they're agile
how do you know they're telling the
truth how
you know
I so I have here and some questions for
you this is a small number of questions
and I usually do this in a large
auditorium so I usually get everybody to
stand up I'm gonna stick to questions
and after each question if your answer
is no then you should sit down obviously
you do it metaphorically so the first
question our team's delivering working
software to at least some subset of real
users every iteration including the
first and gathering feedback I'm gonna
clarify real users real users does not
mean you a t-bill users does not mean
attack
users means people using your software
in a production environment real users
means
if you aren't doing that and you're not
you're not agile and that's step one are
you doing this
getting real feedback and otherwise
there's no agility there second question
is there a product charter that lays out
the strategic goals of your project and
do all members of the team understand
what they are and how
how the work they do contrary
and if not then you're not doing agile I
would recommend a book called turn this
ship around by David Marquette talks
about pushing responsibility down the
organization helping everybody
understand at what the goals directives
are so that they can make better
decisions and stop telling people what
to do
that's this next one our team's
empowered to change their process based
on what they learn and they can they
change their iteration pace can they
change what they do their review
perspectives can they choose to do scrum
can they choose to do a Kanban can they
choose to do something else and all of
those things need to be true otherwise
and agile again oh three more questions
that was number three is feedback from
users turned into concrete work items
for Sprint teams on timelines shorter
than a month
I need to get feedback from those users
that in the first one we delivered our
real software - and we get feedback from
them and we update the product backlog
we bring that information our planning
of the of the future on timescales
shorter than one mark if not then
unfortunately we're still not doing
agile our team is empowered to change
requirements based on user feedback this
can be a real problem in bureaucratic
organizations that have a separation or
still have a separation between
contracts sales and engineer
shouldn't be that separation to this
type of thing you have are a concrete
thing signed off by somebody who doesn't
really understand the interest in
actually building stuff you go to build
stuff you get in front of users user
needs a change wants something different
what you're working on is not quite
right we need to be able to make those
changes and if not then yep you guessed
it we're not doing edge and the last one
I think is or is that the second
M is the full ecosystem of your project
agile agile programming teams followed
by linear bureaucratic deployments
ealier ultimately there should be no
human interaction between a developer
committing a line of code and getting
into production if you're going to have
human interaction it should be limited
to the clicking of an approval button or
some kind of sign-off process it should
not be any script any deployments any
reading server setting up that none of
none of those things
and if you can't say yes to all of those
questions then you're probably not it
and Ross that line into the world
and those are those are hard lines to
cross and this example is from the
Department of Defense in the u.s. they
apply this now for both hardware and
software so if you're building a new
guided missile for the Department of
Defense
all of these things need to be true
order for you
when that procurement and I think that's
that's hard I don't think they're
definitely not there yet that's why
they're doing this
this article in order to encourage
people to move a little bit faster and
do those things but ultimately by
improving our processes and practices by
getting quicker at delivering by using
those feedback loops and large projects
can get up to 600 percent more more
success and more likely to be successful
not numbers smaller for small projects
because the risk is less they're usually
closer to the customer is easier to have
a discussion and change what you're
doing in a small project but in large
projects that can be incredibly
difficult there's a lot of legacy code a
lot of legacy ideas legacy procedures
and practices and that that can be
difficult now I would encourage you to
look at other folks processes and see
the way they do it
I like the largest company I know of to
have actually made a successful agile
transformation our agile evolution or
start their agile evolution is Microsoft
they've made a lot of changes in the
last eight years they moved to
continuous delivery and are doing all of
those things but don't just look at
somebody else's process and try and
rubber stamp it onto your own and there
are many practices out there they're
safe the Spotify model I always find the
Spotify model I'm using because of the
the article was a point in time
don't do this here's what we're doing
now and the Spotify is not doing what it
describes in that article anymore
they've moved on from there and these
are maybe our starting point a place to
glean some ideas but make sure you have
the ability to create dynamic
create and manage your process and and
I'll leave you with a lovely mammal or a
statement from the US Air Force this is
a clarifying statement about a mammal
and it says if you read the top
underlined and highly discuss
discouraged from using rigid
prescriptive frameworks such as scaled
agile framework and safe framework and
in an effort to move towards a DevOps
and a more dev cell cops whatever you
want to call it DevOps and agility and
things like safe and any prescriptive
model is potentially harmful to your
ability to innovate potentially harmful
to your ability to change and it's not
used by successful software commercial
organizations should be an indicator
as I would say that the art of
simplicity is a puzzle of complexity we
have to try and make things as simple as
possible
do that over time well thanks for
watching hopefully you enjoyed beam I'm
hoping the silent problem was a little
limited to a particular time frame and
if not I will have to look at and I
managed that
very much
you