so the co the core value of the product
owner class is that the the the the the
core value of the learning right you're
gonna You're Gonna Learn a bunch of
stuff about the product owner how it
works what it isn't what it is you're
going to get an assessment where you're
able to hopefully pass that assessment
and get a credential
um that's really the core value
proposition is understanding the product
owner
perhaps getting the credential and
looking forward into where do I learn
things next
um the added value of the eight week
class is actually being able to connect
the things that we're talking about in
the class back to your real world
organization try and practice some of
those things and then get feedback on it
on a regular basis so instead of two
full days it's eight weekly four-hour
sessions