so the question is what is the most
destructive thing that a client can do
to an agile consultant
and I think it's shut them down it's not
not let them engage not let them uh
speak and engage with people in your
organization because I feel like the
purpose of being a consultant is
actually quite it's quite often to be
difficult right because if if if if
all we do as an agile consultant is
please the customer nothing's ever going
to change nothing's going to be going to
be different
so instead of pleasing the customer
what's what's what's what's what's the
other side of that right what what's the
the the opposite of pleasing the
customer and you know it's it's being
difficult it's asking difficult
questions it's poking at things why is
this the way it is right and and
that needs to be enabled and encouraged
by the stakeholders in the organization
if they're going to bring in a
consultant because those are the
questions that enact
not an act change that enable the people
in your organization to think about why
something's the way it is and that act
of thinking about why something the way
it is is quite often the Catalyst for
the change that's needed in the
organization
um so so
allowing your Consultants
to be difficult add ask hard questions
and provoke people is is is actually
critical to to that value that you're
getting from an agile consultant
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility