hmm that's a good one what what would I
hope to achieve with a new scrum team in
the first 90 days uh 90 days should be
enough for everything that's that's
that's my my view
um it depends on where the team is and
where their organization is and what the
organizational constraints are going to
be because I'm sure there's
organizations I've gone in to help teams
with where there is very limited support
from the rest of the organization and
then you're working within that bounded
box right and you can poke at it but you
get limited ability to do that
but if you have
an open receptive organization an open
receptive leadership within the
organization you you you should be able
to take them from zero to a hundred in
in 90 days right they should be able to
go from from barely able to deliver
a working product or not delivering a
working product at the end of every
every Sprint
um to continuous continuous delivery in
that time that that that should be where
you want to get them that the the end of
that 90 days
um they are able to continuously deliver
a usable working product to production
separating out the ideas of release
right which is a business idea and
delivery which is an engineering
practice and enable the product owner to
um better represent the value right that
the business now have an understanding
of of uh the value or what value is for
them right because that's different for
every organization what valued means to
them so that you can then have rational
conversations with them about what
things are more important than other
things and why so that you have a
ordered backlog a direction a goal right
what is it we're trying to achieve
together and that then informs that
release side right what are we actually
going to ship you've got that
engineering side with the continuous
delivery of value to to to to to
production right continuously delivered
to production and then you mesh that
together then closing the feedback loop
right with learning so are you then able
to collect uh collect Telemetry and talk
to users and figure out whether you're
actually building the right thing or the
business value idea is actually correct
have you validated them and then close
that feedback loop all the way around to
change what it is we're working on based
on those things that we learned
that's that's kind of the minimum that I
would expect to get to in in 90 days and
then hopefully within those 90 days I
found somebody within that organization
who is able to be the champion for this
this process or everyone being the
champion for this process this new way
of working going forward so that at the
end of 90 days right I can I can back
off
um let them get on with it right they
they've built their their
um unique glove organizational structure
right that fits them like a glove that
they're then able to to take forward and
use
um and then perhaps be available to help
tweak coach answer questions and be
available after that but ultimately it's
it's it's their problem to solve it's
their work to do
um and if we can get them to a certain
place in the first 90 days that they
understand it then they should be able
to take it from there
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility