there's a little bit of a a fear um of
uh in in incomplete migrations that
things won't be you won't have them
available when you move to the to the to
the cloud I I've done hundreds of
migrations using
Microsoft's uh import tool that actually
the the database import uh uh tool and I
have never had any data loss in any
context
whatsoever wasn't known about beforehand
there are certain things that don't work
in the cloud that you can do on Prem um
you can you can increase the database
attachment size on Prem um and that will
unfortunately um not be possible in the
cloud right because there's other people
on the system you're not just uh uh it's
not just your company so you're not the
ones just the only ones taking the
taking the hit for performance issues
for having attachments that are too big
or um build lists that are bigger than
normal um so there are some things but
upfront when you're planning the
migration uh we need to call those
things we need to cut them down we need
to figure out how to resolve those
things and Microsoft provide tooling to
help understand what those things are
what the impact is um and what we need
to do in order to make our environment
viable for moving up to to aure devops
um so the there's not really any such
thing of a as of a incomplete migration
within that context it will just work um
I've had migrations get stuck and then
we have to back off restore uh turn back
on right that's how you restore you turn
it back on turn back on TFS locally um
and then replan something because
something's gone wrong or something
needs to be done on Microsoft's end but
usually especially if it's a bigger
migration um you talk to Microsoft first
and they have a support team uh uh
available who know you're doing a
migration um and you can email them and
they'll go kick the environment or
figure out what the problem is at the
time so that you can continue um so in
incomplete migrations from that
perspective are not a big deal if you're
doing a ad hoc pce meal migration like
you're moving the bits and pieces that
you want to move um like would you just
want to move this team or this subset of
this team or this project or just this
data right um
then we will know upfront exactly what
you can and cannot do within the context
of that migration but it's not something
it's not something we can Define at this
point because it it's wholly dependent
upon your data the format of your data
what you want to move what you're okay
with losing right um and having
conversations around that so you'll know
upfront um so when it gets to migration
time uh there shouldn't be any surprises
at all