so the question is if you're working in
traditional a traditional project
management world I know everybody has
quams about the word traditional but
what people have always done um
traditional project management world and
you're I guess daunted by this idea of
of of agile and the changes that need to
happen in order to get there then
probably a a a cand strategy is is a way
that you can gain
benefits over over over a longer period
of time so what lots of lots of teams
and organizations get benefit from
jumping to a scrum process right it it
it highlights where you've got problems
it very quickly identifies things in
your organization that inhibit the
ability for you to move towards towards
an agal process but quite often
depending on the organization that can
be too much too fast um you you can end
up with just bad scrum right we we we
we're going to call everything with the
agile terminology use use the scrum
terminology but in actual fact uh we're
not going actually going to make any
changes to the way we do things so maybe
a better approach for those types of
organizations that don't have the
willingness to change and by the way the
best time to change the way you do
things in an organization is when your
organization has completely and utterly
failed to deliver or achieve something
that's when people are most open to
change so that's where you might bring
in a radically different process like
scrum uh but the advantage of a cand
strategy is you start from where you are
right now cand strategy does not require
you to change the way anybody
works I'll I'll I'll say that again a
cban strategy applying a cand strategy
creating and applying a cand strategy
does not require anybody in your
organization to change the way they work
right
now that's really important to
understand caman is not a way of doing
things it's not a process in itself it's
observational it observes your existing
process and gives you data and
information about how effective it is
being that's the purpose of a CA
strategy so you don't need to change the
way you work you just need to document
how you work right now that's your
definition of workflow right you write
down how you work right now and then you
need to collect some
metrics once you've collected those
metrics you're going to look at
them and you're going to see if there
are any patterns that allow you to
identify things that need to change
that's
it so one person you as the project
manager in your
organization can
yourself Implement parts of a cand
strategy you can at least collect the
data right you can you can load it out
of jira or as your devops into tools um
you can you can you can pull it into a
spreadsheet and figure this stuff out
right so you have the the start date and
the end date the age of the work items
because you get the start date and the
end date you get the cycle time right
how long things take to go through the
process and then you can do some data
analysis on
that you can start to you can you can
you can plot it in a in a cycle time
scatter plot and look for outliers
there's a number of graphs that you
would definitely use within the context
of caman and each of those graphs are
there to visualize the flow of work
through your system right once you
visualize the flow of work through your
existing system that you've not changed
how everybody
works you'll then see things that you
want to have a conversation about it's
it's actually quite quite uh
startling how easy it is once you point
out once you do the graph and somebody
like like myself who's been trained to
read the graphs and have read graphs
from lots of teams point at some things
and say what's this why why is this
group of things kind of like this and
then you're like oh yeah I I can see
that too it's very once you understand
the patterns that you're looking for
it's very easy to
identify at least initially right when
we're when we've not made any changes to
the system it's very easy to identify
anomalies it's it's going to be super
obvious you'll have you'll have things
like lots of dots clumped together
you're like what's that well that was a
release okay well is that the best way
to do that or you've got all of these
dots way up up on your your your cycle
time scatter plot cuz they took a really
long time to complete it's like why did
these all take a long time to complete
well we've got to get the Architectural
Review Board to approve this thing um
and they they only sit once every six
months oh right so you can only get
architectural stuff approved once every
six months what happens if you need a
change in between sorry I'm using this
example because I worked in this
environment what happens if you need a
change in between well you need to stop
work put it into the Architectural
Review Board and they meet every six
months so you need to wait and it it
could take years to deliver a a product
because you need to make changes to
it those types of things you probably
already know some of them right you
already know that some of those things
in your organization are broken you know
it handan strategy will give you the
data to prove it and if you can prove it
you can put it in front of somebody who
can do something about it and say look
at the data I would like to run an
experiment stuff's taking a really long
time to complete I think this is the
problem this data is telling me that
this is the problem I'd like to change
this and we can see if the data
improves you just Chang your
system you just
optimized your
system keep doing that and you'll get to
the most optimal system
for the type of work that you're doing
which will be different for every team
every group everybody right but that's
how you make that transition you need to
understand how the system works in order
to be able to make the
change so how long would it take to
transition from traditional uh uh
project management to cban as long as it
takes right you optimize as much as you
need at whatever speed you
want and that that's up to you if your
current system of work is failing you
then you would benefit from creating and
applying a camand strategy our
professional cand trainers and
Consultants are ready to help don't wait
the sooner you start the sooner you'll
improve get in touch below