so the question is what what is the
difference between a newbie scrum master
and a seasoned experienced scrum master
and I think it's their approach
right so so when you're when you're new
at something and you have lots of
choices on the way you approach a
problem
you're gonna pick away and try it right
you're gonna practice
and
the result of that
gives you a little bit more experience
right some XP points to to start
leveling up and figuring out what are
the things that you know work
better within a context
right because I guess it depends on the
context of the team that you're working
with the context of the organization and
if you shift those you might have to
relearn a lot of stuff again
but
the the the the
season scrum Master already has a bunch
of that knowledge and experience
and quite often those experienced scrum
Masters go off and you know write books
and blog posts and and do videos that
that the Newbie Scott Masters are going
to watch to try and get a leg up but
there's a difference between knowledge
which is what you're gaining that way
and the experience of how to use it
right because those those experienced
scrum Masters have seen
this is the practice that I I kind of
like that's my default right so I'm
going to default to this
but you know for this type of company
that's probably not the best way to do
it maybe I need to go to to want to try
one of these other practices because I
know already before I walk in the door
that this one's not going to work or
it's not going to work yet right I know
that I can get a group of a group of
people in a company to move towards this
thing by doing these little steps along
the way so I'm going to try each of
those steps yeah so I think the
fundamental difference is is iterative
and incremental right actually living
the scrum dream rather than just talking
about it I.E it's not a bullion value
proposition
using scrum in an organization it's not
a you're doing scrum you're not right
it's it's a it's a
you've got a journey to get from what
people aren't doing like where you want
them to get to and usually those things
are not they're doing a daily scrum
right who gives a crap about a daily
scrum right do they continuously and
transparently understand as a team where
they are on a daily basis right that's
what the value proposition we want over
here how are you going to get the team
towards that so that they understand
what's going on on a daily basis their
tactical daily daily situation what
about their their long-term strategic
right do they understand going forward
into the future over the next five or
six iterations that they're working on
or five or six things that they're
they're doing do they understand what
direction they're going right do they
understand the overall strategic
direction of the product
right if they don't understand those
things we need to bring in mechanisms to
help them get there and I think uh a
newbie scrum Master will go straight for
the for the end game oh we need a
product goal right well let's deploy a
product goal now that's fixed right and
they wonder why why it doesn't actually
change the way the team's working it
doesn't actually change the value
proposition that the organization's
getting but the the battle hardened
season scrum Master will know that if
you go straight for this it will become
mechanical nobody will get it they'll
just do it because they've been told to
do it not because they understand the
value of that thing therefore they want
to do it and want it to work well right
everybody in the team has to do has to
want to do it and want it to work well
in order for this thing to be successful
and this is true for whole companies as
well not just for a team right micro and
macro
so the seasoned experience scrum Master
is going to start
perhaps start with teaching the scrum
the scrum team basic some of the basic
concepts back to back to empiricism and
transparency and lean right are we
actually able to create those things
what does it mean if we don't have those
things let's look at the data for what
we're actually delivering and see where
the problems are and and lead the people
to their own conclusions which hopefully
positively impact those things and start
moving us towards that that goal and
that's where you start getting into more
coaching rather than Consulting right
because you you you're creating an
environment within which the person or
group of people are able to understand
and come up with their own answers
for the problems that we're trying to
solve in the situation we're trying to
get to whereas Consulting is a little
bit more the something we need to fix
something we need to a flip switch we
need to flip we've got to get that
changed quickly and then perhaps the
coaching kicks in later and because they
don't know how to do those things so I
think that that's uh the difference
between a newbie
scrum Master slash agile coach because
for me the same thing
um and the battle hardened scrum Master
at Angel coach
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility