okay so we have about 15 minutes left
for the folks that know what they're
doing and I can see most folks are now
in the way I would expect and as an
indication of whether you're in
correctly the two things for you to go
and check the first one is the drop-down
list at the top of your team's it should
say naked agility with Martin into it
also when you go into the show
participants yes
d-ohh were you just playing around with
the hand raised functionality I was
going to explain that in just a second
also when you roll over somebody you
should see their presence information
rather than Victor's fixed himself as
well and it would just be blank
and just so the name at the top rather
than show the presence information so
that shows that everything's set up and
configured correctly for all the people
that are here just now maybe Oh bagel
everybody's managed to get it organized
so awesome so that's like two ways to
check is one check the drop-down list at
the top and the other one is to check
your presence information there so
during the class we're going to we're
not going to use the chat so much most
of its going to be variable
communication we're going to have a
bunch of interactive sessions and we're
all going to work in teams and in those
teams we're going to work on a little
project that I have you are going to be
asked to create some output from those
projects and so you'll be working
together interactively creating a little
bit of software you're going to choose
what technology you use so use whatever
you are happy with and in that obviously
a development team is made up of many
different people so some of you will be
coders some of you will be testers some
of you will be project managers some of
you will have all different skills UX
whatever that happens to be and so
you'll be asked the star
of the session on Monday and to break
down into cross-functional teams once
we've broken down into those
cross-functional teams you'll see
there's a teams at button on the far
left here if you click on that and
you'll be able to click on it just now
you should see something similar to what
I see but obviously with less classy
setup you'll see this live virtual PSF
for workday in Dublin that might be the
only one that you see just now and
you'll see this one after the class or
when I run my scripts to set everything
up for the after the class part and when
you're here you can see the two channels
that are set up once the general channel
and one's the team one tech check you
can see that there is meeting currently
running in general by virtue of this
little icon here and when you go into
when you're viewing the posts of that
channel here and you can see that the
live tech check it's being recorded
who's in the meeting how long it's been
going and you can just join it straight
from this view and that that the
recording will be listed here as well
but I may need to go download that
process it and put it somewhere else for
you and because there's some some weird
issues with that and and you can see
that the main meeting that I set up for
the classes on Monday and Tuesday are is
set up here as well so this will just
have that join button on it so when you
come into the team you can just go to
general and you can just join if the
meetings not started yet like you come
in early I doubt you'll be earlier than
me but if you do come in early you'll be
able to just come in here hit the join
button and it will start it and I've
enabled this that everybody who has
permission to this team again it's
authenticated so only you folks will be
able to get in and you have permission
to start those events and do all of
those things I will have a
co-facilitator
on Monday Russell he's not here today
because it's still
30 a.m. for him and he's in Atlanta but
he's going to join us get up early and
join us from Monday and Tuesday classes
to help out with the facilitation so
what if you notice in the general tab
there are at the general channel sorry
there are a number of tabs and just to
be helpful I've added the scrum open
assessment and the scrum guide right in
here so feel free to read from here and
if you want to start a conversation you
can actually tag me in that conversation
and if you well maybe I can't tag myself
but if you type at Martin you should see
me pop up in that list and you'll be
able to tag me and I'll get a
notification on my phone and I'll be
able to come and answer any questions
you have so if you're reading this gum
guide before it's not required it's
recommended so if you are reading it you
can ping me any questions that you have
as you're going through obviously will
answer most of them in the class but
anything you can preempt is always
useful and so while we're running the
class what I will have over here and I
have team one tech check I'm actually
going to I'm just going to start an
event in here and for that team so that
team will have our open channel all day
and you'll be able to switch between the
two channels so let me just quickly open
it and if I do team one tech check so
this is what will be up here and when I
click meet now I'm going to get
disconnected and from from from you guys
I'll leave come back in and show you how
this bit works hold on a second
okay so let me share my screen again
okay can everybody see my screen again
yep yeah thank you for that feedback so
on the left hand side remember we had
the little light on the general tab we
now also have a little light on the team
one and I go in and there's the the team
one chat any of you in your team can
just go start that by clicking meat now
obviously nominate one person rather
than have everybody click it because it
will create separate meetings but once
it's been created it will be listed in
this channel and you can actually just
leave it open okay so you'll notice up
here that I have team one tech check on
hold and I have a little play button to
resume the call and I also have a hang
up button if I don't hang up when I
switch between roles it just leaves them
open and puts the other call on hold and
so we're gonna spend some amount of time
in the main room which is in the general
tab and then when we have exercises
maybe we have an exercise around moving
some stickies around or creating some
information or working on your sprint
you as a team will go to your team
channel connect to your team room and
have just the five people or or between
five and nine people depending on what
happens on Monday and you may have just
that group of people in your room and
you'll be able to have conversations in
isolation without everybody else at
getting in the way so that that's a how
we are implementing breakout rooms in
this tool if you've used soom and it has
dynamic breakout rooms this is more
self-service at breakout rooms so
they would like you to do just now and
if you can is join this a new team one
tech check at meeting as well and you
will then go into that meeting you'll
leave this one it will be put on hold
and and then come back and just see that
experience of switching between the two
and so that we get that smooth for
Monday and usually a folks have seen it
then it's a lot easier to grasp how that
works on the day and make things a
little bit faster and slicker and also
you can help out your teammates who
weren't able to make it today so do you
want to jump into that and just connect
in there I will give you a few minutes
for those that don't do that or that are
back already you'll see that em in each
room you can see who's on hold and who's
not if they're on hold they're in
another room and if they're not on hold
they're they're here it doesn't refresh
super quickly but mostly quickly you'll
see David's still listed Dave's still
listed as on hold but maybe he's back
already that means that you'll have this
team one and you can very you probably
saw the experience was super quick
now that you've joined that team and
it's open it's even quicker to switch
between those teams because you don't
need to go through that kind of audio
dialogue at the start so that's a very
quick way to jump into your breakout
room have a five-minute conversation
with your team if that's the time box
that we use for that conversation and
then come back to the main group
somebody have any questions on that
okay so that's really all of the the
tools and that we're going to use in
teams I know the workday is moving to
war on my understanding I might be wrong
is that workday is moving towards teams
as corporate standard so hopefully this
will help you out with that as well
and you'll be a have a leg up in
participating in those things I do want
to add and a couple of things that are a
little bit useful one of the things that
I'll be doing and as we run the course I
can't remember if I added tags yet did I
add tags yet manage team I did indeed
add tags so you can see oh there's
Jessica I will add your tag there we go
so I'm going to tag everybody with the
team that they're in once we get started
once you've decided which teams you're
going to be on and there's a
facilitators tag and a students tag so
students is going to be all of you
facilitators is going to be Russell and
I if you are in for example your team
one tech check and you pop open the chat
dialogue on the right-hand side you'll
be able to type one of those tags and
that everybody who is in that tag will
get a notification to say that there's a
new message that they need to look at
and I'm pretty sure it will pop up on
activity it will pop up on chat and it
might be listed under team I'm not sure
how that's visible for you and it would
be awesome could somebody in any chat
you want and tag the facilitators that
would be pretty cool so you could do it
in the chat for this meeting or you
could pop in here and do it in any of
either of the channels there we go so
I've been tagged as a facilitator and so
I can see I get an alert
I've been added in the team and it will
show me exactly which channel and I need
to go go look at yes thank you David
there we go so it makes it very easy for
us to see if somebody needs some help
because you can just tag the
facilitators and it also means that we
know where to go and it's the same for
for you folks as well what I will often
do is put time checks in your chat so
for example thank you Suresh you how'd
you say your name it's you
Zuzu yeah okay I will try and remember
that thank you very much and you'll
notice that if you went into in fact
I'll show you over here because
everybody's in this room it's a little
bit easier and you can see that we
where's our current tech check there we
go our tech check that's online and if I
put a message in here you will see that
it will be automatically in you're in
the room you'll see it as our that I
can't remember the name of the thing the
overlay that pops up we'll have a little
chat window and if I tag students in
here you'll see that it's not going into
the main room like David's two chats
just went into the main channel and this
is actually going into thank you David
it's going into the reply for that if I
can where's my pop-up gun i minimized it
to keep it out the way it's actually
going directly into this channel so
you'll be able to see it there right
away okay
and so that's that's a simple way to
make sure that you're on time that and
we don't have to go chase you down by
switching rooms or will Russell and I
will do that and if the if folks aren't
back on the time box so we are expecting
you as a group to self-organize to look
after your own time boxes
we will we will help out where we can
and make sure everything runs as
smoothly as possible
so the final thing and to have a quick
look at which you can actually do on
your own time I'm going to put a link I
think I put a link in the email that I
sent you folks let me just check sent
items did I make one I maybe didn't cuz
I was lazy it might be in the event
sometimes I'm too lazy and I don't do
all of the bits oh no I did I did a
mural so in the calendar invitation
there was a mural link which I just put
in the chat which you should be able to
open I'm just going to open it just now
bring it across you should see this
experience it is perfectly fine to use
this anonymously and that's my
expectation for you to be able to use
enter anonymously and I'm going to sign
in which will give me a facilitator
experience and Russell and I will have
the same capabilities while I'm hoping
it will there we go there we go I can
see are loads of folks are coming in
already
I'll see you just as these little
anonymous shrimp lobster crab things
going on that's that's okay and it's not
super difficult what I will be doing if
I go to preparation and I summon
everybody you'll see that you will all
get located to what I'm looking at so
when we're using the mural and you can
have it open on your screen we don't
need to share anything on desktops and
you'll just get sucked into where we're
focusing and when you're in your team
murals which they'll be a mural for each
team and you'll be able to do
as well and and we're going to do
exercises using this as our as our as
our wall as our our sticky so you can
actually double click anywhere and
create a create a sticky so I just
created that my first sticky there if
you double click next to a sticky you'll
actually create the same type of sticky
if you go over on the left you'll see
you can create other types of sticky so
I'm just gonna drag a pink one across
well is it pink or purple and somebody
else is editing it already but if I
double click next to that sticky it will
create another one of the same type this
is a super useful tool for facilitating
anything that you would in the past have
used a white board and stickies on a
white board this is this is super
awesome and you're not just drawing on
it but it does have a it does have a
drawing tool I've not really used it I
don't know how useful it is but it does
have such a thing so if I say done
drawing and I have this and I should be
able to drag it drag it around and
delete it so it makes things a little
bit easier you can upload pictures and
you can add little icons so you want a
pen or a star or you want to put a shape
on there you can do that as well and you
can make some shapes and symbols and
we're going to use this oh that was my
bad I clicked the wrong button where are
we PSF 2020 or 525 main PSF there we go
i disappeared because i clicked the
wrong button there we go um so we're
going to use this for a lot of the
exercises and feel free to play around
what I will do is I'm in the main mural
which is the only one you need to save
the link for um I'm going to make this
little display clickable oh oh yeah I'm
sharing a hint teams anyway I'll bring
everybody over someone everybody um I'm
going to bring put this little display
on each of the teams and if you double
click it
it will link through to your individual
team room for that team and so will do I
can a team-building exercise where we
add little pictures of ourselves and so
I can import an image from my computer
and I can just go where's my picture
it's in here I'm gonna put that one on
and I can put my picture on and then I
can just add a little caption and see
and then I can make it smaller and then
when we break into teams I can choose
which team I want to be on for the
self-organizing exercise that's that's
roughly how we're going to facilitate a
lot of the exercises and working in this
tool and so having a little bit of
familiar allottee with it is okay as you
can see some of you been playing around
with it it's not super difficult but if
it's something you don't know then and
there's a little bit going on there
there any questions on mural awesome so
let me stop the share
so you will be able to see everything
that's in the murals yourself you'll be
able to move around that is um if if you
guys want to play around in that you're
all between now and Monday I'll be
checking it on Monday and if I need to
create a new blank one I will but
otherwise that will be the one that we
use maybe I can just go clean up some of
the posters everybody leaves lying
around that's okay too
and really that's everything unless
anybody has any questions feel free to
raise your hand you have a have a
question and I can call on you or just
unmute and check out cool well it looks
like there are no questions everybody
managed to very quickly get into a state
where they are all in and correctly I'm
I'm super happy with that experience we
had and thirteen people in at one point
so that's more than half of the folks
from the class so hopefully we don't
have so many people and with issues if
you do know some of your colleagues who
are coming into the class and then
please ask them to either watch the
video or try and connect into teams so
that they can see at this the display
like this with naked agility at the top
and that will make the class on Monday a
lot much easier a lot much easier that's
not even English much easier at the
start up okay thank you very much
everybody for your time and I look
forward to seeing you on Monday okay
thank you thank you very much