it's a lot more expensive than you think
having poor quality
Cod there are lots of hidden impacts
you've got the the obvious stuff is the
cost of fixing bugs right because you've
got poor quality and people find issues
and that cost gets exponentially more
expensive the closer to production you
get right more expensive for to fix it
with the customers but you've also got
the cost of customer support that's
that's obvious stuff the the the things
that people generally don't think of is
thing things like brand
reputation right what what is the impact
on poor quality on brand reputation not
just poor quality in your product but
poor quality in the way you do things
the most recent one is crowd strike
right they they they they had poor
engineering practices that result Ed in
a massive Global impact when something
went wrong and all all they did was what
lots of companies do which is push
something to production and didn't
really think about controlling the blast
radius or any of the other modern
engineering practices that they might
have so you've get you've got you've got
L loss lost to your brand you've got
you've got productivity of your team
right if you've everybody's got to run
around trying to figure figure out what
the problem is because it's too
difficult to figure it out
then you're going to have a massive loss
of productivity not not just producct
there's lots of engineering practices
that people use that reduce quality but
they don't think it reduces quality one
of those is branching right having a a a
a a really large branching strategy I I
worked with a a company recently um that
had 96 teams and they had 96 branches 96
long running branches one for each team
and then each team created their own
branches of that um and the cost in Lost
productivity to maintain that to ensure
that you have working product is just
enormous and add to that if you're
maintaining multiple versions of your
product right this is a massive cost you
you in
general you should not be maintaining
multiple versions of your product you
should not be supporting multiple
versions of your product you should be
supporting the latest version of your
product and not anything
else in general there are I can off the
top of my head I can think of
circumstances where I might have two
versions of my product or maybe three
absolute tops but if you have more than
that perhaps you have a version of your
product per customer that's a very
common one that's a massive cost not
just to support and maintenance but in
in Lost productivity if I'm a developer
and I UND I I I fixed a problem I fix a
bug right could just be a bug let's take
that as an example I fix a bug in in in
the main version of our product the
latest version of our product but we
realize that it's in lots of customers
versions maybe there's 10 customer
versions have this this bug can I fix it
the same in all of those versions
probably not right because they diverge
over time and perhaps things that I used
to fix uh uh the product fix as part of
the fix in in the main version aren't
there in older versions or it's slightly
different or it's not quite the same
version or all kinds of that increases
the cognitive load on the engineers it
increases the likelihood of something
going wrong because you're increasing
that c cognitive load um and because you
have to backport all of those fixes
across all those different versions
what's the cost and missed opportunities
because your team's having to mess
around with lots of work that is
avoidable I'm going to put that in there
these are all avoidable losses in
productivity what are the missed
opportunities for your business what
features are you not able to ship
because it's harder for you to add
features a a great great fantastic my
favorite example is some data from the
Azure devox team the aure devops team
had a very long tail on figuring out
whether they they they'd been successful
in in in building the product right the
engineers have been successful in the
code that they write and having the test
and validation of those things done and
it was taking 48 to 72 hours to figure
that out they invested a bunch of time
and energy in paying back poor choices
they'd made in the past some of them
deliberate that's okay but poor choices
they'd made in the past and things they
didn't realize were poor choices in the
past that they now realize were poor
choices paying that back it took them
nearly four years of investment in that
story to pay it fully pay it back right
you know just like if you take out a
loan you pay it back over a longer
period of time a little piece at a time
so they were paying it back as they had
time they were prioritizing it so it was
important to them so they were spending
time on it but they're also doing other
things so not it's getting done over
time so it took them four years to pay
it back but that
plus fixing that problem refactoring
that problem re architecting that that
that part of the problem so that they
went from 72 hours that was the longest
72 hours to find out whether you'd
broken stuff to three and a half minutes
right so that's a massive shift so
shifting from long running system tests
to small discrete unit tests as their
measure of validation massively impacted
their productivity they went from
25ish features to production each year
with 650 people to over 800 features to
features to production with the same 600
people not quite the same right because
it's four years time but more or less
the same 600 people and even in the
first year when they had a really big
focus on paying that back although there
was a long tail right a really big focus
on paying it back they spent most of
their time in the first year focusing on
fixing a lot of these types of
architectural problems of dealing with
that they weren't focused on features
and they still managed to go from 24
features to production to like 60
something features to production almost
three times the number of features were
delivered to production at the end of
the first year and they weren't even
focused on delivering features they were
focused on building up engineering
Excellence fixing those older problems
that had crept in over time you know
it's like 15 years working on this
product and it had this massive massive
massive boost to not
just productivity right the productivity
of the team but brand reputation went up
because you're delivering more features
more experiments more things that your
customers need you're missing less
opportunities and you're having less
security breaches because if we're if
we're iterating much more quickly which
is what you're trying to do is reduce
those feedback loops
you're you can't leave security to the
end one one of the main reasons that
that companies get large scale high cost
security
breaches is that they they leave
security is an afterthought it's not
baked into the process and if security
is an
afterthought you find a problem in the
way you've architected your your
product it's a lot of work to go back
and fix that so most people in teams
don't because it's maybe hundreds
thousands of hours to go to go fix it or
we could get out the sticky tape and
super glue and stick over the top and
and and create something over the top
that prevents the hackers getting into
that that flaw but hackers spend copious
amounts of time figuring out how to peel
back the edges of those sticky things
and get underneath and and get it access
to the system so by paying back this
technical debt of increasing the level
of quality in your
product you have all kinds of
exponential benefits to your ability to
deliver product to your customer the
happiness of your customer and you're
able to not just reduce costs technical
debt is not just a cost it's a oh what
would you call it it missed
opportunities right how what money are
you leaving on the table because you
haven't had the ability to go uh tackle
those opportunities you haven't had the
ability to try those
things this is fundamentally why having
high
quality usable working product on a
regular Cadence is a superpower for your
teams and for your organization in your
ability to deliver Val you