product backlog management is getting
lots of attention right now because it
is one of the most deficient things in
organizations that I and my colleagues
encounter um most
organizations do not have uh adequate
backlogs they do not have backlogs that
represent transparency the work that
needs to be done um and they don't have
enough information for people who even
with within the context of that
organization context of that product to
be able to explicitly understand what
that thing is and what you're trying to
do with it um and that is hurting the
ability of teams to deliver value it's
hurting the ability of organizations to
understand what it is that what the heck
the teams are doing at all anyway and
that's why product backlog management is
the biggest critical Focus for
organizations right now
if you want to have a discussion about
your unique needs or situation then
please book a call or visit us at naked
agility doccom uh we also have our
immersive and traditional public classes
on our website and we'd love to hear
from you