I think caman is becoming popular in the
creative Industries because there's very
little other help out there for for the
the creative type work where you're
you're for example building computer
games or you're building um uh uh uh
marketing content or you're building
videos whatever it is that you're
building that's not really software
engineering cuz everybody thinks of grum
as a software engineering
process and find it a little bit weird
trying to apply it within their context
right they actually they're actually
running into the same thing that
everybody runs into that doesn't that
would things don't work that way here so
caman is a much better uh starting point
um for getting into to making changes to
the way the way that you work and trying
to optimize your your
processes um so
so coming up with that definition of
workflow for your existing process is
usually much easier than trying to apply
something like scrum so for lots of
organizations they don't want that big
bang change right when you uh when you
apply something like scrum you're you're
you're making a leap from the way you
currently work and changing it to
something else and this is going to be
your starting point so that would be you
start at scrum and then you're going to
move forward from there and optimize
you're still going to use cban campan
strategy and you're going to optimize
from there but if your way of working
right now is kind of working and you
don't want to disrupt that too much or
you don't feel you don't know the if
you're going to get value from that
scrum thing then start from where you
are right that's that's the beauty of a
caman strategy is it doesn't care what
the it doesn't care the way your system
currently works you mod model your
existing system that's where you start
from so um you you you can take any
industry any system creative or
otherwise and you can just model your
existing system a a huge difficulty
though um I've worked in quite a few
creative uh I've worked in the creative
industry right uh when I when I first
started as a software engineer uh after
I graduated back in
2000 my first jobs were
um New Media
agencies um You probably wouldn't call
them that anymore but New Media agencies
I worked with a groups of designers
building flash applications uh flash
websites if anybody remembers flash if
not don't even look at it it's mental um
and th those those kind of thing working
with with the creative industry and it's
it's it is a very difficult space
because of the way art works right it's
very difficult to be iterative and
incremental right away in that in that
space because the way we traditionally
work with art is it's your personal
thing and your personal thing is going
to a certain point till you're
personally happy with it and then you're
you're you're providing it to other
other people to to to give you feedback
and and that kind of thing
so there's there's a much more personal
nature to that than there is in um in in
maybe other Industries like software
engineering right where where there's
less a little bit less personal it can
still be personal but a little bit less
personal so that that's why creative
Industries and creative folks um
struggle with uh something like scrum
because it it it talks about team it
doesn't talk about individual and
creativity is about the individual so
finding the balance in that and it's is
very standoffish so cand strategy but
the hardest part of a cand strategy at
least at the beginning is writing down
writing down your your your your
workflow right documenting your your
definition of workflow how are you going
to get five creative people in a room
and agree what your existing workflow is
um so that's going to be your first
struggle but caman is popular in
Creative Industries because it seems
like actually
I'm I'm actually going to recant some of
that a little bit I think that caman is
popular in a lot of places where people
don't want to change and they see scrum
has a bunch of rules and caman doesn't
have a bunch of rules and they feel like
they can just put a board on the
wall call it caman and they're
done that's not caman having a board on
the wall and moving cards across it is
one very small part of camand maybe an
important part that visualization part
but have you taken the time to actually
Define your workflow to agree as a group
all the people working together that
this is how we are all going to act how
we're all going to make decisions in the
same way I I I doubt that happens in in
in most organizations have you agreed
what the working process limits are how
much work is going to sit in each column
if you don't have whip limits you ain't
got cban at all right so so sitting down
and agreeing that these this is this is
really hard stuff it's hard for a group
of people to get together and make these
decisions and come up with these
rationals it's just it's just hard I I I
do workshops with with with groups of
people talking about this stuff and you
can you can do a 4-Hour workshop with a
group of five or six people and not get
anywhere near a definition of workf
nowhere near and this is this is people
who largely agree on what it is they're
doing because the devil's in the details
right when you're when you're when
you've got you've got a bunch of work in
a pile and you need to start a new piece
of work how do you choose that piece of
work
how do you choose
it right we have to agree as a group how
we're going to choose it because this is
our system that we're all working
within so how who who's who's way of
choosing it do we pick right out of the
five different opinions on how they
select work well I like this type of
work so I'm going to take that no that's
not good enough that's not how you
optimize a system right that's not how
you optimize the flow of work through a
system what is the most valuable piece
of work to take next now that's an
interesting conversation and how do you
define value and does it matter whether
you as an individual are comfortable
with that piece of work or not right
that there's probably some yes some no
right within the bounds of that so so
making these agreements and writing them
down is very hard and although caman has
become popular particularly in the
creative industry I definitely feel
there's a lot of Can't Ban right that
they really don't want to do anything or
change anything or have anything imposed
upon them and their way of
working I know a lot of creatives
creatives are very much very much H my
way of working is the best for me that's
how my muse right um and that's
absolutely reasonable but we're all
working together within a business
driving a particular outcome and that
business needs to optimize the work in
order to maximize the return on
investment right so how much effort we
spend versus how much money we get and
yeah we we we need some level of
standardization and a core critical part
of caman is is defining that
standardization have personal caman if
you don't want to work together as a
team each individual has their own cbat
problem solved right everybody just
decides their own way of working their
own workflow as long as they Define it
they write it down they have the the the
visualization limit their work in
process personal caman there's a book on
called personal caman on personal caman
and I highly recommend that as well
so I know cam man's getting popular uh
but please do look
at the cang guides right take a look at
the cang guides look at what is actually
involved in creating a c a caman or
using a cand strategy against your work
and usually there's there's there's more
rigor more effort more ambiguity and
more difficulty than something like
scrum if your current system of work is
failing you then you would benefit from
creating and applying a cand strategy
our professional camand trainers and
Consultants are ready to help don't wait
the sooner you get started the sooner
you will improve get in touch below