oh hi my name is martin hinchelwood
um i'm the owner at naked agility um i'm
a professional scrum trainer
with scrum.org um i'm a microsoft
mvp and i've been delivering software
for about 20 years and working in
organizational change for more than 10
years
i'd like to thank akaditi and nana for
the opportunity to talk
to you about the inevitability of change
i speak uh often in ghana um i
i i love coming to going to ghana
um and i uh have done a lot of uh
training and consulting there with uh
akaditi
um i'm was looking forward to being
in nigeria uh but obviously uh that
is not the case um but this is
second best for sure getting to to meet
all of you and interact
at this level so
um please feel free to ask any questions
in the chat and i'll hopefully have time
to answer them all
at the end hopefully akidity will
moderate those
uh for me um failing that
you can ask me any questions on uh
twitter as well um and obviously
linkedin
i have a whole bunch of webcasts over on
naked agility.tv
that i've recorded previously i'm sure
uh akadetti are going to be publishing
all of their uh recordings uh later
and i'll be providing a link to the
presentation
in the presentation at the end of the
the final slide has a has a link and a
qr code
to get you access to the presentation
something that i've been considering for
quite a while
is that there's really no such thing
as an agile transformation a digital
transformation
devops transformation or any other
transformation in business that you can
think of or that you might have been
sold
you can't you can't buy agility and you
certainly can't
install it there's no end states no
optimal
outcome and certainly no best practices
only adequate practices for the
situation at hand
so instead you have to grow
and nurture and prune agility as it
grows
inside your organization and eventually
you too will be able to take advantage
of
business opportunities as they arise
in whatever changing marketplace that
you're in
this is continuous change it's an
evolution
not a transformation
it's easy to see uh the the
uh uh if you think of the evolution
uh sorry the transformation of a
caterpillar
that transforms into a butterfly
it has a beginning state and it has an
end state
and in between it has a transformational
state
and it starts in one place and it
finishes at the end
but evolution is a constant
and continuous set of experiments the
successful
experiments succeed and do well in a
particular niche
the unsuccessful ones fail and die
the same is true with companies and
organizations
in the past the ebb and flow of niches
in the business world
was was very slow uh niches
that we could take advantage of existed
for a long period of time
look at the length of time that the coal
industry has been around
or the oil industry and there are
many of those types of niches that were
there for a long long time
tens if not hundreds of years
and we could grow our organization to
fit into that
niche slowly and once we owned that
niche
it was very hard for competitors to come
in
and disrupt our abilities we
owned that space today
however niches grow and change
much faster than ever before
my belief is that it's due to the the
new
flow of information the internet
has made things a lot faster we find out
things
quicker we have a a
feeling that we need to do something
with this
information much more quickly
um and that that as it gets faster
we need to react facts faster and thus
a virtuous cycle of increasing change
perpetuates and however for now
organizations
only change when they are in danger
fight or flight kicks in and they either
adapt to the changing environment
or maybe they die that's the way it's
kind of always been
but very very slowly ask yourself
if your organization or organizations
you can
you can think of that you interact with
would have survived
covet 19 20 years ago
think of the technology that we had 20
years ago
the the the average worldwide internet
connection speed
20 years ago it was 56 kilobits per
second
you wouldn't have been able to do video
conferencing you
we wouldn't have been able to run this
conference
what about 10 years ago was the
technology even there 10 years ago
to solve some of these problems and
allow many organizations
to continue with very little disruption
the big tech organizations that were
mentioned earlier like
google and microsoft um
have had very little disruption any
organization
that has people sitting in an office
doing work
shouldn't need to be disrupted in the
way they potentially were
because they weren't relying or they
didn't have the new technologies
that have become available in the last
20 years
if you did have those technologies but
you
put them in maybe five ten years ago
you probably rely on vpn
so suddenly instead of having a few
employees connecting into your network
to then access everything
you had all of your employees trying to
connect in
and access everything and most
organizations vpns couldn't cope
with that number of users they you know
expect a small number of users to be
connected to any one time
rather than everybody in the company
connected all day
but if you had already adopted
many of those cloud technologies that
are available
like the one we're using now at
microsoft teams
it is all set up in the cloud all of you
are connecting
not into academies offices but directly
to microsoft servers in the cloud in
order to
uh take advantage of all of your
internet connections
rather than be restricted by one single
point of
failure and how many
of those organizations made that change
so if you've been able to utilize
the cloud if you've already moved your
services online
then there was very little disruption
employees working from home
probably got faster connections
than the connections they got on the in
the office because they're using their
home connection that they own the whole
bandwidth
rather than the office bandwidth that
they're sharing with all of their
colleagues
if you had changed if you
had adopted new things as they became
available
i often hear the phrase if it isn't
broke
don't fix it but i think that
is a very outmoded and old
phrase for today today i would much
prefer to hear if it isn't broken you're
not
pushing change fast enough you're not
trying new things you're not
experimenting
evolution is about embracing
failure and learning from it
it's okay to fail we do it all the time
but if we learn from it we pick
ourselves back up
and figure out how to do things a little
bit better
because success is the result of
continuous
experimentation at a sustainable pace
that enables you to take advantage
of whatever business opportunities
occur as they arise this
is the inevitability of change
our current way of working the
management practices that i
and my colleagues see as prevalent in
the world
i'm not going to say that everybody is
using these management practices
but the vast majority of people are
still using
management practices that were developed
130 years ago during the industrial
revolution
and they were created in an environment
of very
low change things weren't moving
fast at the time we didn't have the
communication levels
that we have now and those practices
were able to support those systems of
the time
but they're no longer able to keep up
with the constant evolution of now
prior to the industrial revolution
manufacturing took place
at or near your home in small workshops
you might imagine a cobbler making
shoes in a village his compensation came
through
earned value that was based on how well
he made the shoes
and how uh uh how
well they fitted the needs of the
customer he
understood who his customer was you're
muted
martin i'm muted ah
so again uh please don't use the mute
all button otherwise you will mute the
speaker
uh if you look through the list of
participants
you will see people flashing uh that are
making a lot of noise
and you can click on them and mute them
individually
uh where did i get to can you help me
you know
we didn't mute you maybe she couldn't
hear you but we could hear you
sorry oh okay perfect
ah now i've forgotten where i was we
were talking about the cobbler in the
village weren't we
uh because he understood who his
customers well he probably
engaged with them a lot more often
than we engage with our customers he
probably met with them for a drink in
the pub
uh the the local policeman the farmer
they're gonna drink and they're going to
have this person right next to them who
made
the shoes on their feet that they walk
about in every day and they can complain
they can say what you liked and what
they didn't it's a very
powerful way to work and there was
purpose to the his work he could see
and engage with his customer and get
that purpose
and because he had that purpose it also
enabled
mastery think about the the master
and apprentice system that operated
at that time and you would have
uh the the the not the great wealth of
knowledge uh that the long beard had
created over many years of being a
cobbler and they would pass it on
to the next person down the line whether
that
is uh just
out of interest i have a lot of
background noise here is it okay for you
we can't hear it awesome i'm using that
crisper thing uh so it's deleting i i
all i hear is a lawnmower outside my
window
but i'm glad you can't hear it so that
mastery that master and apprentice
system passing knowledge down through
the generations
uh people chose uh to work hard
and well in order to get better at what
they did
so that that getting better at what they
did
becoming a master either manifested
itself
as increased wealth or greater time to
pursue other
interests that they have uh whether that
be drinking in the pub or
whatever other things they like doing
so during the industrial revolution
at big change happened in the way we
work and the way we do things
the industrial revolution changed the
world forever we've already had
a show talk talking about it earlier we
need to
we needed to scale up really quickly but
technology of the time
couldn't build the quantity of goods
required
without human help we needed to
mechanize the workforce we turned
people's jobs
into robotic jobs workers
no longer had a purpose beyond the
paycheck
and neither understood the value the
customers
and didn't have any mastery people
became replaceable
cogs in a machine think about that
modern even today management practice
where it's okay we don't need to
help and support our workers because if
somebody quits
there's 10 people waiting at the door
that can go do that job
that's for unskilled labor if you have
somebody who's solving problems with
their brain
then that's not good enough you're
losing a lot more than just an
uh an individual you're losing a lot
more
than just a cog in the system
so i would say what's the difference
between
these two pictures on the left we have
the master passing
a wealth of knowledge on to the
apprentice they understand the whole
context of the product they're building
they understand who their customer is
and how they're using the product
what their job is what they do day to
day and the customer has direct
access to the people that are making the
product
and on the right we have a bunch of
factory workers
making something
i actually don't know what they're
making i'm pretty sure
you would not be able to figure out what
they're making
it's a round thing with some pins in it
and there's lots of people doing the
same thing
do they even know what it's for do they
even care does that even matter
maybe it doesn't and the
thing that happens when you're doing
that kind of mind-numbing work
the example i always use is if you you
might have read a book called
charlie in the chocolate factory by road
al uh
in that book charlie's dad lost his job
at a factory
uh and his job was screwing the top on
toothpaste bottles
that was his job day in and day out and
he was replaced by a robot
he's just a replaceable [ __ ] he's a
machine
waiting for me for uh robots to happen
so because people were disengaging
uh from the process uh
there's this idea and they had a name
for it at the time it was called
it's soldiering which is not the
soldiering that we know today but
it was this idea of somebody working
more
slowly than their capacity they're
deliberately
working more slowly than their capacity
uh
you might use the phrase to loaf or
uh that depends on uh uh your cultural
background whether those words
have meaning uh but uh that's just to
work more slowly than one's capacity to
lay about not doing much try and avoid
doing the work
going in hiding around the corner from
where the supervisor is because you
want to have a cheeky extra cigarette
break
whatever those things are loafing and
malingering
so i want you to imagine that you
are a management consultant
around at the time of the
1890s now i have
a link that i'm going to put in the
chat which might uh make this
a little bit easier so i'm going to put
it in the chat
can everybody see my slide oh yes you
can see my slides
so one person was saying they can't see
my slides they i they're
they are displaying uh so it might be a
computer
network issue i've put a link in the
chat
uh it would be awesome if everybody
could click that link
and and they will go to a tool called
mural
so this is a web-based stickies on a
wall
post-it system uh i don't see anybody
coming in yet i can see
when you're coming in because i'm going
to give you an activity
in a few minutes you can use the link
that's on screen
uh so that's uh nkd agility.net
forward slash soldiering
1980 uh capital s
and that will take you into the mural
has anybody been able to do that
no no this includes you as well
it doesn't look like anybody's uh
joining maybe you
will we do it over the chat then instead
i'm just on it awesome i will give you
another
uh a few few minutes to figure it out
i see i see one person in i see adi
ah he actually has an account for this
system it is just fine to join as a
guest
uh to click the um
visitor uh and come in that way so i see
there's two people in
we need more people so i want everybody
uh to click that link in the chat
and open up at this lovely
uh mural and go in there i only have two
come on we need more
we need you to to this is this is not
just a presentation we need you to
engage in the process we need to come up
come up with some ideas because
i've hired you
i'm the owner of a paper mill and i've
hired you
to to help me come up with some ideas
to defeat uh this loafing and
malingering workforce that i have
they're all they're all laying about
they're trying to avoid doing work
they don't want to do anything so we
need to figure out how we're going to
deal with this
so i'd like you to use this mural
and if you double click anywhere on the
mural
and it will create a post-it i'm going
to create one now for those that are in
there already
so they can see create a little post-it
and you can
type in your idea so
what i would like you to do is create
as many ideas as pos as you can think of
for dealing with these loafing and
malingering employees
we're management consultants uh you're
management consultants and you need to
help me
deal with this problem what are your
suggestions
going to be so i'm going to put
uh two minutes on the clock
so i'm gonna give you two minutes from
now it's the timer has started
to go and add as many ideas
as you can so all you do is double click
anywhere on the page
it will create a little uh post it yes
you can create multiple different colors
some people are over achieving and type
in that post-it
your idea uh for uh
um solving this problem and i want you
to
think like it's 1880
okay so it's not 2020
it's 1880. so you don't have to be
politically correct
think that like you're in the 1800s
yes thank you arthur
so anybody who is uh you'll be able to
see
what's going on even if you don't want
to participate by clicking the link
and you'll be able to see the mural and
zoom in and zoom out
um we have a few suggestions already
not many but it's doing good so we've
got
uh dock their pay sack them
you know if they're not going fast
enough let's sack them
um cut their break times because they're
not
working fast enough we're not getting
enough widgets
therefore we're not making enough paper
so you're gonna have to have shorter
breaks you're gonna have to work longer
time
we're gonna have to do some overtime um
if you don't look like you're performing
we're just going to sack you
um what else are we going to do
close the toilets adi i don't think
that's going to
work we're going to end up with a very
smelly uh factory floor
punish the slow ones how might you
punish the slow ones
how might you punish the flow ones or
how might you create incentives
to have people work faster or harder
food reduction
oh that's mean
that's mean it's not it's not going as
mean as it has done in the past
what things happened in the the 1800s
chinese conscripts building the
railroads in the us
i'm sure they didn't get paid well uh
what else was happening in the 1800s
humiliate them send them to australia
yeah everything's trying to kill you in
australia sack them punish them
make them make them join the army
okay so we've got a few uh suggestions
the time
uh is up thank you very much
for your participation uh i will
just quickly move this over to the other
views so that everybody else can see
uh and for the recording at what was
created
uh these are our interesting ideas so
punishing the slow ones cutting their
brakes making the mark over time
uh docking their pay uh sacking them
they're not doing enough work uh i have
run
this exercise with many many people
in the room and just to give a little
example of what sort of
uh ideas have been created in the past
uh time off after deliveries
tapping into personal motivation
decreasing lunch time so we saw that
already
employee of the week you know some kind
of bonus
for being the best person this week
uh discipline uh lar well i i don't know
if you
see on the right there there's armed
guards enforcers
threat of imminent death large amounts
of screaming
those whips and there's also free beer
so you can see there can be a lot of
different ways
that you might come up with to solve
this problem
and really um there was no holds barred
in the 1800s there were very few things
that were out of bounds for you as a
company owner
on what you were able to do to your
employees very few rules
um so kind of a little bit open so what
what really happened well the thought
leaders
at the time the main thought leader was
a gentleman called frederick winston
taylor and he coined this particular
phrase i'm going to read it out because
i think it's very important
hardly a competent worker can be found
who does not devote a considerable
amount of
time studying just how slowly they can
work
and still convince their employer that
they're going at a good pace
this for me has been the
fundamental basis upon which most
modern management practices has been
built
we don't trust people we they're going
to do a bad job they're going to try and
get out of doing the work
so we have to control them
that's the founding basis of these
management practices
and it was true at the time
we had disconnected workers who didn't
care about the work
but if you want people to care about the
work maybe we need to do things
a little bit differently so this phrase
became the foundation upon which
traditional management practices have
been built
and he created something called the
scientific management method
and and all of the the you put some of
these ideas
on the mural i see some folks are still
looking around
uh on the other ideas that are in there
uh but
let's develop some standard methods for
performing each job so we're gonna train
the workers
in those standard methods so that was on
the list
and we might divide workers into
appropriate ability
based groups so the people that make
widget a
will put all of them together and the
people that make widget b because then
we can just control them separately
we're going to create incentives for
increased output
there were a number of incentives that
you had on the list
over time i'll paying them badly
let me flip back over to uh
the ideas that you created make them
work overtime cut their breaks dock
their pay
sack threat sack them or just threaten
them with sacking
humiliate them punish the slow ones
these are all things that are
creating incentives uh
but we need to plan their work we don't
want them to
think we want to plan all of the things
that we're going to do
i'm sure in some of those statements you
might you might see
some of the things in your current
management practices maybe in your
organization
maybe some of these are things that
you've been doing
that's entirely possible these are
practices that
are ingrained in the way we work they're
part of our bureaucracies and
we're going to talk about why we need to
change them in just a moment
after taylor was another fellow called
henry gant
yes that gant and he built on those
tayloristic ideas
and used scientific analysis to improve
the efficiency
in the industry remember we're
mechanizing people people are just
robots they're just widgets it's
unskilled labor we can train anybody to
do these jobs in the factory
so they created the task and bonus
system
they created a basic wage based on
expected low performance
and then you get a bonus for exceeding
uh
the expectations and maybe we should
bonus the managers for motivating their
staff
to exceed that proficiency so let's
let's find all the the the the bullies
make the managers
uh at the time today there are many
types of managers
around i've worked with some awesome
managers that
have to work within this system of
traditional management practices and
they do things a little bit differently
and use it to their advantage
i'm not saying i'm not painting every
manager with the same evil stick
but there are certainly many evil
managers out there the system allows
that to happen
i would like you to also think about the
traditional classroom
in schools create a picture in your head
of maybe the classroom you grew up with
but
the traditional classroom view that you
see
in in schools everybody sits in rows
everybody has to do the same thing at
the same time
no talking rewards for fulfilled tasks
and incentive based learning
that sounds like a factory floor to me
the school system the modern school
system was designed
to train people with just the
information they need
to work in factories now it's changed
over the years and there are good
teachers and there are bad teachers but
that's the fundamental basis upon which
the system
has been built so traditional management
practices
focus on output not outcomes
traditional management theory comes from
these turn of the century manufacturing
ideas
that came about during the industrial
revolution that had that emphasis on
output
it was what they needed at the time they
needed output
and in that system you measure
efficiency be
by how many output you get
by given input that's the only measure
that really matters
so these ideas were formulated by an
organization
uh called harvard harvard graduate
school
and this is their first ever graduating
mba class in 1908
that's a very long time ago and these
were it was harvard so these were the
wealthy
leaders or the the children of the
wealthy leaders
of the time and they flocked to
organizations around the world
and these tayloristic uh practices
these traditional management practices
spread
all over the world that's kind of where
we're where we where we ended up
and then in the 1950s a new way
of this new way of working uh
emerged where we're going to divide the
workforce into specific skills
create things sequentially so in in a
particular order
tell them how to do their work encourage
them to specialize in just one thing
and then reward them based on individual
output that sounds a little bit familiar
it's just
the next uh phase of that idea
this was the birth of sequential working
where you complete your stage and then
pass it on
to the next department marketing
markets the deal sales clinches the deal
contracts codifies the deal business
analysts
document the deal the makers maybe
coders
build the deal could be manufacturing
could be anything
uh testers test the deal and then
operations deploys
and runs the deal whatever those things
are
they don't need to understand anything
outside of their
little box of operations or marketing or
sales or contracts or whatever those
things are
the us military complex came along and
they became the largest
purchaser of services and goods in the
world
for those that don't know uh the us
military today
has a budget of 850 billion dollars
every year and has 2.8
million employees so that's not
including
contractors it's not including uh
consultants all of those things all of
their vendors
and and they became this largest
purchaser
because of that focus uh of trying to
defeat
communism after the second world war the
us turned towards the russians
and they created a bunch of processes
based on
these ideas taylor and gant
and rewarded their suppliers and
contractors
based on the incentives model so it just
became part of their procurement process
and because it became part of their
procurement process they demanded that
all their suppliers work the same way
sequentially that's where these ideas
came from this sequential way of working
it spread across the world because it
was so effective when applied
to the most common type of work at the
time which was simple work
widgets in factories however in the
1980s
things began to change it was really
changing before then but this is when
things really started picking up speed
communication got easier data began to
be processed and the internet
was born this sealed sequential uh
workings fate
even if it would take many years for it
to even realize
that it was doomed today the world is
moving faster
than ever before and how many of the old
guards
are still left the best analogy i have
uh and i don't know uh culturally how
this translates but the best analogy i
have
is this thing called orienteering which
apparently is some weird sport
in europe um but it it came it has
military
origins because if you're a soldier and
you need to get from one place to
another
uh you have to use a map you have to be
able to read a map
and orienteering was a technique for
practicing map reading
but it's become a sport but in
orienteering uh you have a goal a place
you have to get to or potentially a set
of check
points that you have to get to along the
way
uh here is one of the the the the
participants in the sport
checking in at one of the checkpoints
they usually have a little a way of
identifying themselves so they have to
get to every checkpoint along the way
um but the caveat i have for how it
doesn't quite relate to orienteering is
though checkpoints are changing
all the time rather than being in a
fixed place like they would if you were
all
in a sport together and but you
as a business leader probably have a
vision that describes
the the intended outcome that you
want to have from any change uh
effectively what you're currently
envisaged end state will look like
that end state will evolve over time
but for now you've got this idea of this
is this is where i want to go
you have a goal and we can get behind
that goal you
not some external coach and consultant
need to decide not only what the initial
end state will look like but
what are your first steps going to be
along the way and how you're going to
measure
the outcomes once you have that
you need to make that first step and see
where you get to
while there are some well-known
checkpoints along the way like having an
adaptive backlog
of tactical changes or self-organizing
teams
mostly it's an open field that's why
there's so little guidance
when you speak to agile coaches and
folks in the agile industry you say what
should i do next
it's like well i don't know you need to
decide what you want to do
let me explain the problem you're trying
to solve
you've come up with the ideas you as
leaders
need to understand why you are taking a
particular direction
and what you expect the outcome for your
organization to be
while you may need help you are
accountable
for the changes ahead and only you if
you're the leaders in the organization
you're accountable for those changes as
you take each step along your journey
you may realize that you were wrong that
this direction leads not to your
intended outcome but
somewhere else you then need to decide
if that somewhere else is actually a
better place than you thought of
at the start and then figure out what's
my next step where do i need to go next
you need to be free to experiment accept
that any processes and practices you
create would be
imperfectly defined and adapt
to what you discover along the way you
will use
orienteering to stop periodically
reassess both your goal in the direction
you need to go
and then take the next step towards
your intended outcomes experimentation
is key to this process you will not
know what will work until you try it
you'll also not know what will not work
think back to how you might have built
your company in the first place
it was likely a short iterative process
where you continuously tried different
things
figuring out what was a good way to do
things and keeping the things that
worked
and ditching the things that didn't this
entrepreneur
entrepreneurial spirit is what we're
trying to retrieve
and create a system within which we can
maintain it
indefinitely over time we need to remove
bureaucracy and get back the creativity
that was smothered by that bureaucracy
of these traditional practices i want to
be clear
that this new state of agility in this
new state of agility
everything will change every business
process you currently have
was built on the bureaucracy that you
have in your organization it was created
slowly over time
these bureaucratic processes will have
to be dismantled as they are no longer
valid
for the new speed of the world that
takes time
focus and commitment this type of change
is not something you can buy in from the
outside
and it must be organically and
iteratively grown
inside your organization you may hire
many consultants coaches and trainers
along the way
but it is you who must be driving that
vision
and setting that direction don't get
trapped
into a transformation of one
bureaucratic
process for another instead
evolve your organization out from under
it
and innovate your way to success
this is the inevitability of change
thank you very much
so uh there's a link there
uh this uh this link uh here will take
you to
a copy of the presentation it has my
notes in it as well but a copy of the
presentation
and if you have a camera you can just
take a picture of the
qr code and get to exactly the same
location
uh please i also head off to my
youtube channel i have lots of videos on
there
is there any questions
thank you very much martin please is
there any questions
for martin you can put in the chat or
raise your hands
and then we will let him answer it for
you
any questions for martin
i see i see a question that says could
that be frederick
taylor um i'm not sure what the question
is
maybe it's i think you made a comment on
management and
frederick winston taylor he's the source
of all our problems today
he's not really he was doing the right
thing at the time
if you are currently managing a factory
you're probably going to use the ideas
that he came up with but as your factory
moves towards
replacing the people automation with
robot automation
mechanical automation the people that
then run
your factory are going to be creative
people who are solving problems on a
day-to-day basis and you'll need these
new
so any questions
and the question will take about
three to four minutes at five minutes
we'll take some few any questions please
any questions for martin
wow so i think martin your presentation
was quite
clear and i think people have yeah
temptation by the way that's all
what's that sorry wonderful presentation
thank you for the parties uh
collaborative um attendant
i tried the board i didn't succeed
it depends on how fast your computer is
and the internet and all kinds of things
so
um it's okay i just put a a link
to the presentation in the
chat um and i also put a link to
my linkedin profile as well if you're
interested in some of my other content
there any other any other questions it
can be anything it doesn't have to be on
what i was talking about
i don't mind
awesome no questions
[Music]
martin i actually do have a question
yeah
i took my ipod modification with eggs in
and i want to become like you right
so that i can become a pm a scrum dot
org trainer
so i reached out to scrum.org and i said
to them
that i'd like i want to do their
certifications
and and they said that for me to become
one of their trainer i still have to go
through the process of doing the um
the psm1 and above
i mean what advice do you have for me
though
uh so for psm1
reading the scrum guide is probably
reading and understanding the scrum
guide is
is really the the what what you need for
the psm1
psm2 is a lot more situational questions
um so having some experience as a scrum
master works well
uh for for psm2 um
psm3 is a lot i think it's um
i think there's five five plus essay
questions
uh so it's marked by uh a human rather
than
marked by the system uh and that's
that's a lot more complicated if you
want to be a trainer you need to get
95 in order to
pass um
so i would just follow the the learning
path
on the website there's a list of on the
scribbler website there's a link for i
want to be a trainer
and they have a number of different
routes in there's a route in through
kanban
there's a i think you're not a coder
mercy
i'm not a cro i'm not a coder i'm a
scrum master
okay yeah so the that you want to use
the psm
roots then there is a coder route but uh
you want to use the psm route
um so yeah it just it's it's taking the
assessments getting a high enough score
and you will need 85 percent you also
need to attend
a special um psm
class uh that's run by scrum.org they
run them periodically and they're
special
train the trainer uh kind of
events that's a little bit longer and
they dive into
some of the things around why we talk
about things in the class and the
purpose of the different exercises
um it's it's it's an involved process
it is an involved process it's much so
you should have become a trainer when i
did 10 years ago it was much easier back
then
i reckon that much anyway but so
basically for me to become
a scrum.org trainer i need to go through
their process
basically i mean my certification
that's the advice i was given so
basically i have to go through it yeah
okay thank you so much everybody
everybody needs to go through
uh the process uh there is a page
on the site uh become
a professional scrum trainer uh that
will show you the
the steps um and the the
stuff you get and who you need to speak
to there's a lot of content on there
uh but if you can click apply here it
will tell you all of the prerequisites
uh um and just follow follow the path
and it's not it's not cheap by the way
to start up but
um it can be very useful
thank you so much appreciate it very
welcome
thank you very much martin and mercy i
think one of the good news for you is um
scrum dot org the director for pst
has reached out to us in terms of
how to get more africans to become pst's
in terms of assisting you in your
journey so i think once we have your
database and everything we'll get in
touch with you
awesome we'll try to guide you through
the process
thank you very much is there any other
question
and martin i sent you a connection on
linkedin already thank you
perfect just so you know there are no
psts currently in africa scrum. would
love
to change that um i think
having having african trainers uh will
change the the the the change the
landscape
of organizations in africa because
you've got the you've got the advantage
you're not saddled
with a lot of the baggage and
bureaucracy that a lot of companies in
in europe and the us the old world have
and that's an advantage if you can take
advantage of these new ideas
and build your organizations around them
now
it's gonna be awesome