hey Jacob you both the link and the
invitation code only work for people who
are already a member of your Azure
Active Directory so that's not gonna
work for students or for for me what you
need to do is you need to go to the team
so to be the team here and then you have
to add a member and if you put in Martin
at nkd agility comm it'll come up well
mine says I can't find any matches but
yours should come up and say an
invitation let me copy your email I
don't know what the emails are for your
Azure Active Directory but this will
come up and say at guest so I can click
Add Oh awesome so mine's messed up
because your email address something
weird is going on with that that I might
have to fix so I'm gonna go into the
admin system and try and fix that so I
can add you in there but that's how you
do that you have to hit add members I
when I'm inviting students to the class
if I get them up front and I use our
power shell script that loads the excel
sheet with all the students in it and
I'll load them all in to Azure DevOps
and does your DevOps to the system
active directory for authentication and
instead of them getting the automated
email I take their I build their
invitation links and then I load that
into MailChimp so they get an email from
me like you know like course email that
just has that here accept this
invitation clickable link in there and
then they are authenticated with Active
Directory and then they can get into the
team but if you just add them on teams
they'll get an invitation I wanted you
to see the invitation email so I'll try
and go and fix that so you can get
the invitation email okay