if you're an
organization and you're trying to
respond to changes that happen in the
market you want to be able to respond to
them as quickly as possible so those
changes could be surprises surprises are
usually bad um that you have to go deal
with or it could be opportunities right
things you want to go take advantage
of and if you have a long lead time
between
deciding you want to do something and it
ending up in production then you're not
going to be able to take advantage of
opportunities that arise lots of
opportunities are going to float by and
somebody else is going to take advantage
of them or you're not going to be first
to Market or any of those things so one
of
the I'm going to use an example so the
aure devops team when was TFS back in
201 uh 10 2012 type of time frame they
were they were doing a 2-yearly ship
schedule right so they were shipping to
production every two years that was
their Cadence with a service pack
halfway what would invariably
happen is they would get halfway through
their development their two years so
after a year or maybe a year and a half
they would they would ship a a beta of
the new version of the product and
people would start kicking the tires on
the beta and they would have lots of
feedback and some of that feedback could
be incorporated but maybe the feedback
was a a bigger missing feature or
something that customers are doing in
the market that that isn't in the
product or some change in the way we do
things that's a bigger change something
a little bit meteor right and there's
there's no way we can we can fit that
into this version of the product right
so there's there's six months left to go
we're we're effectively mostly bug
fixing and tweaking from our 2-year
development they coming to the end of
our two-year
development and we've already planned
the work that's going to go
into the next version of the
product so in actual fact unless this
feature is super important it might be
just a little problem for
customers we're not going to bump
anything out of the next version of the
to fit this in so those
features aren't going to make it into
the product for more than two years
because it'll be not the next version
but the next next version of the
product and that was a huge conundrum
for them because devops was starting to
move
faster Azure was taking off and
customers wanted these faster Cycles
faster deployments and visual studio and
TFS and those kind of tools weren't able
to keep up at all windows as well but
that was a little bit later not much
later but a little bit later
so they need they needed to shorten that
delivery time right they had to have
high deployment frequencies rather than
low deployment frequencies and they
literally went from from in 2010
Microsoft was doing something like 20 or
30 deployments a year right so the the
the the the deployments of their
products and and by the end of 2018 I
think they were at 880,000
deployments per year across the
organization and that's just in aure
devops not for aure devops but in the
product aure devops that they used for
for that so when you shorten your
feedback
loop between getting an idea out there
getting something in the market testing
it in the market getting that feedback
look back around how quickly can you
adapt right time to learn is going
around that effectively going around
that Loop twice so in order to do that
you don't want a yearly deployment you
don't want a six-monthly deployment you
don't want you don't even want a two-
weekly deployment you want continuous
delivery to production you want to
continuously be able to get the features
that you're working on that your teams
are working on in front of real users as
quickly as possible you want to take an
idea that you have and you want to take
like what what's the smallest test we
can do what's the smallest feature we
can build smallest thing we can build in
our product to validate whether this
this Market opportunity actually
exists right and and get that into your
product as quickly as possible then look
at the data look at the Telemetry and
decide whether you're going to invest
more in that or it needs to be changed
slightly or
yeah it was a great idea in my head but
once we started engaging with users it
wasn't a good idea and in order to be
able to do that in order to be able to
move with Market changes meet Market
demands and look forward into the future
to preempt and try to get ahead of the
market right you want to be the one
setting the market you don't want to be
following your competitors you want to
be the one setting the market trends and
in order to do that you have to be on a
tight release frequency you have to be
continuously delivering your product to
to to production you have to be getting
every change you make in front of real
users and that is going to help you um
adapt to Market opportunities deal with
Market surprises and maximize the value
that you create in your product