that could be you know when dealing with
bug reports or it could be just with
engaging with them and talking to them
about the problems that they're
encountering and trying to solve within
our within our product domain um and we
want to be benevolent we want to be seen
as we're providing them with something
that helps enable them to do something
else if they see our product as a burden
or they see our product as um I don't
know what the what's the cost version of
Burden for me burden's Broad and then
there's a cost like a cost center if
they see your product as a cost center
then um they're they're not going to
think of your product with kindness um
and you're probably not thinking of them
with kindness