if there was one thing that new product
owners should know above all the other
things that we've talked about that's
that they need to focus on continuous
learning they need to be looking at um
what's happening in the industry what's
happening in the market what are the new
new tools and techniques that are
available it doesn't mean you're going
to use use them there's always a little
bit of a danger of the cult of the new
right well we're using it because it's
new but you need to understand all of
the different tools and techniques that
are available to you at least enough to
know what thing you might choose for a
particular circumstance so you can have
a goal the more tools you have in the
toolbox the better um there's a great uh
uh blog post that I read years ago it
was focused on um developers uh coders
but it applied the theory applies just
the same and it started with the phrase
if you're reading this you're already in
the top
10% and that's because there's only a
small number of uh people that actually
focus on continuous learning that
actually try new things all the time
that are actually reading up on
different techniques and different
topics they don't have to be new they
can just be new to you they can be older
things that you're uh going and figuring
out crossing the chasm was written in
the'80s right what are the things that
you're reading how do you enable
yourself to be in the top 10% because
that's how you maximize your chances of
getting the best gigs right is you need
to be in the top 10% and if all you need
to do to do that is read some blog posts
every week maybe a couple of books a
month that's not a high bar to get into
that top 10% and then you'll be the one
uh with people knocking at your door
trying to figure out uh how to get you
to be their product owner right so as as
a new product owner read voraciously
read uh blog posts watch videos on
YouTube uh follow on LinkedIn the other
product owners out there that you'll be
able to find product owners and product
managers what are they talking about
what are they into what are they
teaching you uh learn about
evidence-based management hypothesis has
driven engineering uh okrs all of those
marketing things around AB testing um
Mechanical Turk different tools you can
use to
enable you to have the information you
need to make the best decisions you can
around maximizing the value of the work
done by your scrum team or if you have
multiple scrum teams by all of those
scrum teams what is it that you're going
to do to maximize the value continuous
learning is the key to that um we can
help you we have a bunch of at scrum
classes or from scrum.org uh we have the
um the professional scrum product owner
uh Advanced product owner if you want to
dive a little bit deeper but on the side
of that you've also got the professional
scrum with caman bring in those flow
mechanics and flow stories professional
scrum with ux which is focused on the
lean ux go read the lean ux book if you
want to understand what that is these
tools and techniques along with many
others that you can learn uh online that
we can certainly point you to are the
things that are going to differentiate
you from all the other product owners
out
there you need to focus on continuous
learning if you find it hard to focus on
continuous learning if you don't know
where to look or what to do then my team
at naked agility can help you or point
you in the right direction to find the
help you do need don't let the plethora
of misinformation out there uh get in
your way we can help you filter all of
that nasty stuff and get to the Nuggets
of gold that will help you stand out as
a product owner use the links in the
description to get in touch um and let
us help you