there we go so what what I normally do
for students is I do I schedule a
half-hour or a 1-hour tech check the
week before the class and sorry any of
these teething problems so the types of
problems that I sometimes get just like
if you want to join a Google hangout or
you want to do any of these meeting
tools you need an account enabled for
the platform and in this case Microsoft
will let you use any account you want so
you can use a gmail account you can use
a hotmail account you can use anything
if it's not already enabled for I might
as a Microsoft account they'll ask you
to create the the just the profile for
it so it'll be the same email address so
your your Gmail or your your whatever
mail your company mail and if your
company has as your Active Directory
that's all done already and you'll just
be able to use your corporate
credentials to log in so your students
if you're working with a big enterprise
customer quite often they already have
office 365 they can just use exactly the
same credentials that they use to log
into teams that they use in the office
to log into teams so what they'll get if
I share my screen and then pop it back
up because it helpfully minimizes it for
me yes they will get a little drop-down
list at the top right here of teams so
if if both the accounts are the same or
you are a member of two teams accounts
under the account you're logged in as
you'll get a list of the different
places you can go so I have my own
company tenant in in Azure and I also
have I can access the Microsoft tenant
and then I have two customers in here
who have added me to their tenant yes.we
if the account you've
I already had a Microsoft enabled for it
and has already been added to a
customer's account or your own you'll
see that there I know we lost their
child's I think yes child lost Charles
he's trying to get something sorted
Charles has office 365 under his own
brand and so he has his scrum crazy in
here as well so you'll see whatever
makes sense at the time it is key to
know that the only problem I really ever
run into is the one that a couple of you
have run into that the email address you
log into teams and the email address you
were invited on or different in that
case you can see on the right-hand side
here that Jose does not have a little
red dot and when I roll over his picture
oh look they fit all of the PII is
removed so I cannot see his email
address whereas if I roll over yourself
I see that you're in a call it has the
presence information it has your email
address and I can do a direct video call
email and message you that's how you
know they've come in in a way that you
can do all of the the things that we
want to be able to do okay if you just
want to have a meeting in teams then it
doesn't matter how they come in they can
just use the invite link anybody can
come in with any link north indication
required okay and so that's how Jose has
come in so we can both coexist in the
same thing as well so if you do have a
student that has a particularly
difficult problem it's not the end of
the world that they can't see everything
else that that we can see we can we can
figure out something something for them
I did have a student earlier who had
that sort of problem and he didn't sort
it out till the the first break when he
could reboot his computer or whatever
the problem was
we didn't have a problem until then our
there's some new features in teams since
Magdalena I don't know if you can see
nine pictures yet while there's not nine
people in but on my machine up here I
can see six five people because they've
added the capability to have up to nine
people being seen
cream you can also see I've got raise
your hand functionality oh you get four
so it's it's still rolling out it's not
for everybody yet but over the next week
it's going to go in to finish rolling
out yeah yeah I saw I saw you did that
so you got a hand raised functionality
and you can see it on the right here and
I can actually go in and lower your hand
once I've dealt with whatever that
question is and the people with their
hand raised pop to the top of the list
which is quite handy so you can see
people and then you can see on the
picture down here and you might be able
to see that or you might not but Hegel
Charles has raised his hand so you'll
get the hand popping up there I mean
these are just I know zoom has some of
those features as well it's just nice
features to make sure that we have so
the thing that I think are the useful
features in here one one is the security
is obviously it means it's more
difficult but it is secure if I don't
want anybody else to come into this
meeting they can't get in which
obviously has its downside as we've seen
and but on the left hand side here you
can if if you're m oh and I see oh no
just it's just who's they that wouldn't
so you won't be able to click on here
Jose and see what we see and but you'll
be able to follow along that's why I'm
sharing so if I click on teams and you
can see the teams that are within the
tenants that you're connected to so I'm
connected to my one obviously a mr.
scrum crazy will have
his company name in here as well oh yeah
he's not able to get his camera working
that's okay and you can see the
different teams for different classes
that I have run or I'm running and at
the moment we're in the general channel
of this live virtual face-to-face on ms
teams that I created for scrum the dark
group and you'll be able to see that
there is a call on going because in the
general rule there's a little light
which shows that the the calls running
and anybody can come in and join that
call and see that it's being recorded
and who's recording it all of that
information is just provided in here and
you'll notice that I can see Charles's
chat from inside of the meeting outside
of the meeting and I can actually reply
from outside of the meeting as well into
that that chat that's that's can be
pretty useful especially if students are
in a call and you want them to come back
you can just ping them in their chat
without having to actually join the call
as well and you can add applications to
teams
aerosol Russell's been running a bunch
of classes on teams with me and he had
the unfortunate happenings of zoom going
down on Sunday for a class on the second
day of your class yes yeah so we set up
in record time a team and got all his
students in in order to carry on the
class on the second day so to have a
backup anyway because these things
definitely happen and I know of a couple
of times when teams has gone down as
well I mean every platform is going to
have these kind of things you just need
to be able to pivot when when things go
wrong I was just saying that you can add
apps to the to the team and by default
you'll have posts files and Wyck
Wiki is a really really cheap wiki don't
get your hopes up it's a very cheap
poorly implemented wiki but it might be
good enough for what it is you're doing
I usually just remove it because I don't
I don't I don't want the wiki there and
so posts and files is the default
they're the only two that cannot be
removed if I go to files and you can see
I've uploaded the PSM reference guide
here so everybody who's a member of the
team will be able to download the files
that are there and they can actually
sync them to their desktop as well and
so I'm just gonna show you this on my
machine so if you've used onedrive
you'll know you get a personal onedrive
and a corporate onedrive entry if you
log in to both on the same computer and
if you click the sync button here you
actually get this other one appears
which is shared folders from teams or
web sites or SharePoint from different
organizations and and it works exactly
the same way as onedrive and but there's
I don't think I've synced this one but
if I open up this one which is for one
of my customers you can see there's
general team one team two team 3 it
creates the folders for each of the
channels and if I open up it will have
and I uploaded the tech check in there
where I'd recorded it for the customer
and I stored the the the roster for the
the class and there as well since it was
a private class it would not there's not
a BPI problem sorry a PII problem I have
personal identifiable information if you
for for losing Europe that's a thing we
have to worry about a lot um but for for
public classes obviously I wouldn't put
there just put the roster em in there
you if you're used if you're used to
using other storage platforms you can
actually just add Dropbox or Google
Drive or whatever you want in there so
you can integrate it with whatever you
want and and I did mention you can add
apps
kind of like an app the storage account
but you can actually I mean I'm pretty
sure if you look for it they've got it
and it's a very extensible platform so
lots of people are built for it so
there's there's mural there's that wiki
that I was using but also those all
kinds of crazy stuff even Stack Overflow
have built our a plugin for it because
they've got corporate Stack Overflow as
well so you can do all kinds of i-i've
not really looked through the whole list
there's tons of things you can get
Trello
right on here and everything just right
on the display and however I am not
using the mural plug-in because the
mural plug-in requires that everybody
login as an authenticated user and I
want people to use the anonymous login
so I don't have to pay a license which
is always good because they're not cheap
from Europe and so if you click on if
you were to go to the same place that
I'm looking at and click on mural you'll
see it will say enter anonymously and I
can just enter anonymously or or login
and you get exactly the same experience
as in a browser and you can even if I
pop this expand tab it will make it
relatively fullscreen relatively and if
the students want to pop it out they can
just click go to a website and it will
open in a web interface and you can even
chat along with this item and it will
appear as a conversation in the in the
list as well to do with the tab so that
can be quite useful I just did it as I
just did it as I I just added a web page
so you can just add a website so I also
added the scrum guide because you know
that could be useful for students and
the scrum open straight into the
assessment without all of the chrome
surrounding it so that that can help as
well
pair is that is that an actual question
from pep
I can't even I can't even wear the right
oh I have to go back into the call which
I click here there we go
pear pear Pete who's pear ping pear okay
did you have a question uh-huh it's okay
I thought there was a question there was
an indication to be that there might be
a question cool um so you I mean you can
add as many tabs as you want obviously
there's some there's gonna be a
limitation of space and whatever
resolution people are using and all that
that that that governs in here and and
when you create a team helpfully
Microsoft creates a bunch of stuff
behind the team and those are a group
and which is a male enabled and security
enabled group that's created in your
Azure Active Directory and so you can
send email to an email you can actually
I think you click on here and say it's
somewhere around here there we go get
email address and it will get me the
email address for this channel and if I
send emails to that email address those
things will appear in this channel so
you can do all kinds of some of this
stuff you maybe don't care about from
running a class but there's there's
loads of other features that are above
and beyond just running a class you can
connect it up to a bunch of things I'm
trying to build plugin for teams that
will enable kind of more class centric
stuff that we need and things that I've
done manually so what I do when I'm
running a class is I create a team
that's the first thing I do and then I
give it a nice friendly name and then I
add my students and you can add any
email address you want and it will
invite them so occasionally a student
said oh I can't log in on that email
here's a different email and I just add
it I'm not worried about
removing the the old one and I use a
tagging system in here so let's see if
we can tag the folks that are if I
manage team you'll see this 43 people in
this team because we had the previous
event as well so let's do Session two
and I'm going to create a tag called
session 2 and I'm gonna find where's
Charles make you students and session
two right Delana
session two up Ben didn't make it you
Liam Session two Russell's around here
somewhere
oh there's Peter open this so and one of
the nice things you can do is I all of
the students with students I tagged all
of the facilitators with facilitators
and if there's more than one team I try
and tag the people in team one with team
one team two a team two
now in the general tab I can say at and
and what what did I call the remember
why I called it now what was that what
did I call the session they call it
session to session - thank you as soon
as I start typing session you'll see it
comes up with this tag session - six
people are in this tag and you can send
a message and they'll all get that
message flagged so I quite often use
that to pull people back from their team
rooms because in teams it's not going to
create bake-out rooms for you and then
pool kill the breakout rooms and pull
students back students have to be
responsible for their own time box I've
noticed that it depends how you treat
your students if you let them self
organize they actually will and they'll
keep the time box them cell
if you don't provide any hints and I've
just been given notifications like one
minute remaining and and then bringing
them back and so that comes to how do
you do breakout rooms
yeah breakout breakout rooms are at
they're actually super easy in teams
every meeting URL and teams is unique
okay if you want to create a new one you
can actually just go down to meet now at
the bottom here click it type in a title
click meet now and oh if I still got
that crazy background on there we go and
type in whatever you want to call it hit
meet now and everybody in that channel
will be invited to that team so I could
create more than one meeting in the same
channel I'm not gonna do that I'm gonna
go over into team one and I'm gonna
create a channel called team one so when
I click meet now I'm gonna disappear
Russell would you show them again how to
how to instantiate a meeting how you use
the meet now function yep no problem so
and if you want to get the the meeting
at the bottom here there's a meet Now
button down here if you click it it'll
pop up our create a meeting dialogue and
I'm just gonna call it team one and then
I would click meet now and when I click
meet now I'm going to get the call that
I'm in with you just now is going to get
put on hold for me and then I will go
into team one but I'll be back in just a
second hello and that's how long it took
me to go set up the other room for the
students so now you'll see in the team
there's no two little lights was one
next to the new team one antilope you
could you reserve the screen oh yes I
can they did get kicked off thank you
very much ah so on the left hand side
you'll see that it has a general and a
team one meeting logo now to say that
there's some kind of meeting in progress
you can still see this one still being
recorded up here and even though I
wasn't in it I can leave the meeting and
rejoin and it stays but if I now click
on antelope you'll see that those are
join button here now as well and Russell
why aren't you going ahead into that
room and we can show everybody how this
works because what you'll see when
Russell disappears and join this room a
little logo will pop up here that shows
who's in the room well I may put a snag
in your plans because I'm not here if
you look I have the little red dot
beside me yeah you'll have to invite me
I'm not here in the same context as your
other no you don't have the okay well
since Russell couldn't follow
instructions maybe at Magdalena would
you like to jump into this team one room
and then and then pop back after a few a
few seconds uh-huh so peeking c'mon and
join right yep
so she's joining this room and I think
maybe I have to refresh hmm
in a few seconds it will pop come up
with our Magdalena's little letters to
say that she's in this room and you'll
notice that I up here have a team one on
hold if I want to go to the other team
like if I'm the trainer and I want to
hop between teams or I'm a student and I
just want to go into that team I can
just click that play button and I'll
jump there really quickly hello welcome
back yeah so it's it's very quick to
jump into the team so if you want to go
do that just now I go trying for those
that are that have come in correctly
Russell go try and jump into that that
team and then I'm back you can see here
what I mean by the little toggles about
who's in the in the team well they are
doing days Martin did you see my senior
an email with the Microsoft account only
invite me again
bring this over here that's okay whether
it would just work for what like I said
I do I do a check tech check with
students true the week before cuz that
these sorts of things are sometimes sent
to tryouts in they've have so in fact
you'll see the invitation process cuz I
like to go and invite you put in an
email that is not currently a member
might mean it will just say add as a
guest at the moment team's doesn't care
what type of account that says you
decide that when you accept the
invitation so I add that and then in a
second right you should be you should
have an invite in your email within the
next few seconds I look for it
I just stopped thank you I actually
joined you during a class break I
appreciate you doing this for us
I'll see you later you're very welcome
Russell sue Wharton yes and what can be
done when the team's not joined so I can
set up the teams
I can set up the rooms but I can't label
the in that the people I've invited
already so I have to do this when they
are life understand you labeled you
labeled your team members with the
student 1 yep
student and team 1 general no house
formation to do that in here
only the facilitators do yes but do they
have to be joined in already or can you
do this in preparation of the class no
you can do this already so if I go find
I just invited was they from the other
should be another Jose in here somewhere
it is so he's not accepted it yet
and I can go I can go tag them so I can
set it up beforehand that's fine and
then you'll you'll notice that I can see
information about people that have
joined correctly so I can go check
whether they've joined correctly as well
so I can pre prepare that and maybe
chase people up and if I go I'm gonna
see if I can bring this other window
across for you to show you Jose do you
mind if I put your is you is it okay to
have your email address on the recording
yeah we just pasted it any way you can
yeah I I'm trying to login anything this
is give me to create a password is that
correct if it is not already a Microsoft
account it will ask you to do that if
it's a ad account it'll ask you to login
so troublemakers my account as far as I
know
so and you just like diverting no one
else okay so if you if you go into as
your active directory you can actually
look up I'm not going to go to the list
of users because it would be more people
and random students so and I can't
control what it displays but this is you
would type in the person's name it would
come up with this and at the moment it
says invitation accepted no and I had to
resend the invitation and you can also
get the URL and just send them an email
and say here you you've not followed
this process click here to follow the
process bla bla bla so you can make sure
everybody set up and before you start
the class to be honest if I do a tech
check the week before I've not really
had any problems with real students I've
only had problems with PS T's same as I
do class you only have problems with PS
DS so I'm teaching a PS k at the moment
and I have I have five PS T's in my
class which is always fun yet it's it's
called there being a masochist I think
that's that's a good question so the
number of free so I you can pay three
three pounds a month for one user for
you like an office 365 business basic
account and that gets you unlimited yes
okay unlimited guests you can invite now
in teams there is a limit you can only
have 5,000 people in one team so you're
not ever
hit back Oh unless you're gonna have a
class with five thousand five thousand
and one people in it you're fine all
right in in in the team's when you
create a channel you can actually have
both standard and private channels don't
use private channels until you know
exactly how they work okay private
channels are a whole additional
complexity they're actually secured in
their own right so it's almost like
creating a new team inside of your team
and you get a whole new set of assets
for it they are completely isolated so
if you upload a file in there there's no
way anybody else could get access so I
just use the public ones and when people
self organize at the beginning of the
class using mural into teams
they then know which team they're in and
when I say go into your team's if you
know you're in team one you go off to
the team one at call now you'll notice
that this team one call is just on hold
it's just been sitting there there's
nobody in it it's not going to stop
until somebody kills the call which I go
kill the calls later I have left them
open and I come back in 24 hours and
they've been killed so I assume there's
some kind of time limit but I've never
hung about to figure out at what it is
and for that three pounds per user per
month for licensed users you get
unlimited teams you get the 5,000
members you can run a single call can
have up to 250 people in it and
depending on the type of license you've
got and I've got I don't know what
license you need and but I can run
something called a live event which can
support up to 40,000 attendees but I
think I I have I have a special I do
have I have something called an e3
license for for Microsoft which is an
enterprise 3 which I think is too
$800 per user per month I don't pay that
don't worry and I get it as part of
being an MVP so as I basically pay
nothing for it so it's awesome yeah each
lesson shooter has basic six dollars six
six dollars and
well I've never I put it this way I I
just I just have the basic licensing
there's only two licensed users in my
whole account which is me and my wife
and I have four hundred guests in fact I
actually run this which is a community
portal for all of my students ex class I
don't know how many people are in here
must be they go 239 in that one team so
that's all my previous students that
also can come in and chat and access
extra stuff so I just run that in here
as well it's not as slick as slack you
know you can just send out the invite
URL you can't do that with teams you
have to invite emails explicitly but I
found the people that have come in and
done the live virtual class and teams
are quite happy to use team you know to
continue to use teams to come in and
chat and leave messages and and and talk
about stuff so that that's been that's
been quite good I did want to point out
something I did there was something I
wanted to point out and let me see if I
can remember how to do it and if you're
somebody who does like something like
and zoom right but you want the other
capabilities in here as well then I'm
pretty sure I saw there now it's not
there I have to go over here down to
apps and then I think I can go zoom and
I can let's see let's add this to the
team where's the face-to-face so I'm
going to set up a zoom bot in this
Tim so all you do is you like I think
there's a button here somewhere they go
there's a zoom button start a meeting
schedule a meeting in zoom so if I just
go start a meeting it allows me to sign
it
sign in to zoom and teams and then it
are where you go and I think if you type
zoom oh I just hit space do I do at zoom
oh there we go and then you would start
a zoom meeting safe an organization is
blocking zoom and their home team's
would zoom it in to be right will not
bypass an organization's block okay one
of the reasons I use teams yeah is that
I'm not happy with them security
therefore if I'm using teams I don't
have to worry about that but if and I
mean Jim might not be the best example
for that but I'm pretty sure
where's zooms under communications so
probably there's a I don't know I don't
know what what this fuse that's a
communication service there's WebEx
integration zoom was in here
I mean there's there's a lot of the
other platforms that provide
communication channels are in here as
well so you could would be able to use
multiple channels if you wanted to use
multiple channels that's all I was
getting at with being able to add the
the zoom bot it basically just sits
there in ads builds calls behind the
scenes and now I'm I'm writing an app
that is the same idea that will let us I
want to be able to do things and
there's an API for calling for the
calling infrastructure so in theory you
could do a 1/2 for all or other
liberating structure and actually
implement as a thing that that for
example and ever you know you give
everybody a minute and then you call
what wouldn't be one to four all via to
400 wouldn't it you you call it to for
all commands and it will go and take all
of your students break them up into
pairs and call each student and put them
in with a pair and then you can join to
Carl's so there's all the api's are
there to do that it's just a case of me
figuring out what the code is to
actually do that which is a little bit
harder because I suck at going these
days but I've built some stuff around it
like I can log in and get a list of
teams and I can do I've done some stuff
already and but I'm just messing around
with the API is just now to figure out
what is possible Microsoft are building
breakout rooms for teams dynamic
breakout rooms like zoom I'm trying to
get a hold of the folks that are
building it to maybe get proof of
concept maybe get us into the beta
program or something but I'm just
they're not very responsive like other
groups that I prefer but yeah they're
not very responsive are there any
questions those are something I missed
Magdalena Lee Martin Tory to recycle the
channels and the teams so you set this
up once you have the general channel you
have team one team two and to recycle
this for a next class I'll just
so I I don't so if I go into my edit
team I actually create one for each
class and then I can f it so I don't use
this very often but if I go down here I
can actually go those are active teams
and I can actually go archive the team
which will make it read only but the
data is still there they use
can still access it if they want to
means you do you don't have you don't
actually have to you don't have to do
that and I at him while I've been
playing with the app stuff to trying get
it up and running and I do have I do
have some lovely PowerShell if anybody's
interested and which goes and I've
actually got groups for each of the
types of class that I use to secure a
bunch of assets like seeing that and
remember I showed you the the the this
professional scrum community group I
have our courseware folder and in the
files is gonna folder for each of the
classes and inside of that it's got the
courseware only students who took the
PSM class can see this folder it's
secured against the PSM group right so
when I I built you know you have to
build an excel of students anyway
because you got to import it in the
scrum that org and you got to do all
this all the other stuff we've got to do
and I just import that CSV into here I'm
and down here somewhere it goes and
invites the user creates it actually
creates the team creates a class called
friendly name and invites the user
creates the team sets up all of the
stuff adds them to the right groups and
I just run that against the powershell
and that builds everything for me and
then once that's run I can just that's
how all they got there before I change
the way I did it and then I just go in
and and I add the picture and make it
look I don't know if you can see the
pictures on yours I think I've had
problems with that some people can see
it some people can't um but that just
makes it a little bit more friendly and
I don't do that much customization I'm
at the moment I'm waiting till I've got
all that I can add all of these tabs
with code and
can I you can everything except the
tagging which is unfortunate everything
except the tagging has an API and
they're just not ready to release the
API for that yet but there's got to be
one behind the scenes I just can't call
it yet
so almost ever I'm gonna qualify
everything and I'm if I'm building a
website that allows me to set all of
this up I'd be happy to share it with
everybody the more people using it the
more bugs I find that's how I think
about it um but I find it for the
classes that I've run so today was the
first day of the fifth virtual class um
and I ran one with Russell in zoom uh
Friday Thursday Friday and after using
this for a bunch of class II zoom was
really painful for me really painful
like lots of stuff just just is are much
easier in here and I think I think it's
the stuff that matters like this is more
complicated for me as a trainer to set
up once users are in and they can switch
between the rooms it's it's super
straightforward I mean the whole
thinking about the infrastructure like
you've got as your Active Directory and
you've been office 365 and then you get
count invitations that's all like your
brain explodes but at once it's a shame
cause it's a bit of a pain to set up and
make sure you've got all the bits set up
but once it's all ready create a team
start adding people and quite often and
even before I've built the excel sheet
and added people to the to the right
grips and stuff I'll just go up when
they register and go add their email
address and then almost almost this is
my list of students and I can export
that I could I could have the PowerShell
connect to this and then use this as my
list of students to go do the other
stuff that I want to do and these
already
these will already have the the like the
while that says face to face
PSK Edinburgh and date and if I go edit
team that's why I'm using this code so I
already know it's a PSK I already know
the date so I can add students for life
students manage all of that
programmatically as well just makes it
easier you're very quiet by the way I
don't know if you can bring the
microphone closer limit al-sabah
carbon moisture I have a question is it
possible because I have as you know I
have two Microsoft account one is for
Gmail and one is paid Microsoft account
on Microsoft and is it possible to
integrate Calendar from Gmail into the
on Microsoft account because I cannot
schedule and any friend using Microsoft
things because my calendar is a label
day so when I when I shared you're in
here mm-hmm an ad so yeah I see what
your problem is so if you're coming in
under a Microsoft account you're coming
in under the free setup I don't know
what restrictions there are with the
three set up but like I said it's it's
three pounds was that as about three
euros yeah here's our per month for a
basic license business license I'm not
sure which one even even the lowest
license I just Russell set heads up
yesterday and the lowest license with
that has teams is three three euros per
user per month and he said it up as a
month-to-month which i think is like a
dollar more to do month to month per
month but then you can cancel at any
time rather than just paying a years
description I've had my account firm for
many years so since the since they
existed which sometimes causes me other
problems but because you know baggage
baggage is always fun but yeah I don't
know what meditations there are for the
free accounts oh yeah okay that's might
be an issue
yeah I will investigate it Thanks
no problem thank you and give us a sense
of so first of all do I understand that
you recreate the team life it's your
face let's see I can walk you through
the process super quick oh sure man so I
just join or create a team create a team
build from scratch private or public
actually doesn't matter in my context
but if your company is bigger you you
probably want private and then I just
give it a name and this is the this is
actually the trick this is this is the
trick the first name you put in is what
it uses everywhere for URLs and stuff so
I do class and let's do a PSM 2000 and
2005 18 yeah so the PSM in fact let's do
a PSN that starts in a couple of days
there we go so I just put that in there
hit create and it will create the team
it's gonna go build the backend it's
gonna set up everything for me and then
I can start adding people right away but
I usually skip that because the name of
the team is going to come in in the
email so I don't want to add people yet
because it doesn't have a friendly name
so then I just go edit the the team and
this would be ah let's do live virtual
PSM I don't know where is it in
20th May 20 2001 in barcelona okay that
okay there we go
you know crap sorry
yeah it's complicated but it's possible
it's fun yeah no it's no it's setup and
if I if I I'm trying to see if I can get
to something that will show you like
when you get a link to the team or you
get the email address for the team the
email address will be this at my tenant
calm so it's kept that as the core name
while having the friendly name for the
emails and stuff so then I just go in
and I should be able to click on here
just do that a branding partner skin the
dark well not that one yes sir just
stick that in there there we go then
then I've got my friendly set up I go
into the general tab and I go yeah get
rid of that wiki and then I maybe add
some web pages like I did in the other
one that just takes a few seconds see
just website and yes yeah nope I don't
post channel cuz then you don't have to
have a little post in there then you've
got your website and then I just go
manage team and I start adding members
so if they exist already you can just
add them and they don't need an
invitation but if I did you obviously
doesn't exist I would then get to get to
invite them so now Magdalena would be
the only one who can see that team and I
don't know how quickly it refreshes it's
usually pretty quick yeah
immediately so because she's already a
member and already in there as soon as
you pop it in she can she can see it and
you can set up I mean that that's pretty
much all I do and then because this is
no team I can go to my calendar and I
actually do a jewel a new meeting and
there's a little clever thing here that
I can go into see this ad channel I'm I
can go to my live virtual PSM in
Barcelona general and I would call it I
would use the same words and if I and
then you saw there the content that I
put in the invitation I effectively put
that in here you know go and do these
things going to install teams but
everybody who I add to the team who then
accepts the invite will automatically
get paint as soon as they accept the
invite they'll get pending the calendar
invitation to the class after it's
automatic if you're if you're a member
of the team you will get the calendar
invite I don't know how often it polls
but it seems to just all do it all
automatically and then every time you
open up the calendar invite it goes and
updates the calendar invite and adds all
of the people who've accepted in and it
does lots of cool stuff for you which
it's nice it's nice not perfect but it's
got some nice features that's very cool
and what about the group's you were
mentioning that you were setting up
that's open show you that well let's go
and I just say send that out hmm
what was your the group yes only yeah
you mentioned that you had groups in
Active Directory ins and all that yes so
have you ever have you ever used have
you ever used
I might been joined to a Microsoft
domain
well yes I'm just in the process of
doing it so registering all this had me
created the domain etc I've been about
this you just go you just go add groups
and in fact I don't know if you you can
you can hopefully see that but there's
actually a group for this class created
already okay all the members will be
automatically assigned into that group
and you can see that it's a current
currently got an outlet link and a
SharePoint Lync and the teams one will
pop in there in a little bit and it just
takes it goes and sets up stuff behind
the scenes there's the email address
that was created for it and then if you
remember in my parish shell I used our
gooood and to reference it that's that
so you can get all of the date out of
the places you need and then oh there's
a new groups experience whoo oh it
doesn't change that much
oh I was hoping for awesome coolness but
I just got me the openness so you have
all of the the grips set up there and if
I go back to the root and I don't know
if anybody saw but when you go to login
and in emails you have my logo and
various things quite often if you try to
login to my domain it will pop up
we need the login box we'll have my logo
at the top and you've literally just got
company branding and you go set up
company branding and you can do multiple
languages if you want as well so all
those groups created while using team so
is it your your scripts that creates
also automatic okay
it's just when I created but I just you
saw I didn't run any scripts true true
the parser 101 and if I go look at
members oh wait hmm cool thanks yeah
I don't know what else to show you guys
yeah well it's just a question how are
the students reacting with all the
emails they receive they are lost you
have to guide them a lot how do you
handle that no no in the clinic for
students in the classes I've run I
haven't had any issues whatsoever okay
nobody's questioned anything nobody's
said they've got a problem with anything
they're just quite happy to to come in
and join there was one um team member of
my last class that said that and I think
he doesn't have install rights on his
local machine okay
so we couldn't install teams and it
wasn't there but he used the web-based
version for the class and it worked fine
for him okay because they need that they
need the rides to install at least the
client you want to install the client
you're gonna need rights to install it
if you but you can use the web-based
version if you just go to teams X off
comm exactly the same yeah and they have
the same the same features and they they
can run it from here
so I admit I've never actually used the
web version but it looks like it's
pretty much identical you've got all of
the different things pretty
straightforward for me for me and
because I've set mine up over a long
period of time it's it's pretty
straightforward once you get there okay
and then you don't have any for example
I've been working with a client and they
denied to use zoom directly maybe they
said here iterations to meet so but with
this if if I told to an organization and
they are not related with teams and they
have to install teams what do I have to
say to them
so to convince them that it's more
secure than zoom
the eye I have I have never encountered
any customer okay Witten office365 backs
almost every large fortune 500
organization in the world I mean it's
it's it is the tool that office365 is
the tool that most big enterprises use
I'm not saying that there's no
enterprises on other stuff there there
are for sure but if you if Google's not
on it but for for most big organizations
that this is what they use as their
communication platform now what you
might find is that an organization might
not give people install rights they can
use the web access an organization and I
do have one customer so in Active
Directory the default is that it allows
my employees so members of my Active
Directory to become guests in somebody
else's Active Directory but that can be
locked down because again it provides
the security that enterprise's asked for
so I do have one customer that cannot
use their corporate email to log into
teams even though they have teams in the
office because their corporation denies
it you know have you ever been on site
with a customer and they they've got
that login federated ping pong thing
goes on yes it's long and it pawns over
to their federated and them back if a
corporate user with that system logs
into my teams they go through the same
authentication for their corporate
identity so their corporation can deny
it that is possible but then they can
just login with a Microsoft account it's
fine like an MSE that's the Azure Active
Directory that's the corporate accounts
or Microsoft account MSA
that's the same when you log into Xbox
that's just the free one like Magdalena
was saying she came in on it's just a
free one mark I know buddy that wanted
access that couldn't get access okay
Martin how do I see which license I have
oh my goodness me oh yeah Maureen's also
interesting because as I said I have two
accounts and one is this is we account
and thing if you go to office if you go
to office.com and you make sure you're
logged in with the email address you're
expecting all right you should be able
to click on now I'm guessing here so I'm
just gonna click it and see so I've gone
into my account if you end up here
you're you're using a corporate
credential if you end up on account stop
Microsoft calm which is you end up Oh
sign in yeah that's how I love you yeah
this is the non corporate we end Oh
where's my
to factor and fingerprint if you end up
here
that's a Microsoft account yeah so I've
got my Martina and she would calm
enabled as a Microsoft account and then
you go into I don't know payments and
billing I think in here or maybe service
and subscriptions actually and it should
list
what subscriptions you have but I'm not
sure that any sort of personal page for
account will give you the features that
you want okay because I have a Microsoft
365 family oh I probably needs to make
my credit card but um that that's the
the but that gives me the office tools
but it does not give me teams I'd be
using teams for free if I logged in
under this personal subscription however
this is my corporate my corporate
subscription yeah which I set up so it's
not I don't work for a bigger company
it's just me yeah like like you guys and
then if you get to this page you click
on subscriptions on the left and you can
see what subscriptions you've got so
this is the one that I pay for for me
which is business standard which
includes should be teams on here
somewhere I think it you just get it
almost often but things being killed
awesome that's a good idea because it
sucks um but I also have our III assign
to me developer account which gives me
more stuff but that's where you'll see
what subscriptions you've got and and
you can you can set up and as your
Active Directory accounts set set aside
some time to go through all of if you're
going to set it up for yourself so
you've got that capability you're going
to need to set aside some time to invest
and maybe reading some of the docs and
figuring out if you just walk through
the process and it does they
do a pretty good job of leading you
through the process I hope Russell
through it yesterday but there's
definitely some bits where even I was
like oh how do I do that and I had to
look up the docks because I did it
organically over time everything's
really well documented on the Microsoft
site and sometimes you have to just have
to follow the five-step process to solve
a particular problem like by default
guests can't join your teams you have to
go say explicitly yes I want to allow
guests to access my team's there's just
a five-step web page that says go do all
of these things in this order and then
you're done so if anybody wants help
with that process I'm quite happy to
help them and point them in the right
direction and what you set up but you
ultimately if you just go to I think if
you just go to Microsoft comm forward
slash office I think and then you see
for business rather than for home you
can get office a Microsoft they've
changed that Microsoft 365 basic and
that includes teams you know I suppose I
have this plan because I have paid
Microsoft for my company for invoices
and everything but I need to check the
base legal standard mm-hmm if standard
just did only definitely basic and
standard as you get the apps yeah yeah
so some more applications than getting
basic yeah and they have they have a big
list of here's all the crap you get and
if you just hit by now it'll lead you
through the process to create an add a
subscription and I can either add it to
my existing account which would be the
one I already have our sign up for a new
account in which case if I hit sign up
for a new it's gonna save me out see
there's my local coming in and my
background e thing you can do all of
those nice brandy stuff and then it's
gonna ask me
what what am i setting up so if I do a
that's probably gonna say that doesn't
exist create a new account and then I
could go through the process of setting
that up does that make sense yeah not a
question you've invited me with my gmail
address but I think I was in it with the
other address I can't remember okay when
I switched my to my gmail address now to
the the toolings I have are they
registered to my other account now or
how would that work so when I when I
invite you you have to use the email
that I invited if that email is a
corporate account already it will let
you it will take you to your corporate
account login and then create your
account in my Azure Active Directory
based on your corporate account so you
only ever use your corporate credentials
if your email address has already been
enabled as I'm msai a Microsoft account
so for example you use it to sign in to
your Xbox already yeah so if you sign in
to your Xbox with your your gmail
account it will just again ask you for
your existing credentials and then
you'll log straight in if that email
address has never been used on any
Microsoft service then it will say you
need to set this up you need to enable
this as a Microsoft account and it'll
ask you for a password you put in the
the you pick a passwords and then that
is now a Microsoft account and you can
use that same email address and password
to log into my services go over to X
barks calm and login there go over to I
don't know any other thing that accepts
Microsoft accounts and use it there as
well does that make sense so is that
there's actually only three things that
can happen and the old result in the
same thing which you have an entry on my
account and you saw that a well I've got
rid of it now but your when it says I
can't type when I brought up yours Peter
it said a Microsoft because it's a gmail
account so it can only be a Microsoft
account but for example and if I don't
want to go look it up cuz you'll see
everybody's data and but if I look up
somebody who's used their corporate
credentials it will just say external as
your Active Directory because it's
already an external account so I'm not
taking anything from if a corporation
already has an existing policy
I'm not overriding that they're using
their credentials in my service so I
don't have their password I don't reset
their password their company controls
that I don't do anything that's where
you can run into the problem that they
blocked it deliberately but it's open by
default so they have to have gone and
done it deliberately likes when you get
IT departments run by nasties that's
when that happens it's actually our
government it's the the the Department
of Work and Pensions in the UK that's my
only customer that's that has that block
and I've worked with defense companies
as well and they don't have that blocked
any other questions that have to do that
or I mean obviously if you were going to
set it up you'd probably end up in a
place where you went how the hell do I
do that thing Martin showed me and I'm
quite happy to to help with that when
you get there uh there is um I believe
that Microsoft are somebody at Microsoft
through Steve Porter offered everybody
six months all the trainer six months
for free
does anybody remember that I remember
that strong yeah so the the I don't know
I don't know how you claim that but if
you find I think it was a neat was an
email on the channel I think it was an
email in the channel because they were
external maybe but they worked for
Microsoft and they they've organized for
all of the trainers to get six months
for free I don't know if it's still
captured in that in the document I Steve
put together for the live virtual
classes I think it was recorded there ok
cool I think it's just embarrassing you
email and they're gonna give you a code
and you've somewhere in here it'll ask
me for money and at that point I can put
in that code instead of money you might
stay in a credit card cuz they're gonna
want their money after the six months a
bit like it's three dollars per user per
month it's not like his what what zoom
zoom
twelve pounds per user per month
something like that 15 days yes it's
like $150 for you yeah so yeah but but
think think about what you get with this
all the the the act I mean maybe if you
don't care about the extra services I
guess it doesn't matter but you get your
corporate email on your corporate domain
you get a terabyte of cloud storage to
put all of your stuff and if you pay the
it's less than the price of zoom the
name the ten you pounds per user per
month you get all of the office apps you
get five licenses for all of them for
your tablets for everything you get
SharePoint you get not that everybody
likes SharePoint but the new don't paint
the new version of SharePoint sharepoint
online the modern sharepoint with the
old sharepoint stuff the old sharepoint
sucked it was a horrible platform i had
to use it and support it and maintain it
with microsoft taking the pain of that
away it runs really well and has some
good features that are useful yeah and
and over the weekend i i i just
subscribed for the microsoft business
basic any is the first six months of
three I didn't go through stronger org
okay
so if you think you have to take a year
early early subscription but the first
six months you got a Half Price
effectively exactly yeah
and that half price is pint fifty per
user per month and you only need to buy
one user well they're still that limit
of five so I'm guessing because you
don't have the basic you have two
standard
I guess they they remove the limit for
the standard but for my account when I
was reading through the documentation
there was that limit of five invited
guests have you guys tried it I'm not
there yet
I didn't when you find you get there
maybe you could invite all of us and
then we could we could see if we can
break the five limit hmm
yeah that would be that would be a good
way to test it because I there's so
there's a secret there's lots of things
that um we meet you buy a license for
but if you buy the license for one month
and turn it off it doesn't disable the
stuff so like I I used the Active
Directory advanced set up I can't
remember why I wanted it but I in I
turned it on I enabled a bunch of stuff
I decided it wasn't worth the money I
turned it off but I still have all the
stuff that I turned on when I had it I
just the page just now says all you have
to buy it to use it and like it's all
configured now I don't care there's a
bunch of branding stuff and other things
and stuff to set up so yeah I I'm not
sure which of the the licenses gives you
more team's access and so you can add
more guests
I would like to find the page that
understands that so that so that we can
see but b2b is one of the features of
Azure Active Directory that's business
to business accounts which is what we've
been using here and because ultimately
it's
so that you know that thing where you go
to a customer site and they give you
logon credentials and you're like I'll
crap another thing I've got to remember
and this is designed to replace that
system so you just use your own
corporate credentials and can log into
as many customers as you want or as let
you that's how come I can switch over to
the Microsoft tenant here as well
they've added my account as a guest in
their tenant if there's no other
questions we're a little bit over but it
seems like you were having fun and
nobody wanted to leave so I kept talking
and I did that it's complicated question
it's complicated to set up your own
domain in this tenant and all this stuff
so know once so once you once you've got
it and once you've created the account
that thing I was following through one
of the steps was set up your business
yeah when you set it up you'll have your
business name dot on microsoft.com
as your email address ok and then you
literally just open up by gwyn out of
directory and click on custom domain
names so there's my my default one which
has my old company domain name then you
just click Add
what's your domain put for example agile
six one one calm six one there we go and
then it then you have okay then it will
give me the text and MX records to
validate it and set up all of the emails
and you don't have any limit abusers
when you add students is aghast in here
for your bed actory or is this just you
here no I mean I just I oh I probably
did want to go in there
ah no I have let me put this on the
other screen so I can lick oh yes so I
just sent so I just sent the link where
they say there's a limit up to the
number of invited yes where did you send
it in the chat the Chad b2b licensing
guidance let's see we should go down
just a bit 60 gets users yes Microsoft
account yeah well it says it's right
there what that does it actually doesn't
make any sense
so I haven't tried to break the limit so
I have two licensees on my account
yes and I have like 500 guests guests
okay yes that's enough yeah and you can
always I think you can make it unlimited
by by buying this yes so that's that you
have been 203 so that's why you don't
have a limit
yeah I have it Ivan III as well all
right
but even if I I'm the thousand it's a
lot yeah but even if you just like you
can buy a premium p1 and a premium p1
would be $6 if you have one user in your
account and a p1 but that's where it got
confused I got confused was that
office365
no so this is separate uh-huh they gives
you extra features so here let me let me
trying to F because they really like the
color the company branding and all this
stuff so there another one guest
features
[Applause]
so for each paid when you're ten you can
invite up to five users for additional
guests beyond the fifth one I don't pay
anything but you're an MVP I know but
it's it's I'm gonna have to go now I'm
good I have to go edit the video and
delete that [__] anyway um I know but I
and this doesn't know I am an MVP okay
does that make sense
this is just don't even know where it go
to find out how much I mean for that
usage until 8 X 3
nope this one this one this one nope I
click the bad button yes this asleep
shins is what you already said well so I
but I do so I do pay for other stuff on
here ok because if you want to spin up I
can spin up a server on here and I paid
for the server I'm trying to find how I
I bet you go here and billing there a
billing thing ill cost management and
billing and you can create badges cost
analysis it's not easy to figure out how
much you pay for stuff on here by the
way still loading
oh well that's nothing so 30 pounds
that'd be bound for that using the
beyond so that's for some tools that I
run let's try the other one did you go
select
No Oh it's loading I'm just too
impatient I'm used to the old world that
it just takes it just yeah I don't think
I pay anything on here so that that's
the only billing I've got which is not
for any of these your stuff so forecast
is about fifty fifty pounds uh a month
and that's for some server stuff that I
run I can actually probably delete that
server okay good idea
I run some DNS I have added my DNS in
here as well here okay so it cost me
very cheap there's my wife's DNS for her
server twenty twenty-one pence so I bet
where would I go to find out the other
stuff so if I go to account so then
that's that's the stuff that my company
pays for mm-hmm
this is the stuff that I pay for like
kind of as an individual it goes through
the company cards and know I'm in the
wrong place now that's just my account
where how do I get to the where was i
before that's the only thing office
that's where we were before and then in
my account so now we might offer stock
and subscriptions yeah but I bought it a
barrel it doesn't have if you notice it
doesn't have teams in there no it it's
further down though I know I have teams
as part of this I also have other stuff
that's part of the e3 the e3 has a
minute but and I also have this
if you want yeah so that one was the six
dollars per user yeah yeah additional
six dollars per user so I pay for two so
additional twelve dollars and I get the
the extra I get the extra layer of
security and all of my two-factor
authentication and a bunch of other
stuff that I use because if I've got
everything on here I've got all of my
student emails are in excel sheets
secured on this system so it has to be
has to be secure so I pay a little bit
extra and for additional security
I'm just looking for where I actually
pay money for this I'm good to know I
know it comes to my credit card put it
this way I checked my credit cards I
don't have anything come out that I'm
like holy crap look at that and maybe
pay a hundred bucks a year for office
365 and maybe fifty bucks a month for my
user stuff and that gets I've got a
bunch of servers and other stuff in
there as well and that pricing was for
the servers and DNS and that kind of
thing so it's maybe I pay a hundred
bucks maybe I paid two hundred bucks a
year for office 365 stuff and that gets
me everything hmm so what if I wanted to
get the issue p1 because I'm already
invested I have to make that work for my
you just you just don't put you open up
an active directory on any of the things
like if you went to nope
enterprise applications no no not in
there
I don't know so to be honest I would
google it and then I would figure out
from there that's what I normally do
okay but there's definitely I think
that's a premium feature yeah I'll look
out how I get I can get general
collaboration properties maybe no I
actually don't I don't know where you go
for that stuff to be on yeah I'll figure
it out thanks thanks that's very
interesting
instructed hopefully it was it was
useful it is it is let's go edit that
recording so that I do we follow GDP our
stuff sorry about that
dammit all right man thank you very much
for this this has been very helpful and
Wow yeah that's it have a good day have
a good afternoon
you are very welcome okay