agile went wrong fairly early on it
started to go off the rails almost right
from the beginning because there were
there were certain assumptions that were
made by the folks that codified it that
created the agel manifesto so think
think of those folks as um they were the
right people that were available at the
right time right so there's probably
people that were around at the time that
could have been in that room but weren't
right uh just because weren't available
or whatever but the people that were
invited to to to
Snowbird um
were the best of the best working with
the best of the best so because um they
they were already very highly regarded
in their Industries um they were already
working with people who were very highly
regarded and there was an assumption of
uh competence I Assumption of capability
um of the people that were participating
within the process that we're talking
about so for agile to be
successful um we have to be
continuously trying to figure out
whether we're doing the right thing we
have to be
continuously validating we have to be
continuously learning and figuring out
new ways to do things and continuously
closing closing those learning loops so
that we change the our mental model of
of of of how things
work
and I don't think our current systems of
education and the world itself is is set
up to create the majority of people that
are like that I feel like uh the
majority of of people aren't really
interested in all of that stuff and
perhaps just want to go to work get a
paycheck and go home I think a lot of
people can be convinced to work
differently but I I if we're talking
about what's the current status um I
would probably Hazard a guess and it is
a guess um that that only about 20% of
people are really interested in that
level of uh of commitment of figuring
things out of of of trying to do things
which means
that the demand for folks that
understand agile now that's quite a wide
bucket right folks that understand agile
within organizations whether that's for
um leadership positions like scrum
Master on up through the organization or
for product focused at folks product
management through the organization or
for um
doers right the the the the I work with
software teams so generally it's the
engineering team members that I'm
talking about there but the doers up
through the organization um what
percentage of of of your leaders
um product people and doers actually
take the time to go read blog posts read
books um experiment uh discuss and
collaborate like I I participate in a
number of of of
communities
um like meetups where people gather to
discuss some of these topics and learn
more and there's not that many people
there compared to the number of people
that are doing that type of work right
um when you sell a book on a particular
topic and the the well-known people you
know they sell more copies uh H the new
new spring gold book has been doing
awesome but still the number of people
that buy it is a tiny percentage of uh
the
people that probably need to read it
right so I think
that when we we need to caveat when
we're talking about
agile agile
teams are like Special Operations
teams right they have distinct
particular focus on maximizing the value
from the work done right and
continuously iterating on that and
learning new things and practicing they
probably spend quite a high percentage
of their time learning and practicing
and trying new things and that's not
most teams that's not most organizations
that's not most people I I read a blog
post years ago um and I it struck me
this was when I was brand new um it
struck me very much that that the first
line was if you're reading this you're
already in the top 10% it was about
software engineers and learning and that
kind of thing if you're reading it
you're already in the top 10 per. what
percentage of your people actually read
and learn and trying trying better
themselves that
that is the
assumption that you're going to have a
team of people like that that comes from
from from from agile there kind of a
fundamental requirement of being agile
is having folks like that and that's
kind of why um I guess the scrum Master
exists to proxy some of that because
you're going to have lots of people on
your team who are not like that so the
person who's like that on your
engineering team the doer who's most
focused on the effectiveness of the team
is probably the perfect choice to be the
scrum master and and then move up
through the organization through
leadership roles right a great example
of that is satian Adela right um was a
software engineer now runs the whole
runs the whole show um so the thing that
went wrong is agile accelerated much
more quickly than there was supply of
these folks there was an assumption that
these folks had those skills and
capability and they're just not there
and they don't exist today um there's
not been systemic
investment in
bettering people within organizations of
hypothesis driven practices right of of
encouraging people to experiment and try
things and H place bets right if if you
can get that that that that efficiency
um we can spread that across the
organization because it works within our
context if we don't then we advertise
the the the cost of running that
experiment across the whole business and
that that philosophy is just not
fundamentally there so when we do find
people that are really good at it that's
the folks that t that that we want to
have promoted through scrum Master
through leadership in our in our
organization um but they're so few and
far between that even within that
context most people in positions as
scrum Masters um there's some data from
an organization called scrum match um
who if
effectively I'm I'm I'm going to
paraphrase this it's not quite the way
it works but they're effectively
validating um scrum
Masters so that if you're going to go
hire this person as a scrum Master you
know where what you're what you're
getting um so it's validated through a
valid an in iners is not the right word
but a face Toof face uh validation
process with two professional scrum
trainers um who understand not just the
scrum Masters uh competence within scrum
right but their competence within their
enabling teams to be effective enabling
product owners to be effective and
enabling the organization to be
effective so all the way up the tree and
they they give effectively a a level a
capability level based on based on based
on their their engagement with that
person I think it's like a two or three
I think it's a two or three hour process
right validation process of of of of
talking and discussing and describing
scenarios and and talking about the
skills and what they
found not everybody that's coming to
them is looking for a job for example I
went through their their their process
um and I'm not looking for a job right
um but that's their intent is you have
this moniker for your for your for your
CV to validate for
employers that you do have a certain
level of skill so there certainly going
to be a bias to people who are who are
looking for work um and what they found
was that
39% of the people that were
coming and saying I'm a scrum master um
hadn't hadn't even read the scrum guide
hadn't even taken the most basic
learning step
of reading the
manual manual for the thing the job that
they're taking and there you know the
scrum guide exists it's there it's been
around for h four 14 years it's been
around for 14 years
and these were not just new scrum
Masters these were people who had been
in rooll for up to 10 years so this is
somebody who's been a scrum Master for
10 years in organiz ation and hasn't
read the scrum
gu for me that's AB
incompetence that is not capable of of
fulfilling the role of of of of scrum
master in an organization I mean it may
depend how the role of scrum Masters
defined right I'm kind of separating
here the idea
of what the accountability for the scrum
Master within the context of scrum and
the job title of scrum Master which is
company specific specific and will have
other accountabilities um but a
fundamental level if you're going to be
a scrum Master you should have read a
scrum guide and even I think there was a
further
12% um that that had read the scrum
guide but had a really
rudimentary understanding of of scrum
and then another few percent that that
probably weren't capable of applying it
within the context so what it ended up
with was
61% of of people people who identify as
scrum Masters perhaps currently hold
jobs as scrum Masters um are not capable
of being scrum Masters yet they've been
holding positions and have experience as
scrum Masters um and that is systemic of
what what we're talking about here
that's systemic of the problem that the
the the the two things the the demand
has outstripped Supply therefore
organizational hiring practices have
systematically reduced the bar to meet
the Demand right the quality of the
participants that they demand has
dropped um so that they can fill the
positions um and that means that there's
a lot of people who have absolutely no
business being scrum Masters in in role
and you may go look to hire somebody and
they're like I've been a scrum Master
for 10 years at XYZ and they are still
incapable of of fulfilling that role um
I just saw a a comment recently um it
was highlighted by one of one of my my
colleagues on LinkedIn of a scrum master
who had been in role for two years
they've been a scrum Master for two
years didn't know what a release plan
was no idea what a release plan is no
idea how to create one or what one looks
like how can you possibly cach a team
within the context of that organization
and not understand the things that that
organization needs to function rightly
or wrongly you might not like release
plans right or you might have a
different idea of release plan from I
have from release plan but if you've
worked for two years in a company in a
role for maximizing the effectiveness of
teams and you don't know what the assets
are that the teams need to create in
order for the organization to consider
them
effective you
right and why I mean that's a specific
that's a very specific occurrence not
trying to throw them under the bus um
but why why do people not have this
information why do they not understand
it why why are are are businesses hiring
people that have no ability absolutely
no ability to do the job and and for me
there's a couple of things that this
comes down to it comes down to the
supply demand issue I.E there are very
few people who take the time and effort
who care enough about their
capability to go do that stuff to go
read blog posts watch videos uh try
stuff learn there's very few people in
that in that in that category I know
lots of people in that category right I
know lots of people who do that but I
think I probably wouldn't know the
people that aren't because that's the
circles that I'm in
right so all of my colleagues are kind
of like that I do come across uh people
who have absolutely no interest in in
learning anything new um none at all so
that that that's a big piece but I also
think a big piece is organization's
willingness to cut quality to fill roles
it's just not I mean I I can I can I can
kind of understand that in certain cont
text right if it's if it's software
Engineers people on teams doers right
you can you can train doers um I I would
say it's much it's much easier to teach
somebody a programming
language or teach somebody a a a test
tool or some capability that they don't
have than it is to teach them a
philosophy so that fundamental
philosophy of continuous lifelong
learning is something you need to hire
for not teach for because you're
probably going to be very difficult to
teach
that I think please correct me in the
comments right but I think that's going
to be very hard to to to teach for
so for such a
fundamental pivotal role as the coach
for the
team how are they possibly going to be
able to be capable
without deep knowledge and understanding
of the context of that team the context
of the product and the context of the
organization right those are the three
contexts that that person needs now you
you gain contexts in the organization
General organization you're your
organization by being in it for for time
right um you gain context of the product
by either working in that industry or
that context for a long time and then
that specific product for a while and
you gain context of the type of work
that the team are doing by doing that
type of work for a time so the most
logical
people to go through that promotion into
scrum Master right for the team which is
which is should be a self- selection not
self- selection I I select it but the
team selects the person they're the
candidates for moving through leadership
in the
organization they have they have empathy
they have skills in the context of the
work that we're doing they have skills
in the context of the organization and
they have time in the organization
experience in in understanding those
things that's who you want as scrum
Masters you don't really want to be
hiring them in in because they're not
going to have any of those contacts or
potentially not have any of those
contacts this is this is why um
H the the the financial industry who
have very
specific kind of
idiosyncrasies tend to require if we're
going to hire people they need to have
worked in finance before we're not going
to hire somebody who's not worked in
finance because it's too much trouble to
teach them and it's too
disruptive because
finances like this so I need we need
people who are already able to work
within that environment that that that
struggle
um so why does that just apply to
finance why doesn't that apply to to to
to other
places this fundamental lack of not just
lack of initial competence
right but our skills atrophy I I I I
once and this was in finance I one work
worked in finance many mons ago I
probably wouldn't do it again as an
employee for sure um but I worked in
finance and the person sitting next to
me um I just started a new job the
person that ins to me was a user
experience specialist um and they were
complaining that they hadn't done
anything new they've been working there
for four years and they hadn't done
anything new in four years and they felt
like they were unemployable
think how sad and dejected and unhappy
that person
is and how much effort do you think they
spend on enabling the success of the
organization none right they're not
spending any time on that they're biing
their time that organization actually
didn't last super long um after that
but that's that fundamental competence
that you should be looking for and
we we we need to have that Focus
otherwise we're going to continue to end
up in exactly the same position which is
bringing what what this is what
organizations have been doing for many
years is we're going to take the most
Junior unskilled person and make them
the scrum Master who's accountable for
the effectiveness of the team how the
most Junior unskilled person is going to
be able to do that I do not know um
because it's not deemed as a valuable
thing therefore there's no
leaders to promote through the
organization who have a fundamental um
background and understanding of what it
is that we're doing how we're building
products and that experimentation and
and and ideas up through the
organization so I think we've kind of
done it to ourselves this is this is
there are po there are pockets of
agility there are folks out there who
are really good at this stuff uh but
they're generally not listened to um
they're generally skilled enough that
they go become a consultant right
because of the supply demand issue if
the supply demand issue was different
they would maybe still the employees
because they would be being successful
and having fun within an organization
but they're not they they're they're
getting frustrated that organizations
can't change and organizations can't
change because they're fundamentally not
addressing these core competency issues
they don't have enough momentum they
don't have enough people who have those
core competencies to move forward
um and these folks get frustrated and go
s this I'm going to go start my own
business being a consultant and at least
I get paid more for doing terrible work
with with these
organizations um but there I mean
there's there's light at the end of the
tunnel if you're an
organization
who is already on their
journey to improve the agility of their
organization or you want to be higher
for competence hire for lifelong
learning hire for somebody who has the
interest enough to do more than a PSM or
CSM level one
certification to be that
thing I I I really fundamentally don't
understand why HR and hiring managers
are expecting somebody who's done a
two-day
course to understand how to I mean I
kind of do I years ago I worked in an
organization and the accountant was sent
on a MS project course and when he came
back he was the new project manager and
it was the disaster that you're
expecting in your head it was the a
absolute
unmitigated accounting focused disaster
of of of
uh yeah so
so I understand that it's happening but
if we want to be different if we want to
get the value from agility that we need
we have to change the way we approach
that we have to hire for competence
within the context of the roles and that
probably means now I don't know the the
Cs um I'm not a scrum Alliance trainer
I'm a scrum the do trainer so my
understanding my knowledge is is more in
that space um I if I'm looking to hire
scrum Masters I am not looking for PSM
one not even remotely looking for psm1
I'm looking for if I'm looking for a
scrum Master for one team in a large
organization I'm at least looking for
psm2 but realistically I want a PSM 3
psm3 has demonstrated knowledge and
capability it's essay based questions
we're no longer in the multiple choice
world so it's much harder for somebody
without the competence who isn't
interested in lifelong learning it it's
much harder much much harder for them to
gain that
certification right uh the psm3 so
that's that's probably would be my
minimum bar I would it be my minimum bar
I think it has to be my minimum bar my
minimum bar would be psm3 if I'm hiring
a scrum master and I'm bringing them
into my business minimum psm3 and I then
want to look at what's the context of my
my product does that scrum Master have a
experience within that context so if my
context is software engineering which
mine generally is I want to hire
somebody who understands software
engineering somebody who has experience
and understands the philosophies of
devops who understands the the the the
practices and techniques that make sense
to help teams be effective because a
good coach coaches and teaches the team
in practices they don't understand or
aren't very good at right and in order
to do that you have to understand them
if you want to teach those things so at
at the very least PSM 3 then look at um
engineering
competence then look at product
competence because they need to help
coach the product owner product
management in building a better product
and then business well that's kind of
business product/ business and then I
guess it's called organizational Evol
uary context right what skills and
capabilities do they have in
organizational change in building
relationships across the organization in
doing those things these the folks that
can do it all are fairly rare right
folks that can do it all are absolutely
fairly rare I I I agree there but if
I've got somebody just for a team I
probably need mostly if it's a new team
mostly engineering support with a little
bit of business and a little bit of org
if I'm hiring for somebody who's looking
across multiple teams I probably have
the engineering is maybe not as
important but the business context is
much more important and if I'm hiring
somebody who's looking across the whole
organization then the organizational
transformational Mastery is is is the
most important but I still want business
context and I still want I'm calling it
engineering context right but he cont
context the work context uh uh on that
end as well so this is fundamentally why
somebody like Sati and Adella is is so
hugely successful within the context and
has absolutely turned a multi-million
dollar business around because while he
has engineering capability he
understands engineering he understands
the proc practices he understands how
important it is to spend time on
learning and those practices and those
things he also understands business
which is how we made it up through
management the organization and he
understands organizational
transformational context right how do
you change an organization how do you
adapt it towards a new outcome that
opens up new markets and new
capabilities and that's why he's the
CEO right and he's been hugely
successful at it he's got a book hit
refresh definitely worth uh a
read this is what we're talking about
this level of competence is what's not
there and this level of competence is
what we need to fix