if you want to maximize your return on
investment for the time and effort that
that people put into into into the
products that you're
creating you need to try and enable
Foster a culture where the people that
are working within the context of your
your
products care about the products and
your customers right they care about
what it is that they're creating because
because they feel that they have own
people care about things they have
ownership of right so there are a whole
bunch of ways you can do that you're
effectively fostering a culture of
continuous Improvement kind of a little
bit of Buzzard Bingo there right but the
idea is that we when we talk about
hypothesis driven practices we we're
having an idea we're trying a little bit
of that idea we're getting feedback from
the customer and then we're adapting
that idea to be better so it's it's
double down right we're going to invest
more in this because it looks like it's
awesome we've got pivot which is we we
change what we're doing based on what we
learn or we've got kill it which is stop
investing in it and do something else
like don't keep keep doing this you see
Google Google are doing this a lot
there's there's two websites there's uh
Microsoft graveyard and Google graveyard
it's product that Microsoft and Google
have killed right over the years some of
them are very high profile some of them
are are lesser known right and it's
about the more high-profile it is
probably it's been invested more Money's
been invested in it and more people
liked it but not enough people it didn't
make enough of an impact to continue to
invest it for the cost uh uh uh that it
is
so if we
want the people that are doing the
work to care
about our product to care about our
customers and to spend money which is
their time right that's their time
they're every time they do something
they're spending your money right every
person in your organization is spending
your
money if we want them to spend that
money ah diligently I don't like that
word with
care then they need
to understand the
context within which they make that
decision about whether they do this
thing or they do not do this thing or
they do it this way or they do it that
way right so in order to do that and
this is something that I see lots of
organiz there's a a I consider it a
little bit of a dysfunctional behavior
that I see lots of organizations doing
especially Professional Services
organizations but also uh product
organizations as
well they
Shield the people doing the work from
the finances of doing the work because
it's all shifted off to a finance
department right departmental
finance and what that does is remove the
context of
money from the people doing the
work imagine you trying to run your
business and make decisions about what
you're going to invest in and what
you're not going to invest in but you
had no information about budget you had
no information about money you had no
information about spend you had no
information about
Revenue how good are you going to be at
making successful decisions to make a
successful business if you don't have
access to any of that information it's
going to suck right you you're going to
make bad decisions because you don't
have all the information that's every
member of every team in your
organization they're they're right now
they're potentially making bad decisions
about what features they build about how
they build those features because they
don't understand the ROI effectively of
what it is that they're they're they're
doing because they might might think
it's going to provide value but do they
actually know and do they know what it
costs to
make I'd
advocate for every team doing their own
p&l
right what value are you as a team
bringing the
business what do you
cost I want value to be higher than the
cost right if you're a team and you're
thinking about those things you're going
to make different decisions because you
have additional context you turn every
member of every team into an
entrepreneur
trying to figure out how do we maximize
we're doing this work within the context
of this product how do we maximize the
value that we return what should we be
working on well we should be working on
this stuff over here because that's
going to give us the biggest return
right biggest short-term return biggest
long-term return right because when
you're thing you as a business owner you
as a CTO or CEO are thinking about how
you invest in your company you're
thinking about shortterm wins to
generate Revenue quickly you're thinking
about the longterm objective of the
business and how you're going to make
money in the long term and
sustainable income right and and that's
all part of the story it needs to be for
every member of every team you can't if
you hide that information from them if
you obuse it and create a a a a filter
so they don't see any of that stuff
they're going to make bad decisions so
don't Shield them from that build that
into the story of how a team
operates do p&l with every team have
that filter up through the organization
and I guarantee you'll see higher return
on investments and higher value being
delivered