one of the seven signs of the agile
apocalypse is the
Antichrist uh and in our context that
Antichrist is um fake agilists I think
that's probably the best way to describe
them people who perhaps have a
certification in agile they passed an
assessment perhaps they didn't even take
a class they just passed an assessment
and they believe that they're qualified
to help engage and enable software teams
when they have no clue whatsoever how
software is made those are the
Antichrist thanks for watching the video
If you enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked
agility