I often get asked about best practices
that help teams do continuous delivery
how do how one of the best practices and
I'm I'm going to start right up front by
saying there's no such thing as best
practices when you work in the complex
environment there's no such thing as
best practices best practices are for
simple work in simple environments where
you can have a procedure and you follow
it continuously it becomes the best
practice the best way to do it and you
get the same results every time that's
not the world that we live in so the the
phrase I quite often use which is I
guess a little bit passive
aggressive there's there's no best
practices there are only adequate
practices for the situation at hand and
the situation might change right that's
that's fundamentally what we're talking
about but there are a bunch of
practices that we see many organizations
leveraging and getting success
from and we should try them and see if
they work for us that maybe that may be
makes more sense than than than best
practices so the question usually is and
if I take out the word best there what
practices enable cross functional
collaboration to support continuous
delivery without compromising quality
one one of those practices is some way
to control
what code ends up in production or not
that's a that's a very powerful practice
or what code is enabled for people
that's probably a better way to just say
it most most organizations most
products are have moved or are moving
towards or are thinking of moving
towards more of an audience-based
deployment pattern or delivery pattern
rather than an environment-based
delivery pattern right and so there is
still environments within the context of
this depending on how it's set up but
one of the the I think one of the core
practices that supports this idea of
continuous delivery that supports this
idea of continuous quality in in in
production is is definitely moving
towards audience-based delivery strategy
so in the old the old in the ye olden
days the delivery strategy was Dev test
staging production right Dev test
staging production kind of thing and
everything was done in Dev the
developers built all the stuff and then
it got pushed
to test testers tested all the stuff and
then it get pushed to staging and
something else usually load testing
there and then it got pushed to
production maybe if you're deploying to
customers they have in the way right
there also a uat enironment um these are
all costs these are all at costs and
they're extreme costs and they're not
worth it costs they they they not only
have a cost to actually do at the time
they have massive massive cost
implications on our ability to build the
right thing they have massive cost
implications on um the cost of fixing
stuff later and they have massive cost
implications because we're we're
effectively testing quality in rather
than building it in right testing
quality in is the most expensive way to
gain gain quality building quality in is
is how how we should be doing that so
this this practice of audience-based
right audience-based delivery means we
switch to a model and I'm I'm going to
use the words I'm going to use make it
sound like we're testing in production
and in
fact that's one of the the terminologies
that that we do use in that context is
testing and production right and the
reality of the world in which we live in
Building these complex interconnected
systems that we all build and work on is
that there is no place like
production there's there's no way to
simulate production there's no way to
truly validate that What You've Done
Works in production until you get to
production so wouldn't it be better is
if we can get a small change quickly
into production for a small set of
users and then be able to
increase or decrease that user set on
demand so that we can validate that the
product works in real world and real
real scenarios and that's effectively
what what what we talk about with this
set of practices this idea of of
Shifting left and
continuous continuous delivery and
there's a lot of practices that help
with that so so audience-based
deployment model is probably um the the
the the main thing and if you're
thinking oh our product is too big and
too complicated to be able to do that
the windows team move to that Windows is
deployed on an audience-based
model rather than more traditional
environment based model there's because
there's is a physical product that's
physically deployed to people there's
still a little bit of the old school
environment in there for sure so it's
not a complete
thing Cloud products you can go complete
but they go their their time from uh
cutting code to it being in production
with real users is only I I I think for
themselves it's only a few hours like
internal to the windows team but nightly
as I understand at least nightly they're
deploying new versions of Windows out to
all of the participants within Microsoft
so if you're inside of Microsoft and you
take a a BG it that's their internal it
Department BG build of Windows like
you're not self-managing BG build then
um you you're you're getting nightly
builds of Windows or or I think many
people are that means that what the
Developers wrote yesterday you're
testing today and it's in production
because you're you know you're a manager
in Microsoft um you're doing your day
job which is managing people you might
be a mar managing marketing people right
inside of Microsoft uh or managing
Consultants or managing whatever and
your machine has the latest version of
Windows you're you're using it in
production so that's getting into
production as quickly as possible and
then what they're doing the engineering
team is they're monitoring the Telemetry
this is the audience-based deployment
model they're monitoring the Telemetry
and deciding what whether they want to
open that particular build out to more
people um and when they open it out to
more people the next ring they I guess
Microsoft called them Rings ring based
deployment model right but it's really
audience-based each ring has an audience
of people and they're they're all
production and they're just opening it
out to more and more people that's
that's a pretty simple version because
it is a physical product that's deployed
on your machine right physical which
your operating system so so it's it's
got to run on bare metal and in Cloud
but it runs on metal right but if if you
look at something like Microsoft teams
Office 365 right they they have the
ability to switch on and off features
for specific users so regardless of what
build is shipped in Microsoft teams for
example and I have I'm in the tap
program for teams basically their
version of the Insiders and I get
features before the general public the
the the everybody gets features and that
can be specific to me as an individual
user within my company or all users
within my company and that enables that
choice right so you even as a customer
in the tap program I can choose that I
get the oh my goodness me The Cutting
Edge latest and greatest and somebody
else in my business gets
the reasonably reasonably stable they're
kicking the tires ready for for moving
to wider audience more general public
audience and then general public have a
way to opt into some extra features and
things so it it we're all able to
communicate with each other right we can
all join the same call and some people
are using more different features from
other people within the context of that
call some of them have new capabilities
whole new code bases that are that are
running their part of that that story
and it's really interesting because I I
I do I do do calls with Folks at
Microsoft and I've had Folks at
Microsoft who are on much earlier builds
than me because they're choosing to help
out that team or they work on that team
and yeah occasionally their call drops
and they have to log back in like oh
sorry early build I got a bug and
that's there's a risk benefit analysis
there if you're working in a company and
you
want to take the earlier features so
that you can pre validate them for your
company understand what they are to help
with training and whatnot of people in
your company understand what's coming
down the pipeline then you can choose to
do that but you're choosing to take a
little bit of risk right because it's
going to be a little bit less stable
it's going to be a little bit L this is
this idea of testing in production I'm
not expecting a complete crash of
everything and nothing works right but
the occasional glitch the occasional
weirdness I'm good with that I teach
training classes on Microsoft teams I
teach all my classes on Microsoft teams
using Microsoft teams breakout rooms
using all those things I'm in the tap
program I have an earlier capability
occasionally things go a little bit
weird for me that's just a teaching
moment in the class cuz we're talking
about how we deliver software and how we
deliver products and part of that is
accepting that there are going to be um
some mistakes they're going to be if
you're doing continuous delivery to
production there are going to be things
that get past your your automated Gates
Right and and end up in production it's
what you do with that information that's
one of the best complimentary practices
I'm I'm going to use the word best there
is is that philosophy and how you do in
fact it's not even a practice it's a
philosophy you need to have a philosophy
of fix it find it and fix it so if
something does make it past into
production and you're doing continuous
delivery you need to figure
out how why how did this get past my
automated
checks and how can I change my automated
checks to be able to catch those things
that's that's that's that's it
if you find oh it's not possible to
change our automated checks because of
the way we've architected the system and
this you might be ask I would expect a
team to be asking themselves the
question should we be changing our
architecture so that these types of
problems can't make it into production
and how long is that going to take a
great example the aure devops team had a
a bunch of
incidents where one service that really
shouldn't be mandatory took out the
entire platform right so they're running
a an online platform and for example the
profile service this is the the this was
their first example the profile service
stops working does it matter that you're
showing like the ID of the user or the
good of the user versus
The Friendly name of the user because
the pro you get that friendly name I've
got the gooded I get the friendly name
name from the profile service and now I
can display the friendly name but what
if that profile service is down would
you rather your entire system was down
or it showed a good in place of a
username in some cases right some small
number of cases I'd rather it showed the
good and the system still worked because
then my users can still do their job my
users can still use the system they just
see a a small controlled glitch right
and then when that profile service comes
back up or we fix it that turns back on
again and there's a pattern a coding
pattern called the circuit breaker
pattern and it's exactly what you think
it is when one of the services stops
working it breaks the circuit and then
every so often it tries the circuit to
see if it's back up and if it's not up
it just breaks the circuit again and
then Waits a little bit longer and then
tries the circuit if it still doesn't
work breaks the circuit and waits a
little bit longer so this service on
this site is not down because it can't
connect to this service and the Azure
devops team had this problem that the
profile service took out the entire
system so millions of developers all
over the world were unable to look at
their code do their work items do all
these things because the friendly name
couldn't be displayed i' mean a bit
factious with that but the profile
service was
down that's insane so one of one of the
practices that you need to think about
is one of the let's call it philosophy
the philosophy you have to think think
about is no we need to change it we need
we need to we need to look at the impact
to our users and make decisions based on
our ability to maintain our service
maintain high levels of quality maintain
the ability for people to continue to
work within the context of our product
even when the unavoidable happens which
is systems are going to break systems
are going to be down how do you uh cope
with that that's probably if I was to
say there's a best practice it's not a
best practice it's maybe a best
philosophy and that's to to continuously
seek to better your product better its
ability to support its users and do that
continuously and relentlessly