so one of the civil and deadly sins of
agile is greed and this usually
manifests in um in
organizations by a an overwhelming focus
on resource
utilization let's let's get rid of the
fact that we're calling everybody
resources as if they're cogs in a
machine rather than actual people right
but but that focus on resource
utilization was a fantastic idea when we
were running
machines and machines could churn out
things on a regular Cadence and we were
able to the more your machine is running
the more value you're getting in return
for the the cost of the machine and the
cost to run it right um that's how you
would what where that re resource
utilization idea comes from but when you
start looking at people and how people
do work people need a a thinking time
people need uh um do things different
ways right if if we can automate stuff
that we do the same all the time but if
we're going to do something different
all the time which in my world
background is a software engineer
everything we coded was something new
otherwise we would have used an existing
framework
right um so anytime you're writing code
you're doing something new anytime
you're building a product that doesn't
exist yet you're doing something new
that's never been done before right so
when you're doing those even if it's
been done before by somebody else it's
not been done before by you um and when
you're doing that uh you need to um give
people the space to be able to do things
well to be able to think about things to
be able to learn things to be able to
try things and that means that people
aren't always 100% focused on the work
that they're doing they they're they're
doing other things while thinking about
that work uh some examples maybe um have
you ever uh been working on something
and got
stuck and the only way for you to get un
no matter how much time you spent on
this thing you were stuck right you're
100% utilized because you're working on
this thing
but you're not making any progress
you're not delivering any value but if
you just go uh go out for a walk right
or you sit with your wife and you
explain the problem to your I do this
all the time I explain some problem to
my wife and she doesn't necessarily
understand the problem that I've got
right I'm talking about code and
architectures and things and halfway
through explaining it I figured out what
my problem was right cuz I knew I just
didn't have a
moment to look to the side I don't know
if that makes sense like like an out of
body out of idea experience out of body
experience and look at that thing from
the
outside um so that that resource
utilization is a fallacy uh when you're
talking about people um there's no such
thing as resource utilization you want
to be looking at flow efficiency and
value delivery how much value Are you
delivering to your customer and I
actually I don't care if my team members
are sitting around on their butts for
90% of the time as long as we're
delivering the value to the customer
right the value to the customer is the
important thing is the customer happy
are we getting an adequate return on
investment for our product those are the
ideas uh that make sense um I worked
with somebody years ago who ran a little
experiment with some teams um that he
worked with in a in a company in the US
and he uh decided to to or got convinced
leadership that per Sprint he would
remove an
hour from each
Sprint so you can imagine you've got a
40h hour
week per week per Sprint you've got a
40h hour week the next Sprint he's going
to do a 39h hour week with the team and
the Sprint after that he's going to do a
38h hour week with the team and the
Sprint after that is going to do a
37-hour week with the team and I've got
a question for you at what point do you
believe that value delivery
suffered if the focus is on value
delivery delivering features now that
doesn't mean that for the other two
hours people aren't the the the the
hours that you remove people aren't
actually working right if you think
about it scrum team somebody who's
focused on solving problems um works
100% of the time right when I'm when I'm
having a shower in the morning or when
I'm I actually do a lot of my best ideas
at the gym I go to the gym I'm working
out the gym and I go oh that's a great
idea and I go on my phone and I message
it to myself right and then the next
idea Pops in how to solve problems and
figure these out is not something that
you get from 100% utilization it's you
need thinking time uh so can you guess
where he got to he got to 16 hours per
week before um uh uh value delivery
started to suffer because all the rest
of the time is thinking time that the
team needed thinking and then noodling
time um
so very much Stop Being
Greedy stop trying to get people to
maximize their
utilization and instead focus on
maximizing the flow of Val all you
delivery to your customers thanks for
watching the video If you enjoyed it
please like follow And subscribe I
always reply to comments and if you want
to have a chat about this or anything
else agile scrum or devops then please
book a coffee with me through naked
agility