the most common thing I hear in a pspo
course
um is from
um from the product owners saying
um but but we don't have that kind of
control we we aren't able to change the
order of the product backlog we aren't
able to influence the product goal we
aren't able to uh discuss with the
business about the Strategic direction
of the product right that they just
aren't playing at that level
um and for me that's that's always an
invitation right if you're you're not
playing at that level but you realize
that you're supposed to be playing at
that level what can you do within your
organization to start playing at that
level what are the meetings you can
invite yourself to the conversations you
can have with other people to
demonstrate your knowledge and
capability because in order to get
accountability you have to demonstrate
competence