are legacy contracts keeping you stuck
with the wrong vendors you're not alone
Vendor lockin is a real issue for
organizations trying to modernize their
systems of work It happens when outdated
contracts proprietary platforms or
deeply embedded dependencies make it
nearly impossible to shift Instead of
focusing on what's best for your
business you're trapped maintaining
somebody else's business model So how to
break free first let's talk about why it
matters Sticking with the wrong vendors
doesn't just slow you down it limits
your ability to adapt You're forced to
work within their constraints whether
that's rigid licensing slow innovation
cycles or overpriced services that no
longer align with your needs At Naked
Agility we don't sell tools We help
organizations make sense of their
systems of work the way teams
collaborate plan and deliver value
Because the real issue isn't just the
software you're using it's how decisions
are being
made Breaking vendor lockin isn't about
swapping one system for another It's
about making better choices Choices that
give you flexibility control and the
ability to adapt as your business
evolves We work with teams to understand
their real constraints whether that's
technical contractual or organizational
Then we guide them through pragmatic
step-by-step transitions towards more
open adaptable solutions This isn't
about throwing everything out and
starting over It's about untangling
dependencies enabling better decision-m
and creating options instead of dead
ends If you're feeling stuck the first
step isn't buying another tool It's
understanding the choices you actually
have Let's start a conversation