the applying professional cang course
from Pro caman is really that
foundational class on understanding how
to apply a cand strategy to your
existing system it doesn't really matter
what your existing system is you could
be doing scrum you could be doing uh
waterfall you could be doing anything
whatever process you've got right now is
the process that you apply uh uh the
campan strategy to and this uh course's
purpose is to help you understand what
is needed in order to have a camand
strategy um and how what are some of the
starting points and tools and techniques
you can use to get started with a cand
strategy and what's the minimum you need
uh uh to be to be to be doing caman
right um so what are the minimum metrics
we need to be collecting visualizations
we have to have and decisions that we
have to make in order for our H uh that
that continuous Improvement to start
happening um and how do we start
interpreting the graphs start
understanding the data and analyzing it
in order to get better at whatever it is
that we're doing um so it really helps
improve the flow of value through the
system um it helps you get an idea of
what your current flow is um and that
helps you figure out how to ask more
interesting questions of your team if
you want to have a discussion about your
unique needs or situation then please
book a call or visit us at naked agility
docomo have our immersive and
traditional public classes on our
website and we'd love to hear from you