one of the seven signs of the agile
apocalypse is Judgment judgment
manifests in many forms usually it
manifests as rules that you need to
follow and you are judged for not
following them you're judged for not
having the velocity that somebody else
wants you're judged uh for having too
many bugs you're judged for writing too
many lines of code than they would like
or not enough lines of code these are
all judgments and those judgments have
an impact on the team you need to set
goals and create metrics that help you
monitor progress towards those goals and
when those metrics create negative
behaviors in people you need to adapt
the metrics to make sure you're making
progress towards those goals thanks for
watching the video If you enjoyed it
please like follow And subscribe I
always like to comments and if you want
to have a chat about this or anything
else agile scrum or devops then please
book a coffee with me through naked
agility