foreign
is how do you select the most valuable
items for the Sprint backlog if you take
a look at this the scrum guide it will
it will just say you magically select
the ones you need right you you kind of
craft craft
uh uh uh a Sprint goal and then magic
fairy dust is sprinkled on it and and
you get a list of things but the reality
is a lot more complicated than that the
reality is that
um you have to take information from
information from the business the
business context the product owner's
context and their understanding of of
the market and the business context the
engineering context what's happening in
the product what what's what's going on
there and you bring all of that together
and then you figure out what your Sprint
goal is going to be and that Sprint goal
then at least shapes the initial set of
work you're going to bring into the
bring into that that Sprint
so
um
the most important things could be the
things at the top of your product
backlog
could be
um but I would say that the order of the
product backlog informs but does not
control the work that the Developers
accept pool into the Sprint because
there might be other considerations that
take priority right this is the most
important thing we need to work on yeah
but in order to do that we've got this
big chunk of architectural stuff we have
to do first therefore we're going to
focus on the next most important piece
of value and this architectural stuff so
that next Sprint we can hopefully take
on this most important thing right that
might be more considerations for that so
it has to be carefully thought out and
buy the whole scrum team so the product
owner needs to work closely with the
developers the developers work closely
with the product owner to figure out
what are we going to take into the front
the Sprint and it's not always the most
important thing in the product backlog
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility