the purpose of naked
agility is to help organizations create
great teams I it's something that
I've it's plainly obvious when you say
it but if you have unhappy sad people
you're not going to get good work out of
them you're not going to build great
products and I believe that
every person
deserves to be using great products we
as customers we as users of products
don't deserve bad shitty products we
don't deserve that we deserve great
products that provide us with a great
experience and do great things for us to
help us do the things that we need to do
and unhappy sad teams don't create great
products they create bad terrible
products
in order to have happy
engaged people we need to create those
ideas of great teams within our
organization how do we engage with
people how do we enable them to be the
productive story that we're trying to
create and in the creative world in the
software world that that means autonomy
Mastery and purpose right autonomy is we
need to be the ones making the decisions
we need to be the ones that are on board
that are engaged in the story The people
doing the work need to be engaged in the
story we certainly need to be also be
masters of the work that we're doing we
need Mastery we need expertise we need
skills we need knowledge we need to be
able to be uh uh the best that we can be
at at at what it is that we're doing and
lots of organizations suppress that we
need purpose we need to understand
understand what direction we're going
and why we're going there and how the
work that we're doing contributes to
that story otherwise it doesn't matter
what we're working on like why would I
care about the product if I don't know
what it's for or who it's helping and if
I don't
care what care am I taking in the
product in the work that I'm doing I'm
taking less care because I don't care
and enabling you can't just tell people
to care right you have to enable you
have to create an environment within
which the people that are participating
that are working on the software
products that you want to create and use
and
develop care about what they're doing
they have that autonomy they have
Mastery and they have purpose and that's
how we create great teams that create
great products