oh that's a good question so the
question is why do I prefer agile
Consulting
over agile coaching
and for me it
I believe
the the leadership within your
organization
is a business critical function
right this this is not something that
you should be Outsourcing to somebody
else
and I feel like too many organizations
bring in coaches who are their
semi-filled time probably over a number
of years and those coaches are bringing
leadership to the organization they're
filling the gap between traditional
organizational leadership and agile
leadership and they become a crutch for
the people in the organization and the
people in the organization don't
actually learn to do things differently
um it's like for if you were to equate
it to software engineering it's like the
the mythical rewrite of a product right
you go rewrite the product but you don't
really realize that the people that
built
the crappy called coded product you have
right now with the same people that
you've got doing the rewrite and why
would you think it would be any
different right and it's this is exactly
the same thing you have the same people
in your organization so when those
coaches rotate off either because
budgets get constrained right because
that goes in fluctuations over the over
the the years we're in a budget
constrained environment right now
um and we're seeing big swathes of
organizations
divesting themselves of agile coaches
and scrum Masters mostly in the
Contracting space because
um they're they're not seeing the value
right they're not seeing the value
anymore and those people are leaving and
then the organization's falling back
into its old traditional practices
because there was no actual learning
taking place inside the organization
so the way I look at it is an agile
consultant's job
is to go in in a very short space of
time
help people in the organization
understand what they need to do and how
they need to change and work on their
mindsets and then they're the ones doing
the work they're the ones Taking It
Forward they're the ones cleaning up
their own mess and dealing with uh the
issues that are a result of their
decisions they're the ones learning
right
um so so then you've got that intrinsic
to the way your organization functions
now so when the agile consultant leaves
they're no longer that crutch right so a
normal engagement model for me is to to
only work full time with a team for for
a couple of weeks maybe a month tops I
think the longest engagement I did was
was three and a half weeks
um but then come back periodically
um and help with advice for for the
scrum Masters advice for leaders in the
organization have those constant touch
points where they're they're bringing me
some of their problems and I'm helping
them figure out other things to try
right that might might help resolve them
so that I'm not in full time I'm not
helping them full-time