we've been doing
devops for quite some time um
the it's really difficult to
provide an overview of our devop
services
because our devop services tend to be
bespoke for every single customer that
uses them there's there's not there's
some patterns but there's not that many
formulas that work everywhere every
company is different every group of
people is different every outcome that
they're trying to achieve with uh uh the
the philosophy that is devops right
every outcome that they're trying to
achieve is different so but there are
some patterns that do kind of make
sense um one of those is um one of the
patterns we use quite often is a state
of devops report um so the idea is the
you want to understand as an
organization like where based on Modern
engineering and devops
practices where are we where are we
where do we sit because it's difficult
to understand where you want to go
unless you know where you are right now
that's the first thing you do when you
have a map and you're trying to figure
out how to get somewhere you have to
find out where you are so you can then
figure out what the direction to go um
so that kind of state of devops state of
agile state of devops where are we right
now um in in our our understanding of or
our application of what of devops
practices so um we might talk about
things like H how how are products being
released um we might talk about things
um like wow wow how are how are products
been released um what sort of um tools
are being used within that context of of
releasing products um I worked with an
organization that had 13 different
Source control systems in use for one
product right so there's there's a lot
of waste there that can be identified um
what what are we actually doing how do
we how do we take the ideas that we've
created in our product and and how how
do they actually get into production and
not just what leadership thinks is
happening but what's actually happening
on the ground um so we tend to interview
a bunch of people in the organization
usually try and do solo interviews
because people are more willing to speak
when there's not somebody else and this
kind of anonymous uh uh
information and we find out all sorts of
things like I worked with an
organization that was their team
understood their team of 30 engineers
understood branching but they didn't
understand automatic merging so they
were manually copying code with a a text
diffing to between branches in order to
merge code which is just mental um I
worked with an organization that had
built a custom tool because the business
had asked for a capability they built a
custom tool that allowed product
managers to pick
features and create a build of the
product that only had those features
merged together into the product um
which might sound like a good idea if
you're on the business side but from an
engineering standpoint and creating a a
cohesive valid high quality usable high
value product that's that's totally
insane um there's all sorts of
things
that are non dysfunctional behaviors I
tend to call them opportunities for
improvement right because it's a little
bit more positive but the reality is
they're dysfunctional behaviors that are
really common in the industry and have
been for many years because people are
pushed towards solving a problem and
they don't necessarily know that there
are known logical ways to solve that
problem already and even if they do know
about those non-logical ways to solve
that problem somebody in the business
has an objection to to it uh a great one
is automatic deployments right uh and
the the the the objection might be that
oh are we're under socks audit you know
we we're we're sarban Oxley compliant
therefore um we we need a separation of
developers from uh the people who do
develop the code the people who do
releasing the code
and that means that we can't have
developers with access to
production that's actually not true with
SARS B Oxley not true at all but because
somebody believes it is you then end up
with these ideas where development and
operations is a separate
thing one of the
biggest values that we bring biggest
benefit that we bring to
organizations when we're talking about
the devops philosophy bringing the
practices that help fulfill that Pro
that philosophy into
organizations is that ability for um
higher quality more frequent
delivery less friction in your ability
to get software out the door and that
idea
that it's really it's some of it's about
just about ownership that idea of
ownership if if if it's you you have an
idea you're going to build that idea
you're going to deploy that idea you're
going to monitor that idea and you're
responsible for the upkeep of that idea
the support and and and continued uh um
value ad of that idea and that should
all be within the control of a of the
group the team right um so
so IDE all the way through to deployment
and closing those feedback loops um
should be part of that story and that's
very difficult to do within a lot of
organizations so what are the steps that
you can do to get towards that what are
the tools that you can use to ensure
that you meet the compliance that you
need to meet right in order to continue
to meet your compliance but do these new
uh things and how do you maintain
quality right how do you maintain the
level of quality um if for example
you're not doing uat because uat is a
cost center not a Value Center for for
software engineering if if your uat is a
a Value Center because it finds stuff
and protects your business then we've
not got high enough quality delivery of
our product um but if we we create that
high enough quality and uat becomes a
cost center we want to get rid of those
cost centers what how do we
ensure um that we don't end up up with
um in the same situation as crowd strike
right um there's a great example of an
organization recently in the news that
caused massive disruption I think
they're going to be sued by Delta for
for 500 million dollars that Delta has
lost over the week that they had a
problem which which part of that is
their own problem with devops um but
what what could crowd strike have done
differently well they didn't one of the
things they didn't do was control the
blast radius right you don't just deploy
to production you don't just deploy to
100 I I'm not sure exactly how many
machines run at crowd strike but you
don't deploy to all of them at the same
time that's
Insanity uh even Windows who have very
high quality in the in the product that
they ship um they deploy to a small
number of people first right they
control the last radius what are are
what are our lowest impact customers or
customers that would be impacted the
least by an outage and deploy to them
first perhaps deploy to our own systems
first and run it for a few days see if
there's are any problems monitoring
right monitoring that that feature and
that capability that's being deployed
not deploying on a Friday the best time
to deploy is Monday morning when
everybody comes in because you get a
whole week to fix any problems deploying
on Friday is probably not the best idea
um there's all kinds of things that make
logical sense and are within the context
of this devop story that we can help um
educate uh coach and engage with your
team your engineers as well as with your
business and your leadership to
understand what these things are what
value you get from them and how you
maintain your ability to control risk
within this new world of continuous
delivery to production