the course will definitely change your
product development
game first point uh you will be able to
increase user
value why because you are going to um
deliberately design experiments to
better understand user needs and find
effective ways how to address them so we
believe this is the best way how to how
to increase user
value second
point because you will be able to to
increase user value and have this
process more conscious with a lot of
learning you are definitely on your path
to decrease
waste as a result H you will also
improve return on
investment when it comes to what the
team is working on so you will invest
based on evidence you can adjust your
budgeting based on experiments based on
the results based on the data that you
get and in the end of the day thanks to
that you can Embrace um agility
principle of simplicity so in that Pro
process you will be also
maximizing the amount of work that is
creating little or no
value another important point we as
human beings we really really often uh
jump into solution space immediately or
just by briefly presenting the problem
and in this class us we we want to
unlock creativity by thinking in
problems and showing a different
perspective on that so hold your horses
and let's try different experiments to
make sure that we truly understand what
the problem is you might be amazed how
many different solutions Maybe finally
created when we first pay a lot of
attention to understanding the
problem another
Point some of the customers some of the
teams companies complain when it comes
to collaboration with
stakeholders with this class you
actually might be equipped with some
tools and ideas how to improve
collaboration uh between the teams
between the
stakeholders and this
collaboration may change completely
because if you invite others and you you
show them this different
perspective your product development may
start with using data not
opinions and in that case it might be
also easier for you to uh to get a green
light from important stakeholders but
also to show them that certain paths
certain ideas are not worth
investing so
finally I believe it's also a class that
is improving our toolbox our product
development toolbox because after the
class you will have a bunch of valuable
practices techniques ideas when it comes
to Discovery when it comes to
validation and you can start using them
immediately after after you leave leave
the class so it might be a great
beginning of changes that you will start
very soon just after you say goodbye in
our class