one of the ghosts of agile past is
Dogma we've all run into those
dogmatic uh uh folks that that try and
pursue an idea irrelevant of the the
data and the experience of the people
around them um we need we need to kick
those folks to the carb um I usually I I
I I can be not dogmatic is the wrong
word um almost 100% of the time when I'm
working with teams I'm pragmatic but I
can also be pedantic if I'm in a
training situation whatever it is I'm
training if I'm teaching you that thing
I'm going to be uh H
um specific about what things are called
and what they mean based on what they're
called whether that's scrum or
continuous delivery or C or or whatever
it is there are specific meanings for
the nouns that have been defined within
the context of the thing that we're
learning and we need to understand what
they are what the impact is and how they
engage with each other in the real world
with
teams we need to be pragmatic we need to
understand that people call things
different things than we're expecting
they have different uh uh um Knowledge
and Skills they've come from different
places where they use things in
different ways and we need to work
within the bounds of what it is we've
got so one of those ghosts of agile past
is Dogma oh there's been some dogmatic
things I've seen uh the worst one was
told to me uh by a good friend and my
boss Steven Borg about a scrum master
who had just been fired from their job
in Washington State uh because they had
been adamant that if the team weren't
standing up during the daily standup
then they weren't doing scrum and you
have to be standing up in order to do
scrum uh but that team had specifically
decided uh that they wanted to sit down
because they had a disabled team member
in a wheelchair and they didn't want to
be towering over that
person that is the right thing that is
the very definition of a scrum team of
being respectful to each other of
openness respect and courage to do the
things that they think are valuable and
one of those was let's all sit down so
that we can be at the same level and
work together and this
dogmatic uh scrum Master uh got
themselves fired for cause and I think
anyone who is
dogmatic and dogmatic is where
you're see Dogma has this relationship
to to to to religion it it's really
about believing something in spite of
the evidence to the contrary that's what
I think about Dogma right so that team
was told that if they're not standing up
they're not agile when in fact they were
demonstrating agility and sitting down
and the other person was just following
and it's not even the letter of the law
cuz there's no stand up and scrum right
but the letter of their understanding of
the law in order to just enforce that
rather than working with people within
the context and learning more and that's
where uh Dogma differs uh from just
being pedantic right uh pedant pedan
pedant I can't even say that word but
being pedantic is uh uh sometimes
valuable within the context of training
uh but being pragmatic is the way most
scrum Masters and agile coaches uh
should be don't be dogmatic be pragmatic
and try and get rid of one of those
ghosts of agile
past if you are being haunted by this
ghost of agile past we can help you
exercise it or help you find a coach
consultant or trainer who can don't let
this Phantom undermine the effective
of your value delivery and the longer it
lingers the more it will damage your
team's progress so email me
martink agility
docomomo about your unique needs or
situation then please book a call or
visit us at naked agility tocom uh we
also have our immersive and traditional
public classes on our website and we'd
love to hear from you