okay so um if i uh scroll down my page
you can see that this uh list here is
rendered vertically rather than
horizontally and that's supposed to have
bootstrap
uh loaded and if i view the page source
f
you'll see that the bootstrap code
is not
in here
however if i go to
my dashboard
and i go to
where the
elementor
custom code
uh you'll see boot trap bootstrap head
um so if i edit that
these are all the same body they all
exist on all the pages you'll see um
here's the code that i expect to see
which i do not see
and then on the right hand side here you
can see its entire site
okay so this should
be
in here however it's
not in here
and none of the predefined code elements
are appearing there and if i click on
edit conditions
and you see i just go save and close
um i get an error message and there is
no
uh
more details than that
uh if i go check my error messages which
i might need to open in your browser to
do that
error logs
current error logs
here is the current
uh error log and you can see that all
i've got is some elementor pro upgrade i
tried to downgrade elementor pro don't
get me started it didn't work totally
garbled the whole site so i rolled back
to previous version
um
but anyway uh uh the site is there and
none of these
error messages are actually listed for
for that so that's the error messages
there
uh
so on the main website
um you can see that the
it has the impact some things are built
using um
bootstrap in the background so this
isn't loading
and
if i go to one of my courses
this is supposed to be in two columns
not loading
um and this is supposed to have a box
around it with a different color not
loading so i don't use it for a lot of
stuff but the stuff i do use it for
is important um but
that as well both um that code for
bootstrap
and if i go back to elementor and custom
code
uh the linkedin stuff not loading uh
the end the start none of this none of
this stuff is uh
being rendered in the front end
they all have high priority um i've
tried clearing all the caches doing all
of those things completely resetting
everything uh doesn't make a difference
and if i
install a previous version of elementor
it works uh with the
one version back it works
this version does not work
um
let's check because you'll probably ask
about themes
and i am using i think i'm using your
hello elementor
theme it says the new version even if i
update to the new version um it does not
make any difference it doesn't make any
difference to the to the to the output
of those rendered
software bits code custom code