one of the seven signs of the agile
apocalypse is war this manifests as team
conflict it's fine to have disagreements
on your team that's where the awesome
ideas are generated but if it escalates
to a contest right the aim becomes to
win the argument that's the line at
which uh the scrum Master probably needs
to step in and help um if it gets to
Crusade or World War uh with the teams
then you're just hosed um you need to
deescalate that so one of the seven
signs of the agil Apocalypse War
manifesting as team
disagreement thanks for watching the
video If you enjoyed it please like
follow And subscribe I always reply to
comments and if you want to have a chat
about this or anything else agile scrum
or devops then please book a coffee with
me through naked
agility