so the question is what can a leader
pragmatically do with a team that is
identified as the question is
incompetent right but identified as
deficient in some way um before you
resort to to any kind of firing there's
plenty of things to do um so you may you
may want to bring in you may want to
bring in training um training is a good
way to Broad
paced uh some knowledge across across a
group of people um they might not
remember everything that they learned
but I I do find um although we might
remember 20 25% of what we uh learned in
a in a class um we learn that 25% is
spread across all of the capabilities
that you maybe learned maybe there's 30
topics or let's say there's 25 topics
and you remember 1% of each of those
those topics um that that 1% of of the
total course in each of those topics
that you remember enables you to know
where to go look where to go find that
additional information um so as long as
um the people that you've got have some
kind of
um how would you describe it they
they're willing to to do things
themselves Discover right um then then
you can just broad paste some training
perhaps the um applying professional
scrum for software developers right uh
get some broad paste of these modern
engineering practices across the team at
least they're understanding them and
thinking about them and they can go do
additional research on those on those
topics and it shows commitment from the
organization on on on on updating uh but
if they're um already in
a I guess I would say dejected State um
I worked at a organization in the UK
another bank um and they had I I worked
beside somebody who believed themselves
to be unemployable because they hadn't
done anything new in four years um that
kind of depressive dejected their
already unhappy but don't know what to
do about it State you might find that
over time they learn not to learn right
they stop learning they stop figuring
stuff out cuz they're like why bother if
I'm not going to be allowed to do
anything um so you need to you need to
build that back in slowly you need to
start encouraging them to learn new
things and it might not be that you
encourage them to learn you might say
you need to learn this new thing so we
can do this new capability I have them
learn the thing and then do the new
capability have them learn the thing do
the new capability suggest they learn
the thing drop in the new capability
right so then they're expected
to it has them have that feeling of if I
learn it I get value from it rather than
if I learn it I'll not get value from it
because nobody's going to let me use it
so you have to start building back in
that capability into the team into into
the whole organization right because
people don't get that way uh um out of
the box most people that I um have ever
worked with most teams most people that
I've ever worked with are interested in
learning more about their uh their field
unless the organization has beaten it
into them that they that they're not
going to be able to use anything they
knew they learned um I spent my early
career as a net developer uh hopping
between companies uh because I would I
would go to a company because they were
using net to um and then i' would be
working there for for a couple of years
um about halfway or three quarters you
know a year to 18 months in net 3 would
become available um and I'd be starting
to learn that technology and then asking
them so when are you going to use this
new technology and they' be like maybe
in 3 or 4 years and I'd be like okay I'm
job hunting then for somewhere that's
pulling in net 3 um and then I'm going
to go work with that not net 3 this.
net4 comes out I'm going to be learning
that new technology and then if my
organization isn't willing to change
then I'm going to change right change
your org or change your org and I think
um that continuous move into technology
maintained my ability to be employable
my ability to learn and grow my
knowledge and career and I personally
wasn't afraid to switch between
companies but lots of people are right
so it can be beaten out of them very
easily that was that was um um through a
number of organizations Investment
Banking as well as other other stuff but
um you you you you need to create an
environment within which people are
rewarded that doesn't mean financially
but rewarded for learning new things and
figuring out new ways to do things do
you give people the freedom to try stuff
out do you give them the freedom to fail
right doing something about doing new
stuff is you might find things that
don't work right well yes we can do it
this way no okay well this bit doesn't
work we're down a dead end we need to
backtrack a bunch and then go down a
different route and there's some waste
in that but the waste that you get from
that is often
overshadowed by the clever and
interesting ways that you solve those
problems and the capabilities that those
ideas bring to the organization you
don't open out new markets new
capabilities get new users by just
staying in your lane you have to be
continually switching Lane and figuring
out what the best way to solve a problem
is so if you have a team uh that you you
take over as a product product owner or
as a development manager or any way you
come into contact in leadership with a
with a team if it feels like they're
they're not they don't feel they're
allowed to learn that they're allowed to
use new things that they're allowed uh
to do
stuff you need to fix that problem in
your organization fix the system and
then you'll start seeing a difference in
the teams you'll start seeing a
different uh Vibe a different k ability
a different interest in solving problems
in clever and interesting ways thanks
for watching the video If you enjoyed it
please like follow And subscribe I
always reply to comments and if you want
to have a chat about this or anything
else agile scrum or devops then please
book a coffee with me through naked
agility