scrum is a lightweight framework that
helps people teams and organizations
generate value through adaptive
solutions for complex problems
the scrum framework is made up of five
values three accountabilities three
artifacts and five events
in this video I'll go through an
overview of each one explaining what
they're for and why they are there
Focus will be on the process itself and
will leave any complementary practices
until later
my name is Martin henchewitz I've been a
professional scrum trainer for 12 years
professional kanban Trainor for two
years and a Microsoft MVP in devops for
14 years
scrum is based on empiricism
the three pillars of which are
transparency inspection and adaption
empiricism is impossible without
transparency and in order to get
transparency we need trust without it
we'd be unable to see what's going on
trust is not something that just happens
it needs considerable and deliberate
effort to create and maintain
five scrum values help guide and inform
the team decisions and help support
trust and empathy
these values are courage Focus respect
openness and commitment
their purpose is to help build and
support the trust needed to maintain the
transparency required
to get the most effective teams the
three accountabilities
although you may see these same names
used as job titles this was not the
intent of the scrum framework and as the
result of 25 years of accumulated
misunderstandings
there are three accountabilities in
scrum which together form the scrum team
the scrum team is entrusted by the
organization to create value for each
Sprint they operate as a decentralized
collaborative and autonomous team that
is responsible for stakeholder
collaboration verification maintenance
operations experimentation research
development and anything else that might
be required to create a successful
product
the accountability of the scrum team is
to effectively create a usable working
product of the highest possible value
let's see how that breaks down
the product owner is accountable for
maximizing the value of the work done by
the scrum team
there are many activities that they
might imply to help them maximize that
value
for example developing and explicitly
communicating the product goal creating
and clearly communicating product
backlog items ordering product backlog
items and ensuring that the product
backlog is visible transparent and
understood
file the product owner remains
accountable there is no requirement for
them to physically do this work
themselves
delegating some are all of these
activities enables the product owner to
scale and to focus on the strategies
they need to be successful
scrum developers are accountable for
creating a usable working product
the term developers here includes
everyone involved in developing the
product those folks may have skills and
Analysis user experience coding testing
legal architecture devops or whatever
other skills are required
the developers take accountability for
planning quality and each other
the scrum Master is accountable for the
effectiveness of the scrum team they do
this by providing services to the
developers the product owner and the
organization as a lean agile
practitioner
they have deep knowledge of the
technology required by the scrum team to
be successful
these Technologies might include
processes practices tools and techniques
relevant to the context of the product
under development
they Foster relationships between
developers the product owner and the
stakeholders to create an environment
with which within which they can all be
successful
the scrum Master does not write or order
backlog items administer jira or tell
the developers what to do
in addition to these three
accountabilities there are stakeholders
stakeholder is a general term given to
anyone outside of the scrum team that
has an interest in their work
while stakeholders do not have specific
accountability they are expected to be
involved in the process by providing
feedback and collaborating with the
scrum team as often as needed
while I have you here please like this
video And subscribe to our Channel below
so that you can get access to more of
this type of content
there are three artifacts in scrum
without being able to see what is going
on we can't really make effective
decisions and each of the artifacts
exists to provide the transparency that
is the foundation of any empirical
system
to provide this transparency there are
three artifacts in scrum
first is the product backlog the purpose
of which is to provide transparency over
what we need to do next that is it
provides transparency of the future
the product backlog is an ordered
inventory of things that we need to be
true for the product to be successful it
should not contain more items than the
product owner can easily understand and
articulate but enough to Foster
understanding and the success for the
product
too many items create too many
assumptions
the commitment to the product backlog is
the product goal
product goal reflects the desired
outcome for the next few Sprints and in
forms but does not control the contents
of the product backlog
while the product goal provides focus it
does not preclude incorporating feedback
features of opportunity or other things
as needed
next is the Sprint backlog
Sprint backlog contains three things
a Sprint goal the work that the
developers have selected for this Sprint
and an implementation plan to help them
get started
the purpose of the Sprint backlog is to
provide transparency over what we are
doing now Ergo transparency of the
present
the commitment to the Sprint backlog is
the Sprint goal which informs but does
not control the contents of the Sprint
backlog
during the Sprint the contents will
dynamically adapt to the changing needs
of the scrum team in the business while
maintaining the focus of the Sprint goal
Sprint goal is collaboratively created
and owned by the scrum team and reflects
the why of the Sprint
while the Sprint goal may only reflect
part of the Sprint backlog with
attention also given to augmenting
existing functionality refactoring and
updating the product dealing with
technical atrophy and creating
automation
lastly we have the product increment
representing the entire product it
provides transparency over what we have
done I.E transparency of the past
each consecutive increment is a concrete
step towards the product goal and must
be usable
usable is a combination of backlog items
themselves and the quality measures that
represent completeness
formal description of those quality
measures is the definition of done
the definition of done is the commitment
to the product increment it represents
the minimum product and Technical
qualities that are required to be able
to deliver your product to customers it
should mirror shippable
there are five scrum events that serve
empiricism
Sprint planning daily scrum Sprint
review and Sprint retrospective are all
time boxed events this means that you
should spend enough time fulfilling the
purpose of each event but not more than
the maximum specified in the time box
wrapping the entire scrum process is the
Sprint itself the Sprint is our fixed
length iteration within which in all the
other activities are completed and
represents the Cadence of adaptation
between the scrum team and the
stakeholders
while mentioned in the scrum guide
product backlog refinement is not a
specific event it's a term that
represents all of the work done by the
scrum team on items in the product
backlog rather than those selected for
the current Sprint
all of the work to understand evaluate
document and size things that may end up
in future Sprints is regarded as
refinement and every member of the scrum
team participates as needed
it's also important to note that scrum
is 25 years old and the technology
available to us at the time necessitated
a clear focus on people being physically
together
applying new technological advances to
the context of scrum are allows teams to
operate in both synchronous and
asynchronous collaboration as needed
while still fulfilling the intent of the
scrum values
the first event in scrum is Sprint
planning this event is where the scrum
team inspects the product backlog and
adapts the Sprint backlog
its purpose is to plan the Sprint
Focus for the upcoming Sprint is created
with the Sprint goal that is formulated
by the scrum team the developers then
select items from the product backlog
that best enable them to work towards
this goal while considering the order of
the product backlog and the needs of the
product
these choices may also trigger a change
in the Sprint Cup
next the developers create enough of an
implementation plan to allow them to get
started creating too much of an
implementation plan would create
excessive overhead for the scrum team as
new information is discovered
the output of Sprint planning is the
Sprint backlog which contains the Sprint
goal
selected backlog items and enough
implementation details to get started
foreign
next is the daily scrum
daily scrum is a daily event by and for
the developers where they maintain the
transparency of the Sprint backlog based
on what's happened since the last one
the purpose of the daily scrum is for
the developers to plan what they are
tactically doing next to achieve success
in this Sprint
based on the work that has been
completed and new learnings uncovered
since the last daily scrum we may need
to adapt the contents of the Sprint
backlog
while this tactical plan may change the
Sprint goal remains constant and only
the product owner can choose to abandon
the current Sprint goal and the Sprint
itself
the Sprint review occurs near the end of
the Sprint
this event includes both the scrum team
and stakeholders and is where the work
for the scrum team is offered for
inspection
purpose of the Sprint review is to plan
what's mixed and maintain transparency
of the product backlog
in pursuit of this transparency of the
future we need to reconcile the impact
of changes in the product the business
and the market since the last Sprint
review on the product backlog and the
product goal
this is a collaborative event where we
physically update the product backlog to
bring it in line with our current
understanding of the future maintaining
its transparency
finally we have the Sprint retrospective
it occurs immediately after the Sprint
review and allows the scrum team to
inspect themselves and adapt their
processes practice these tools and
relationships
purpose of the Sprint retrospective is
for the scrum team to plan how they are
going to increase their effectiveness
finding ways for the scrum team to be as
effective as possible within the bounds
of the organizational constraints is the
responsibility of the entire scrum team
pushing the bounds of those
organizational constraints is the
accountability of the scrum master
these four events wrapped in the Sprint
form a set of concentric feedback loops
that create an empirical process control
system and allow the scrum team to
iteratively and incrementally create the
best possible product within the current
constraints
so the scrum framework is made up of
five values three artifacts three
accountabilities and five events nothing
more nothing less
ROM framework is like the timber frame
for your house it does not control the
use that you put to each room its
decorations or its content it does
however give structure and support where
needed to maintain its structural
integrity
if you want to change the timber frame
of your house you can but due
consideration must be given to the
impact on that integrity
if you found this video useful please
like And subscribe to our channel to
encourage us to make more if you need
help getting started or just tuning up
your existing scrum please use the QR
code here or the link below to book a
free consultation