so what should you do if the Sprint
review delivers harsh scathing feedback
um I feel like it's more likely that you
get no feedback at all that's as scaling
as you can get we don't care enough to
give you any feedback right
um but perhaps you should consider what
it is you're building and what the
direction it is that you're taking the
product in
um so thinking about are we building the
right thing
right are we building stuff that our
stakeholders care about if we're not
building stuff or stakeholders care
about why would you expect them to turn
up and give you feedback
if if they're forced to turn up right
like they've been told it's mandatory
they turn up and they don't say anything
it's because they have to turn up and
they don't care
you want your stakeholders to want to
turn up and want to give you that
feedback
um and if you get a bunch of negative
feedback that's awesome
right that's that's that's our in our
indicator that we're going in the wrong
direction that we're maybe doing
something wrong or maybe it's we're
doing something right we're right we
were deliberately trying to ruffle
feathers and and and and and generate
some more ideation in the product but
the product owner and the whole scrum
team needs to really focus on on what's
what's next if we get horrible feedback
they hate our products
are we even building the right product
is it even worth continuing the product
is it worth investing in this do we need
to change tactical direction do we need
to change strategic Direction have we
got the right product go these are all
questions that you can ask uh during
that Sprint review and don't don't in a
Sprint review don't just go we got bad
feedback and stop the Sprint review you
need to dive into why you're getting
negative feedback what do the
stakeholders what's the difference
between what the stakeholders expected
and what they got so that you can try
and close that cap right if you don't
know what that Gap is if you don't know
where they thought you would be
um you don't know how to get there and
uh it could be that we just canceled the
product that's that's a perfectly valid
outcome from a Sprint review is we
decide that you know we somebody had a
great idea somebody thought it was worth
spending some money on we tried to spend
some money on it and we didn't have any
good outcomes so stop wasting money and
go after the next idea at something
different right that's entirely possible
so the kind of kind of three I guess
three outcomes from a Sprint review
um are stop doing what you're doing
that's one outcome
um pivot we love that word don't we we
pivot and change direction right we need
to do something slightly different or
even a lot different
um or perhaps perseverance right we know
we're on the right track it's not yet
resonating with the with the customer
base but we have a firm conviction and
belief that this is the right way
forward and that we'll be able to get
there and that's that's that's your
three choices at the end of the Sprint
review
um
make them well
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility