you don't need to know everything you
need to know what matters that might
sound obvious but if you're a CTO right
now it's hard to believe new frameworks
new tools AI models dropping loot weekly
every conversation feels like a pop quiz
you didn't study for and under it all
that quiet
fear if you're not on top of every trend
every shift you're falling
behind let's be clear that that's not
leadership that's FOMO and it's
exhausting at Naked Agility we help
CTO's make peace with not knowing
everything because we help you get clear
on what actually matters we work with
you to help map out your systems of work
uncover the strategic constraints and
identify the technical capabilities that
will move the
needle we filter out the noise fast not
every trend deserves your attention some
things can wait others are critical we
help you know the difference so instead
of reacting to everything you focus on
what drives outcomes that's how you stay
relevant not by knowing it at all but by
leading with clarity and intent