so what is the most common common
Epiphany in the psm2 course I think it I
think there's more than one and I think
it depends what level you're playing at
when you come into the class
um which Epiphany you get
so
the probably the the the most
the biggest Epiphany is the the
realization that the scrum Master is not
just focused on the team right that's
that's the big Epiphany for for most
folks because I think
even though it's very explicit in the
scrum guide it absolutely States here's
the scrum Master's accountability to the
team and here's the accountability of
the product owner and here's the
accountability to the to the
organization
most people seem to forget or kind of
gloss over that bit for the
accountability for the organization and
when we start
kind of double clicking on that and
expanding it and figuring out
um
what the implications are of those
accountabilities for how the scrum
Master
purports themselves within the
organization I think I think it changes
that Dynamic it expands those ideas and
they really have that realization
um that they perhaps need to be doing
more that they need to be poking at some
of those asking asking difficult
questions right that that's something
that I I find is very important as a
scrum master and even if all that
difficult question is is why right
um something happens a particular way in
the organization is getting in the way
of the team why right because you do
find depending on the organization that
there can be rules in place that are
ancient rules
right I I I did been doing a little bit
of uh digging recently on um Royal Bank
of Scotland
and they have these these these rules in
place for how their teams work
but there are there are 200 plus year
old bank right there's rules in place
because they were a great rule 100 years
ago for whatever context they were
created in
but are they still relevant today that's
kind of like your organizational package
and your organizational craft and who's
going to take care of that who who looks
at that craft so I think that that's
that's one of the big epiphanies
um at that level and then there's the
meta Epiphany in the PSM 2 that I think
is really important for those people in
the room that are also facilitators so
they kind of get a double Epiphany and
that's that that
how to engage with people and have more
people participate in the discussions
like have a two-dimensional scrum Master
right how to become a two-dimensional
scrum Master rather than that
one-dimensional of just looking at scrum
how do I start bringing in additional
tools and practices in the way that they
do things and demonstrate their own
behavior in order to to to facilitate
change
um of the people and and and and
participation in the events
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility