the scaled professional scrum is a
hands-on activity-based course where
students develop a collection of skills
that can be applied to overcome
challenges when scaling scrum even after
achieving success with scrum teams are
still limited by the amount of work they
can do and the value they can create
they need to expand or scale to groups
of scrum teams working together on the
same product
with doing so they encounter common
challenges with cross-team dependencies
self-management transparency and
accountability when introducing
heavyweight scaling methodologies teams
often find that the added overhead slows
them down
and distracts them from the essence and
benefits of scrum the scaled
professional scrum with nexus class
builds on the nexus framework by
introducing complementary practices and
techniques proven to help teams at scale
the course also includes a free attempt
at the globally recognized scaled
professional scrum certification exam
our training is delivered as an
interactive activity-based course over
half-day sessions using microsoft teams
and mural
students work together in a nexus to
organize and simulate a scaled product
development project
throughout this case study based class
common challenges in scaling are
presented and more than 50 practices for
overcoming them are revealed students
will develop an understanding of how to
launch structure organize and manage a
large agile project using scrum
they will leave the class with a toolbox
of techniques for identifying and
overcoming common scaling challenges
between each of the daily sessions we
provide additional reading writing and
watching activities to maximize the
learning opportunity and complement the
classroom experience after the
conclusion of the class we provide
access to a community of peers and
continued access to the trainer through
office hours quarterly catch-ups and
constant engagement to maximize
validated learning all students are
provided with a password to take the sps
assessment and if they take it within 14
days and are unsuccessful they will be
granted a second attempt as part of our
validated learning experience we provide
a 30-minute learning review
a one-hour coaching session and access
to future courses at a 30 discount
[Music]
you