with evidence-based management it's
really important to gather the data the
evidence that you're going to use to
help you in your decision- making to
help inform your decision making so we
need to to gather a bunch of data and
then we need to be able to analyze that
data there's lots of different places
you can get your data from depending on
what type of data it is that you need so
if you're remember there are uh four key
value areas in uh evidencebased
management that we want to kind of try
and make sure that we have at least
something in each of those
areas so in each of those key value
areas we want to find what it is we want
to collect and then figure out how to
collect it then we have to actually
collect it and then collecting it's not
good enough we have to actually analyze
it so uh there are some areas that are
easier than others so in the the
organizational capability the two um key
value areas that are part of
organizational capability uh uh time to
Market and ability to innovate um
there's a plethora of data that you can
collect within the context of your
engineering teams my focus tends to be
around engineering uh software
engineering so uh I might collect at
things like how much technical debt do I
have how many bugs do I have uh over
time right so the trend of of of bugs I
might be collecting oh there's loads of
data I can collect um I could collect
code coverage or the trend of code
coverage over time that might be uh
valuable at some point there are
hundreds of different data points that
we can we can collect within that
context uh a few that might make sense
so in if you're in ability to innovate
you'll probably find a lot of metrics at
coming from D if you look up the Dora
metrics lots of great stuff in there so
there's things like defect Trends but
also Innovation rate is really important
what percentage of time do you spend
innovating versus doing all the other
stuff that you need to do um and
collecting things like technical debt um
so some of these things are easy to
collect um Innovation rate is fairly
easy you just categorize the work that
you're doing as net newwork um
augmentations to existing functionality
and then and support support and
maintenance work whatever you want to
call those categories um and then you
you graph that over time right so you'll
be able to see uh uh uh what's going on
there and you can then make decisions
right um based on the amount of money
that you're investing in each of those
areas do you want to change how you in
your investment strategy Works um do you
want to spend more time on Innovation or
do you need to spend more time on um
augmenting your existing functionality
and that might depend on some of the
other metrics from the market value side
of the story right so in in in market
value we had current value so what our
product currently does and unrealized
value which is the things that our
product might do that it doesn't do yet
so this would ultimately result in your
product backlog and this is your actual
increment your actual product so if we
were looking at data for your actual
product we might uh be looking at
something like uh customer satisfaction
how satisfied are the users of your
product with your product how satisfied
are they with the features do they meet
their needs you know there's a bunch of
questions you can ask around that um
interviews you can do to try and get
some of that data and and that might
inform where where you want your
Innovation rate to be right if your
existing customers are very unhappy
then perhaps you need to address that
right perhaps you need to invest more in
augmenting the existing stuff or
figuring out what you're missing in that
space that could be an expectations gap
which would be more on the um unrealized
value Right Stuff your product doesn't
do yet but understanding that data
informs the decisions that you make so
there's a piece of data um in in our
organizational capability specifically
in ability to innovate um and our
Innovation
rate our decision on what should we do
with that data depends on this other
data right data on how people feel about
our current product or the features in
our current product maybe it's all the
way down to individual features
granularity is quite important there and
what we're missing in our product and if
we're missing a lot we probably want to
invest a lot of money in the missing
stuff if we're not missing much but our
customers are unhappy we probably want
to invest a lot in uh increasing the the
satisfaction of our customers within our
our existing product structure and all
of these
decisions are informed but not
controlled by the data right so um not
only do we need to collect the data but
we need to realize that just because the
data says something doesn't mean we
should immediately act upon it there are
some things that you absolutely should
immediately act on like if defects Trend
the trend of defects is suddenly
shooting up or um customer satisfaction
suddenly takes a big drop those are
things that you want to check the data
first then perhaps have some kind of
bigger action on it um but you there are
times where you might take the opposite
action so one of the things things that
you would collect definitely collect in
uh um current value is your us usage
index is what they call it in evidence
base management um but um how what it's
usage data it's Telemetry in your
product right so um do you know if you
have a if you have a button that takes
you to a
feature um and that feature has options
um how many what percentage of your
users use that feature how often do they
use that feature and when they do use
that feature what parts of that feature
do they interact with that should be
data that you have on hand right that's
data that we can reasonably easily
collect it requires engineering work
your your your developers need to add
stuff to your product to collect that
data um if you're building a website you
might get some of that with Google
analytics but um usually we're we're
we're looking for a deeper story than
just what pages are hit depending on the
way your website's constructed if you're
doing web um but um exactly what
features how long features take to load
um how long actions take these are all
parts of that that Telemetry story that
give you an absolute wealth of of of
data that you can access um I Heard a
great story um from uh a car company
that I that I worked with um and they
were talking about how easy it was to
access dat that that data within their
organization their organization most car
companies collect this type of telemetry
even if they have no overthe a updates
when your car goes in for a a service
and they connect up the computer system
at the dealership um it sucks down all
of the the Telemetry data on all of the
gear shift how the gear shifts performed
there's a big log in the system they
load that data and it gets sent off to
or for faults and all those kind of
things that gets sent off to um the
parent company and then the idea is you
would analyze that data right uh and
they were talking about their inability
to access that data even though it
exists to get access to data to a slice
of that data to a piece of that data
required a whole bunch of time and
approvals and it was I think they in
this particular case they said something
like 6 to8 months before they could get
access to the data once they requested
it and that's far too long that's us
then making business decisions based on
six to8 month old data Because by the
time we get it we get that slice of the
data it's old and we need a new slice of
the data um whereas
they told me that they work one of their
colleagues worked at Tesla uh and at
Tesla everybody has access to all of
that data instantaneously continuously
you can go look at the real time stream
of that data from the Cars um to know
what people are doing how people are
interacting with the features and
capabilities within the
car that's gamechanging data right um
having it at all is
gamechanging having access to as close
to where people as close to real time it
doesn't have to be real time real time
is a a little bit of a fallacy but as
close to real time as possible like if
if I'm if I'm working on a feature right
now and I'm doing let's say I'm I'm I'm
doing continuous delivery so I'm
shipping to production on a regular
basis let's say it's on average every
couple of days I'm shipping this feature
to production and it's shipping out to
all the cars like like Tesla does right
they do continuous updates then I want
data at this point I want as close to
this point as possible so I make a
change I ship it in I've got two days
till my next change I'm going to push
out what do I need to fix what do I need
to change well I'm going to be analyzing
the data in that segment to update my
product backlog and engage with the team
and figure out what what what needs to
happen this is this is what product
management is all about right you're
actually managing the product and you're
managing the product with the data to
understand how you need to manage the
product and this is this is hugely
important and and that
difference is your customers loving your
software or hating your software um I
have a I have a Nissan I have a Nissan
Leaf and their software is probably some
of the worst
least
useful I don't know how much more to
describe it is is the the most horrible
software to use and work with and the
least useful um from any perspective in
the way that it's constructed the way it
functions the way I engage with it it
doesn't provide me with the things I
want it doesn't provide me with the
things in a timely manner um it doesn't
it it's terrible it's just terrible um
and that's likely because nobody's
looking at the data nobody's looking at
I think it has the the the the Android
store it's got a I think it did have a
1.2 rating at one point it was horrible
horrible app um
that nobody must be looking at that data
or they don't care right if the business
doesn't care about that part of the
system then why provide it right maybe
they're providing it because they feel
they have to but if you have to provide
it because it's table Stakes it needs to
be good otherwise it reflects on your
company and your business right so um
collecting this data as a product
manager um is the whole ball game so we
we tal we we just talked about one
metric we started with an innovation
rate and we ended up connecting all
those stories together um the visual
studio team at Microsoft they get 7
terabytes of data per day and that's
just from the clients the visual studio
desktop clients out in the world that
are on networks that allow that data to
be to be sent lots of big organizations
have those things locked off so that
that data doesn't exit the network right
so this is just a subset of users but
it's a subset of data that they can
interact with that they can see what's
going on in the product that they can
make a change and push it out and then
see almost real time whether they've
been successful or they've not in
achieving the the hypothesis that they
had right we think adding this feature
is going to make a change in people's
behavior in this way let's look at the
make a change look at the Telemetry did
we improve the user engagement with this
feature did we improve uh uh the number
of people that used it right if
not we didn't achieve our outcome with
that change let's think about why we
didn't do that maybe we want to talk to
a couple of users and figure out why
they didn't change their behavior right
all of those types of things are part of
building great
products so we've we've we've talked
about some where we can get some of the
data uh we talked about how to collect
the data um some of it is just I guess
uh uh I guess we talk about to collect
it some of it is just you stick it in
Excel right there's nothing nothing bad
about Excel is a great tool um so you
just record it on a on a regular Cadence
and and stick it in Excel that could be
from customer survey data that could be
a slice of your Innovation rate when
you're when you're looking at it if
you're really
um on the ball you might feed all of
that data that you have into a a data
warehouse and then use something like
powerbi to analyze it and have
dashboards that show you what's going on
uh um near real time in your product in
your system when your customers are
doing and how they're interacting with
it um there are leading measures and
lagging measures leading me measures are
ones that change frequently right that
you can get a you can make a change to
the system and then see that data
changing lagging measures are things
that take a little bit longer to to come
to fruition like if you surveyed users
on their satisfaction then that's going
to be a lagging measure right you're
making changes to the system isn't going
to immediately reflect changes to the
data um you would need to analyze it
over a longer period of time both are
important right um your leading stuff is
changing the work that you're doing
right now your lagging stuff is perhaps
affecting more your overall strategy and
what's going on there's a great example
of a a feature that the the visual
studio team built um called intelletrace
um if you don't know what it is it
doesn't matter but it was a big big
expensive feature really expensive
features it was only in the Enterprise
product to start with um and it was a
very expensive feature to build um I
can't overstate that enough it's like
huge amounts of money more ridiculous
amounts of money than we could possibly
imagine um and what they found was that
nobody was using it so they built this
feature they spent all this money on
this feature they shipped this feature
and then they're looking at the
Telemetry and it says nobody's using
it so what do you do do you do you cut
that feature do you stop investing in
that feature do we invest more in that
feature we maybe need a little bit more
information so when when they did dive
into it right go see a little bit of
gamber right go have a look talk to
people they found that people weren't
using it because they didn't know it was
there and it was off by default and they
had to go turn it on in the settings um
so in the next version of the product
because this was actually when they were
on the two-yearly releases so it then
took them let's say 18 months or or or
uh whatever amount of time to to get
this change in so that's 18 months
of because people aren't using the
feature remember of that feature
effectively sitting on a shelf and
depreciating while your competitors
might have that feature and you do have
that feature but your customers don't
know it's there so they don't use it so
they might go to your competitors
because they think your competitors have
a feature that you don't
right um and when they turned it on by
default shipped it out nobody turned it
on very few people the percentage of
people that turned it off was very small
and then they were getting that usage
data and getting that usage Telemetry
that's why I always say the the data
that you collect informs but does not
control your decision- making because
then the the there needs to be more to
it than that you're playing poker not
chess right if you're playing
chess all of the
information that's
available is in your hands right you can
see the state of the board you know all
the moves you know all the possible
counter moves and that's where you get
to to those grandmas things with they're
thinking 20 30 moves ahead I don't know
how many moves ahead they think but
they're thinking so many moves ahead you
know it's 10 moves to checkmates right
and then how does this person get out of
it and the only way they can do that is
to to to I guess maybe fake you into
doing something or you make a mistake
right I'm going to win unless I make a
mistake I'm going to win this game and
there they know so there's there's no
hidden
information
um but
for Building Products it's more like
playing poker we have incom complete
information we don't understand all of
what's going on now ideally we want as
much information as we can on the things
we can find
out to fill in enough of the gaps so
that when we're looking at our big
picture or even our little picture we
can kind of say well we think this is
what's happening right we can infair the
missing information CU when you're
playing poker you know the cards in your
hand you know the card that are open on
the table on the type of pool you're
playing and but you don't know what your
your your competitors have got in their
hand and you don't know what the dealer
is hiding or what the next card's going
to come off the stack now if you're
really good at card counting if you're
Telemetry and data then you can have a
more informed decision making if you get
very good at reading the other players
around the table really reading their
emotional intent right the the the that
those those tails that they have then
you get more information that you can
use and that's who the best poker
players are right they are poker players
that recognize the cards that go through
the deck they so they've got good
memories they recognize um the emotional
engagement between the players and the
game to be able to discern more
information about what their competitors
are doing without actually knowing right
it's a lot of guess work um and then
they make decisions on whether they're
going to anti- up fold or um increase
the might go all in right I've
definitely got the winning hand we're
going to go all in and and and run with
this so that's what we're playing as
product management so understanding the
data collecting the data viewing the
data analyzing the data um some tools
for analyzing the data wow
um i t i prob is probably the big the
big big H tool um my background is in
the Microsoft space so I tend to know
the Microsoft solutions for these
problems um but I know a lot of people
like powerbi even when they're using
other platforms to store the data um but
powerbi to put all the data together um
probably things like app insights is
great application insites is Microsoft's
tool for collecting uh Telemetry it
supports open open Telemetry there's a
platform called open Telemetry that you
can use and you can store the data
wherever the heck you want um but it
enables you to collect and stream data
direct from customers that's your
Telemetry capture um yeah
this and this is part of the story right
so you've got you you've got your data
you've analyzed your data you've been
able to tell the difference between your
your um
what you think is happening versus what
you know is happening right you're
intuitive versus your actual data
and you need another tool you need a a
tool to
help enable your organization to more
quickly adapt um and sync through those
those processes so the the main tool
that I would use to collect data to
understand our processes right so it's
exactly the same as understanding our
organization we want to understand our
process that our team or our product is
is our operating model for our product
um and probably going to use a cand
metrics right that's going to give us um
quantitative data on what's going on
within our system that our teams have
created that are we've created within
our organization to handle work
um and then I want to make tweaks to
that system and be able to see in the
quantitive data that it's changing right
and and it's changing in a way that we
want it to change right we're improving
reducing our cycle time improving our
throughs all of those kind of things
right
so that's
great caman really allows you to model
any system right but there are tools out
there Technologies out there that you
can adopt that allow you to kind of jump
start that process cuz you might be way
over here on um my team every team in my
organization made up their process and
every member of every team does their
own thing right that's that's that's a
pretty common place for most
organizations to be um and we want to
have a little bit of standardization
while enabling the teams to be free to
do those things that we've standardized
in any way they choose um this the same
idea that that Microsoft talks about one
es one engineering system that's as your
devops right um and this idea that you
have one place to store all the stuff so
everybody knows where to go look
everybody knows how to go set things up
in that thing um so we're when an
engineer moves from one product to
another product they're not going and
hunting for well where's the automated
builds what technology is this I need to
learn a new new technology to even
change and understand this automated
build you don't have to do that we
understand that stuff already and then
it's just looking at how does it
actually run right um and then we can
jump start our people coming into that
process and the same is true in process
like 1es for our actual Engineering
Systems um scrum is a social technology
for our social systems right so we can
jumpstart our um move towards agility so
doing scrum doesn't mean you're agile
right we want to improve our systems and
scrum can be a good
application to say here's our bounded
environment right so that when if you're
familiar with cotter's Change Model you
create a bounded environment for for
change so you create a set a set of
principles that are going to guide that
change and perhaps there's some rules in
there at the start right we need a set
of rules to get people started so that
they're then following the principles
and then we start taking away like you
don't have to do this you don't have to
do that right you know when you were new
at this you had to do it this way you
know like training wheels on your bike
and then you can take the training
wheels off and suddenly you're riding
your bike on your own um and that
that if you look at the scrum guide it
has a literal a literal set of of rules
but it's based on a set of
principles so the rules are not a must
the principles are a must if that makes
sense in the scrum guide but the rules
are there
because most teams especially when they
start out especially when they're coming
from something else need an example of
how to start doing something and once
they are doing that thing and doing that
thing well and understand why those
particular structures are in place they
can then start doing something different
from those Pol particular structures in
order to still fulfill the same outcome
right from the principles so that's why
I talk about scrum as a social
technology we've got our our our
engineering you know one es one
engineering system what is your 1es your
one engineering system that helps um
from an engineering perspective Ensure
that everybody in your organization um
is able to move between different
products is able to help each other and
collaborate with each other share
knowledge and and and and ideas because
they're all working within the same
relative context even though how they
actually do stuff is completely up to
them um and scrum is that
social one social technology right um
around which you can allow people in the
teams to do what they do however the
heck they like right um but have a small
set of here's some some points at which
uh we engage with you
which leadership engages with the teams
the teams engage with leadership
engaging with the customers we have
those kind of touch points but within
that they can do whatever they want um
so evidencebased
management is really your lead into a
whole whole bunch of things that we can
do really really well and to understand
how we're doing things so you can apply
evidence-based management to your
business you can apply evidence-based
management to your product you can apply
evidence-based management some of the
metrics to an individual team and you
can figure out what's happening with
your system how your business is
organized and then when you make changes
to that system you can see it's the
empirical data that you need to
understand not just your engagement with
the market and your engagement with your
users but how your people are engaging
and your products are delivering within
that market so that you can adapt your
strategic uh uh intermediate strategic
and tactical
plans in
order
to have a success uccessful business
build the best product possible and and
generate lots of money