so the PBM course is a fantastic idea
for product owners because ultimately
product owners are uh uh the the
entrepreneur the mini CEO of a product
and if you want to be making um good
decisions about um which bets to make on
the success of your product right which
features to build you need to understand
the holistic outcome of your product the
whole product and ebm evidence-based
management can be used to look at a
whole product and say these These are
the metrics that we've decided in each
of the the key value areas right
unrealized value Uh current value
ability to innovate and time to Market
um and we can we once we've chosen those
metrics we can then monitor them over a
long period of time and see that we're
taking the product in the right
direction ction right how do you know
when you're going off topic uh when
you're going on a tangent to what your
organization is trying to achieve when
you're off the beaten path maybe off the
beaten path is the best place to be
because you you look at the data you
look at the metrics and holy moly this
has been really successful right um and
then you need to have a conversation
with your business about well we were
going this way but actually we think
this way is a better way to go that's
going to add more value how do you know
how do you know to have those
conversations with the business how do
you uh make uh those determinations we
need to understand what's going on in
the product right we need to understand
our ability to innovate we need to
understand our time to Market how
quickly we can get things through to
maximize our capability as a product
owner you want to maximize your ability
to deliver business value right that's
that's that's you that's your whole job
is maximize our ability to deliver value
maximize the value that we deliver so
our capability of our teams that are
delivering value right are we maximizing
the throughput of our ability to deliver
value and then are we delivering the
right value our market value are we
maximizing that and how do you know if
you're not measuring that's why uh
product owners like the pal ebm uh the
evidence base management class is
awesome to help you give you extra tools
to help you figure out what that is help
you engage with the rest of your your
team and bring them along on that story
and perhaps help you turn some of your
developers from developers to product
developers if you want to have a
discussion about your unique needs or
situation then please book a call or
visit us at naked agility
docomo have our immersive and
traditional public classes on our
website and we'd love to hear from you