evidence evidence-based management has
improved um agility by a a actually
having some way to monitor whether we're
making changes to the
organization um and I think one of the
core problems that we we've had is that
there hasn't been any real metrics and
if you look at the research out there on
um agility uh in any form whether that's
a a um uh uh plans or uh safe or
um Dad or less
Nexus um scrum whatever it is you decide
to do in general organizations are not
being successful by implementing those
things they're not making systemic
changes to their organization they're
not getting the benefits that they
expected to get and part of the reason
that that is that is true that they're
not getting the benefits is that they're
focusing on the wrong thing we're
focusing on delivering the agile which
is which is not the point the point of
of of this is having a successful
business that delivers value into the
market so that we increase the the the
value of our organization right that's
what we're trying to achieve and agile
is just a set of tools and practices and
capabilities that we can use to help us
be better at that but unless we focus on
what it is that we're trying to achieve
being being being more successful in the
market we're not going to get the
benefits from agel because we're not
going to make the changes in our
organization that we need in order to be
successful right that's where when you
look at organizations that are hugely
successful at agile a at at in the
market right and they're using agile
they've
monitored what's going on in their
organization and they've changed things
in their organization the way their
organization functions the way they do
business the way they lead people the
way they manage people the way the way
everything in their business operates
every process every service every
workflow has been impacted um and
they've made those changes based on the
data that they see right they're able to
make a change in the way they do their
business and and monitor that data so
evidence based management
practices
is even without using those
terminologies is how every successful
organization has become successful right
and then we get complacent once we get
to a certain size and and the
organization quite often stagnates every
startup um every startup that ends up
being successful is using an
evidence-based approach every
organization that is continuous ly
growing not necessarily through the the
acquisition model right is a different
model but growing through their ability
to deliver is is is doing that based on
looking at the data making the right
decisions in the market and and
expanding that this is how you scale an
organization is you use the
data to figure out what's next so
evidence-based management just
quantifies that and says is you know
just looking at revenue is not a good
idea right we just look at Revenue what
about what about markets we haven't
tapped yet right the the unrealized
value what about ability to innovate
because if we continuously just deliver
stuff at some point we're going to get
slower and slower at delivering stuff if
we want to maintain our ability to
deliver stuff into into into production
hopefully the right stuff right but and
maintain our ability to deliver stuff we
need to be continually making sure that
our ability to innovate and our uh um
time to Market is of a manageable size
right there's balance in this framework
of unrealized value current value
ability to innovate and time to Market
that enables you as an organization to
make better decisions to focus on the
right things for your business to be
successful so for forget about the agile
piece right evidence-based management is
about how you adapt your organization to
be more successful how you enable your
organization to take uh uh to deal with
the surprises that come along in the
market so they could be good surprises
or bad surprises but when things happen
how quickly can your organization take
advantage of that surprise or mitigate
the the the cost of that surprise um and
that ability to adapt is what people are
trying to quantify when they talk about
agility so really evidence-based
management is the thing that helps your
organization be successful in the market
if you want to have a discussion about
your unique needs or situation then
please book a call or visit us at naked
agility tocom uh we also have our
immersive and traditional public classes
on our website and we'd love to hear
from you