test D driven development is not about
building better code it's about having
better architectures we create better
architectures because we only create
what we need to support the things that
we need it to do doing pair programming
means that we've got more eyes on the
code it feels like it's going to be less
productive but productivity is not a
moment in time for the engineering team
it needs to be looked at across the
whole system and we can take uh what
seems like a a hit on productivity to do
pair programming because there's two
people doing things why can't we have
them both doing their own thing but we
have less problems that we need later
which are much more expensive than the
pair programming is at the at the start
right same with