hi i'm michelle chronister i work for
usa.gov here at the us general services
administration
and we're in the process of
restructuring some content on our
homepage and we created some wireframes
and we wanted to just do a real
quick and dirty simple test that was
pretty lo-fi so hopefully we could get
some honest feedback and people didn't
think that they were gonna hurt our
feelings with the you know really
polished final product so what we did is
we printed out our wireframe for mobile
on a really long
piece of paper
it's just you know text boxes nothing
super fancy
and we i took a manila folder
and i taped a
picture of a phone to it and i cut out a
window
and then what i did was i tested people
in the hallway who were willing to give
us five minutes
and i you know had a trusty test script
and i asked them some basic questions
about you know where they would go to
find things um and the reason we did the
folder with the cutout is because you
know just showing this big long piece of
paper for mobile is kind of overwhelming
but this allows people to get a sense of
you know what they would see on their
phone at any time and if people said oh
i would click here i'd say okay well if
you clicked here this is what happened
and then i'd move the paper and then say
you know is that what you expected to
happen and they would say like yeah i
did or no and then we continue with the
test and i would let them move it up and
down i would move it up and down if they
did something where
it would move for them automatically
so we did this for both mobile and then
on the other side of the folder we have
a cut out for tablet so we did mobile
and tablet and it's exactly the same we
just did a printout of tablet resolution
and we put it in the
folder and we did the same deal we asked
the same questions um you know we would
move it we would let them move it
it's definitely not perfect it's kind of
clunky
and it wasn't meant to be perfect
because we were hoping that if it was
really
uh
really simple and not too advanced that
we might get honest feedback we learned
a lot from doing this we did make a few
changes to this and then the next round
of testing we did instead of using the
paper we used a simple wireframe but we
put it on a mobile phone as a pdf and
then we gave them the phone and actually
let them scroll up and down so we could
see the behavior with a real touch
device
it was actually very similar so it
confirmed a lot of the things we found
from this test
obviously with the improvements we made
those were no longer a problem but we
found a few other issues so it was
really helpful it took about five
minutes to make this and you know zero
dollars so i would definitely recommend
it if you're looking for a creative and
cheap way of testing something