one of the agile practices that puts us
clearly and explicitly in the category
of agile banditry is using say do
metrics that's metrics where you're
looking at what people say they were
going to do and then what they actually
did a great example of that is uh um oh
oh I guess my favorite example is from
an organization that I worked with many
years ago
um that the head of pmo brought me into
his office to show me uh some of the
metrics that they presented up to
leadership in the organization and for
each of the projects uh this was many
years ago each of the projects that they
had underway I think there were five
projects they had underway um they they
had a original estimate versus actual
that's the quintessential s do original
estimate and actuals uh uh for for each
of the projects and they were in the
thousands of hours right like 5,000
hours um and something I noticed right
away when he showed me this this this
presentation it was a presentation to to
to show the leadership was that of the
five projects all of them were within
20% but if you know your bcks and you
know your statistics you'll probably
know from the uh chaos report of the
Standish group um that
65% of the features that we think we're
going to build change during the life of
the the the the project so how could it
possibly be only a 20% deviation between
the amount of time we think it's going
to take and the amount of time actually
going to take so that was my first clue
that something was up my second clue was
that uh uh three of the projects were
within
15% two of them were within 10% and then
I noticed that one project that said
5,232 hours original estimate
5,232 hours
actuals and I just turned the graph
around pointed at that one and said but
this is
BS how how could you possibly have these
numbers be the same and he said well
right you know there's something bad
coming when somebody does that that well
in La last year last year yearly budgets
whole other problem last year we uh
created this report uh with with what
what happened and we gave it to
leadership and they had a tantrum and
threw their toys out the prom and
shouted at us um and made our lives a
misery so this year we made a change to
the system and we allowed project
managers to make a change request to
their original estimate and that project
manager just got his change request in
just before we completed the report
before the deadline uh so the original
estimate had been changed more than once
in order to get the graphs to look like
they did so they're going to go and
present this to leadership and
Leadership is potentially going to make
decisions on what they fund what they
don't fund based on this type of data
this data that is complete Fiction it's
just complete fiction so you don't want
that in organizations if you have a
monitor s do uh metrics there are many
other types of s do metrics but the most
common one is original estimate and
actuals right um monitoring s do metrics
reduces psychological safety right that
that pmo the pmo of a big organization
didn't feel safe and enough to show
leadership the real data they had to
create vanity metrics in order to make
them happy um we tend to focus on output
rather than outcome right well you said
you were going to deliver 10 things but
you only actually delivered nine things
you suck right whereas an actual fact we
delivered nine of the most valuable
things wasn't that better if we
delivered nine things that were more
valuable than the 10 things that were
asked for
right or you delivered zero of the
things we asked I I I remember um being
at a at a MVP Summit AT Microsoft um
where they they they invited us to come
and talk about the product and the year
before we' done a whole bunch of stats
and uh learnings on what are the most
valuable features that we as MVPs
believe as your devops needs as a
product I think it was TFS service at
the time what what are the cool features
we need we did days like five days of
figuring out what that was and came up
with a list of here's the top five
things that we believe all of our
customers need in the product and the
very first thing uh uh uh uh the next
year when Brian Harry uh got up to do
his key you know Keynotes entry starting
presentation to kick the the next Summit
off he said here's a list of the five
things that you said were the best
things we could build and I'll tell you
now we've built none of them here's what
we did build instead of building the
things that we thought were the most
valuable he went off and totally blew
our socks off with all the things he did
build that were much more valuable to
our
customers if we'd held them to the say
do
metric they delivered nothing that we
asked for and that is absolutely not the
case so don't focus on output over
outcome you want to be focusing on the
outcomes what it is you're trying to
achieve um and it that over
emphasis that comes from it on
estimation is is key to that negative
feeling that people have uh when when
you monitor them with s metrics just
just stop doing se s metrics uh don't be
a bandit um and give up on that agile
banditry of s do metrics
if you're being ambushed by agile
bandits in your organization then my
team at naked agility can help you or
help you find a consultant or expert who
can you can set up a no obligation
consultation using the links
below and don't forget to like And
subscribe if you enjoyed this video