oh that's a great question so how does
somebody become an agile consultant
well I don't think I don't think well
become that's probably the the linchpin
there
it's really hard a hard question because
you have to be
good
at something
right agile is not the thing that we're
doing
agile is a bunch of ideas practices that
you bring along to the thing that you're
doing in order to make it more effective
right you can say the same about lean
how do you become good at lean well you
have to be good at the thing that you're
focusing on with lean
and then you bring in lean practices you
apply it to the actual work that you're
doing you bring in add your practice you
doing
you get
seen by people around you as
understanding some of these things more
and how those things interconnect and
how we can maybe change and shift the
way we work in order to become more
optimal
um and those people that recognize you
as as doing that encourage you to do
more of it you do more of it and
suddenly you're an agile or devops
consultant right that's that's that's
how you become that thing it's not like
it's uh uh
I can just go well I'm going to be an
agile consultant for
um I don't know a car factory
right I'm not gonna go do that because
I've never worked in a car factory I
don't understand all the Nuance of how
car factories work that would be a dumb
idea to have me as an agile consultant
or a lean consultant for a car factory
my background and expertise is in
software right you you you you be a
software engineer for 10 years you be a
devops consultant for 10 years and then
maybe you have enough knowledge and
experience and stories and or currencies
and understanding on how to link those
how to abstract it's really about
abstraction right you're at you you need
to understand the thing you're doing
enough to abstract
the agile and lean story from the work
see how it impacts and affects it in
your particular expertise
and then perhaps you could go help and
advise outside of that context right
because you've then got 10 years of
helping and Advising in a particular
context go help and advise in another
context so for example
um I think it was 20
2016 I did uh some
uh Coke some training for the Ghana
Police Service
so this was training line police
officers
um they were not by any stretch of the
imagination software focused not not no
software skills whatsoever
and they wanted to understand how they
could use scrum
to enact organizational change
right so instead of the scrum being the
the product is the organization
how do we enact organizational change
over a long period of time and
incrementally uh change the organization
so that and then we see the results what
data do we need to look at to monitor
the feedback and increase that and part
of that was the the new Inspector
General of police uh used to work for
um uh Interpol an Interpol use scrum
apparently right I no no no no clue in
what context but he wanted to bring some
of those stories into the way he was
doing things in in Ghana and that
experience of
I was very clear when I was doing the
training I'm like everybody be I want
you all to be very clear I know nothing
about policing
accept what I've seen on TV which is
probably woefully incorrect right
um and what what was interesting was
while we were really talking about how
organizational change worked
um the head of CID
uh which if you don't know what c idea
is it's the the detectives right they're
they're solving the the the complex
cases the murders and the stuff like
that the head of CID
um was engaging me in lots of
conversations about what but how would I
apply this to solving a case right so we
had to talk about
you know I'm giving them information
about how this would work in my world
and he's trying to figure out how does
he apply that in his world right because
it's completely different and I can't
tell him how to do that because I don't
know how he does his work
and that's that that piece is it you
need to
be an agile
or or a consultant within your context
for long enough that you can see the
abstracted ideas that would work in any
context and then you can consult on them
even if you don't know the core context
that takes years of of of experience of
doing that to be able to get that
abstraction level to be able to work in
another in our department so for example
if you've spent the last 20 years
working in finance where should you be
an agile in devops and not devops right
but agile and lean consultant
um in the in the in the financial space
right look at Finance teams delivering
the stuff that Finance teams deliver
and figure out how to how to bring some
of those ideal practices into there do
that for long enough and then you'll
have the experience to go into another
uh uh um industry and do the same thing
because the same stuff applies right you
just need enough knowledge and
experience to be able to abstract it
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility