patching defects at the end is too late
If you're finding problems during UAT
staging or after release you've already
lost Every latest stage defect costs you
more time more money and more reputation
than it should And most of them they
could have been caught much much earlier
At Naked Agility we help teams shift
left We strengthen the definition of
done to embed quality checks early
validation during deployment Security
built into the pipeline Telemetry ready
before everything goes live When you
move quality to the front you stop
firefighting at the back You save time
You save face And you deliver increments
you can actually trust Need fewer
production surprises Let's shift left
and catch issues earlier