why shouldn't this what do people know
about devops
um
but really don't
I well the first thing especially for
I have been a Microsoft MVP in Azure
devops for uh 14 years
so lots of people when they say devops
around me
um they mean as your devops they mean
the tooling and that's quite often the
case with a lot of these these uh when
they talk about the work what they mean
is jira right the the the the tool is
not the value
the tool is just there to help you
surface the value or leverage the value
that that comes with that idea
um so the thing that people know about
devops but really don't is that it's
it's not uh
it's not a tool
it's not a
process it's not a practice it's an idea
right and it's really that idea born
very specifically in software
engineering right I mean that's that's
really where where devops focuses
um around how do we
if we're talking about agile and we're
talking about getting faster at doing
stuff
what's the impact of that on our
Engineering Systems what's the impact of
that on the way we create our product
the way we approach our product the way
we design our product what is the impact
that enables us to shorten those
feedback loops
um Beyond just talking about it right
because agile is the people in process
part and devops is the
wow
the the the the the the nebulous part of
the not just the tools man that's hard
to describe right
um devops is just an idea just like
agile's just an idea so tools may help
you but figuring out
how you're going to use those tools or
how those tools uh work I I had some
great conversations
um with a gentleman Who was the the
almost the source of Team Foundation
server originally uh Visual Studio team
Services as it was called the first time
round and the ideas behind it which is a
gentleman called Sam guggenheimer
there's a great Twitter account which is
what would Sam say which is his people
that worked with him created because he
would see all sorts of I don't know
clever and interesting and funny for the
rest of us stuff
um but Sam had this laser focus looking
forward into the future what do we need
going forward looking out into the
future in order to support this idea of
devops
and TFS and his journey into Azure
devops right is the result of that
thinking not the cause of that thinking
right the tools are not the cause the
idea is the cause and the tools are
there to support it
and that's I think what people
understand about devops but really
really don't because they always default
to the tool the tool the tool no it's
default to the idea and the tool
supports that idea
um and that's where you want to be
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility