let's start with the why why PPD V
course was
created based on our
observations uh how companies work how
teams work seems there is still a lot of
attention when it comes to delivery one
may also think that hey if we have to
put just one goal of every spr what is
the most important that we have to
achieve is creating increment product
increment done product increment
so seems this is an important topic
right but this is not
enough and we I believe forget although
we emphasize this a lot that we are
solving complex
problems what does it mean we along this
product development Journey we will make
a lot of
assumptions what is even worse some of
those assumptions in some of the cases I
would dare to say even majority of them
might be made
unconsciously so we made an assumption
we take Next Step but we miss learning
opportunity
and this may lead us to feature Factory
problem of course we have a lot of memes
and stories like hey strong stakeholders
stakeholder driven development and T
here we go we have feature Factory
problem in place but if we think about
it deeper there might be a lot of
factors affecting affecting this
problem maybe we have insufficient user
understanding maybe we believe that what
our users say is the truth well this is
what they say but guess what do we
really understand what is the need do we
have all data evidence to find the best
ways to bring solutions to fulfill users
needs
this is a valid
question maybe we are facing reactionary
development okay customers want it
because competitors did it is it really
so that's another question maybe we are
facing insufficient collaboration with
our stakeholders and this is not the
healthy
collaboration and maybe we have chosen
wrong metrics we we have a misalignment
here all those things may may cause
problem that we call Feature Feature
Factory
problem so what do we want to to do with
this course we want to emphasize the
topic of
assumptions in the complex world in the
complex
environment we don't know many things in
fact we in many cases we don't know what
we don't know yet so that's why this
path towards creating high value towards
creating valuable products and solutions
to the customers should be some kind of
way how we navigate around
assumptions our biggest question is what
works best for the
user and and to find the answer with
with the knowledge gained in that course
we will Embrace that in fact full
endtoend
empirical cycle uh requires
Discovery delivery and validation so
those three
elements work together to help us
navigate around those
assumptions so our new
course is designed for product leaders
product owners product managers but also
for product teams in
general we believe that everyone
involved in the product development
process will benefit from from this
class so this class is designed to be
one day course so around 8 hours which
can be also split into two half days or
smaller smaller chunks in this class we
will use case study that will help us
navigate through different concepts
through this whole story how to better
incorporate Discovery and validation
into product uh development
process thanks to that we will get
familiar with working with assumptions
experimentation collecting evidence and
important word for this class learning
so it will be a conscious learning how
to build better and better products