so negotiation really important so as a
product owner Apprentice there's a great
book the title is never split the
difference I never split the difference
is about negotiation it's written by the
FBI's head hostage negotiator for the
last 20 years and he talks about it as
whether you're negotiating bedtime for
your kids or negotiating hostage release
is the same tools and techniques that
you use
um he has a a master class on
masterclass.com um and what you need to
consider as a product owner and if
you're helping out an apprentice product
owner they need to understand the
ramifications of the decisions that
they're making and how to engage in
communication that gets them to an
effective result