so the new immersive learning program
for that we apply to pretty much
everything we do now is uh designed
around this idea of um not not just
imparting knowledge right not just uh uh
going through some
content but it's an immersive format
where we have
um the content delivered over a much
longer period of time so we have a
structured program over a much longer
period of time and it includes some
learning right we want to learn some new
things some new tools some new
techniques some new philosophies some
new ideas um but at the end of each of
those learning learning
sessions even though we've done some
exercises perhaps practical exercises
demonstrating how it might work within
the context of of the learning right um
we use we use liberating structures to
help uh um create smaller groups and
have people figure out how to use the
knowledge but it's still within the
context of a of of
of still within the context of that
group of people right it's not out in
your real organization it's not out with
your real product and your real teams
and your real customers so at the end of
each kind of learning learning session
where we learn something new um we have
a we have an assignment and That is an
outcome based assignment the idea is
that for each assignment we're trying to
achieve something so for example um I
just had the third session of the
product management um Mentor program for
uh a a company in in Sri Lanka and their
product managers we we talked about
value with the product managers um The
Learning the piece the new information I
was providing for them was here's how
you can think about value here's how you
can understand value here's how you can
potentially measure value so we talked
about evidence based management we well
we talked about the value pyramid then
we talked about evidence based
management um and we talked about other
metrics and uh stories around that and
even people kind of because we were
talking about metrics they started to
bring up other questions around you know
answering that a old question when will
it be done so we talked a little bit
about just a little bit about
probabilistic forecasting um and flow
metrics as well right so they drove the
learning content as well as me having a
plan for for what I would like them to
understand and then the outcome based
assignment the assignment that they've
got
is to go
apply that to their organization like
what what
metrics go out into your organization
and figure out what metrics do you
currently use in your
organization how what do you collect how
do you use them and how does it impact
on decision making right that's that's
their that's that's the the kind of core
part of their assignment is to go
understand what it is company has and
what the company's doing but
then in addition to that perhaps they
should start a conversation about do we
have the right metrics is is is there a
simpler way to collect the thing we're
trying to achieve can we optimize this
and start having those
conversations so the
outcome from that that I'm trying to
achieve is that they as a group so this
was this was about six 16 product
managers for one company they as a group
either in small groups go off and have
those conversations as individuals have
those conversations or they can do it
all together I I I leave it up to them
but when they come back and we're doing
our facilitated Reflections we're going
the idea that I'm trying to achieve is
that
they they understand more about what it
is that their product does and and how
does it work and what they're trying to
achieve with it because they've looked
at how they're measuring their success
they've looked at how they're measuring
their capability to deliver the product
um and then
they're thinking about whether those are
the right things they should be looking
at right because a lot of the time in
organizations we're looking at the wrong
things we're looking at the wrong data
we perhaps have vanity metrics uh
metrics that look great uh you know like
velocity or story points but don't
actually add any value to the
conversation you know we've managed to
get our our original estimate and our
actuals within you know 10% of each
other we're awesome yeah but what value
does that PR provide to the organization
does it actually provide any greater
degree of predictability does it
actually help the organization
understand when things will be done um
and the answer is no but trying to
trying to figure out uh
and have those conversations so they're
starting to have those conversations
within the organization not just within
themselves but with other people within
the organization so they're starting
that conversation generally in the
organization and then when we come back
for the next session which is usually a
week later a week or two weeks later
depending on the the what it is we're
doing when we come back for that
reflective uh
session they're
explaining what what it is they did what
they managed to learn um what they
discovered in their organization as they
were doing those things
and really sharing with not just with
each
other
but I can help provide them with
potential directions that they could
take if things weren't working for them
or if things were working well what
might be possible next steps that they
could try
and hopefully over time they're able to
figure out a lot of those things
themselves right when you start from a
position of not necessarily
understanding something not doing it not
knowing that you have to do it and not
knowing what you're trying to achieve
with it you need that kind of
facilitated reflection to start thinking
about what value it brings as you start
understanding the value that the the
outcome that we're trying to to achieve
and the value it provides to you and
your business you start getting more
engaged with that topic you start poking
at it and pulling it threads and trying
to figure that out so this idea of um
immersive immersive learning right
immersive uh the immersive program so we
we apply it both to our training classes
and to our uh mentorship programs that
you have this
[Music]
um these these
outcomes which will hopefully enable
changes within your organization so
there's no there's no guarantees for
anything right absolutely no guarantees
for anything your organization could
completely ignore everything you're
trying to do but I find that this type
of
Engagement has the best chance of impact
because the par ipants are able to go
start that conversation and then come
back and we can all share ideas on why
did that not work why did people ignore
you why did they dismiss what it was
that you said I I've had product
managers come back and they've been told
stay in your lane right this this is
this is above your pay grade you know
this is you need to stay out of this
when in fact it's something that
somebody who is a product manager should
be heavily involved in and heavily
engaged in where do the requirements
come from right
so each of those assignments is designed
to be a catalyst for change within the
organization through conversation and
discussion within that
organization and what we want to be able
to do is enable the teams and people
within the organization to be able to
become more effective right by having
those conversations discussing those
things hopefully we'll even make small
changes or at least plant the seeds for
changes and then start them growing over
multiple sessions right because we come
back around on on similar topics to
reinforce them um and that should enable
teams and people within the organization
to become more effective and be able to
focus more effectively on the goals that
they're trying to achieve and hopefully
have better outcomes for for their team
for the people for the organization and
for the business