another key question to ask leadership
about their way of working is if their
teams are empowered to change their
processes based on what they
learn this is this is one of those
critical things that in order for a
group of people to work as effectively
as possible that doesn't mean they work
like another team working on the same
product or another team working on on a
different product it means that every
team although we're going to perhaps
follow some general guidelines about how
we want to uh do business with our
customer um perhaps that represents the
Cadence of delivery to our customer we
need teams to be empowered to change
their process based on what they learn
because just because you've decided that
something um needs to be a certain way
does doesn't mean that that adds value
to this team it might actually be waste
for team a while it is value for Team B
and we need to recognize that we want to
maximize the amount of value that teams
are able to create which means we need
to minimize any uh uh waste a great
great example of that is I used to work
with um work for an organization I was
Employee of Merl Lynch back in the day
and because they had had a a trading
desk software within the body of their
organization there were certain
processes that had to be in place for
all software in the
organization even if it had nothing to
do with this trading desk bit so the
trading desk defined those processes and
everybody had to follow them so I I was
building a small CRM system uh for a
group of about 20
um sales folks who were making calls uh
uh calling people up selling the
mortgages and what they wanted was a way
to uh you know tapy interface pop the
call I'm running it on my my desktop or
my laptop and I'm able to click see the
phone numbers call them up see notes
that kind that just a simple uh uh CRM
system and in order to deliver that I
had a whole bunch of constraints that I
had to work within one was that um I had
to have the architecture signed off
before I started and any changes to the
architecture need to be signed off as
well so if you think about as you're
building the product you can't go oh
actually that architecture I thought I
was going to use is wrong I need to do
something different it all has to go
through an architectural Change review
board right Central Central environment
and it was very time consuming so they
didn't get back to you within a few days
uh they got back to you within a few
weeks or a few months because they maybe
only sat once over a over a period or
they had a backlog of work right so
that's that's one thing for a small
system that doesn't have a lot of
consequence or any consequence for the
rest of the business and only affects a
small number of people that's a little
bit of Overkill right um I also had to
have all of the systems that I used even
though they weren't publicly facing uh
pent tested so we had to pay an external
company about
$20,000 per pentest to pentest our
system even though it was internal and
the data was of no consequence it's not
the trading desk system it's a
small data set for a small group of
people yes it has some PPI um but from a
risk value Factor we probably could have
done a lot less security Overture and
still provide Ed on the the the
compliance for the PPI external PPI
compliance site so that was a bunch of
waste uh that we couldn't change um and
what was the other there's two more we
had
um uh when I when I had to deploy to an
environment uh I had to have three
servers front end middle tier back end
so the database uh running on one server
um I had to to have a separate server
for um the the the middle tier the the
API so it had to have apis uh that were
available and then the front end had to
run on a separate machine and so you had
to have those three servers part of that
mix so you had to pay for them so it was
actually worked out about $33,000 per
month for those three um and then you
had to have a Dev environment a test
environment a uat environment and a
production
environment so that was $3,000 per
environment and I had to have four
environments for a little system that
was just used by 20 people in a call
center total Overkill total waste for
what it was we're created those were
processes that were imposed on us from
the rest of the business even worse we
were doing continuous delivery and in
the organization if you didn't uh submit
a change request for a deployment of
your product
uh more than I think it was 6 weeks in
advance it was considered an emergency
and you got a black mark against your
name and we were doing daily continuous
deliveries on a number of different
products uh that we were creating so we
got a lot of black marks in fact we got
the most black marks of any Department I
think the combined black marks of every
other department in the whole
organization because we were doing
continuous delivery because we were
starting to use modern engineering
practices we were punished
within the organization because that's
not the way we do things here so are
your teams empowered to change their
processes based on what they learn so
they can make everybody's lives better
and maximize the value that you deliver
to your
customers if your answer to any one of
these questions or the answer of your
business to any one of these questions
is no we're not doing that then you
would probably I probably wouldn't
consider that you're already in the
agile space right you're not already
agile you might be working towards it
and you might have put in loads of
effort but unless you can Mark every
single one of these six questions as yes
we do this this is how things work here
then we're still lacking we're still
trying we're still working towards
being agile now this is just a litmus
test dreamed up uh by uh the US
Department of Defense but they are
probably the least likely place for you
to expect something um with this High a
bar to have come from and I'm not going
to um go into a team uh and work with a
team or a company and if they're not
doing these things then I'm going to say
well you guys suck you're not agile
because you're not doing this that's
that's not how we work towards success
uh but I think it's hugely valuable from
the perspective of
self-reflection for you all to think
about the processes and practices in
your organization and are you a how many
of these six questions are you able to
achieve and what could you do to make it
a little bit easier for the teams for
the people doing the work to work work
towards this idea of not being agile BS