so what would you learn on the
professional scrum Master
Class yeah that's a great class as well
um so it it there's a lot of theory in
that class um so the the actual material
for the class is very Theory based
whereas the the the aps ditches some of
the theory in order to have the
Practical experience uh the PSM f
focuses very much on the theory and
being a scrum master so there's lots of
um lots of exercises where you have
these people who are W to be perspective
or currently are scrum Masters in
organizations um discussing and figuring
out uh how things how things work and go
together um and how they can interact
with teams better so ultimately I think
what what you learn is what are the
ramifications of the scrum Master role
right um so a lot of people have a
vision of the scrum Master role that it
is the scrum Master accountability um
that it is just focused on a team right
um and there's there's reasons why
people kind of have that blinkered focus
on the team uh but really there's three
there's three parts to the scrum Master
role there's the scrum Master service to
the team
the scrum Master's service to the
product owner product management right
and the scrum Master service to the
organization and they need to be able to
focus at all of those levels in order to
be effective cuz all of those things
affect the ability of the team to
deliver value and deliver usable working
product right there's no point in the
focusing just on the team and the team
being awesome and fantastic at
delivering they're doing continuous
delivery but they're delivering nothing
that's useful to the customers so the
scrum Master well not directly
accountable for the value or directly
accountable for the quality is directly
accountable
for them being
effective at what it is that they're
doing and that's what we try and get
across in uh the PSM um along with
foundations in empiricism and the
ultimate
value of usable working increments of
work on a regular Cadence CU if you
don't have a usable working increment
then you're not able to get feedback
you're not able to mitigate risk right
those are those are things that are so
important in that story so the PSM is
really the hitting on um from a theory
perspective all of the the the the basic
capabilities of what is the scrum Master
what they're supposed to be able to do
on a day-to-day basis um how they're
supposed to interact with the
organization opening up the scope of
their work um and figuring that out but
I think there's there's there's really
more to it than that
because each
trainer brings their knowledge of
working with
organizations of helping people who are
scrum Masters deal with their problems
in
organizations so there's a piece of the
course which is the cours Weare and the
theory um and then there's also another
piece of the course which is the the the
trainers experience right the all of our
trainers are not just trainers they are
also people who are coaches Consultants
um in in in devops in um in agile in
whatever it is that that they've been
doing for years and they're able to
bring that those experienced stories and
I actually feel like there's a third
layer there's a third layer in there
that is the The Meta conversation about
how the trainer is running the
class and those are skills that the
scrum Masters can also take on board to
help them run the events that they
they're doing in scrum right so how do
you how do you run a daily standup
effectively how do you um have people
organized together when you've got a
larger group of people turn up what
happens if you get 70 people at the a
Sprint view right um how do you make
sure that you get information from all
of them and and all of our our trainers
are they they use it in different levels
based on their taste right so
everybody's different um but we have
folks that that that use and talk about
trading from the back of the room um
lots of liberating structures right in
able to engage people and while we're
not explicitly teaching those
things we're using those things to
facilitate and run the class what which
enables the more advanced scrum Masters
in the room right who maybe aren't the
the the the one ofes or the maybe going
to get the jobs but the actual doing it
just now to have a a a an extra level of
Engagement understanding and learning
that they can take from the class as
well