the way we measure
people informs the way they
behave so when whenever you're working
within an
organization and you find somebody's
working against you or somebody's not um
being as involved as they you think they
should be involved and you're wondering
why there's probably some organizational
measure or metric something being levied
against them um leved or on them that
that enables that behavior that enables
ensures
encourages that that behavior in in that
person so the best way to figure
out why somebody is doing something in a
particular way that maybe you feel has a
negative impact on the way your things
need to happen is to figure out how how
they're measured