we need to change the way we focus and
what we focus on within the context of
these organizational strategies business
strategies technical strategies that we
need um to be able to adapt to complex
work right did you see how much I try to
avoid the word agile there don't think
about it as agile think about it as
increasing our capability maximizing our
value and maximizing our Effectiveness
to to to deliver that the name the
moniker is irrelevant cuz what we've
ended up with by a focus on the
mechanical elements is We've Ended up
with back backlog Barons and scrum
stumblers um that's product owners and
scrum Masters that have no uh capability
uh to do what they're being asked to do
and they're pushed into positions of uh
uh just not knowing not knowing what
they're doing so what what we you can
what I've got a couple of previous
videos on this topic on the detail of
what went
wrong but a summary is that demand has
outstripped supply of competent people
and businesses have reduced the bar in
order to meet the the the open positions
so we got a bunch of people who don't
know what they're doing um there's not
been a focus on continuous learning and
hiring people for that mentality
especially for the specific positions
like product owner um and and scrum
master um and engineers and Lead
Engineers to be able to to have the body
of people within our organization the
the the the the culture and Outlook
within our organization that that moves
Us in that in that direction so that's
where we are now and we need to look at
where we're going to go next and how
we're going to get there the first thing
we need to do is fix the hiring
practices we need to stop hiring people
who have no competence for the thing um
that we're trying to do it's absolutely
okay to bring
in interns and bring in people at at the
lower levels but we want to be bringing
people in at the lower levels in the
work context right so think of it as
um I'm trying to think how to describe
this uh the way the way I think if we
want good leaders in our organization
who are able to lead products or lead
people right I'm I'm thinking of them as
two separate things because product
management is leading the product um and
I don't know what the name of the other
one is leadership is leading Leading the
People um then
[Music]
we need people who understand the
context that we're working in to be
those to be those people leaders so
where where do they come from well
usually they've done the job right they
they they've done something within the
context I I work with some great scrum
Masters um I by the way this is why I'm
saying this I I'm not talking about
being a software engineer I'm not
talking about writing code I'm not
expecting a scrum Master to be able to
write
codes right I know scrum Masters
well I might roll that back a smidge but
um I know I know scrum Masters who have
never been coders who have perhaps been
a business analyst or perhaps been a
tester right or perhaps been some other
context within within a team and they've
demonstrated they've worked hard
they've brought in and learned the
philosophies around enabling a team to
be effective they've made suggestions
that panned out within the context of
their team their team has noticed that
they quite often make suggestions that
pan out and help them and the team has
promoted them to scrum
Master that's the way I think about how
you become a scrum Master right is you
don't get hired into that position the
team hires you into that the the team uh
enables you to pick up that
accountability however you want to
describe it the team get together and go
uh yeah Bob is really good at this stuff
Bob can you help coach us to do more
stuff to do more capability they've
already gained the respect of the team
by participating in the team
participating in the work that the team
is doing so the team knows they
understand the work and they're making
suggestions on how we do our boards or
different practices or different
engineering things we can bring in to
understand that so uh does somebody
who's a scrum Master need to be able to
code I would say no more than anyone
needs to be able to code which is yes um
I don't know if you've looked at the
international computer driver's license
but um at most of the levels the
coding's pretty basic uh being able to
understand those logical constructs
because then you can participate in
conversations you can participate in
understandings like what architectures
what patterns and practices are valuable
within the context of a particular
product if a product's big focus is
engineering a scrum Master needs to
understand the patterns and practices of
engineering if the focus of the the the
people the doers is
on
accounting right then the scrum Master
needs to understand the patterns and
practices of
accounting so that they can help coach
that group of people towards better
accounting better organization of that
work better planning better all of the
just making things more effective right
so
um that's where we need to get to so
we've got we've got a where we are right
with which is lots of incompetent people
doing the roles and we've got a where we
want to get to which is lots of
competent people doing the roles it's
for me it's fairly logical how we make
that transition is we stop hiring people
that can't do it and start hiring people
that do um primarily try and promote
from within our organization into those
roles um and and improve the overall
capability and lead by example so this
is this is why we want scrum Masters who
are supposed to be lead ERS right so a
scrum Master might be a delivery manager
they might be a defined role in your
organization they might be a delivery
manager they might be a lead developer
who has uh that picks up the
accountability of scrum Master they
could be something else right um but
they're they're they pick up that
accountability and they are somebody who
has those lifelong learning genes I
don't know how better to describe it has
that lifelong learning mindset that
lifelong learning philosophy um that I
want to understand the world better and
they demonstrate that through leadership
so they lead the team and that they are
demonstrating that this is how we want
people in our organization to behave
right every time an organization
promotes somebody who's not capable it
tells every other capable person in the
organization that this organization is
not for
that that's what's been happening
promoting people through lack of
competence um and just not having the
right people in the right place uh
there's a great book
uh
uh the
right ideal team player it's a great
book and it's the ideal team player and
in that book it talks about the types
the behaviors that you want to see in
people that you hire we need to be
hiring the right
people we need to be expanding the
capability of the teams of the parts of
our organization of the product
development effort within our
organization to be able to build better
products that are more effective and add
more value to our customers