I would recommend the pal ebm class
really to anybody who works in a company
who wants to take it in a direction of
success so you could be a manager uh
managing a a team within your
organization you could be managing a
group of teams you could be managing a
whole product or you could
be CEO managing the whole
company um you could be a product owner
you could be um you could be a scrum
Master you could be a leader anywhere in
leadership in the organization the
the the P ebm class is designed to take
the
participants through a a a
story that enables understanding right
that's that's how how we as humans learn
best is to
experience and tell stories and engage
in some kind of activities um and the
PBM class is designed to take us through
those ideas about effectively why why
aren't our existing metrics uh that we
collect being successful right um what
is it about them that's being
unsuccessful so not just this one's bad
and this one's good right but what is
the underlying reason the people reason
why a lot of those metcs are
unsuccessful connecting those dots and
enabling the people in the group to
really understand the impact of having
good metrics almost almost every
participant I've had that goes through
the pal ebm has had Epiphany like
realizations about what they're not
doing in their organization that they
really should be doing right that they
really should be looking at these
metrics they really should be um um
iteratively looking at them over time
seeing the trend and Direction and using
metrics to shape the direction of the
organization while watching out for
negative behaviors caused in people by
monitoring those metrics right there's
lots of great examples out there of of
of of poor metrics we tell a lot of
those stories in the class right in the
PBM class the trainer tells a lot of the
the the stories of organizations out
there um a lot of that information is
publicly available as well that you can
find the the the those metrics that
we've always used right and the negative
impact that they've had on organizations
over the longer term that's not really
obvious in the short term but you do you
do something over five or 10 years in
your organization um and it it can be
absolutely detrimental to the way the
way that you do business uh one of the
stories that I always tell um for
leaders is is is is Microsoft Microsoft
used to have uh used to do stack ranking
if you Google stack ranking uh you'll
find a whole bunch of other
organizations that have also never been
successful using it in fact been wholly
unsuccessful using it uh but stack
ranking was this idea uh that you you as
a as a manager every manager in the
organization stack ranks every one of
their direct reports and the bottom 10%
is out of the out of the team right uh
and if you're in the bottom 10% three
times in a row you're out the company
and one of the things that we we engage
with is how would something like that we
have a lot of different scenarios but
how would something like that impact on
the behaviors of the people within the
organization right and and it's so
obvious in
hindsight the negative impact of those
types of metrics on behaviors of people
that you want to be be collaborating
together towards a common goal how would
this impact with them it's blatantly
obvious to
us the negative impact of that but then
why was it policy within Microsoft and
Engineering Organization for 10 years
right what why did they not change it
sooner and it took Satia coming along to
to to to to make that change and it's
cuz people cling onto their beliefs in
spite of the data the data is telling
them it's not going well and they cling
to it and part of uh uh pal ebm is
transparency right we're have an
empirical system for monitoring our data
so we want to be able to really see
what's going on see the real data and
then make decisions based on what's
really going on not the general fiction
that most business decisions are are are
are made on at the moment so that's why
I would recommend the pal ebm I would
heartily recommend it for individual ual
um but I would even more recommend it
for organization leadership teams to go
through together I've done that a number
of times with organizations and one of
the one of the comments that I got from
a from a um a CIO in in the P BM was
these are the conversations that we've
never had time to have right that that
we should have had before now that we've
all had that little little warning Bell
going off thinking we should have these
conversations and we've just not had
them
because we don't have time we don't have
the inclination we don't feel like we
can voice it and the class creates space
for leadership teams to really have
those deep conversations on how are they
going to measure success what does
success even
mean and how are they going to
iteratively strategize towards the
desired outcome if you want to a
discussion about your unique needs or
situation then please book a call or
visit us at naked agility tocom uh we
also have our immersive and traditional
public classes on our website and we'd
love to hear from you