value only happens when you get it in
front of real users everything before
that is an assumption we can try and
validate our assumptions we can try and
weed out uh uh bad assumptions right bad
features things that we don't think oh
yeah we've done it on paper and it
doesn't look like it's going going to
work but the reality is that until you
get something that you think is going to
provide value in front of real users you
don't know whether it's going to provide
value like if you were bu if you were
renovating a house
right are people actually going to buy
it and are they actually going to pay
the price that you think they're going
to pay if you have a keen understanding
of what people are looking for if you
have a keen understanding of the market
um if you have a keen understanding yeah
of who's going to who's going to turn up
and and and potential buyers then you
can tailor the build of your product
towards those potential buyers and make
it more appealing for them rather than
less appealing