and but i mean fundamentally the
definition of done is the work we're
going to do
so and that's very different than what
the the people that asked us for
something
they need the content of what they've
asked for
that's important but how are we going to
create it and so thinking about that is
our definition of done
what is the least amount of work we
could do
in order to to validate the hypothesis
but also produce
the quality of the work that's necessary
to be usable
in a sustainable way for that end user
customer
my name is mark naumann and i work at
smn consulting
and um my background is electrical
engineering and software development and
i've been working with folks to adopt
scrum and agile practices and get better
at it for
gosh about almost 20 years and
focused in as a professional scrum
trainer here for the past
uh about eight years or so and had a lot
of experience with
data development particularly data
warehouse business intelligence
report writing things like that both
from the perspective of working on teams
doing that work
as well as working with teams as an
agile coach and consultant helping them
figure out how to get better agile
business results
in that particular problem space
well and for people that are familiar
with software it's
it's for the same reason that we want
the the
i'll call it the technical quality of
the work that the team is doing
is developing is appropriate and ready
for the customer to actually use it and
get benefit out of it whatever the
benefit is
so in the case of data
we have to go through a certain number
of technical steps some tasks that we
have to perform
in order to get to that level of
technical quality we're going to be
extracting some data we're going to be
transforming it we're going to be
loading it in we're going to be creating
reports on that data
the reporting data is going to be
formatted in a certain way
when the data changes we have to ensure
that those changes are actually
visible in the report so that the report
can show updates on a regular basis or
trends if it's
visualizing the data as many reports do
and what data we're looking at is a
different question
what what metrics the user wants to get
out of the data
is a different question the way that
they're seeing that data is a different
question those are all what
questions and in scrum those what
questions are answered
on the product backlog but whatever it
is that the
that the end user of our report usually
in the type of data we're talking about
it culminates in some form of a report
it could be an online dashboard
it could be a a pdf file that's
generated periodically
it could just be data ready for
consumption through
an api but whatever that
end result is that we're going to define
that by the product backlog
and we want it to be consumable at a
level of quality
that meets the needs and expectations of
the end user so
we have to make sure that we've
tested it properly we have to make sure
that we've done
whatever cleanup is necessary to the
standards that we've established for
ourselves
that infers that we have standards so
maybe the standards are set by the
organization
that's pretty common in fact if you look
at the scrum guide when it talks about
the definition of done
it says that if the development
organization has a definition of done
then that's the definition we need to
live up to but if there isn't
a definition of done from the
organization then the scrum
team needs to ensure they've defined
what will
constitute done work so if we haven't
done adequate testing
if we haven't validated that it
produces the the type of information
that
is needed at the precision and accuracy
those are concerns that we have
particularly in the data world um
that we're expecting uh for this
particular application type
then it's not done and that means if
it's not done
that we can't deliver it or at least we
should not deliver it at least in a
well-formed
team that's executing scrum correctly we
would not ever deliver done work
we won't present done work uh i'm sorry
undone work is what i meant to say and
at the sprint review we're not going to
review undone work we're only going to
look at done work
and in the words of scrum uh in the
increment
that we develop this particular sprint
only done work is included in that
increment
and it happens sometimes especially
early on in scrum adoption that we
will work during a sprint to try to
produce
done work but we don't get all the way
there we we're not able to complete all
of the tasks
necessary to get to our agreed upon
definition of done
maybe there were some tests we couldn't
perform or maybe
maybe there has to be an approval in our
environment i'm not encouraging that
but sometimes in some environments we
have to get some kind of review or
approval process that has to happen
and if that's part of our definition of
done and we have not done that yet the
work's not done
now that means it can't be in the
increment at least in well
in a mature scrum environment we're not
going to talk about it is done we can
talk about the fact that we worked on
this particular
aspect of the data but we didn't get
there that's fine
we'll be transparent about it of course
and whatever work remains for that
particular valuable piece of work it's
going to go back on the product backlog
and the product owner can validate that
it's still the most important work
or not the most important work anymore
and then in our future sprints we'll
continue that work as appropriate or
either next sprint or later whatever it
is
so that it's really useful to separate
the idea of
what we need to do and why we need to do
it and that's represented on the product
backlog
and um what is the work this team is
going to do
in order to make it usable to our
standards for the end user
and thinking about the end user is
really important that could be an end
customer
it could be a manager in the
organization it could be another system
in the organization that uses the data
that this team provides
in order to do other things for whoever
customers or other stakeholders
so think about that think about the what
versus the ha the that
how we're doing the work itself that's
the definition of done
well typically there's a sequence of
steps that
teams are already familiar with that
work in this space
if it's a data warehouse or business
intelligence or goes by different names
in some areas
um they probably have a way of working
and
even though they're going maybe they're
adopting scrum those tasks that they
used to perform
all need to happen now the thing is
because we're working in these small
increments and we're trying to
produce bits of value and deliver them
early and often so that we can get
feedback
and use empiricism to inspect and adapt
our progress
toward the you know the big goals we
have for this particular
product um
we probably have to apply those tasks in
a bit of a different way
and uh we the etl acronym still works
you know extract
transform load now in business
intelligence there's additional things
we have to do in terms of
report creation all of the steps that we
did
in identifying the data sources
connecting to those data sources
extracting data elements from those
sources
evaluating the quality of that data
and then performing transformation steps
by
joining data sources together
manipulating the data through
whatever means could be through you know
elaborate formula
it could be very simple transformations
of just lookups
and then of course loading it into a new
data which requires that there be a data
model that can contain the data
and that data model has to have all the
right elements
configured in a way that we can read
them out and use them
in whatever the reporting mechanism
mechanism is again a dashboard
uh static report that's periodically
generated or
a live data feed through an api so all
the steps are going to have to happen
but they're going to happen
in a different way and this uh
to think about what's different about it
we have to link back to
what will make this work acceptable so
now we get into this question that we've
kind of touched on of acceptance
criteria which occurs in the product
backlog
and the definition of done which is the
quality of the work that the developers
on a scrum team are producing in our
increment
of course the increments accumulate from
sprint to sprint to sprint in order to
achieve our product goals
so the key difference from the way data
teams used to work
in a traditional environment or let's
say a waterfall environment very
project-centric environment
let's think about that for a second what
are we trying to achieve
let's keep it really simple we need to
produce a particular report
for a particular business purpose
there's a particular audience that we
would focus on
we'd understand what that business
purpose is why they want the data what
they're going to do with that data how
they're going to use that data
and then we would find the sources of
the information and of course it can be
distributed very broadly across multiple
systems usually it is in this
environment
we have to find the data first of all
and there would be we'd find all of the
data
and we would design uh all of the
interfaces to all the different data
sources
some of them may already exist some of
them may be brand new but we do all that
design
up front and we would then implement all
that
extraction of the data and of course we
will have analyzed the existing data to
look for data cleanliness
issues data error problems uh
redundant data and all the issues that
the audience is probably familiar with
we do all of that analysis and we do all
the corrections as part of our
transformation
and as also as part of the
transformation we combine the data
services together and manipulate them in
the way
that we'll have the actual data needed
for the ultimate report
we then that we do all the
transformation then we load all that
data into
our data repository
or get usually a data warehouse uh
depending on the technology you're using
and uh we would load all of all the data
into the data
warehouse and then we would start
working on the
the whole report and would create all
the different elements in our report
if it's a dashboard or a
hard copy output of course there'll be
formatting involved there'll be
visualization involved in one form or
another and we'd
produce the entire report and then
deliver the end result
okay the problem is that that process
takes months or longer
and maybe years and typically by the
time we actually deliver that report to
the end user
who requested it many months ago
we discover all the errors we made in
interpreting what they asked
for first problem more importantly what
typically happens is they don't need
that report anymore because it took too
long and now they're off and they have a
different need
which is why we need to go to something
much more responsive so in a more
responsive environment
we need to be able to get a little bit
of data directly to the user as quickly
as possible
that'll help validate that they have the
data they need to avoid the kind of
errors and interpretation
that we're still going to make we just
want to find them really fast
but more importantly we may discover
that what they ask for isn't what they
really need and we can change what we're
doing
as we continue to deliver in this
continuous fashion
but that means that the what we need to
do is going to look different than what
we're used to
from traditional development so we're
not
going to design all of the extraction up
front and identify all the data and then
do all the transformation that
you know that sort of relay race
waterfall
approach instead we're going to look at
the individual
information that the end user needs for
specific purposes
so maybe they need to understand the
current
uh customer ordering of a particular
product
and so we need that means for that
particular information of the
ordering trend of a given product we'll
need to find information on the product
uh itself the name of the product maybe
it's
product sku number uh we may need to
find information
on customer orders for that particular
skew number maybe there's a variety of
sku numbers
for a given product because it's a
product family we have to understand all
that
well instead of trying to collect all of
that data for this one little element of
the report maybe we're just going to
find
uh the product sku number that we're
looking for
and be able to load that data transform
it in a way that's usable in the end
report
and say here is one product okay i don't
have the order information yet
yep that's true we don't have that yet
uh but
is this the product that you're looking
for is this in a format that's usable
for you
yeah it's good so far i just need more
of it or they might say
well it's the product i'm looking for
but it's not in a format that i can
understand i can't use it that way
i don't need a sku number that doesn't
tell me anything i need to actually have
the product
name with its description because of
what i'm doing with this data oh okay
well that's important to know
so we don't even need to show you the
sku number we but we need to make sure
we've
collected the data associated with that
oh we're going to make a correction now
we're going to change what we're doing
based on feedback from the end user but
we need to get that feedback
uh certainly in you know certainly less
than many months that it took us to get
the whole report
in fact i'd like to be able to get
feedback like that in a matter of days
or maybe even hours if that were
possible
based on our ability now the question is
what do we have to do along the way to
collect that little bit of product data
to extract it from its source to
transform it into some useful
uh information and uh
load it so that we can then create that
bit of a maybe it was a table that has
this it has only one row in it
which says right now it says the
product's you number
that how we're going to work but what
we're going to do
is our definition of done this is what
we expect of
our cells in the scrum team the develop
what the developers are going to do
they're going to do some analysis of the
source data
they're going to create technology
which is often a you know software code
that will connect to that data source
they're going to build an extraction for
this one bit of data
they're going to uh and when they do
that they're going to test it by
finding different sources of data to
make sure the data is transmitted
accurately
so there's now we've done a an analysis
a design
an implementation of the code and
testing of that code
and that's only for this first stage or
first couple of stages of extracting and
maybe transformation
then there's the same thing of
connecting it to our data warehouse
we've got to make sure it it's loaded
correctly we're going to test that
by looking at various aspects of data
all along the way
we may need to collect information about
what we've done
because we know this is just one piece
of the whole puzzle and we're going to
modify it in the future
now a lot of people first hear what i'm
saying and say oh my god this will be
terrible well
we'll have lots of rework and
fundamentally rework is the wrong way of
thinking of it
in the agile world we're simply
enhancing what we already have so
everything we're going to do is an
enhancement
there could be rework if we make an
error
particularly an error we don't find
let's say that we
do some of the steps in our definition
of done of analysis and design and
implementation
but we forget or maybe there's a lot of
schedule pressure from outside and we
we skip the testing of that it'll work
it's so simple
we've done it so many times we don't
have to bother testing that
the problem is inevitably when you skip
steps like that which you might know is
creating technical debt
we're going to discover the errors we
didn't discover when we created them
some point later that's going to be
reworked when we have to go back and
correct something that we could have
found right
when we did it the error that we made
when we made it
corrected it right away and carried
forward with good
uh a good product so that good product
is the definition of done that we're
looking for
the thing that will make it acceptable
is the particular information in the
right format
giving the right the
the right level of accuracy
precision and visibility
of the data itself so that the end
business user can make the kind of
decisions they need to make
in this data reporting business
intelligent
business intelligence realm so that's
the acceptance criteria that's going to
be on the product backlog the steps
we're going to do to create that value
is the definition of done and um
i think that that's an important aspect
that we ought to be thinking about so
what what do you see on the definition
of done
you're going to see those analysis tasks
whatever they are for you you're going
to see design tasks
whatever those are for you that'll
include data modeling
it'll include uh code implementation
what interfaces do we need what objects
do we need in our source code
uh what methods are going to exist in
order to
do transformation for example that's
design activity as well
we're going to implement that through
code implementation
through creation of data models
through the implementation of data
interfaces
various signatures maybe you're passing
data with json or something like that
all of that has to be
implemented and then we've got to test
every step of the way those are really
common ones that we would see
in the code world that's pretty clear in
the reporting space
it's the same problem but it looks a
little bit different
uh because let's let's take a pdf report
we're going to have we're still going to
do analysis which is to say
what is this report going to look like
and how are we going to implement
it that's design then we have to
actually create the data
the report we have to have a report that
we can look at and evaluate the testing
to validate that it's actually doing
what we thought it was going to do
and then as we get even more mature in
scrum all of this has been
what we would call a hypothesis this is
what we believe the end user
is looking for that's going to create
the value that we need and now we want
to
validate that hypothesis and this should
still be part of the work that the scrum
team is doing
and the only way really to validate this
hypothesis to get the end user engaged
so in the case of this hard copy pdf
report let's give it to the user let's
talk to them about it let's get their
feedback and say is this what you need
will this solve your problem will this
allow you to make the decisions you need
to make
yes or no or what do we need to do to
make it better
that provides new information on our
product backlog so that we can really
deliver what they need
so again another way to say this is the
task that a developer would do
in their day-to-day work is the type of
things that we would see on the
definition of done
the things that the user needs that's in
the product backlog
and that'll help us understand what will
make this acceptable or
as we say acceptance criteria
well that brings up a good point because
in the data world there's often
well it's not it's it's true virtually
for everything but there could be a lot
of regulatory concerns
um depending on what the data is and how
we're using it what it's used for
there may be additional things we need
to do in our definition of done to
ensure compliance to
regulation or governance issues and that
could be governance
from within the organization or external
governance
again like regulators and any
audits that might occur either by
other independent organizations or by
government entities or whatever it might
be
you know that's an interesting question
because this can show up in either the
acceptance criteria
or the definition of done or both
depending on what you're doing
um if the end client let's imagine that
we're developing
uh we're one company we have a client
organization a different company that
has hired us to create a particular data
report and we're implementing the report
for them
the overall process doesn't change but
they need that report for some specific
business purpose
which includes all of their governance
needs their regulatory compliance needs
things like that all of that customer
needs
uh including the governance and
regulatory compliance needs to show up
in our product backlog as part of the
items on that backlog and the acceptance
criteria of those items
at the same time we have our own needs
because
what we produce is part of the the
quality of our product the brand image
of our organization and the way we
interact with our clients
and we're not willing for example to
give untested code to our clients
to fumble through and find defects let's
imagine we work for an organization like
that
and so our definition of done is got to
ensure that what we give to our clients
is that the that appropriate level of
technical quality to meet the um
overall objectives of our own companies
brand image and commitments to our
clients because there may be even
contractual
commitments around that and then of
course we have our own
governance and regulatory compliance
issues
whether that's reporting to
in the united states we have things like
sarbanes-oxley and other things that
virtually every company has to comply
with
and very often the data we collect is
how we demonstrate compliance
to the regulators of those particular
concerns
then we could have contractual
requirements from our client which is
another form
i mean we wouldn't call that a
regulation maybe but
there's a term or a condition in our
contract with our client that says we're
going to have done something
we may well need to show evidence
of perhaps they could audit us or
perhaps they simply
expect it from us as part of our
delivery to demonstrate that we've
actually done
some work well that would be need to be
part of our definition of done to record
the fact whatever that means
that we've done what's required of us
and
a lot of times the tools we use in our
environment maybe it's azure devops
or any other tools in our development
environment might collect some of that
data
but if it doesn't we still need to
collect it that's still required
for us to fulfill those particular needs
and even if we have to
collect it with a clipboard and a pencil
then that needs to be part of our
definition of done that we've collected
that particular
information that's necessary for the
operation of our organization
so again the your point is really
interesting and important because it
actually could show up as either
acceptance criteria in the product
backlog
or our definition of don and so
having a clear understanding of the
difference between the two is crucial
from that perspective
and even more importantly what is the
ultimate use of all this information and
what are all the different
dimensions of need it's not just the end
user need or the client need
there's also these regulatory needs
there's our own operation there's
perhaps governance from uh interaction
with our customers and clients
so all of those will have to be
considered sounds like uh
coming up with your definition of done
is rather complicated
well it is complicated and that's why if
our organization has been focusing on
how to
develop things in an agile way hopefully
the organization's helping us out
through a development whatever
development means
for us but in our case we're talking
about the data warehouse business
intelligence in a lot of organizations
that's its own
let's call it department or organization
and
ultimately i'd want that organization to
say look there's a minimum definition of
done
for all of the data warehouse report
business intelligence and reporting work
that we do
and here it is now you can go beyond
that meaning more
you can increase the quality level in
any team based on the need of that team
but there's a minimum below which we
won't go
but whether there's an organizational
definition of done or not the scrum team
is responsible
to comply with one and if they're not
given one they need to create their own
and then it's going to change over time
this is an interesting aspect of the
definition of done
sort of sounds obvious when you say it
but you have to be able to do the
definition of done i mean you have to
have the technical skills
the tools the capability to get to done
so let me make up a bit of an example
here let's say that we would like to
make sure we run
a suite of automated regression tests
every time we modify
our data warehouse and our report
and we think that's an awesome way to
ensure the technical quality of our work
if we put that in the definition of done
but we have no
ability to run automated regression
tests in fact we don't even have
automated regression tests
then our work can't be done so
what we what is the work we're going to
need what will it take for us to get to
that awesome capability of automated
regression tests
we need frameworks we need tests we need
et cetera et cetera et cetera we need
continuous integration and deployment
ultimately which of course azure devops
can give us all of that stuff but if we
don't write the automated tests
there won't be any automated testing
which means we would not have done work
ever so in the meantime we have an
aspiration to get
to this automated regression test idea
but we can't do it yet
before we can change the definition of
done we're going to have to go do
the work that's necessary and maybe this
team is doing that work so maybe there's
some
fraction of our capacity we're going to
do to create that while we're still
building the k the the data warehouse
and the reporting and delivering value
in the way we're currently able so we
got to keep delivering value otherwise
we're not valuable and as we gain new
capability
in raising the bar of technical quality
like
the ability to begin doing a few
automated tests
we can start to modify our definition of
done to include
maybe a few key automated tests even
though there might still be many tests
that are not automated it doesn't mean
they're not necessary anymore
it means we'll need to do them in the
way we used to do them until we can
automate those as well if that's part of
our goal so the definition of done will
modify over time as we continue to raise
the bar
on our technical quality and the
delivery to our customers
as well as meeting the overall
objectives of our own organization
automating tests is one key way to get
faster at things because computers are
really good at that type of
work that sort of repetitive
step-by-step things computers should do
that work we shouldn't be doing that
manually
that'll take a lot of our manual effort
away and allow us to focus on other
things that humans are really good at
that analysis part the design part the
implementation part
those creative aspects are what humans
are good at and as we get computers to
do more and more of the manual
stuff that the computers are good at
will get faster at what we're doing
that's usually a goal for the
organization because
i've never encountered a data reporting
group that didn't have too much to do
so finding ways to be able to get faster
would be great
well um i would say that the hardest
part of all this
really isn't you know the events of
scrum or the artifacts
having a product backlog or a sprint
backlog or even in
an increment per se or even having a
definition of done the real hard part is
thinking about this problem in this new
way uh most people try to use all of
their waterfall practices in the scrum
environment and you know fundamentally
you're just not going to get very much
benefit
i'll even be bold enough to see it just
doesn't work
so um learning to think in this new way
is the hard part
so there is a reference work i usually
point to people
in in the in the state of space ken
collier
who uh he may still be i at least was
the chief technology officer
of thoughtworks which is a pretty famous
maybe some would say infamous i don't
know but um the agile software
development organization
and ken collier wrote a book called
agile analytics
so this book breaks down how do you
develop data warehouse and reporting
capability
for your organization whether that's for
clients or within your own company
using agile practices and as he breaks
down how to do it
helps understand what are the
consequences and talk through how it's
different and
overcoming the different objections that
people have because this new way
of working seems to be quote unquote
inefficient
and from the old way of thinking it
probably is
but it's so much more effective in
delivering real value
that it's worth it um also as we grow
the definition of done
just to link this back in and ken's book
and again agile analytics by ken collier
as he talks about the different
practices you needed to adopt
like automated testing and continuous
integration and delivery and all of
those practices
as they apply in the in the data space
will actually get to be very efficient
in addition to being very effective
which is really the ultimate goal for
any group like this
yeah do they really are they going to
use and get them not just even use but
are they really going to achieve
their goals the customers goals are they
achieving their goals
with what we deliver and that'll require
this
new way of working so that we can
validate our hypothesis along the way
but also continue to raise the bar on
how we're developing in such a way that
we can do this very very rapidly
and adapt what we're doing so they get
better benefit maybe even than they
thought of
and um that's the way we're going to
beat our competition whatever that is in
the data world our competitors are often
you know excel spreadsheets and data
dumps that people are
are manually manipulating and unless we
can deliver something better and faster
than that
they're going to continue to use those
approaches and
what value we're delivering will always
be in question so
but that's that's the ultimate goal
we've got to help our customers be
successful that's the only way we can be
successful
well thank you very much mark this has
been awesome thanks for inviting me
appreciate it mark you're welcome thank
you