Azure DevOps isn't isn't just a a a tool
set. It's designed as a platform for
excellence. It's designed as a a
platform engineering capability,
something that you can use within that
context. And the reason I mean Azure
DevOps is is the brainchild is probably
the way you describe that. The visionary
behind Azure DevOps was a gentleman
called Sam Gubenheimr and he'd been
around for for for quite some time in
the ALM application life cycle
management space. Um and she
envisaged this world
where we as
builders of products, software
engineers, uh managers, all the people
involved in build building products were
able to see what's going on
really well. I want to be able to I want
to be able to see if if I've if I if I'm
if I'm in if I'm a manager, product
owner, if I'm um in product management,
and I want to be able to see where my
feature is, what state it's in, not only
are the bits finished, but in what
environments those bits have gotten to,
right? So if you're doing a ring based
deployment model, are they in are they
have they have they are they still in
the canary environments or have they
moved up to the preview environment or
are they in production? How how do I
know how do I get that visibility
without just going and asking people and
and and
I want to be able to see that
information so that I can ask more
interesting questions than where's my
stuff, right? Where's my stuff is not an
interesting question.
So that that his idea was to create a
system like that and Brian Harry in the
good old days um was the product unit
manager. He was the delivery manager for
for that vision. And a lot of those
things that that we we would like Azure
DevOps to do are are are in there.
they're in there and they're usable and
they really bring um capabilities to for
our our our developers that perhaps you
don't even realize are there. Right?
I've been using Azure DevOps um since
7 2007
uh when the preview was launched. So
very long time. And Azure DevOps has a
bunch of capabilities that most people
have no idea are in there. So for
example, you can get full traceability
from the work that you're doing, the
work items that you're working on, all
the way down through
to the lines of code that were changed
to fulfill that
capability. And that can be at the task
level, at the
backlog item level, at the feature
level, or at the epic level. And Azure
DevOps has that hierarchy because it
does this clever thing that as long as
you're well your developers have to do
something. They have to associate the
code that they are working on with the
work item. So they tag it in the
comment. This is what I'm working on or
this closes this item, right? And then
the automated build system inside of
Azure DevOps picks up all of that
awesome uh uh data and then it goes and
writes onto the um work the work items.
They have a hidden field called the
integrated in field. They go right into
those work items. This this the build
number right all the way up the chain.
So then the epic will always have the
latest build number that it has things
in. And then you drill down to the next
level and you've got a set of features
and each of those features have the
latest build number that has stuff from
that feature in it. And then all the way
down and you can see
with that build number you can then look
at your environments
and see well where is this
version? what version is in what
environment.
Now, that would be a pain in the butt if
we had to manually go figure out all
that stuff. So, nicely, you can open up
the environment and you can basically
say what features are in this
environment. what code has been changed
in this environment from the previous
environment or because you've got a
build that's deployed a build ID and
Azure DevOps is able to do those diffing
between any two builds right what's the
difference between these in features in
uh uh source code changes so
think about the value proposition of
that from a business perspective you
might be looking at risk analysis. You
might be looking at, well, we're about
to do a new release of this version.
This is the version we were on before.
What's changed between these two? Here's
all of the tasks, all of the backlog
items, the stories, all of the features,
all of the epics that have been impacted
by these changes. And then for the
technical folks, here's a list of all of
the changes, all of the code changes
that have been made. Audit audit
problems solved, right? all of your
audit problems are solved um um with
that story. And that's just one of the
capabilities inside of Azure DevOps
that's actually they're called the
DevOps features. They're there
specifically to support a DevOps story.
So this integrates the the the Azure
boards for planning with the Azure repos
for source control and Azure pipelines
for automated builds and maintains a
level of traceability. across all of
these these items. Then you bring in
things like the test tools. So hopefully
you're doing automated tests. Automated
tests are already associated with your
build, right? Because you're running
them within the context of your build.
But then you can also bring in manual
tests, right? We we may there's two
there's two types of I'm going to I'm
going to be flippant and say there's two
types of manual tests. There's the old
school manual tests which should really
be automations
um that are are are test scripts, test
cases, right? You have a test case, you
you work through it. There's reasons why
you might definitely have test cases for
sure. I can think of a couple of
scenarios. I might mention one. Um and
then you've got
explor things like exploratory testing
where you're you're looking through the
system and you want to find it. And both
of those are supported by the test tools
in Azure DevOps. Al although one of them
is completely free. You can use the
feedback tool for free. You've probably
not not seen that tool. It's a feedback
tool in it plugs into your browser and
let you you record and create tests.
It's awesome. Um validate tests as well.
So that that test those tests are run
against a specific version of your
product. Right? So now when you create a
bug,
the bug is associated with the version
of the product that you're testing.
You know what codes changed between that
version and a previous version that
didn't have the bug. It's much easier
for the developers to find the bug and
fix it. Once the bug is fixed, the bug
has the build number on it
that tells you which build it's been
fixed in. So you don't have that problem
of the develop the the testers finding
that bug again because
they can see that that bug has been
fixed in a newer build than the one
they're testing right now. So it's it's
been fixed. It's just not fixed in the
version we're using and we can see that
information.
This this reduces
that I I would call it bug pingpong,
right? The developers say it's fixed,
the testers say it's not. it is fixed
but also it's not right. So it reduces
that big bug ping pong. It increases the
levels of traceability. It increases the
levels of transparency between the the
the the people that are working on the
product. Ideally you've just got
everybody working together in one team
but the realities of lots of
organizations are not there yet. We want
to work towards that but we're not
there. So how do we we do that in the
interim? Um, and it has this this really
a really compelling story is the the for
the test tools, a valid story for the
test tools. This is this is my agile
story for the test tools is that you
you're going to find a problem. You're
using the feedback tool on the app um
and you you find a problem, right? So
you provide feedback and that feedback
um is or or a user provides feedback and
then a tester needs to go in and
validate that feedback. So they go in
and create the steps to reproduce in a
test case. Right? So that's a test case
work item type. You test case with a set
of steps. You can automatically generate
that from the feedback tool but test
case in in in steps. And then you run
that test case
collecting whatever data you want around
that
and
create
the bug.
So the bug is associated with a test
case that proves that that bug exists.
So when the developers go to work on
that bug, they can see the test case,
they can see the test steps, they can
run those test steps to validate that
they fixed the bug, right? So you've got
that full life cycle and then when they
close off the bug
that this not bug ping pong, it goes
back to the tester and the tester says
it's still there.
They've run the test case.
the bug is gone. Give that back to the
testers and the testers can then
validate in an environment where the bug
is fixed so they don't false positive
it's still broken.
Those types of traceability features are
really powerful. Those are just
examples, a couple of examples of things
within the tool that allow you if you're
using the tools,
if you're delivering engineering
excellence within the context of the
tools, if you build a story around
platform engineering where you're
talking to the developers and the um
coders and the testers and management
and everybody about the capabilities of
the tools. and building a developer
experience. What is the product
developer experience for for your
engineers within your organization? You
can really pull out and simplify the
story that you have with traceability
um and observability around your
building of the product. Same as you
would within the context of your product
with telemetry coming from your product.
This is telemetry and data and
transparency coming from your
engineering platform. Um, which in this
case we're talking about Azure DevOps.
Um, you can also integrate that with
GitHub as well. So you can have your
code on GitHub and do all these cool
things within the context of of Azure
DevOps integrated with with GitHub. So
if if you want a platform
that you can build across your
organization that that improves your
developers experience and encourages
developers to use those features, you
need to tell them about those features
and explain them and educate and
they'll want to use the platform.
They'll want to use those features.
DevOps.