oh that's a great question so so the
question is what's the difference
between resource efficiency and flow
efficiency
and and first off I I do want to say
that that most organizations and most
teams focus on resource efficiency
um that's where uh you worry more about
your access to materials with people
being considered materials in this case
right people are resources
and we want to optimize the amount of
time that they spend doing the thing as
if they're machines in a factory that
you're paying a rent for right you're
paying maintenance for and you want to
maximize the output of of of of that
machine
um unfortunately in in in our world of
of complexity
um we're not doing the same thing over
and over and over again like a machine
does so we can't optimize with with
patterns in that way I mean there are
patterns we can optimize with but not
not in the same way that we can with
machines
so when you focus on on resource
efficiency
with a group of people you end up with
feature factories you end up with
unhappy people you end up with high
staff turnover right because people
don't really care about your company
they don't really care about what you're
trying to do and they feel like you're
not rewarding them for the expertise and
capabilities they're bringing to your
organization so they'll be like well
I'll go somewhere else that's offering
me more money or I'll go somewhere else
because I don't like you anymore or my
boss sucks or whatever it is
whereas in a flow efficiency environment
you're looking holistically at the flow
of work through the system
rather than optimizing any particular
resource right a great example of that I
think is in organizations that have
sales teams quite often they optimize
sales for leads and more work coming
into the system but you don't actually
have the capability to deliver work
deliver that work in the system so sales
is overselling and then the engineering
teams need to suffer because they have
to try and deliver within the bounds of
of of that world of we're under high
pressure we can't actually
solve the problems that we want to solve
we've just got to get stuff out the door
get it done get it finished
and that doesn't breed
happy people or
um you know it doesn't break the craft
craftsmanship or crafts person ship I
don't know if that's a word but that
that idea that
um I want to be good at what I do I want
there to be value in what I do I want to
understand
uh uh um what it is that I'm trying to
achieve and why it matters right what's
the work I'm doing and how does it
matter to the overall organization so
flow efficiency tries to look at
holistically across
um the the flow of work right are we
optimizing in the right areas are we
able to
um see that when we increase the
um what would you call it
if we if we optimize this reach this one
resource what effect does it actually
have on the rest of the system
right what does effect does it have down
the down the line if we optimize for for
software engineering the developers are
churning out stuff and we've got testers
as a separate entity here are are they
then overburdened and then it looks like
they're the problem and we're all
blaming the testers for not getting
stuff done
so flow efficiency is about looking
holistically across the system
understanding the flow of work through
that system and how do we optimize to
maximize the value that we're delivering
through the system
resource uh uh efficiency is looking at
um how do we deliver more stuff we just
need more stuff
right whether that's
projects finished or it's widgets in a
factory or whatever it is that's that's
a resource efficiency versus flow
efficiency Loop