hey folks
i thought i would just uh give you a
little uh show of this oh i've got on
the wrong monitor so i'm going to be
looking over here sorry
um so if i go to my uh mighty networks
community portal
um this is my mighty networks community
portal and i have a bunch of content and
questions and things that people fill
out and interact with so these are
some students just passed at the psk
this is in a secret area just for those
psk students you can see it's in the
particular training
um but i have content which is this is
just a public
right it's a private network but it's
public for everybody who's in here so i
asked the question should the scrum
master always remove impediments and i'm
getting a bunch of
previous students and other people who
are interested who've joined my
community
answering those questions and
interacting
um i post
a bunch of things reading lists and
content and get interaction and people
asking questions and
all kinds of stuff going on
um
i have a training
and each of these
training entities this is the class
three classes i'm running just now for
our company um so there's three
um
apses and so i've opened this one which
i was teaching today um i've just done
the third day
students come in
this is where they get invited to
initially the other stuff that they can
see if they go there they're
automatically invited to that but they
they get in here which is private to
them
um and then i have before
your training and session one
is open for them normally right at the
start
and i get them to do some introductions
and to
answer some questions there's a question
there how do you feel about your scrum
knowledge at which they fill out and i
want to have you read the scrum guide
right so just just
stuff
and then the warm-up for session one
fundamentals of scrum i get them to read
the agi manifesto uh watch uh the
introduction to conifen i can't remember
whose that is it's one of ours it's one
of the
things
uh read the three pillars of empiricism
right so there's some content around
around that that way i don't have to
just teach it they should already know
it when they come in
and then i ask them to write a statement
about
why transparency is so important for
scrum
so you can see this is students from
this this particular class not everybody
has done it there's like 18 students but
enough have done it getting people
engaged getting people talking about the
process getting people doing stuff
um and then
at the end of day
session one so i do four half-day
sessions
i open out at the fundamentals of scrum
uh um sorry the wrap up for the
fundamentals of scrum so they write
what
changed the way we think how does this
new knowledge of complexity right
because we've just talked about the
fundamentals it changed the way you
think a bunch of people
reply um and then they watch something
watch so this is the
nope i'm on the wrong one there we go um
watch empiricism and is essential
ours
uh read the new new product development
game right and then write something so
they write a short summary of what they
learned and i think one person did this
right that's okay because these are
suggested this is essential and these
are suggested okay
um and then so that's the warm-up for
session two is just read the scrum guide
um and then
they do session two remember session two
is just the scrum framework
um and then i do a wrap-up for that is
what's the big difference between what
we just learned and what you do today uh
so quite a few people have answered that
you know it gets less as the course goes
through just because
of the topics um so they they watch
ethics in scrum
from ravi uh slaying technical debt
uh from
oh i can't remember my brain dies um and
then write what part do the scrum values
play
in scrum and you can see nobody's
answered that one and that's okay
because it was suggested
right they're doing the essential stuff
and not the suggested stuff but they
were really heavily engaged after that
session
verbally and as well as in the in the
class
and then the warm up for deeper
into into scrum read the scrum guide
again obviously and i think i just say
even if you've read it before maybe read
it again and i have the scrum guide in
here so they don't have to go somewhere
else um
surprising truth about what motivates us
so read the watch the dan pink video
uh and uh the
daily crumbs not a status meeting video
because i think those are important at
that point
and then the wrap up for that is
watching uh this video on empathy and
this other one on performance versus
trust both from simon sinek
uh and then for this new session the
um
session four tomorrow i've just opened
out
uh read
uh
changes flipping um which is from uh
nils
level of the complexity guy
um and then in the closing uh which i'll
open out uh
this wrap-up what outstanding questions
do you still have i actually need to
change oh no there we go i've got i need
to change this a little bit but um i
asked them to just go to the root of the
community and ask those outstanding
questions so they're asked with
everybody else in the community so maybe
other people will answer it
uh read the scrum guide write the
scrum open assessment and i just have it
set up like that
um
reference material so i have the guides
already in there right and then i'm
going to put links for the pdf and the
live mural
and so that's where the material is at
the end of the day
they take the psn one assessment so the
full assessment so i've got the
preparing for and some content there i
just copied off the website
and review the scrum master learning
path oh that's before that i asked them
to write the assessment so do the first
uh um
first assessment before you do the scrum
master learning path so they know where
to focus and based on your trainer's
recommendations review the learning path
so i have a uh
should be in that order there we go
uh review with the trainer so i enable
all the students can just book a 30
minute learning review with me um and we
just go over their score any problems
they've got any questions they have they
get 30 minutes it's pretty good
um review the learning path and then you
know collaborate and be part of the part
of the part of the community
so then anytime
they have have to answer questions um
i'm going to get them to to go in here
and some of the questions are going to
oh on the home page there we go
uh some i've just added some questions
on here so for the next
version of this i'm going to ask them to
answer here so it'll be in a more public
space but i do say if they want to
answer it privately they can
but it'd be nice to engage with
everybody else um
yeah that's that's
what i do so i have the the trainings
um which are effectively um
i think they call them courses
with
this stuff course materials an activity
feed
right so there's a question who are you
and why are you here and they're
responding to that there's that question
how do you feel about your scrum
knowledge so this was then before the
class have you read the scrum guide
seven people answered it this is for the
first one
this group's more engaged so if i
actually go
back to the second one which is the
group i'm running just now activity feed
why are you here
well 17 people answered have you read
the scrum guide i got 15 people to read
it i mean 50 people to say they've read
it but they're pretty good this is a
good group and then how do you feel
about your scrub knowledge 17 people
engaging in it so i'm doing i'm doing
better iteratively getting better at
getting them engaged in that process
getting them communicating with each
other communicating with me on here and
in the class and by having them do some
prep warm-ups
right and getting them prepped for each
day and wrap-ups um i'm i'm getting them
to to to think about the content that
they've
we've talked about that we've done in
the class and what's different and that
kind of thing so that's really good
um
oh and i add
the events in here so you can see if i
do it past there's three the three
previous sessions and the current
session and if i edit that we'll see
edit all events there we go
it's just a recurring event
um monday tuesday thursday four days
here's the link to the meeting and then
there's a link to the mural in there as
well and if they want to add it to their
calendar or they can just come in here
and click the meeting link
but what it does do is if i go back to
the home page it's not it's gone now but
it will actually say live
in here and they'll go in and see their
their events that's tomorrow's
class and then i've got a
meetup that i'm going to so i put that
in here i've got a conference that i'm
speaking at so i put that in here and
then that's the class next week um
the the
these again these are private events
where's the private i think it's in here
it's like
well anyway it says aps3 that's the
third eps for that customer so that's
how i manage students um i just get them
in here as soon as possible as soon as
i've got enough students signed up for a
class um that i'm gonna run it
i create it in here i actually have a
few i have to go create and so i've got
my
psu on the 10th of january um all that's
just our reference set uh but there's my
pspo and these are in very oh that's not
a good one actually because this was
very early on when i started using this
tool and i didn't have
very much
content in here but you can see i've got
some
but if i go to the psk which i ran
last week psk and the evm that was the
two i ran so the psk
um
i think i have some some stuff i need to
update it with what i've been doing
recently
um but that's the the the idea
and there's the activity and i had
students engaging and there we go just
get two students have passed they're
saying oh we passed does anybody else
pass the assessment um and i think
that's that's good interaction to have
but everybody gets to see
the the main homepage content
this is actually quite a good tool it's
super easy to to to set up
you just go to mightynetworks.com
create your network and and this is what
you get and i think my
billing
like it's not free for sure it's not
free and you can actually have paid pla
there's all sorts of things you can do
that i don't do right because i'm not i
take payments through my website um it's
not good for timed classes like ours
um but if you had a class that that was
content delivery you could do that in
here
and i think
i don't know where i go see
martin's
pay
what does martin pay where do i see that
click on view profile maybe
no i don't see what martin pays but i
think it's uh uh i think it was
90 a month for
full branded
access that's all the features
um
when you're creating content you can
do live videos
quick posts articles questions and polls
um set up events
and then the idea is that the cohorts
are just groups right that's just groups
um so i have a professional scrum
a cohort
that i add everybody who's been through
a class not many people post in there
but i also have a trainer cabal
where we talk about some trainer stuff
with the cool trainers that i have and i
have some some content and there's a gym
in there um
yeah it's been pretty useful a couple of
customer ones but
that's don't do that
just have
your main community and then your
trainings and then if you need other
stuff do it from there but don't
compartmentalize too much it doesn't
doesn't work that well
well that was just a
hopefully a useful
uh
run through i need to check
a bunch of people are asking what's this
what's the question
ah should the scrum master always remove
impediments and i'm getting people from
uh the class uh going and adding
uh
some answers to those which is good
always good lots of answers
hopefully that was a useful overview so
i will stop this and
send it to you