the product management Mentor program
for software development is really a
program to
allow companies that are building
software products to build better
software products there's a huge gap in
the way organizations approach software
development and software engineering and
and and building those types of products
where when we start
transitioning they realize that the work
is so different and so complex and
different all the time that the kind of
more common ways of managing projects
like you might for building houses or
Building Bridges is just not going to
work um because everything's so much
more complex so they try and shift from
those old ways of working where you have
uh uh Gant charts and plans and
Milestones and deadlines and they try
and move
towards uh agile right what ever people
are calling it locally they move towards
that story
and they don't they take away those
milestones and Gant charts and
traditional project management tools
right that are supporting that story
they take those away and then they don't
replace it with anything and they wonder
why it doesn't work out right things
start to go wrong fairly quickly things
go off track we're not going in the
right direction and it's because they're
missing a piece of that puzzle and it's
a pretty big piece of that puzzle and
it's Vision value and validation that's
what's missing they they don't have what
um if you go look up him in the
dictionary it's a group of people
working together towards a common goal
so if you want people to work together
towards a common goal whether they're an
individual team or they're your whole
company you need to have that common
goal that they can all get behind and
they can all um follow that they all
understand that it's been communicated
effectively and what I see in a lot of
organizations is they'll maybe
communicate at once they'll maybe set
directives and they don't involve the
people that are part of the the story
the people that they want to follow that
goal and the reality is that people
don't follow your goals they follow
their goals so in order for you to
engage with all of the people in the
organization the people in the software
teams building the software the people
in the legal department in in in cyber
security and all of those different
parts and have us all working together
towards that common goal of building and
delivering this product to customers
that's going to maximize the value means
that we all have to be going in the same
direction we all have to understand the
same thing right what is it we're trying
to achieve and that is one of the main
focusing
of the product management Mentor program
we're talking about tools and techniques
we're talking about theories and
principles and practices that help us
understand why those things are needed
and how we get everybody moving in the
same direction how do we as product
managers enable not just to communicate
that Direction with the people within
our organization or outside of our
organization as well to involve those
stakeholders and those customers in the
story but also do we how do we measure
whether we've been successful right how
do we bringing in things like
evidence-based management right looking
at our or our whole product and are we
moving in the right direction are we
looking at the right numbers do we have
the right measures to be able to figure
out what're where we're going looking at
things like hypothesis driven
engineering practices right why are you
adding this feature what would you like
the world to look like after this
feature has been delivered what would
you expect the difference to be how are
we going to measure that building that
whole story Into the way we build
products so that we can maximize the
value that we deliver to the business
for the return for the money that
they've put in