we are going to take a look at how to do
a migration with the Azure devops
migration tools um I'm going to take a
very straightforward simple migration
and walk you through it um we're also
going to take care of any exceptions or
issues and all those little things uh
that come up at least the common ones
that come up so let me switch to my
desktop there we go uh so first first
thing I'm going to do is um
install uh the Azure devops tools we
need to get them first um if we go to
GitHub the tool repo uh you'll find just
down on the right hand side you'll find
a little list of all of the releases and
the latest release will be at the top um
so you can use this release here um
whatever the latest one is is the one
you should be using we only support uh
the latest one we have one going through
the pipeline at the moment uh but if you
open up that
release uh if you're in an environment
where you can't you don't really have
internet access you don't have any of
those things then you can use uh this
version of the file
here and you just download that and you
will be able to unzip it to any location
any folder and then run
the migration from that folder um so you
can you can do that I'm not going to do
that today uh because if you check out
the documentation which if you scroll
down a little bit you will
find a link here to the documentation in
the
documentation it talks about how you uh
install and configure the tools and
there a little getting started link up
here in the top left um and it talks
about the install now we deploy uh to
winget and and
chocolatey so if you are on a Windows
Server uh you need to use chocolatey you
can use chocolatey anywhere in fact uh
that you're running Windows uh but we
also have wi get as well uh for those of
us that are on Windows 10 or Windows 11
um so let's uh put this in the other
mode I'll switch over here there we go
so what I'm going to do
is I'm going to open uh a command
prompt and one thing uh to note is that
you want to use a non-admin command
prompt there's actually a bug in winget
uh that if you use an admin command
prompt it doesn't add the app folder to
the path um you don't have to worry
about what that means but they don't
addit to the path which means that you
get a missing file so I'm just going to
find the package so if you do Wing get
uh search then I'm going to do um Azure
devops um and pull up the list of tools
that are available for aure devops and
I'm just going to
copy that uh uh ID
there and I'm going to do uh Wing get
install that tool and you'll find that
will uh shoot off and go do go do that
it'll take a a minute or so it's going
in downloading the package verifying it
and then unpacking it and setting up uh
uh some stuff but again it is just a
portable uh uh portable setup while
that's running um you can go to uh do I
have the chocolatey Link in here no I
maybe don't have the chocolatey link
anymore cuz we want to use we want to
use the the the new stuff so there we go
starting the install of the package and
it's it's set it up uh so now if I uh
switch to uh
C
imp and do di you'll see that I've got a
config file in there I'm actually just
going to overwrite it and create a new
one um by calling the tools so if I go
CLS right so if I I want to use the
tools I just call devops migration uh
that will initially show you uh because
you've not selected like what do you
want it to do it will say what the
options are and there's in it and
there's execute execute is for executing
a a migration and in it is for creating
config files so if I do in it and then
do help H you'll see it's got some
helpful options there uh for for what
things are available
um but we're just going to call in it
and it will
create there we go it's updated and
created this config file in C temp so if
I just pop that open and go to Temp
there we go I have that configuration
file here I'm going to open it in visual
studio and there we go I'm all set up
with this is the default out of the box
uh configuration file um we've got some
changes to the default configuration
file coming down the pipeline just now
they're not quite here yet so there's a
couple of fixies that I have to make so
if you have an older config file or
you've generated one before uh there's
some fixes that you're going to want to
make uh the first fix is going to be to
remove all of the um field maps here
field maps are great uh for for when you
want to move from one process to another
process uh but they get in the way
especially the default ones do get in
the way uh so we've we've changed that
um so when you create uh although we're
on
uh
2.23 I think if you do
2.2.3 which has already been updated
while the package is being deployed um
then you will uh have these things will
already been removed so you need to
remove that and then down down here uh
there's a skip to final revised work
item type uh that should be false by
default is currently set to True um and
the other one is these node paths
just get in the way so you uh best way
is just to delete them and replace it
with null and then they are gone we
don't have to worry about them those are
the two things that you have to that
that will be the default what you see
here um will be the default in by
tomorrow by tomorrow let's
say all so what we're going to do is
we're going to set up um this for
us so we have a source project and we
have a Target project okay now the
source project uh we're going to use
prompt to connect to it um and we're
going to connect to an Azure devops
instance in uh preview but uh not this
project that one doesn't exist so I'm
just going to
open that and go to migration Source
this is my uh default uh uh migration
source project here and something to
note here is that um you will need both
the URL of the
collection and the URL of the project so
this one here is the project and this
here is the collection so if I take I'm
just going to copy the project because I
already have the collection in there and
you'll see here's the collection and I'm
going to update the project
now for the source you don't actually
have to worry about reflected work item
ID is not required for you to update
this it can be anything uh you like it's
not going to use it on here and you can
leave this as prompt because we're only
going to read from the source we never
write to the source we only read from it
um so I'm just going to use prompt there
because it's just easier just now and
then we need a Target project so what
I'm going to do is I'm going to create a
brand new Target
project um and I'm going to call it uh
migration Target three cuz I have lots
of Ingenuity on what to call things um
so I'm going to use the same process so
the source is also this process and I'm
going to create that project here so
while this goes off and creates the the
project this is going to create an empty
project um it is worth noting there we
go uh so this has no work items work
items nothing here uh recently updated
nothing uh recently created nothing
okay but it does have uh the process
here and if you're looking for the
process I just clicked the project
settings on the bottom left and then uh
once you've got that open uh you will
see the process that's connected to your
project in here and if you click on it
that will go into the definition of the
process so you can take a look even if
you can't edit this you will be able to
read it but you will need to be able to
edit it on the target environment uh for
sure okay uh because every work item
type that's in scope needs a special
field on it so that we can track which
work items we've created and what
they're related to in the source
environment and so for that we actually
add a field H called reflected work item
id if you are migrating work items
restructuring your Azure devops or just
needs some help my team at naked agility
can help you or we can help you find a
consultant or expert who can you can set
up a free consultation using the links
below and don't forget to like And
subscribe so I'm just going to add a new
one just to show you what it would look
like for you so I'm going to create a
new
field ID uh I'm just going to call it
reflected workout let's call it cuz I
think I already created one called two
reflect work item id 3 it's a single
text line it can go anywhere no default
value and it can go anywhere so I'm just
going to stick it in details CU I don't
care okay so there is added it if you go
to edit again and go to options you'll
see what the name of that field is okay
so this is the ref name rather than the
friendly name this is the friendly name
here and then the under the covers name
is the custom uh do reflected work Item
ID 3 if you've added or had already got
a reflected work item ID in your system
like I do would you remove that one
which is this one you can go check in
options what the ref name is and you can
see this was created quite some time ago
and as your devops has changed the way
this works yours will probably say
custom if you're adding it recently um
if you've added a long time ago it will
say the name of the process within which
it was added so that's M NK scrum so I'm
just going to copy that go back in uh
here and now I can update uh the target
element to mkd scrum that reflected work
item id okay uh the other thing that's
worth noting is that in the Target if
you're using uh uh
Azure as your target um you will need to
fill out a personal access token there
are certain capab cap abilities in Ado
um that require us to do some weird
patchy things that require a pat token
um so all you do is on your environment
uh click on the little uh person Cog
with personal access tokens and create a
personal access token you see I created
one earlier so I'm just going to
regenerate that
one and there we go I've got my personal
access boken h now you'll notice I have
it set up as full access you can try
other stuff but we tend to use full
access when uh creating these so now all
I need to do is put in my personal
access token in there and if you want to
only use the pat token and not use
prompt um you can
say access token in the authentication
mode and it will just use the token so
we can set that up here so we're going
to use prompt for the source and access
token for the Target um prompt just pops
uh as your active directory
authentication and that's that's easy
peasy you don't need to worry about
these language Maps if you have uh you
may need to worry about it in the source
if you're migrating from uh let's say a
German uh installation of uh TFS where
it the database is set up as a German
collation then uh you'll need to fill
out whatever the German is for area and
whatever the German is for iteration cuz
that's uh uh how the system uh stores it
and then that will make sure all the
mappings work uh so you just fill out
your language specific uh terminology in
here uh but 90% of the time you're not
going to need to uh you're not going to
need to do that at
all so then everything else is kind of
uh uh not needed for a simple migration
if you're changing the process or you
want to move data from one field to
another um I've done things like I had a
customer who had uh the version number
as Year Dot number I think it was year
do month in uh their Source system and
in the Target system they wanted two
Fields one with year and one with month
so I just added a field map to Reg X
those out into the individual Fields no
problem at all uh the documentation uh
has a list I jump to the
docks the docs have a list on the left
hand side under under V1 under ref V1
you'll find a list of field maps here so
there's the regx field map um and all I
did was set up a source field being my
version Target Field my version year
only pattern match the year out and put
it in the new field right that's that's
pretty pretty straightforward so you
would just copy this um obviously change
it to what you need and put it into the
field map okay so it's just a a list of
field maps and the field maps are run in
the order that they're listed there
right so you can control the order a
little
bit if you have links from your work
items to get repos then um you will need
to have those links fixed so that in the
new system um they will match up it's
worth noting that we only fix the work
item connection to the git repo we don't
fix the git repo connection to the work
item so in your git uh permit text uh
you might have IDs or work items that no
longer exist they're not links it's kind
of invalid it's just text but uh um the
link from the work item to the git
commit will be fixed with the tool so if
you've changed the name of the git repo
um you just create a name list of name
value mappings in here similar to the
language map right uh and have the
original G repo and the target G repo um
under here um at only you only need it
if you've changed the name of your git
repo during the migration if it's the
same name on both sides doesn't matter
you don't have to do anything in there
okay so then uh the main uh body in here
is the processor that's the bit that's
got all the goens for actually doing the
migration and we're actually pretty
close to being able to run a migration
at the moment so we've set up the the
connection and and then in here uh we
have the the the migration the important
bits are what type of processor it is
and then you've got your work item query
bit here that's one of the most
important uh sections here we're going
to run into a few problems when we do
our migration we're going to fix them in
here uh so I can show you what that
looks like so what I'm going to do is
just show you this uh this query so in
this query here you can see it excludes
certain work item types these are work
item types that we do not migrate at
this point using this tool um there are
things you can do with shared steps and
shared parameters uh but that is
definitely more advanced feedback
requests test plans and test Suites
should never be migrated with the work
item migration processor there's a
separate tool um for for for doing that
stuff so in here uh this is this bit at
the front um and Clos date equals
nothing means that it will only migrate
things that aren't closed uh but I can
just delete that and I will just not
migrate those types of work items
everything else will come across that's
basically everything uh this is great if
you have a really big migration if
you've got more than 10,000 Things uh
that come back from your query you're
going to get an error um and what you're
going to have to do is shape your query
so that you bring back chunks of smaller
than 10,000 work items um so you might
do that with date rangy p uh uh you know
let's migrate everything that's that's
uh been changed in the last 90 days
migrate everything that's been changed
between 19 120 days and then keep making
those chunks uh in order to migrate it
across
um and yeah so that's that's it we've
set up our query we've set up our
connection uh we should be good to go so
I'm going to run the migration so I'm
going to switch back to my codes there
we go and what we're going to do is
we're going to do devops
migration
execute uh minus C for the for the
config file and it's c m um and
it's is it Jason I actually can't
remember what is that configuration jent
there we
go so I'm going to run
that there we go so it's loaded the file
and it's done nothing so this is the
first thing that will happen when you
try and run it because you have
forgotten something uh in the config
file you'll notice that it has processor
enabled equals false we need to change
that through for it to do anything uh
this is so that you can actually um you
can set this up so that um you can have
multiple configs in there and then
enable and disable them as needed I tend
to have multiple files um just to make
things less confusing uh but now going
to go back and run it so this
boom okay so now it's you can see oh
it's went quite quickly there and I got
an unhandled exception I maybe messed
something up so I will need to check
that
so it connected
here
[Music]
to the source Grant it then it tried to
connect to the
target with access
token and then I got access
granted and oh look what I did
see there we go what I did was I forgot
to update the project name always
something that Martin does that things
up there we go let's go back to so it's
migration Target 3 was our empty empty
project there it is Market migration
Target three so there we go I forgot to
update
that so clear there we go let's run it
again and see what happens
so connected to the source connected to
the
Target um and then it's doing a node
migration so it's creating the area and
iteration nodes in the Target all of
these little things here um and they
have to match that's we use a a thing um
called rules
overrides can't remember what it's
called by rules bypass we bypass the
rules engine um which means that uh all
of the areas and iterations that are on
the work items must exist so the first
thing we do is we go through if I make
that smaller there we go uh we go
through and this is uh checking and
validating all of the areas and
iterations that are in the source and
checking that they're in and valid in
the Target okay um but what we also do
is after we've loaded the work items and
you see there's 10 work items we
actually go through the full history of
all of the work items and we pull out
all the area and iteration paths and we
check that they all
exist okay we check that they all exist
because in the history there's two
things that might have happened uh you
might have an area or iteration path
that's from a previous project if
somebody has moved a work item from one
project to another only happens in is
your devops but it's possible and the
other issue is that you might have an
area or it ation path that has
subsequently been deleted right so then
it doesn't exist anymore in the source
so when we create the main set it
doesn't exist so what we're what we're
going to have to do is we're going to
have to create a mapping for these the
system will stop and say the missing uh
um missing iteration uh there there's
one that is missing that we need to deal
with actually there's two right cuz what
it's what it's actually done here is
it's created these two um which it
didn't didn't exist before so it's
generated them on the fly but we're
still missing this one called Sky Point
Cloud because it doesn't recognize what
to do with it right it's from a older
older project uh so if I open up work
item
414 in here so if I just go 414 it
should let me just oh I might need to go
to the source
project source
414 there it
is so here's 414 and you can see well
looks like it's got perfectly valid
iterations but if I go in here and all
the way back to the past you'll see that
the team project that it was created in
was skypoint Cloud that is not this
project this is migration source so it's
been moved from one project to another
but that data is still in the history
okay so it's had history and then it's
been changed and moved to this this
project so we need to go deal with that
in the config so the config has been
helpful and just said here's the missing
thing you need to add um so I'm going to
grab that because that's what we need to
create and go into the config so down in
the config under the processor uh you've
got area maps and iteration Maps I'm
going to give you some secret
information as well that you need to
need to add so effectively we have
an iteration map that we need to add for
this text right we want to match this
text and map it to uh to something else
uh so I'm going to give you some Secret
Sauce first is that um in Jason you need
to escape slashes that's why that's
doing that weird underline so if I put
another slash in we've escaped it uh but
because this left hand side is a regular
expression uh we need to add
we need to escape the Escape slashes so
we need another two slashes to escape so
when this goes through uh the Json it
will turn into two slashes uh to go into
the r x and the r x will turn it into
one slash for it matching um I know
Madness but there you go um and what we
want to do is we only you know we might
have an iteration path that has skyo
cloud in it like old project SL
something/ skypoint cloud/ Sprint one
and that would match that so just to
protect ourselves it's better to put a
hat at where you want the start of the
string IE this has to be at the
beginning skyo cloud and then you can
put a dollar at the end to say that is
the end of the string don't match
anything after that so we only match
this exact text and then our uh Target
project is is migration Target three so
what we where we want it to go is
migration Target three we need to escape
that slash and then Sprint Sprint one
maybe I guess it could be uh uh Sprint
one let's check uh so
migration
Target Target
three let's go
project iterations H there's a Sprint
and there's an iteration that's all
messed up but you know that's what there
is uh so we'll put it in Sprint one and
then just to give you a super secret
thing there's a a bug at the moment
where it doesn't
list the root as a problem and you'll uh
if you remember from uh viewing the
history uh you'll note that the area
path was also skypoint Cloud so we
actually need to match just sky High
Point Cloud on its own and map it uh to
migration Target three for the area maps
Okay so you just need to remember uh at
the moment that if you're doing a a
project to project map um sorry a
project rename or change then you need
to move these in
okay uh so now if I go back and run this
migration you'll see it will
skip past um
that there's loading the work items it's
getting a
list it's going to check it
twice there we go now it's migrating
work items so it's iterating through
each of the work items creating them we
iterate through each work item in turn
let me make that smaller so makes looks
nicer uh we work iterate through each
work item in turn so when you're doing
work if work item a links to work Item B
we're going to process work item a first
and we're not going to be able to create
the links you'll see on the first work
item it will actually usually say uh you
know migrating link skip skip skip right
that's absolutely fine because the other
side the target side doesn't exist yet
the target work item has not been
migrated yet but as it goes through um
so you'll see skips and then as we go
further down will start to see creates
right it's going to create them so when
it creates the other side of the link
it's going to link it back together and
if I go down to the bottom it's probably
pretty close to finished it is finished
so we have just migrated all the work
items and uh links uh for those those
work items and we did it fairly quickly
it took 48 seconds there we go so let's
take a look at what we what we created
so when our migration Target
I'm going to look load up work items
um migration Target three I'm pretty
sure that's what I called it so let's
have a
look there we go they are there it was
just a caching issue if I go back can I
uh there go here are the work items uh
that we just created uh you can see
there's the one that was moved from skyo
cloud and in the history all the way
back in the source it now just says
migration uh three right because we did
that we did that core
mapping um so we got all the work items
if I go to the
backlog close that you able to see that
it's uh linking linking things in if I
change this to look at appearance as
well you'll see there's the feature the
backlog item and the task
coming in as well and we did have some
other work items on there right we had
uh ppis we have uh some tasks and stuff
so we're not we're not particularly
worried and there's all the stuff
there so there you go we just
migrated uh our
first set of work items uh so this
operated fairly fairly quickly um it
brought them all across if you want to
run it again uh you can run it again um
and what it will do is it will go checks
everything twice thinking about how we
might resolve that but it checks
everything
twice um so it's going to go through
each of the it's actually not going to
check all of those work items again it's
just going to say that all all work
items were found but what will happen is
at some point somebody will go to the
source okay and they'll go on to the
Board and
they'll drop that item from resolved to
active right because it CU it regressed
so now when we run this we actually want
it to um migrate that extra change but
it will not because at the moment we've
got a a a thing that will remove all
found work items so what you need to do
is go in here filter work items that
already exist in Target
false once you've turned that to false
uh let me do
clear rerun the
migration and what it will do is instead
just going to check it twice again
instead of just not trying to run all
those work items it will run through
each of the work items it will check the
number of revisions and it's found one
work item that has one revision that
needs to be updated and there you go it
is moved that revision across it's going
to check the links as well and make sure
they're all up to date and it skips it
cuz they're already existing um so it's
checking every revision of every work
item that it exists that it's correct uh
um that all the links work so
it will eventually find that work item
there we go run the whole thing um and
if I go back to so that was the source
we go to the Target
go to the board it should have moved
across there you go it's now uh moved
across so we rerun the migration uh well
that's aoop oop there's a there there's
a bug shouldn't do two of those but
that's the different migration run that
uh we can turn that off in the config uh
but there's that additional change that
came across we changed the state um and
then it's adding this text which it
shouldn't do but uh in here uh uh my
migration comment F stay won't do that
again it can be handy if you want to do
it for the first run because in the
actual work item um it creates a link
back to the old work item so you can
quite easily just click it and go oh
what was the old work item again oh it
was this one does it match yes it
matches right um so people can find that
so there you go that was um a pretty
straightforward uh migration
between two Azure devops projects moving
the work items