so the the question was how is waterfall
how is agile product development
different
from waterfall
yeah that's actually quite that
defining the difference between agile
project management and waterfall is
actually quite a difficult task because
most agile teams that I encounter are
really agile under a waterfall if we
take that idea of waterfall and say well
it's it waterfall is just a symptom what
is the actual thing you actually need to
go back to the the Industrial Revolution
and the tayloristic practices that
created that in the first place right a
whole bunch of ways of working of how
business should operate and how we
should manage people was developed
during the Industrial Revolution to
manage a largely uneducated Workforce so
all of those practices were designed
around that idea and then we move into
the the the modern world and most agile
teams still operate in an organization
which uses those practices
so while they can get benefit from the
iterative nature of agile right so we we
take this big thing that we know we're
going to develop and we break it down
into smaller things they are going to
get benefit from that right
um instead of everything happening at
the end and huge amounts of risk we're
getting a little piece at a time
mitigating the risk of the product
because we have usable working product
every every Sprint right so we're
getting that that iterative but we don't
get incremental because we're still
building towards the same
product that they asked for at the
beginning they asked for a thousand
things at the end of it we're going to
deliver a thousand things and we can
either deliver it once at the end or
lots of times in between
um but true agility
comes from that decentralization and
democratization of the way the business
operates so that they take advantage of
their Highly Educated Workforce that
they didn't have before when the old
practices were created so everybody in
your organization is working towards
delivering value for your business
helping your customers
engaging with the market and reacting to
the market rather than it just all
coming from the top with steering and
budgets and control right so so this I I
feel like there's two answers to your
question right two answers to the
question of what's the difference
between waterfall and agile is
in a traditional organizational
structure
agile increases agile reduces the risk
of non-delivery it reduces the risk that
we're going to deliver the wrong thing
but until the organization
adapts the decentralization practices
and does things like let's allow the
team to change whatever requirement is
required to change that didn't make any
sense but allow them to change the
requirements based on what they learn
allow them to change their processes
based on what they learn will never get
that leap into that true exponential
power of agility which is how
delivering not only high quality but
also delivering more of the right stuff
and less of the wrong stuff although
there's a great metric from um uh if
it's the Standish group in in Boston
they're kind of data analytics group
they analyze about 70 000 projects
worldwide and put out our chaos report
every year
um about how agile's doing and one of
the things that they found was that only
only 35 of the features that we build in
products are actually used by our
customers
right and and that is
intrinsically because when we say to the
customer
we we want some stuff
for us to do
we're going to build a product for you
let me start that part again when we say
to the customer we're going to build a
product for you right uh what do you
need the customer goes oh what you know
I don't know what I need okay well
here's what I need now here's 300 things
I need now so they all end up on the
product backlog and and then they say
Well if you know we've got some business
decisions coming up and I actually think
about it like the the Multiverse of
Multiverse of Madness right you remember
Loki in Marvel you've got those all
those branching different decisions that
happen in a business and down every
branch in the decision making in our
business different features are required
sometimes it's the same features
sometimes it's a subtle difference that
we can handle but sometimes it's quite a
big difference so until the business
actually makes that decision in the
future they need the 50 to 50 features
from this route and they need the 50
features from that route until they
actually make that decision and how many
decisions is it good like that is the
business going to make over the next 12
months if we're doing a 12-month
delivery so they put all of those you
know there's another thousand features
that they find all across the business
for all these different branching
decisions and they put that on the
backlog
how many of those do we actually need
when we get to the end
how many of those are actually valuable
when we get to the end how many of the
200 feet or 300 I think I said 300
features they give us at the start are
going to be no longer relevant in a
year's time
how many of those branches did we take
this route and now there's a whole tree
of features down this route that are no
longer valuable that's by only 35 of the
features that we build are are you are
actually used by our customers and
that's an industry average your company
might be way worse right
um and I've worked with those companies
that think that they know their
customers better and think their
customers use all of that but until they
actually add Telemetry to their product
and understand what percentage of their
features in their product customers
actually use they don't realize how bad
the situation is and how much money
they're actually wasting