foreign
so the Sprint review Workshop
um it helps you
get the most out of what is one of the
most important events in scrum this is
this is the event when you engage with
your stakeholders where you find out
whether you're building the right thing
you're on track for me it is very much
uh marketing event I.E your team and
your product
um is being presented to stakeholders
and you want them to provide you with
their opinions and feedback on what it
is you're doing where you're going are
we missing anything that we don't
understand and that can be very
difficult and daunting for for teams and
product owners and product management to
to understand it requires a certain
level of of exposure right of revealing
yourself and how you work and how you do
things to perhaps your customer that can
be quite scary so the purpose of this
Workshop is to both help you understand
what it is what's supposed to happen and
what you're supposed to get out of this
event right that's that's the important
core
um but also here are a bunch of tools
and techniques that you can use that's
kind of the the the learning and core
Workshop part but then we're going to
help
um coach you through your first few uh
Sprint review sessions and then we can
have a debrief afterwards where we
figure out did our tactics work right
the things we tried resonate with our
stakeholders what else could we try
based on the experience that we we we
got and and using
ultimately the tools and techniques that
companies have been using for years to
engage with their customers
for you to engage with your stakeholders
for you to increase the level of
interest and engagement from your
stakeholders in your product so that you
have the best possible knowledge to
build the best possible product next
for watching the video If you enjoyed it
please like follow And subscribe I
always reply to comments and if you want
to have a chat about this or anything
else agile scrum or devops then please
book a coffee with me through naked
agility