in our new class we will learn how to
work with
assumptions so first very important
point we actually introduce assumption
to our product development
dictionary so one of the very important
points we will learn is this moment of
realization oh we we have made
assumptions and not one not two but many
so what kind of assumptions are we
making When developing products when
discussing potential product Futures
when creating product backlog items so
this is a very important aspect but we
are not only talking about this fact
okay the assumptions were made but
which of them need to be
validated obviously not every assumption
require validation some of them are more
important less important there might be
a crucial role in
ordering our assumptions so which should
be validated first and why we are going
to cover cover that in that course
okay so first point assumptions
realization ordering and choosing which
one to start second one when we work
with
assumptions the next important topic is
about
hypothesis so we will learn how to
create
hypothesis and how to test
it so in this class we will pay a lot
lot of attention to using right data
that will help you verify your
hypothesis in fact we may realize that
our product
development is actually navigating
around some kind of tree of different uh
different hypothesis to test we will
also discuss uh the topic of um import
importance of desired signal or evidence
strength on our product development
process so when we test assumptions when
we talk about hypothesis driven
development it's important to realize
that there will be never 100% confidence
but what is your desired level of
confidence and based on that how high
you want to be when it comes to
confidence uh we will be talking about
experiments that will help us test test
the hypothesis so we will learn how to
manage cost related to product
development based on those experiments
that we
choose and this will be aligned with
desired uh um signal strength with
desired confidence
level another um another valuable
outcome for us is learn how to analyze
experiments how to
take what we got out of our
experimentation journey and how to use
this data in decision making proc
process so we already talked that
learning is important in this class so
think about it as a way of targeted
learnings that will help in this
decision making and critical thinking
thanks to that we want to
avoid toxic love related to our ideas
and to what customer customers told us
instead we will be equipped with certain
way of thinking maybe for some of us it
will be a new perspective on product
development and thanks to that
perspective we will be learning a lot
what to do what not to do how to use
those concept to to be effective in know
our product development