so the the question is within the
context of the changing world and
changing changing economic situation
what what needs to happen before
traditional organizations
um can consider agile
they they need to be really so there's
kind of
um two two ways to adopt agile right
there's the there's the wholehearted we
want to change the way we do things to
have happier people uh more productive
teams uh be able to adapt to changing
Market needs as quickly as possible in
which case you're you're you're taking
apart your existing hierarchical command
and control system a decentralizing and
democratizing the workforce to be able
to to respond more quickly to the market
needs that that's a lot of work that's a
huge amount of risk for your business
right because you're changing
fundamentally the way the way that you
do things across the board
um but that that is what agility is all
about and inside of agility there are
the the big topic of agility or the big
topic of devops there are a whole bunch
of tools to try and help you with this
right the the the everybody talks about
the tools as the point but they're not
the point even agile's not the point
it's responding to market right
um but
there's the other type of agile that
lots of large traditional organizations
adopt at least initially
um and that's kind of like gym
membership agile right where where
you're you're you're you know you pay
the membership to the to the gym so you
can tell everybody that you you go to
the gym but you don't actually go to the
gym right
um you're just paying a lot of money for
for for nothing and that's how most big
organizations seem at least
observationally seem to be
um adopting agile and I get it it's hard
and it's scary to change the way we do
things
um but fundamentally if your competitors
are willing to accept that hard scary
thing before you are then they're the
ones that are going to be responding to
market demand when you can't they're the
ones that are going to be uh creating
environments for people to work in that
are much more conducive to the way
people want to work and engage with
their companies today most young people
want to work for companies and they want
to feel like the work that they do
matters that they have purpose in what
they do that they they believe in they
believe in the company that they're
working for and and that's just not the
case for most big traditional
organizations
um so I I I think it's really important
to have that consideration are you as an
organization actually ready to move
towards agility or are you not yet are
you ready to respond quickly to Market
changes or are you not yet right these
These are important important questions
to answer and by all means you know pay
a bit of lip service
dip your toe in the water but realize
that those things do not result in the
thing that you were dipping you're in
your toe in the water to achieve you're
only going to be able to achieve that
with wholesale systemic and radical
change of the way your organization
functions to a more decentralized
decentralized model
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility