you
hello my name is Martin hen chouet I'm
here with Daniel Vacanti who was one of
the original contributors on the Kanban
method in the quarry creator of the
Kanban guide for scrum teams and the
professional scrum with Kanban class how
you doing Daniel I'm doing great thanks
great to see you're marking great to be
here
cool and I had a UH obviously we're all
stuck in our homes for the foreseeable
future at the moment I don't think
there's anywhere now that's just you can
just go run around and I hear you're a
lover of tennis a little a little birdie
called Scott let me know and he was
wondering how you were coping without
tennis not pretty well I think the
harder thing is that there's no stennis
to wash you know there's big postponed
the whole tennis season until at least
June in this and the decision about
Wimbledon was supposed to come out today
I didn't see did that put that could
publish it I have to I have to go check
but but as we were chatting before
there's there's actual I've got some
neighborhoods coherent as long as I'm
allowed out once a day to go it was
exercise and I was I practice proper
social distancing then I'm actually
coping not too bad probably better than
even many people so thanks for asking I
don't know what what about you and Vasco
I mean it's told mr. aney so you
probably own it be inside anymore it's
actually in it's not been too bad it's
been um six or seven degrees so we've
been out sunbathing in the front garden
it's actually it's actually been okay
it's been a bit cloudy the last couple
of days but there's been some sunshine
so we've been running out to sit in the
garden when it's sunny cuz it's nice and
warm in the Sun but then the Sun goes
away in it temperature drops quite
significantly but yeah we're able to go
out for for walks as long as we're
there's not too many people in one place
so it's been pretty good but we've we've
been getting kind of daily notifications
of what's going on I'm sure the same as
yourself although your
briefings are a little bit more
interesting than ours but yeah so um we
you and I will be co-teaching a Kanban
class and we're going to teach our
professional scrum with Kanban as a live
virtual classroom on the 18th of 18th
and 19th of May and Edinburgh and can
you tell us a little bit about the class
you think it'd be ready with the stock
answer for that right but it's it's
really about for those you know those
those people have been practicing scrum
for a while and for whatever reason I
haven't gotten everything that we went
to out of scrum or maybe just want to
take their you know comes from skills to
the next level or whatever it's really
about introducing the concept of flow to
solve some of those problems that you
may or may not seem as Francis you know
things like we're know hey we're we're
terrible at estimating and we can never
first know how much stuff gets done in
this broth no can't ever tell their
products under when something is going
to be done at the end of this prints
there's always a smash - who says we've
taken on too much work or we can never
get it done you know so you know how how
does flow how does management the flow
just help to solve some of those common
problems that you see you know it's in
several scrum teams cool so how does
that and how does that differ from the
Kanban method it differs it doesn't it
doesn't matter for quite a bit in
several respects probably the biggest
biggest things the biggest difference is
the beauty of scrum stolen supplies and
entirety hire T so easy easy pile on a
professional professional scrub
this concept because difficulty take a
look at the professionals come for
example it's less than right inherited
they're able to keep it as fat as we
come you know as a foundation as our
base so if you go depending on which
other combine guide you you look at
necessarily get into that too much but
you know there's there's a there's a
combine you know a condensed combine
guide that is ninety some pages or one
hundred some pages or whatever which
doesn't sound too it's convinced to me
or whatever
old I said sounds like it's very big yes
I think that's that's the big the
biggest difference is we have scrum as
our foundation we embrace everything
that scrum does we're not we're not
changing anything in scrum we're not
throwing anything out we're not doing
any of that you know take your existing
scrum implementation just kind of bolt
on or overlay some of these practices on
top and you're good to go
cool so there's a couple people hearings
a little bit of feedback I've ordered a
set of headphones from upstairs
I hear they might be on their way but
what I'll do is at the moment I'll mute
myself when you're speaking down and
then maybe that will will help where do
we get that mute button for real life
how do i how do I do that
there there is no mute button for me
personally my wife has tried and but it
doesn't work usually a few men's I'm
just throwing the remote control at me
for sure yeah so I'm wondering if any of
the folks that are listening online have
any questions as well let's let me have
a look
I got a different headphones than I was
expecting
that's okay so I guess have you have you
thought about um the the tools that we
want to use while we're teaching this
class no longer is I've been
conversations past that's kind of
Baseball America no we have we tend to
use the same we have the same expression
intricate as well proper sport I don't
yeah anyway we you know we've been
forced to adapt really look really look
like and because it is you know
fortunately or unfortunately science
itself is designed to do you know very
interactive very hands-on best way to
learn about this sterility sleeves and
do it yeah so at a point I mean how do
we how do we bring in some some tools to
leverage the online experience so it's
may be now may not be as good you know
it's it's hard to say but we do have an
online combat simulation that we can do
so there's that but the rest of it who
knows we'll just just kind of see I'm
kind of excited to see how this plays
out interested to get feedback from
people who have taken to escape
virtually that works and what doesn't
work
yeah I've been thinking of doing some
free sessions with folks for different
parts of the exercises and to see if I
can figure out how best to do that I've
been toying around with a couple of
tools obviously zoom for the video
conferencing it seems to be the one that
has the
I prefer teams when I'm doing stuff but
it doesn't have breakout rooms it
doesn't have that kind of interact
ability you could do it but it would be
a pain in the ass so not gonna go there
so zoom for that mural have you played
with mural yet because that seems to be
the to go to kind of whiteboard
collaborative space choice so yeah I'm
sure we'll do some of that we'll see
yeah employment yep so I'm being shouted
at for having a an echo while you're
talking I do have headphones now and
I've plugged them in but it's not
outputting the audio to the headphones
so I'm just switching that over I don't
even know how to do that it's supposed
to just do that when you plug in your
headphones nope I think they just don't
work I will have to mute you while
you're talk what mute myself while
you're talking is what I need to do so
I've been I've been playing with our
tool you know that I'm into board games
a little bit and there's an online tool
called table topia which is uh basically
as a board game simulator so it doesn't
do any of anything clever
apart from have the PCs on the table and
you can has tools for flipping cards and
drawing cards from a deck and rolling
dice and that kind of thing and I was
thinking about I've been chopping up the
v-2 of the get Kanban game to load into
this tool and see if it's usable as a
tool to still use the the get Kanban
game and I haven't seen another online
version of
- that's why your honor
I thought I should this link with you
but but we we have it's not exactly get
Kanban but it is a compound simulation
it's called it's called twig twig stands
for the whip game and there's an online
version of that that we will be using as
as part of a class so in fact I've
actually I don't I don't know if I
should be saying this out loud or not
but I don't use get comp on in my PS
Ches anymore I used this this online
simulation because I think in general I
think it's a little bit better learning
experience for for lots of reasons
so that'll be that'll be something that
we'll get a chance to see probably we'll
send out a link to the game beforehand
so people might might get a chance to
play around with it before the class I'm
not I'm not sure about that we're we're
kind of going back and forth whether
that's a good idea or not I agree I
think it's um having having something a
little bit different might be maybe
better I'd like to hear about the
simulator that you you have maybe I can
integrate that into into what it is that
we're we're doing I I'm just playing
around with table topia because I'm
using it anyway to get my fix from board
games Scott just said get can ban on
fortnight and shoot Carlos I think a lot
of the folks that are on the the chat
have have played get combat before
probably have copies of get Kanban and
although somebody's putting a little
question mark going what were they
talking about you don't know until
you've played the game and it's a
surprise that should not be spoiled for
you and but it's part of that little
little story and actually I really like
to get combined game because of that
that story and people and when they're
playing the game tend to interact very
heavily with it and they understand the
rules a lot more quickly because it's a
gamification and have you seen those are
there's a tool and that's just come up
to a board game from
called scrum tail in Poland that has
just come out and there is em they've
created our board game for for a group
of eight people working together to
instead of building software which
you'll know we do in the PSF which is a
little bit fun because you sometimes
teach classes with people who don't know
software and in this tool that you build
a murder-mystery you build a novel yeah
III got a demo of it at one of the
conferences that I went to and it was it
was really really powerful
so that's scrum tail which I really
enjoyed interacting with and it was good
for that when you've got a big class of
people who don't have any scrum
knowledge and similar to get Kanban it
doesn't it's not really a software
specific thing cool
so yes Darren you got Table Talk er
spelt correctly if you google for it
you'll find lots of stuff around that as
well and so the the class that will be
teaching is um on Monday the 18th of May
um it'll be I think we're we're
currently thinking it's going to be up
to day a two-day class roughly the same
timing as an in-person class and I guess
in subsequent teaches we may change that
but I think for for a one-off it's going
to be like that Daniel it's gonna be a
bit of a difficult time zone for you I
make it work long as we finish we can
certainly finish with whisky you can
drink whisky I'll drink to rum so it
usually runs from 9:00 until 5:00
I don't know what what's 9 a.m. in here
yeah we did although nobody noticed
because we were all in asleep it's
pretty early you maybe need a whiskey to
start when you're doing some of the
exercises I did work on a scrum team in
Sydney Australia from Glasgow with a 12
hour time difference that was not a lot
of fun it was a good demonstration of
how remote work cannot work if you're in
different time zones well I should I had
four people on my team from Beijing as
well accent yeah well I'll think we'll
maybe wrap it up there is there any
other questions that you had Daniel
likes to experiment with or special
experimentation for all so I think
Martin and I are willing to learn as all
of you so yeah please please just just
just drop us a line just you know
whatever ideas you've got do you have to
hear cool yeah yeah we are we're
planning on running the the class we'd
like to get as many people I I don't
know what what what are you thinking the
limit is going to be maybe 12 or 13
people something like that for our first
class
and just figure out how to how to push
around facilitating facilitating that
for us yeah cool
well thanks very much Daniel for for
making the time I know you had to move
something around to get with us at five
o'clock and if anybody has any questions
they can message me or Daniel directly
it's on Twitter
everywhere same as myself and we'll
figure out how to do the best part oh I
would note that for the kanban class and
I do or we do for this class we do a
discount for people that are unemployed
which might be a lot of people at the
moment we also do discounts for people
that are self funding the class as well
so if your company's paying companies
don't get a discount just people real
people get discounts companies do not I
think that's kind of the best way to go
with that very Scottish I agree cool
well thank you very much for for for
joining us and apologies for the audio
West you I'll try and figure it out for
the next one of these that we do okay
thanks everybody for joining thanks for
the invitation my cringe is great chat
no hnt as well Daniel
you