[Music]
yeah i'm you know one of those fake
backgrounds like no although
i'm just checking the checking the
stream
the problem is the delay
so hopefully
it'll do
something in a sec
wow that's a big delay
so what are we on for time here
[Music]
change that awesome
so i guess uh welcome to this which is
the
wow the seventh
of these workshops uh uh that i'm uh
doing
um we are going to be working
in uh mural on commitment in scrum and
we have a very small group today so um
i'm kind of looking forward to
having having basically it saw oh
there's anna hey anna how you doing
second anna and a mark ii
um
the the
the fewer the people that are here the
more of your questions you get answered
right that's how that works
uh so what i'm going to do
first off
is we're going to do a little uh
exercise around connections
um so i'm going to
create
uh i'm actually i'm going to create
three rooms but i'm only going to use
two of them
um but it's just in case because you
know what it's like these days everybody
turns up late
to meetings because they've got to
finish up whatever else they're doing
and they forget and
all of this kind of thing and then
uh
we can figure that out so let's do room
one
room one and then room two and room two
okay so what i'm going to do is i'm
going to uh
pop you into a room just in pairs just
now but if other people arrive it will
kind of slot them into
the right room um and on the mural uh
let me summit
summon to the mural i think everybody's
around here anyway
uh there is uh just some some questions
to get us started thinking about
uh uh i'm gonna take off the mark each
statement true or false because that's
not what we're doing not green and red
ticks uh but just go round the questions
uh um and see
have a little conversation around them
and and introduce yourselves to each
other all right so i'm gonna open the
rooms and i'll set a timer for five
minutes in the mural and and then we'll
we'll come back and that'll give the
rest of folks a little bit of time to
open
uh
yep it should you should have a little
uh there we go couple people leaving
it's working yeah yeah
sometimes sometimes it just it just
doesn't
erica hi how you doing hi fine thank you
yeah no that's okay um we are just doing
uh a little exercise uh
to start making connections with the
topic
um is it okay if i move you into our
into a room with some colleagues to have
a chat
yes
perfect let me find erica i can go into
room one there we go
i just popped you into room one
uh so you should get a little pop-up or
uh uh please wait 10 seconds or
something and then disappear into the
room
rasha how are you doing
hey
um so we're just doing uh some exercise
around uh creating uh connections
uh so would it be okay if i moved you
into a breakout room with a couple of
other folks
cool they can let you know what's what's
going on when you get there let me find
you in my list
russia i'll be in room two
with brandon and dimitrios
i think and then it would be just as i
think somebody connected and then got
disconnected yeah
yeah i saw that
okay
when okay
uh
it's the other person back or are they
completely gone oh there's there there
she is carla there yeah
having somebody
andre you're
back team is
ever or something getting hell so i
i just immediately leave
the team i don't know what i
should there should be three of you in
there there's erica anna and you yes
okay
absolutely but
there was something
in the middle of uh i'm talking with
them it says uh
said leaving cliffhanger and
do you have a button at the top of your
screen to go to the room should be next
to the leave button on this room
oh no i didn't see it ah
yes carla it's most likely your settings
in teams actually i need a little thing
i can pop up on the screen that shows
how to configure the settings that would
be uh
a good thing so let me let me check
andre and see
um can you hear me
yes
all right so so in the in the settings
for teams uh if you if you click on the
little
can you not hear me
oh
yeah yeah well you can type i know but
then it's lots of writing
let me see if i can take a
screenshot
of the device things
for you
i will explain very quickly i was in a
zoo meeting and then my
audio crashed and then i had
eggs in the
little volume and
i don't know what's wrong with this let
me detect problem detecting problem
that that's why i don't use zoom that
just solves that problem although anna
would say that's why you shouldn't use
teams switch the teams but that's uh
well i i think it's a problem with the
computer because
he was kind of the icons
so it looks like
he was having some problems that's okay
she'll pop she'll pop back and and we'll
get we'll get laundry as well
so
sometimes
everything works perfectly and sometimes
it just doesn't
just
yeah yeah just like just like
the complex systems that we work with
yeah
uh so there's about a minute left on the
on the time box
um we'll see oh there we go on andre i
should be able to
i can invite you to join that team's
meeting now it's realized that you're
not there
did that work
nope it doesn't work
yep it's okay
you you might you might be one of the
the unique
valuable people that i'm not going to
ever be able to send out to a breakout
room that might
might be something that happens i have
had that before um so if that's the case
then i'll i'll have one less breakout
room and we can treat this as a breakout
room um
i have had to do that before
i'm going to struggle pronouncing
pronouncing that
uh who who's seen i think it's just
hussein isn't it
it's his name his name
okay
and oh no another one
mine
awesome i got that one right
here
i am just going to we
yay
i i'm just going to close the breakout
rooms and bring the rest of uh the folks
back so let me close them all um
we do have other people here that were
just off um
talking about it's okay it's okay that's
why that's why we have this exercise at
the start because people are late they
struggle with the technology their
computers doesn't work sometimes
all of those things
yes
the planets are not aligned
in a way that the breakout rooms work or
however that happens
so i am interested in a couple people
that did manage to get into the breakout
rooms any insights
they might have had about this topic
because
it may be one that you haven't thought
about before
russia have you
what did you discuss in your breakout
room what were the important things
uh
first we we tried to
to know each other and to visit each
other because both two of us is in you
and one kind of expert or have more
experience in scrum
brinkley and
we
kind of try to get into the system more
to
apply and find the question and we
discussed just the first one which is
why transparency is important and as we
understand that from the strong point
i'm still as i said
about the transparency in investigation
and um
adapt so in term to get into the room
and they have the
update and i like for the product itself
for for the service or you think project
that okay you need to have this kind of
in transparency in order to investigate
and
and adapt with the team
so
and then the time is finished
we definitely made a short amount of
time for sure
uh would anybody else like to
add their discussion
maybe maybe anna you were in the in room
one
yeah but we did just the same just
introducing each other and that was it
that is absolutely okay when we meet new
people we want to get to know them a
little bit don't we
right but
is time meeting make the first roaming
station it
just so people know each other and get
competitors
that is definitely part of the point of
that first exercise there's not meant to
be really any learnings that come out of
that is just to get us get us going and
get us at talking about the topic and i
think uh russia you're the first person
in one of these free sessions that has
held up a scrum guide for us
um it's been a long time since i've seen
a printed copy uh
but uh yeah that's that's
when your organization's getting started
a good sign is lots of copies of the
scrum guide printed out for people to
read
yeah because
you get it kind of if you've not read it
which i find lots of people haven't
right even people that are um consider
themselves maybe maybe veterans
of the scrum world and they've not read
the scrum guide and i'm kind of
okay how much of a veteran can you be if
you haven't even read the rules
right the rules of engagement
uh if you don't know what they are
you're gonna make uh you're gonna make a
mistake
uh so this this topic
today uh was was was anna's idea
um so
uh are there any introductions you would
like to add
anna
well um
i i
propose this
because i find many times that in
organizations
uh commitments it's like
not really
well understood and it's taken from the
idea of the old television
uh thing
and
we see our managers as soon as her
commitment for specific things
and i find this very useful um
uh to to
to clear up our ideas even mine
and and we have some takeaways to drop
into our organizations
to be able to explain to what we really
have to commit instead of committing to
things that really don't matter
yeah or or maybe have a negative impact
we commit to things that can often have
a negative impact on on the way we
deliver on on on our business and you
know those are the two the the common
difficulty that people have moving
towards commitments in organizations
is that it's it
it's very different it's a very
different outlook
from the traditional project management
practices that we all know
right
and most people in our organization know
them most people have been exposed to
them and then we start talking about
something different so they try and fit
the old way into the new words and you
try and fit the old way into the new
words you're suddenly still doing the
old thing you're just calling it
something new
right we've we've missed the value the
the the the change that we're trying to
try to get to
so hopefully um anna and i um
spent a bunch of time coming up with
this uh workshop for us these exercises
um so hopefully we'll be able to to to
iron out some of these ideas uh but
we'll we'll we'll see
okay uh that's that's gonna be
interesting so what what we have
is we have um a couple of exercises to
do around
getting us a little bit more solid on
what
what the commitments are
and where they fit
in that story
okay in the in the well i i use that
word quite a lot i i i use the word
story uh when sometimes i might mean
rule book right uh but all stories are
based on rules
right
you any novel any movie has a has a
formula within which it operates and the
story is the empathy that's built up
around it and i think the same is true
in any process within your organization
if you want people to follow it
they need to connect to that story
in a way that matters to them otherwise
they'll be like i don't care about this
crap and figure out a way around it
which is
like every security policy and every
company i've ever worked with
uh is somebody trying to figure out a
way around it
um so in this particular exercise we're
going to do we're going to do a little
a little a card sort
okay um so is everybody managed to get
onto the mural i can see there are six
people on the mural so uh
i think there's a couple of people
popped in after
i added to the mural so let me
just paste the link in
that is perfect so i'm just adding it to
the chat
if you can't see the chat for some kind
of company corporate security uh reason
then it did add it to the community site
so if you go to community
dot nkd agility dot com or just go to
nkdlc.com and click on committees
um you'll get to the the free workshop
and in there i've put the mural as well
so if i can't directly message it to you
i've stuck it in there
so hopefully that will bring a couple
more a couple more people in because
what we are going to do
is something called a card sort so if i
zoom into one of these areas just one of
these rooms
and we have uh um
three areas
for each of the commitments
in scrum
okay
so the product goal the sprint goal and
definition done
are the commitments
but i'd like you to sort these cards
here into which commitment do they
belong to
okay
and and uh
this should
um help us get a handle on how these
things are constructed and maybe a
little bit
maybe not necessarily why they matter
but how they matter right how do they
work how do they relate to each other
um
does anybody not understand the exercise
that's always a good sign
people are peace no wait we just need to
put the cards in the right place yep
under the right heading i think it's the
right place yep
that's uh perfect so let me uh i want
groups of about three so let me see
all right so
it's okay not to have somebody was
saying that their teams was crashing
because of the background effect um i'm
not using a background effect either
that is real uh same as uh brandon's
books and anna's bookshelf as well um we
are using real backgrounds and that's
okay too right we're we're definitely
not going to be offended if you have
something weird in the background um
but you know within within reason
you know that that's
how we do that so i've read three rooms
when you go into the room at the top of
your room the title of the bar well at
least in windows i don't know about mac
i would be able to uh um let me know if
that is true and talking and now let me
fix my breakout room fan angle
uh so where did anna end up there
let's do that and then room one has an
extra person so moved into there we go
right so that'll fix that
um
so the title bar of the window that pops
up will tell you what room you're in if
you're on windows if you're on mac i
don't know where it is it'll be around
somewhere hopefully somebody somebody
else in the room can say we're in this
room
and just go to the box that represents
that that room they are color coded to
help us help us find it and start these
cards i will give you five minutes to
sort the cards and carla that is not
going to be enough time
okay to sort all the cards
um but you're gonna have five minutes
and then at the end of the five minutes
over on the right i have the answers
okay and they're hidden behind this
locked panel
on the right hand side so i'll just
summon everybody we get 11 now in the
mural that's pretty good so it's a
locked panel over here and i'm going to
unlock and remove that at the end of the
first five minutes
but i'm going to give you three
additional minutes in the room
just to relate
what's in there with what you put as
well because maybe
maybe you picked uh um
things and thought that they were in a
different place and the wording
will help us help us get there does that
make sense so you'll get the answers
after five minutes but you'll get an
extra three minutes to review
that was maybe a better way to say it
so if nobody has any uh questions i have
clicked the open rooms button and you
should have like a 10 second warning pop
up
um
yeah just a little thing drops down from
the top and says you're moving to a
breakout room in 10 seconds
um
it would be better if it was
instantaneous but it's kind of nice to
have a 10 second where everybody's gone
there we go
yeah i so all all the other trainers are
complaining about the 10 seconds that it
takes to get into the breakout room but
i think if
i take it as an opportunity to either
repeat the exercise
or
i don't know
hello
hello hello
hi ann how you doing
i'm good
uh let me just put a timer on for the
folks that have just gone into the
exercise you are not the only one here a
whole bunch of people just we just
started an exercise
just in case you thought you were a
little bit lonely
just with us
i just put a link in the chat for you to
the mural if you're not already on there
okay
um so if you if you click on that link
to open the mural once you've got that
open you can let me know and i will
uh
bring you into
put you in a breakout room with some
friendly folks
yes sure you i follow the links uh in
the chat not only in the chat okay oh
yeah i'm here right now okay you're on
the mural
yeah perfect so i'm gonna pop up and ask
to be followed for you so you can see
where we are you should get a pop-up on
mural that says follow martin
yes
yep yep so now you're looking at the
same thing as me we've got this exercise
where we're doing we're doing something
called a card sort i want to catch you
up before i send you in so you're not
distracting everybody
and what what we're doing is we have the
we have a a heading
with each of the three commitments
in scrum so the product goal the sprint
goal and definition of done and they're
sorting the cards
under the correct heading
okay okay does that make sense
yeah cool so i'm going to assign you to
a room
uh pick a number between one and three
i put you in room three so you should uh
disappear in a few seconds off to
off to room three um and
yeah so i'll see you back
in uh three four five six minutes
see six more minutes yeah
there we go
so teams has no problem with peop more
people arriving
it's when people leave
when you're trying to do breakout room
sessions that's when it struggles
because i think we lost
did we lose the the girl that was here
at the start i don't remember her name
she was here for the first exercise and
then i think she either disappeared or
turned her camera off and we haven't
seen her again but
it could be either
it could be a connection
thing that's okay too
room three
needs some help
so rooms one and two are doing okay
um
room one's doing pretty awesome
up now they're starting to move them
yeah yeah
is that the the the the girl i can't
have her name girl with the scrum guide
um
right yeah because i don't see her now
in the
in the in the list but um
uh all because all of these cards
are actually just straight out of the
scrum guide i did have to tweak the
wording a little bit on occasion just to
remove the answer
because sometimes the answers in the in
the in the words
and shorten it a little bit but um
i guess the the purpose
so also for the for the for the folks
watching who are bored who are stuck
with us
right because they don't get to go to
the breakout rooms
yeah hey everybody um
the purpose of this exercise is to start
getting people to understand
the difference between the different uh
um commitments what they are and what it
says in the scrum guide and so all i did
was i created 16 boxes
and then i went through the text for
each of the commitments in the scrum
guide and every time i came to something
that i could copy out and paste in here
um i did that
so really this is this is them reading
the scrum guide
uh
in regards to the commitments but in a
card sort kind of way so it feels a
little bit more like a game it feels
less about the reading but because
you've got to make a decision about
which column they go under and then you
have to have a conversation because
there's more than two people in the room
then uh hopefully uh uh they learn and
figure out stuff and then we can have
when they come back or um
we'll do the self-correcting thing
uh so oh yeah i guess the
self-correcting part just means that
there's a there's an answer sheet which
i'm going to uncover that's all
self-correcting means
in 20 seconds yeah
um
visiting pandas following me that's
probably not the best idea
following martin's not the best idea
oh i think
i think it might be getting harder as we
get further down the list
they're actually just random so oh there
we go let me open up the answers
uh
we need class uh well russia has this
problem
and i'm pretty sure she's going to check
it
um but if all the rest have the sperm
guide open they would be able
yeah all of these if you if you open up
the scrum guide or you've got it on
another screen all of these
are super easy you would just have to
find the text
um
and in fact i think
the way i did it was i created the grid
of 16 boxes and then i just added them
in stripes so they were kind of
randomized um
but not really random there is a pattern
so you can you can and then i numbered
them right so you can probably figure
them out if you know the pattern
all right let's check on room three what
have they got in
oh are they struggling with things going
behind no they're not they're
no no
room one is doing pretty good
i wonder if they remembered that the
answers have been uncovered
probably not
i don't see anybody's cursor heading
over to the
heading over to the answers
can we
have something nearer
i did a teams broadcast so teams has a
little mic megaphone button
um that just sends a message to all the
rooms
um
well
done
did they get it right
we'll need to tell them about the bug
and mural
when they come back because i think a
couple of things have suffered from that
that they've kind of dropped
because they're all in front for us
oh no i get one that's behind but it's
because i moved it a little bit
um
i think room one god is stepped
somewhere like they're
arguing about something
uh do you want to pop in and well
there's only like 15 seconds left
sometimes these exercises are a little
bit easier in in real rooms like
physical rooms because you can hear
everybody and when they get stuck you
can just go over and help them
there is a tool we can experiment with
one time anna that has uh we have little
circles on a map and you move them
closer to different groups of people and
it gets louder
that would be pretty cool to try but
i've clicked to bring everybody back so
they'll be on their way
hello i think i think
uh carla your group got stuck were you
arguing about something
no no no okay
we were just observing and we felt like
uh uh
got a little bit a little bit bogged
down
just in moving the cards maybe something
was too contentious
yeah he was looking at the what we have
written and i was looking at the answers
because the screen moving back and forth
it was too time consuming so he was
saying what we put i was reviewing yes
we got it right and we got everything
right what we put and we even had like
15 seconds left from the sprint to spare
awesome
i don't know if we will have questions
about this because we did have a one
question
and that
i just uh let me let me hear from the
other rooms first and then we'll we'll
we'll do that
so
room two was brandon erica and anna how
did you get on
yes we actually got through pretty much
all the cards and uh with mostly
agreement
awesome well that's good
any contentious
items
we just are contentious
so we have doing
groups we are not sure
um
i think we
we had a
very short discussion because we didn't
have the time to
to talk about that properly about the
number four might be fulfilled or
abandoned before a new one is created
and i
was thinking about the product goal
uh and the management was any more about
the spring goal so we we talked about
that because it wasn't
very
i think it was the only
not disagreement but
the only the only point we had the
a discussion and we were not completely
sure about the twelve
also uh so
uh you can see
these two
uh sentences in the middle of the
between two
two commitments because we're we're not
sure yeah i i yep i uh and i understand
i can definitely understand why 12 sits
uh between those two things so
uh we can definitely come back to that
and then in room three it was
um
dimitrios and andre how did you get on
just focus there
anna and i discussed that before you got
back um there is a their mural
is having a problem right now
and that's sometimes when you drag you
drag something so this is just for you
and drop it it goes behind the thing you
dropped it on
and it's not actually behind it it's
just in your render of it so if you
refresh the browser it's back on top
again
or one of your colleagues can move it
but then for them it will be behind and
for you it will be in front it's very
annoying
uh i i've raised it with with uh mural
support
uh but they're not replying to anything
just now so i assume
because they're usually pretty good at
replying that means there's lots of
people at the mural office running about
with their hair on fire trying to fix it
that's that's that's my my assumption
uh uh based on that either they're not
out of bed yet because they're in pst
time zone and they're just getting up to
to that um but for me it's been like
that since monday i had that problem on
monday in a class so uh we'll see
because i've got it last on next monday
so hopefully they'll fix it
the sticky situation there i
[Music]
my opinion is number four should be our
spreading goal because you must be
fulfilled or abandoned before new y is
created
ah
yeah so
so only uh yeah i also mentioned that uh
only under the certain extreme situation
the spreading goal could be abandoned
that brings my uh fading that this one
should fade uh under the sprinkle
so i'm go i'm going to let you in on a
little secret
every single one of these uh post-its is
copied verbatim out of the scrum guide
okay which one question which was chrome
guy the update from 2020 the 2020 scrap
guide i did it this morning
yeah
because you know what the the one
question so i i agree that it's like
really copy it but there was this one
created during the spring climbing event
and this is what i mentioned in the
before the update it did say the scrum
guide if i remember correctly that the
in the part one meeting
this protoner informs about the supreme
goal
the spring gold so
meaning that it's already
so it's actually it's actually been
three versions of the scrum guide since
it had the part one part two
thing
yeah yeah yeah so but that's okay right
um so so
yeah i i and there's a there's a lot of
things
at the that that
so although the words
in the scrum guide has changed
the intent
that the authors had
has not necessarily changed right
but
people's interpretation of the words
means that they then go back and change
the words to try and
not have
incorrect interpretations
so sometimes we read it and we like the
way it was worded like um there's a few
things from the previous verses scrum
guide that i feel feel feel loss
that it's no longer in the scrum guide
and no longer says that
um but it doesn't mean it's not true
right you should be able to take the
intent from any of the versions of the
scrum guide and it's it's the same thing
we're just adding more value adding more
conciseness because the difficulty with
the scrum guide is it uses one word when
it would be better to use a hundred
words
right it's very compacted to keep it
small
um and and try and be a little bit
nimble but it means that there's a lot
of interpretation
a lot of interpretation
um
[Music]
but after your explanation i changed my
mind to more than number four under the
productive goal
yeah
must be fulfilled or abandoned before
the new one is created
it's
yeah before a new one is created is is a
characteristic of the product goal
you wouldn't normally abandon a sprint
goal for sure right
you might cancel a sprint but that's a
lot bigger
cancelling a sprint is a lot bigger more
expensive thing
than just getting to the sprint review
looking at the product goal and saying
we need a new one of those
right because we're either already there
or the world has changed and it's no
longer relevant
right because we're not actually doing
work inside of the product goal
but we are doing work inside of the
sprint goal so we might be mid sprint
when something nasty happens
um any other any what was the other
contentious ones carla you said that
there was something
still and i still have that one the one
about credit created during the spring
planning event the spring goal
because this how i see it and of course
actually mistaken is that it's a kind of
a vision where are we looking as a team
where do we want to go and that will
support us really to make decisions
right yep but um kind of created during
the stream planning event
to me is like okay we have already done
the planning so how does this look like
let's make a summary out of it i'm not
sure if i'm really convinced that the
goal would be
as part of the stream planning rather
than
you know product owner communicating
what what what is the kind of vision for
this what how the implement will look
like for example
and now because obviously i haven't read
the 2020 guide that's okay any other
uh i now i'm even confused then who's
creating because since the spring
planning is everyone there
so it's not really only the product
owner saying this is my vision but it's
everyone which makes sense of course
but i don't know i'm more like pro conor
what is your wishes or my commands ah
you're you're in the benevolent dictator
uh for the product owner that's okay
um i i think
i think i think that that conversation
between
the product owner and the team to come
to an agreement on what the goal is
is
part of it is because
who owns the sprint goal who commits to
the sprint goal
during the sprint
the the the developers right
so if if if somebody else makes a
commitment on your behalf like the
product owner comes and said carla you
have to do this and it's an impossible
task
and that person doesn't believe it's an
impossible task but you know it to be
because you're the technical expert
then you're in a bit of a position
aren't you that's not going to make you
unhappy it's going to make your life
difficult
so that the agreement is to reflect
the realities of doing the work
so that the developers can say to the
product owner
we can't we cannot do that just now
we need to do a bunch of other stuff
first before we can get to that or we
don't have the information or
understanding we need yet
right maybe we need to do more research
maybe we need some training maybe we
need to speak to a bunch of customers in
order to get that so that's something
that might not be able to be done this
sprint
what you just said about there is a one
word when they could use much more for
example i am referring yeah i'm
referring here to goal as a vision and
the vision of the
of course the protocol from the toner
and therefore the vision of how i would
like this increment to look like and
this is the reason why i have
prioritized the backlog in this way is
because this is how i want this
increment to look like but i'm not
saying it as an actual commitment that
yes what what this is this is what we're
committing to do then is devotion
i'm going to bring in a diagram to help
you because
uh
i was just teaching a product owner
class this week
um and one of the diagrams is i think i
think they call it they call it the
planning onion or the organizational
onion
i'm i'm i'm being a little bit choppy
here because i'm opening on a second
mural and my machine's been difficult
today
uh so if i just go in and grab this i'm
waiting for it to load so then i can
zoom in to the right place
there we go i've found it and i need to
oh no i can just copy it
and then i'm going to paste it in where
am i going to stick it let's paste it in
here there we go there we go
so i just stuck it over the top of some
of this other stuff here
so let me let me uh let me summon
so this is this is i i guess my
interpretation of that that planning
onion
where you've got the different levels of
the organization on the left so
delivering validation
value and solution discovery up to
product strategy and then product vision
then business strategy and then company
vision right
so there might be a lot of different
products that roll up to that company
vision
and then the different levels of goals
you've got tactical goals for things
we're doing now
and then strategic goals for thing that
that thing you're talking about carla
that vision is a strategic goal right
what are we strategically trying to
achieve
but sometimes
that strategic goal
is too far away
too far away from the work we're doing
so we as potentially people doing the
work are like i've got no idea how what
i'm doing today relates
relates to our strategy so i don't feel
connected empathetically to the product
and to the vision and what it is we're
trying to achieve
and so the product goal
is meant to be an intermediate strategic
goal that helps the people doing the
work and the stakeholders right connect
to where are we going just now
not where are we going you know where
our end trip is
um but what what's our next leg
of our of our of our trip the next
segment
of our of our trip and we might have a
number of sprint goals which are our
tactical goals
um and i actually i like the
tactical strategic
wording and i like to i actually maybe
i'm a bit weird and played too much call
of duty right but i like to think of it
like a battlefield
right you're tr you're trying to you're
trying to you're trying to you're trying
to win win win the war
right is your your end goal
but
win the war doesn't help us understand
what we need to do just now
uh so maybe maybe we need to
destroy this castle right that's the the
next thing we have to do but in order to
destroy the castle there's 20
tactical things that have to happen in
order to get to the point where that
happens
um and the the the sprint goal or those
tactical
moves towards our product goal and we
might get so far down that
tactical goals we might do three or four
tactical goals
sprint goals and then we realize oh
we we can't get there
or there's no longer relevant or the sun
blocker which means
it doesn't make sense anymore or the
business has changed or
and we need to figure out what's next so
that's where the product go
we have one and then if it then becomes
no longer relevant we pick another one
but we only ever have one
that's the idea so i i think you're
thinking at a higher level than scrum is
well
yeah i mean
again words right vision like i have a
vision for today although like
how do i want the day to look like yes
and it's not my vision for life so he
said but then again then coming
regardless of the word like
who like i understand the commitment of
courses by the team
absolutely no with no no question about
that
but then at what point or
basically what what this is
teaching me in a way is that it is
actually the team so the developers who
are deciding the goal of the sprint
i the developers have to commit to it
but they agree to it in combination with
the product owner and the reason there's
a that combination
right is not so we talked about one side
of the combination which is why why it's
on the developers
list of things that they need to to
connect to
um but also if we don't build the stuff
the product owner needs
to keep their stakeholders happy to keep
the business happy then maybe we're all
out of a job because the business will
just go
oh the the venture cap the venture
funding will just disappear gone right
we're done
so there's a vested interest in the
developers
in helping the product owner achieve
what they want to achieve
but then there's also the realities
of the tactical situation of what we
need to do to get there
and that's that's that balance
so create
this context could mean
it has been proposed by the donor but as
it has been discussed during the
planning and it has been agreed and
that's yes for the facebook yes
it may also change
i mean yeah during the negotiation and
agreement because what martin said maybe
technology doesn't support you or
anything
they created in stream planning created
it means the combination of these three
actions yeah yeah the first owner can
come with an idea
uh that during that negotiation they
agreed something else because um
what you committed is something that you
need to have this time control of
and if the developers don't have that
kind of ownership of what they are doing
they
yeah
yeah exactly i can't sleep now
why don't we use indiana
east coast
what was that dimitri i didn't catch
that
why what why did
you see bm so case closed
cbm
ebn ebm oh evidence based management
yeah yeah yeah
yeah well
having evidence to make the decisions is
always a good idea
um but evidence can only inform your
decision
it doesn't control it because sometimes
we need to do things that's different
from the evidence
right and that could be just to keep
people happy right and they don't care
about the evidence but we still need to
keep them happy
and also there are some things that that
cannot be measured and you can tell them
but also those discussions of course
based on data but
there is a lot of work in that time
there's a good reason that anna works
for a company called empathy
yeah
um was there any other um
[Music]
things that were
that anybody wanted to to bring up
no that's cool
so i see that somebody just posted the
the the scrum.orgs ebm
guide
in the in the chat
i i definitely recommend
reading that as well but carla you've
the first thing on your list is the 2020
version of the scrum guide okay
and that then
yeah and then go read then go read the
ebm
guide
it's i i think there's a lot of value in
it and then come to my workshop in in
next month for uh the professional agile
leadership with evidence-based
management yeah that too but where are
you in uk or i'm in the uk but it's a
virtual workshop i don't i i don't run
any impair i run all my classes like
like this
because um then i don't
actually it's not
right and i'll tell you why
it's a different kind of fun yes but
prior to lockdown i was traveling 300
days a year with 140 flights a year and
in the last 10 years i've been in 32
different countries averaging about 16
countries a year so i prefer this
because it's less travel
oh well yeah
yeah i like it
i like travel for fun carl but we have
to be in in in five cities in one day
then then it's not so not so fun not so
fun yeah yeah
um
because
i'm in argentina now for example but it
wouldn't be impossible it would be
impossible for me to take part in any
app absolutely and and
when i when i when i run it these these
even
i mean these these are these free
workshops aside when i run classes those
people come in from from from
um
you i call it us time zones right but
but it's eastern eastern time uh
i get people from uk from europe from uh
um singapore all the way through to
singapore and everybody's in the same
class
right so we can learn from each other as
well and our different cultural
backgrounds inform some of the
discussions that we have around how
things are done and i think that helps
too spreading the knowledge and good
things and how we approach things
differently
so um
anna
would you like to
you knew obviously
explain the crazy circles
okay so um
we're looking here uh commitment is one
of the some of the values of
uh office
okay and basically uh we can see you
values a lot uh and we really don't know
what it means
uh but basically what what
state rights behavior they write how we
behave how we work with people
and and one of them is commitment and we
commit to a specific thing um that can
be good or bad okay but we can make
specific things in the strong guy 2020
we are committing to a specific thing
so here what we want you to do um it's
um
you have some circles and you have to
put the circles into the right way into
the right place
um you have there's the commitment value
and you have to say what he permits you
where is where it's embodied and the
rest of the officer
[Music]
so there are um
a bunch of circles with question marks
on them
okay that are connected into this story
with commitment in the middle uh so the
first circle out is the largest so there
are three big circles
and that will obviously be
uh it's obvious what they will be right
as the three commitments
uh but then the next circle out is uh
how are those things embodied
right what are they embodied in uh and
then the next uh circles which there
might be two or three
are um how how do we realize that what
what what is that thing
uh um what's the physical elements of it
does that make sense like how you would
break down that thing
was that a better explanation i think i
think we needed both in order to figure
out but carla's still confused
yeah what is embodied
i don't know anna picked that word
what's it in spanish
[Music]
represented by that's a good one for the
rest of us who don't speak spanish even
though i should because my wife's
mexican but
yeah i'm from mexico
i live in finland though oh well makes
sense yeah well finland's nice
my wife's mexican and she lives in
glasgow so you know
that makes less sense
so because it's in you know brexit land
let's not go there uh
so i have i have three breakout rooms
i've randomized them again so we won't
be with the the same the same people in
case you met somebody uh that you really
liked and you wanted to stay with them
you will be with a different group of
people and the idea is just to drag
these circles onto
the ones that it represents now you'll
see that two of the lines
are have the same words on them but one
of them is a little bit different it
says quality measurements
to protect
okay so that's the one that's a little
bit different so there's only a specific
thing that goes in was in that line
we totally on board
and be confused
i'll ask that while demetrius is
drinking so he can't say yes and then
i'll click open rooms and there we go
no problem
um so i will i'm going to
in fact we don't know how long this is
going to take so i'll probably put eight
minutes on the timer and then we'll see
how you get on
oh i think i added you to a romana
yes i did add you to a room
so this is a brand new
exercise if you're watching i think i
fixed the echo if you had an echo right
if you didn't that's okay
um
hopefully you could still hear me and
still hear anna but you could hit
desktop as well and i think i think that
was confusing so um
and i came up with this it i think it
looks it looks like it's interesting um
it probably needs some iterations to get
it like so we could explain it well
um but effectively you're just moving
those uh individual circles on top of
uh
the the dotted circles with the question
marks i mean that's pretty much it it's
filling the fill in the blanks
exercise
ah
anna
are you back
yeah
you you put me in a breaker room i did i
did
yeah but that's
that gave me the
if they understood it and we explained
it correctly and they said yes
completely so
perfect i i actually figured out when i
was trying to explain it again to
everybody else
um
i fill in the blanks
is probably
the easiest shortest
uh way to say it
oh so we get number one i think we got
two people
drop out
a biddy i think hussein has dropped out
or i think i'm saying that wrong again
uh alex looks like he's dropped oh alex
is a pst oh
yeah well he joined like five minutes
from the left or something like that
okay
so there's only two people in in room
one and two three people in room two but
that's okay that's still
that's still a good number
probably makes it easier
well
what i like from this is that you need
to kind of
uh build the whole as you say sorry like
okay i commit to
the definition of don
uh
but it's represented by and so you have
to do the full thinking process and it
only goes one way yeah and i the thing i
liked was the in the definition of done
one you get to the end and you're like
oh right so these have got to go
somewhere else and i have to bring these
other ones over yeah i do like that i do
like that
but
i think it's the
one
it's the one that it
was was the sprint goal the two
i can't remember now
oh no
three
yeah the top one vertical
left
it was like room one
oh yes
[Music]
but
i'll send them a message to
it can be
i just sent everybody a message to say
if things are falling behind other
things you might need to refresh the
browser
there's a couple of weird things happen
there but that's okay
the technology is never going to be
perfect every time
so
having a little bit of best efforts okay
i i i like what they are
i like what they are uh
how they are ordering ordering it
because it's
um
it's the common way people think about
this uh
for example product goal and vote and
voted in product backlash politicality
measures to protect further factual
items order and details yeah
i i like it too
we just need to be able to
explain it much more easily yeah
but that's okay
if they got it so they're doing it
it works we got we got it we got it
explained enough
um
so we're about
15 minutes behind
right now but that's okay
that's much better than i usually are
one last thing with uh on time right the
yeah the definition of done one yeah we
got that we got that time box pretty
great it was the it was the the
um
the coin game one that was just a
complete disaster
that took
ages it took so long to explain it
and then re-explain it and then
re-explain it and then go help teams
that were struggling
you were playing the in the uh you mean
the kanban one
and uh the penny game yeah
okay yeah it was it it
it must have taken us 60 minutes to do
the 30 minute exercise
right but that's the trouble with a 30
minute exercise right if things go a
little bit wrong then it becomes massive
whereas if you've got lots of smaller
ones
maybe you just skip something that is
that's struggling
batch size we're doing an exercise on
batch size and the batch size was too
big
[Laughter]
i i think that when when i took the
training uh with recumbent
um
i i also grabbed some some ideas and did
a training uh at empathy and
and they really liked it
but you've done you've done the the pro
kanban um applying
professional kanban
yeah yeah
i i can i can teach that but i haven't
taught one yet
i haven't done one yet um because i also
teach the psk
the professional scrum with kanban um
which is
i mean literally the the pk is two whole
days just on kanban whereas the the
professional scrum with kanban is like
uh what one day on kanban and one day on
scrum with kanban right so well i i just
felt the full time
yeah yeah
i just haven't haven't haven't uh taught
it yet it looks like uh everybody's
finished
no i don't
well i would have it in my account yeah
yeah okay okay okay
i actually i went to look down the
bottom and they're all the ones that
we've got down there are blank all of
the copies we've got at the bottom are
blank yeah but i have it here
oh cool
yes
i'm copying
it and
should i add it somewhere
or once they come back oh
hold on i think blue team definitely
have stuff dropping behind
luckily i made everything see-through so
you can at least still see it
yeah the blue team stuff yeah yeah
they're writing a little message in
there
and uh i'm not the things anymore
i fixed it for them
and the time is
over
it it is it is the eight minutes is over
i think
two groups are are are done so i think
we should bring them back and
we will we will suffer the wrath of team
two
um
who who
had an impediment
hello
hello hello
that was a perfect way for you guys to
communicate with us room two thank you
for that
because i fixed it as soon as i saw that
because i was like i can't drag those or
i was actually looking to see if i could
move one of them into place and yeah
things were
yeah
so at least do you know what's worse
i i made all of the backgrounds
semi-transparent
so sometimes they drop behind and they
just disappear and you don't know what's
going on
um but at least if they're
semi-transparent you can still see them
i know it's there but i can't grab it
well so that was a bit better
uh so sorry sorry about that
um
six in the
i guess like 30
seconds
yeah
as soon as i saw the tech i fixed it as
soon as you sent me a message to fix it
so but yeah it was a bit late yeah
sorry about that um
anna would you like to
to debrief
yeah well how
did in room one from
the exercise and
what did you see did you find it
difficult
okay do you want to go
okay
no not difficult at all we hope because
we finished in like two minutes and then
we have time to chat a little uh we
found it quite uh quite easy to
um
well to the puzzle and
we started we we started uh
putting the the commitments and then
then we
we filled the one commitment at the time
and it was it was very easy so we didn't
have any any doubt i think
okay
so
for every room it was here where we put
everything and so even for room
uh too that
we're not able to move things
yeah
um
and the the part that is
going on in our team is we have
conversation about
which one is which
so i apologize
we were again
happiness
because i i took i was taking literally
the the represented by
and for instance definition of done is
not necessarily represented by increment
so you know like
that
didn't really
really
that's what i was just i was just
talking what is it that lost in
translation
yes to be
yeah i mean
i i i can i can see the represented by
but yeah maybe it's a little bit tenuous
um
but this will describe in the newspaper
guide
so the definition of that is with the
increment
yeah the so the way the way it's
described in the the scrum guide and i
actually think the wording in the scrum
guide is a little bit weird for this
right but um it says the
the increment is born
when the product meets the definition of
done
which is a little bit weird because then
you weird pictures in your head but
uh
it it i think it does kind of it does
kind of work that's the thing
that lets us know whether if if we
didn't meet the definition of done we
don't have an increment
right
if we meet the definition of done 20
times during the sprints we have 20
things that we could ship during the
sprint if that's what we wanted to do
um that's the essence of continuous
delivery
is that you're meeting your definition
of done constantly because hopefully
it's automated
i see and anna brought in the the
answers grid
yeah
so
so here uh is the solution
um
so yes the definition of that is
embodied in the increment
uh and it's uh quality measures to
protect uh customers organizations and
themes okay so that was the
place to put the definition of them
um
i've seen uh in some teams uh that the
uh the product backlog is the quality
measure to protect the current faculty
items orders and customers and
i don't know how to
um
interpret that
or how you got to that
idea
um
and well first
it's involved in the product backlog by
the product battle of items the order
and the detail and the streamed uh goal
is for the stream backlog and uh
tangible bytes for the backlog items in
the button that's the absolute basically
anything
that you don't see clear here
yes
so we had a discussion about the product
backlog in the details
[Music]
but
most of the product uh backlog items are
not details only the most prioritized on
the top that's why you put the details
in the sprint uh
because there you must have the details
yeah well um the idea put it in is there
i think it's the same that you're you're
saying uh the
produce goal is embodied in the product
backlit and those that detail on on top
of the background
uh it's guiding us to the
to the pedestal
the more you're on top of the mirror you
have uh
how you're going you're committing
that's how i understand it yeah
i think uh my team is
doing the best so all answers are
correct
i i do kind of like the the details
piece as part of product backlog because
one of the things that that is
um
i think much more clear in the new
version of the scrum guide
is that refinement is the activity that
adds details
so details about the what not
necessarily the how but maybe a little
bit of the how
right because there's some there's a lot
of crossover between
um
what you want and how you want it done
and i have a lot of discussions with
product owners about how much detail
should you go into
on your product back clock
and and for things that we need to build
i.e the stuff that's at the top of our
product backlog that are candidates
for bringing into the sprint
we need as much detail
as the
team the developers need
to feel comfortable that they can take
it on and build it
right so what does that mean within your
context if you're building something
that is less complex maybe you don't
need a lot of details
right
but for example i've worked with a
company in norway
who build maritime simulation software
so it's used
with full rigs with rooms that pivot
around to simulate the sea to train
people
uh
to to handle massive ships at sea right
and do all sorts of crazy things like
maybe you've got a storm and you need to
offload cargo from one ship to another
in the middle of the sea it's not a good
idea right it's not a good idea to do
that but there are circumstances where
you might have to
but the complexity of that software
and the complexity of the task at hand
because it has to work
it's effectively a simulation of the
real world
it's the simulation of real world
physics and one of the things they have
to have and this is just one piece right
is there's three months work
goes into the spreadsheet that you need
to understand how the hull of the ship
interfaces with the water
right
and every single ship is unique
so you need that up front because you
can't build
that feature you can't add that ship to
your product
unless you have that information
so that's a whole three months worth of
detail
that you need somebody with a physics
background in hydrodynamics uh phd and
hydrodynamics to be able to to be able
to build for you um so that's a that's
quite a lot of detail right
um but one of the things that we talk
about a lot in agile that is
misinterpreted
is that oh we don't need
to do
lots of stuff up front
right or we shouldn't be doing lots of
stuff up front and that's kind of a
fallacy right
what we are saying is you shouldn't do
more than you have to
how much do you need to do enough up
front just enough
so that when your team walks into sprint
planning they have everything they need
the knowledge they need the
understanding they need and the data
they need to build the thing that you
want them to build
right so that might be a lot in your
circumstances i hoping the team that
builds planes at boeing has lots of
information at their disposal at that
point but if we're building a marketing
website for a small company
maybe we don't need so much information
i don't know if that helped or it was
just a rant
could have been either
okay thank you
yeah i think uh
uh we needed to change that details from
uh
spring battle over to the product
backlog
if uh
i understand what it is then correct and
so also based on the
the scrum guide so it's ongoing activity
to add a details
yep
yep okay
um and that
the scrum guide is a good reference to
go back to for that i mean it's it's
it's
not the be all and end all you've got to
be pragmatic
um as well but sometimes you need to be
a little bit dogmatic to try and
understand what people are getting at we
want to all be playing the same game
um
and if everybody understands something
in the same way uh like having that
conversation like we're talking about
when carla was confused uh with that
particular terminology but we can have a
conversation about it we can agree as a
group well this is what we mean by that
okay now i understand that this word in
this case means this now we're all on
the same
the same understanding but we need to
come to those agreements because
how many different cultures are
represented here in this
uh meeting different people with
different language backgrounds people
with different uh upbringings
i find even if you took somebody
from the west end of who went to school
in the west end of glasgow and somebody
who went to school in the east end of
glasgow they will have a different
outlook on language a different outlook
on how to say things how to phrase
things and what they mean right
uh and that's
within 10 miles of each other let alone
the thousands of miles there are between
all of us
right and what about your team members
where are they from what are their
backgrounds did they all go to the same
school and sit in the same classes with
the same teacher no they didn't
right and every teacher brings their own
story to the puzzle as well
so i think it it's just
definitely these common understandings
and workshops like this can help bring
out some of those things those nuggets
that that people are confused about or
have different stories for so that you
can come to an agreement
about what you mean and what it says
working agreements are really important
excuse something a little bit related to
that we have a similar discussion
to this uh in my team and and half of
them are coming from
uh de la rose and the other half it's
uh chile molly
right so like very mixed
and uh and there was a conversation
about one of the
actually from the jargon from scrum
now i can't remember what was ah yeah
they are using jira right and they call
the pbis they call yeah
they come and they call yeah and they
call them tickets and it drives me crazy
and then at the end i was like no they
were like challenging me yeah but it
doesn't matter what you call them in the
end you're going to work on them
yeah and
and i
while i agree in principle
with what they're saying that it doesn't
matter what you call them
right um
lots one of the reasons that scrum uses
different terminology
from the stuff that came before is to
avoid the baggage
of the thing that came before so it does
matter
at what what what what you call them and
yeah i mean
so many people call call what you work
on in skrama user story
but the word user story is never
mentioned in the scrum guide
yeah
so so it's it it's a choice it might be
a good choice for your team
right but it also might be the wrong
choice i've i work with teams who build
apis and data frameworks
and they're trying to fit everything
into a user story and it makes no sense
whatsoever they've all these
ridiculously contrived
ways of writing these these stories
in order to fit it into that format and
it doesn't work because it's designed
for users interacting with systems
if a user doesn't interact with your
system a user story doesn't make sense
yeah good point yeah but ticket drives
me crazy because i
decide to serve his management strong
background so it just drives me crazy to
do that in any context yeah because
pick it has a lot of connotations
requirement has a lot of tasks has a lot
of connotations for anybody who's ever
worked with a project manager or an ms
project everything's a task right
so but coming to your point about that
to agree
what if you're agreeing on this kind of
terminology that has not really
background that i that i then i don't
mind
as long as
the agreement is this is what it means
right we're looking at the scrum guide
now the scrum guide says sprint
right
uh we're our automotive company and
we're going to call it a race
right because because because that's
what we want to call it in our in our in
our company that's cool
uh it's because it's a scrum team
um or it's a tribe
right i i i don't i don't care it
doesn't actually matter as long as we're
in agreement
what the accountabilities are what the
commitments are
right what the artifacts are to provide
transparency those are the things that
we want to want to agree on and i don't
think it really matters what they're
called
but if
we're here in this context right in our
context here where we're trying to have
a conversation about what does that mean
you've kind of got to go back to the
original
terminology in the scrum guide and what
is it trying to say and why is it trying
to say it that way but when we go back
to the office we can be pragmatic and
say oh you want to call it a
everybody's not a team member they're a
technical fellow okay i don't mind what
what you call people
right
but if you're a scrum master and your
job is updating the gantt chart you're
not a scrum master
yes right you're not you're not
fulfilling the accountabilities of the
scrum master
um if your job is making sure the
developers complete all their tasks in a
sprint right you're not a scrum master
um so i think terminology is is great to
have a conversation about
out with
the general public if that if that kind
of makes sense like when we're all
practitioners
having a conversation about the
mechanics of what it is we're trying to
do
be explicit
right and and and pick on those things
but when i've got a team
i'm going to try and guide them towards
the way i want them to be or way i would
like them to be regardless of of what
they call it
what do you just say so if you're doing
this you're not a scrum master and
wasn't so scrub master well you step you
kind of coach and keep reminding the
team and so on in a scrum as per the
strong guy so that makes me troubled
is you know like how much would you
or not but then organizations
organizations get a get away with it by
calling them an agile project manager
right
so you're not actually a scrum master
you're an agile project manager
exactly exactly
well i got to do the profit and loss
reporting and and do the invoicing to
the customer and
uh
i've got to do the the the product
productivity report with everybody's
timekeeping and
yeah
yeah the kpis yeah so
yeah i think
i don't mind what people call it just be
careful
of of baggage
baggage getting in the way of the the
new way of doing things
so i think um we only we only have
like five minutes left
because we had to get some good
conversations out of that one um and i
think it's pretty late for for anne is
it pretty late for you
no no it's a prayer
you're in canada now
yeah okay so then it's then it's pretty
early for you
cool
um
so so
i i think we should do
um a little bit
will we do a little bit of the conclu
can we do that quickly
can we do a what so what now what anna
do you think in like four minutes
probably not
i think
we can we can give it a go um we've been
giving a girl
we all we've got uh we've got an extra
team member now eric has brought an
extra team member yeah
she's gonna cheat by two heads are
better than one
yes yes
yeah
um
looks like a baby
looks like a baby baby that is a very
observant of you
looks
we just can't smell it it probably
smells like a baby too
yes
how old
two months oh my goodness me do you
remember those days anna
missing them but i don't know why i did
it
i didn't like those
that stunts but i was kind of nervous
yes we can carla yes we can good uh
good good good elmo thank you very much
for that
uh
so let me let me summon
i think i summoned everybody yes
um so we've got there's three three
rounds here and we're kind of going
going to do it just as a as a big uh
group exercise
and i'd like you to to think about in in
the first round i'll put three minutes
on the timer uh or two two minutes on
the timer for the first round and i want
you to think about and add some post-its
for
you know what what did you feel half
what happened
uh during this uh workshop what did you
notice uh what were things that you
observed or stood out for you
um so we'll just focus on on round one
and i'll put two minutes on the timer
for you to add some post-its and if you
aren't able to double-click and add
post-its you can right-click and add a
sticky note that works as well
hmm
and i love those two post-its right next
to each other
right next to the
the other one
different people's interpretations of
the same same activities
i love
that yeah that that is something we did
trying to focus on
stories and how to use stuff rather than
just uh the theory so yeah we did we'd
talk a lot about the scrum guide but
there was stuff stuff in there
that is very good
to admit smiley face notice that i was
wrong for some things
it's
pretty valuable
uh so let's move on to the so what
we've got two minutes again
we'll keep the pace clippy
and what patterns or conclusions
emerged
why why why are the things we talked
about important and are there any
hypothesis
that you can make
relating it back to
maybe the stuff you do at work
i like that it's always good to hear
other opinions
totally that's that's why these sessions
are just open sessions because then i
get lots of different opinions
although
i recognize some folks from classes
in fact both anas anna squared
is always good so let's look at it now
what
what can what can you do what what
letter what's what's something you
learned during this experience how could
you apply it
in in future
uh
iterations
um
what you need
to do in order to improve things next
time what could you what could you
actually change
in your organization maybe it's
difficult maybe it's just something you
could change in yourself
right because it's easy to change the
things we do it's difficult to change
other people
try and avoid when you're not in a
training situation
uh telling people but the scrum guide
says
right that's that's a good thing so
i would use it a lot in a training
circumstance but i wouldn't use it very
much with a real team
right because they don't care
they're like well how does that help me
do anything
right just because the scrum guide says
it
yeah you know martin that i i do that i
avoid using even the name of the scrum
guy because then you sound like a
jehovah witness or you know someone
holding the bible
but
these guys i'm working with they
rub it against me the scrum guide says
so and so and then they take literally
whatever they want to
understand from them
it's easy to to to misinterpret and to
to to use
there's a lot of things
i i think the thing i one of the things
i liked and not just about the 2020 but
the one version before that is they
brought the scrum values
front and center
in the scrum guide and it's still not as
strong as i would like because it's
almost the thing that you're building
everything else on
um but it is it is it is difficult to
coach that into teams um and
you're in a nordic
state
um and that makes your life double
doubly difficult
um i do a lot of work and training in
norway and sweden um not so much in
denmark although i've done some training
in denmark was it denmark
it was denmark wasn't that you were in
carla
not feeling like finland finland no i
haven't done anything in finland but
it's
that
it's very weird it's it
so
um
something that that um
my wife almost always comments on
is that northern europeans
don't show a lot of emotion
and and she has this joke
um that this is the expression that
somebody in in northern europe who's
excited has
this is the expression they have when
they're unhappy
yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah
yeah you just you just you just don't
you can't you can't see
uh what people feel i've done a lot of
presentations at conferences in norway
and it's super hard to get engagement
with the with the audience
but something that i found interesting
is doing workshops in this sort of way i
use a lot of liberating structures and
those kind of constructs
and i've actually found when i i teach a
lot of class i teach regular uh scrum
master classes in oslo
um and we get a lot of really good
engagement after the first few few hours
because you've got to get them warmed up
you know
rub them together to get them warmed up
once once they get warmed up and they're
doing lots of breakout rooms when they
do smaller breakout rooms they start
people start engaging right introverts
start engaging and then when you bring
them back to the main room they're still
in that engagement mode yeah
um so that that that really works so use
lots of breakout rooms lots of smaller
breakout rooms in those groups
yeah yeah
yeah
the more stoney-faced people are the
more breakout rooms you use
yeah that or
bring alcohol
yeah i live in scotland i'm not opposed
to that
not opposed to that
uh well this this was awesome hopefully
uh you have some things uh that you can
you can take back
um what i would love to do and i've lost
my little grid lines so i'll maybe put
uh
some on there but if you could um add a
couple of post-its to our little uh
board here for what weren't what worked
well
uh what needs to change
um
which one uh sorry it's just below the
one we were on i i i didn't want to
summon because people would yeah it's
just because people were still typing so
i didn't want to summon
um let me lock that there we go
i'll add
little boxes obviously hopefully the
mural things dropping behind
uh problem will get fixed
by uh by mural pretty soon
but it's been there for a week so you
know maybe they're struggling
um
the this session sometimes we have
a few people
like this this is probably a mid-sized
session for the definition of done one
last
two weeks ago we had about 24 people at
one point
and i think for the agile leadership we
had 34 people at one point for the agile
leadership one uh they're all they were
all recorded they're all available on uh
youtube
um
so you can go look back at the the old
exercise but obviously it's not as it's
not as fun watching it as it is being
there um
so that's that's why i see regular faces
coming back time after time because we
have lots of fun and trying to figure
new stuff out so if you do have uh
new ideas and topics
particular topics you would like
um
myself or anna and i to create uh little
workshops
on
uh
then we would happily happily do that
and it can be pretty much
pretty much any topic
that you like
um i
i i i'm not sure i can help you with
that with your product backlog there i
i've seen a lot of product backlogs that
look like that
at fubard
um
so
yeah
nexus next is an interesting one because
um
yeah it's i've i think i've there's the
scaled professional scrum class i've
taught it three times ever and i've been
able to teach it for nearly ten years
um and part of the reason for that is it
can't you cannot run it as a small class
you need a minimum of eight
to run the exercises because you need
two teams it's better with four teams so
it's better with 16
and not many people buy a scaling class
most of the time when organizations
contact me and they talk about scaling
i'm like how often do your teams deliver
working software at the end of the
sprint and they're like oh we can't do
that yet i'm like you don't want to talk
about scaling yet let's talk about doing
that first because if you try and scale
before you can deliver stuff well
that's going to suck even more so
and that's actually the first the first
exercise
in the the
the course is don't scale
is the first exercise in the course yeah
that's how you solve your problem don't
scale it's not a good idea
off the first rule of fight
first rule of the scaling a gel don't
yeah that is absolutely the first rule
so what what jeff sutherland would talk
about
is um
if if the difference between a mediocre
team
and a high performing amazing team is
about 400 percent
right so he'd rather take one team and
make them awesome than put four mediocre
teams together because you multiply
mediocrity with the complexities of of
scaling and working together with that
many people
so um yeah but unfortunately many big
organizations just throw a big group of
people at a problem
and expect it to just work out
right and it just doesn't so that's
that's the way it is
oh valuable daily scrum because we did
which one we did sprint review
we did a sprint review
uh uh set up and we did a definition of
done workshop so daily scrum in fact
that was the one you said earlier wasn't
it anna you said you wanted to do a
daily scrum one
yeah um and we're basically going with
that in our organization and we're
changing a lot of things about dailies
and we're going to do a workshop with
the whole organization not only the the
the
uh about daily
uh so maybe i can
maybe we can yeah maybe we can backport
that to yeah and to run as a workshop
then you'll be able to practice on your
on your company and see what works
yeah mo
yes carla
what the review and the definition of
donor yes so on um this is this is the
seventh
free workshop that i've done
um there all of the previous ones are
available on uh on youtube on on the the
naked agility youtube youtube channel
and
a couple of days ago
that is just fine so at the moment i'm
actually running a little uh competition
i think i know i know anna's already
signed up for it i think
but i'm running a little a competition
on my community uh site where you could
win a ticket
for either a psm a pspo a psk
professional scrum with kanban or uh
a
professional agile leadership with
evidence-based management
class yes it's a big mouthful that's
like the longest class ever
that class name um so on
let me get the link to put in the chat
but it's on my community
portal and i know i can't find it
it's here somewhere there it is
um let me get a link to that there it is
experiment wednesday
i put it up uh uh yesterday i'll pop it
in the chat
um
and it's a little competition uh to win
those four tickets to give away one for
each class
is the idea
and
wednesday yeah experiment wednesday uh
so you can you can sign up to that and
hopefully uh get a ticket those
classes are open and available anyway
they're just public classes
um and depending on which region you are
in the world you get different discounts
so if you take if you've taken a csm
this is a good one if you've taken a csm
and you want to do a psm
i'll give you a 70 discount
instead of you renewing your csm
membership there you go
that could be
if you have the scrum alliance and you
do the
scrum work then you get a 70 that's a
martin discount
so i'm i'm like if you go to another
trainer they won't be doing that right
but i so yes
yes so i do something called i call it
the professional scrum reruns
right that if anybody's taking a class
with me
they get a 70 discount if they want to
take it again because sometimes people
want to realign after a couple of years
they want to do it with a bigger class
or a different group of people it can be
a lot of fun anyway because we do it's
basically
14 hours of this sort of workshops right
over four half days uh so it's like a
little event um but if so i give people
who have taken a psm with me that
discount i also extend it to anybody who
has a csm
uh safe scrum master
uh
or
whatever else if you can prove to me
you've done a scrum master class um i'll
happily give you a 70 discount for
another one
uh listen
very very practical question when you go
to the experiment and then click the
link and then it it gives you what kind
of uh ticket you get
is that random or can i just refresh and
try to get the one i want
no so it's it's
okay so
yeah i understand what you're saying so
it's a it's a prize draw and there are
four prizes
so
you can't you're just entering into the
draw
um and if if two people one and two
people desperately wanted to do a psm
then i would probably swap out
the ticket they did win for a psm that's
okay
right i'm i'm i'm not going to be
an ass about it i'm going to be
reasonable
uh so if you if you want a psk and you
don't want to do a psk then i would
probably happily do you a different one
okay
so i just put four there's there's four
tickets up for grabs
oh okay there's four tickets up for
grabs i don't mind which class you come
into
oh yeah and actually it gives you also
the what ticket do you prefer after your
yes i did ask that as well just in case
and i've been looking at the stats for
that as well
cool all right
so uh thank you very much
everybody for your time thank you anna
for helping helping build and run
the workshop that's the second one we've
done together i think it's it's adding
value because she's keeping me on time
step by step
um
so all i hope to see you at the next one
which will be in two weeks which we have
not yet really decided what we're going
to do but it sounds like the daily scrum
is an interesting one for folks
um so maybe
there's a few people nodding so that
might be the one we pick
um
[Music]
doesn't matter it's good
yeah that i and
if there's any topics you do want just
let me know you can ping me on the
community site you can
uh ping me on
how to write a user story it's it's a
very nice topic
how to write a user story did i did i do
that one
no i didn't but i did i did a private
workshop the other day
on user stories
so i'm happy to repurpose that so we'll
put user stories on the list as well
um i don't know if it's an awesome one
but it is one
that makes sense
like sometimes we have to iterate on the
value and
that you actually get out of it
um but i can certainly run one
that might be more popular than the
daily scrum one
his user stories
so if anybody has any questions you're
happy to hang out but i'm gonna wrap it
up
um and
yeah it was it was awesome to have
everybody here and thank you very much
[Music]
you