is there a product Vision that lays out
the Strategic goals and do all members
of the team understand both and are they
able to see how the work that they do
every day contributes to your goals and
strategic objectives if you don't have
that story if you speak to the team and
you ask them what the vision is what the
Strategic goals are and they need to go
look something up then they don't
fundamentally
understand them and they don't
understand how their work contributes
which means that we're probably not
being very agile we need to push
responsibility down the organization we
need the people that are making the
tight technical decisions every day to
have the most context so they can make
the best decisions possible to maximize
the value that you get in your product