one of the key elements of caman is
improving making improvements or changes
to the system in order to see whether
you've manage to improve things or not
so we use metrics and visual tools to
enable us as humans to see patterns and
understand the data to increase
transparency so that we can make changes
to the system so that we can ask more
interesting questions of ourselves and
others that participate in our system so
improving the workflow is absolutely
critical if you're not making changes to
your workflow on a continuous basis
you're probably not doing caman if you
are making changes are you looking at
the right data do you have the right
visualizations to really be seeing
what's going on