there's a quote by uh Steve Denning um
being agile is about questioning what
you do and continuously improving what
you're doing and that that really is
that fundamental kernel of what's the
difference between um what people have
always done and what agile is talking
about we'd like people to do going
forward into the future and that's that
that question everything you do why you
do it value it
creates and if it doesn't
have value that it creates that's
greater than the pain of doing it then
you need to change what it is you're
doing and do things differently and and
and that is why we talk about or at
least Ken talks about scrum as a mirror
right I can't do scrum because here's
something you need to go fix in the way
your organization does business in order
to become more effective cuz the more
effective you are at adapting to
change the more chance you have of being
successful in your Market the more
chance you have of AD adapting around
whatever it is the market throws at you
the world throws at you or your
competitors throw at you and if you can
change and adapt faster than your
competitors can you'll be the one
setting the trend in the market you'll
be the one that they're following
um and you'll be the one um making
making the money first right and that's
that's ultimately what it's what it's
all about the the the the most
capitalistic
organizations are the ones that can
change as quickly as possible to take
advantage of Market opportunities right
that's what it's all about um so so so
be that be that ninja being able to to
dynamically change your business anytime
time you need and and for that you can't
do that you can't make those decisions
as a as a leader in an organization or
as a CEO right you have to have the
people that are um at every level in
your organization need to be looking at
the same thing they need to be not
following the rules they need to be
questioning the rules at every possible
moment they need to be there's a better
way to do this right that could be
faster and quicker maybe we don't need
to do this at all maybe we need to do it
differently um those are all the
questions that should we should be
constantly um asking and creating forums
within our
organization so that you can have those
things dealt with there's no point in
having all those questions asked and
then doing nothing about them cuz all
you do is end up with a bunch of
disgruntled people with working in your
organization who can see all the things
that need to be fixed but they're not
they can't fix them they don't have the
authority to fix them and nobody else
has the authority to fix them right or
nobody else wants to or senior
leadership doesn't doesn't care right
that's that's that's going to have a
massively negative impact on your
business so Focus
instead
about Focus instead on
on creating forums within your
organization where you can have those
legitimate
moments might be continuously where you
continuously look at and question the
things that are going on on the way you
do things uh the choices that have been
made right the decisions that have been
made so that you can
continuously have the best possible
version of your organization emerge over
time if you want to have a discussion
about your unique needs or situation
then please book a call or visit us at
naked agility decom uh we also have our
immersive and traditional public classes
on our website and we'd love to hear
from you