The Professional Scrum Product Owner is a
hands-on, activity-based course where students
explore Professional Scrum and develop an
understanding of the Product Owner’s critical
role on the Scrum Team.
Being a professional Product Owner encompasses
more than writing requirements or managing
a Product Backlog.
Product Owners need to have a concrete understanding
of all product management aspects, including
but not limited to product ownership, that
drives value from their products.
Being a Product Owner is a key position that
sets the tone for product leadership and the
definition of success in the organization.
As a Product Owner, modern product management
practices and mindsets are expected to be
put into practice daily.
The Product Owner is accountable for and has
the authority to maximize the value of the
product and the effectiveness of the Product
Backlog.
Our training is delivered as an interactive,
activity-based course over half-day sessions
using Microsoft Teams, and Mural.
Throughout the class, students learn several
Product Ownership practices that they can
use once they leave the classroom while also
receiving an introduction to Agile Product
Management.
Between sessions, we provide additional reading,
writing, and watching activities to maximise
the learning opportunities and complement
the classroom experience.
After the conclusion of the class, we provide
access to a community of peers and continued
access to the trainer through office hours,
quarterly catchups, and constant engagement.
All students are given a password to take
the PSPO1 assessment to maximise validated
learning.
If they take it within 14 days and are unsuccessful,
they will be granted a second attempt.
As part of our validated learning experience,
we provide a 30-minute learning review, a
one-hour coaching session, and access to future
courses at a 30% discount on future classes.