the professional scrum product owner is
a hands-on activity-based course where
students explore professional scrum and
develop an understanding of the critical
role that the product owner plays on
scrum team being a professional product
owner encompasses more than writing
requirements or managing a product
backlog
product owners need to have a concrete
understanding of all product management
aspects including but not limited to
product ownership that drives value for
their products
being a product owner is a key position
that sets the tone for product
leadership and the definition of success
in the organization
as a product owner modern product
management practices and mindsets are
expected to be put into practice daily
the product owner is accountable for and
has the authority to maximize the value
of the product and the effectiveness of
the product background
our training is delivered as an
interactive activity-based course over
half-day sessions using microsoft teams
and mural throughout the class students
learn a number of product ownership
practices that they can use once they
leave the classroom while also receiving
an introduction to agile product
management between sessions we provide
additional reading writing and watching
activities to maximize the learning
opportunity
and complement the classroom experience
after the conclusion of the class we
provide access to a community of peers
and continued access to the trainer
through office hours quarterly catch-ups
and constant engagement to maximize
validated learning all students are
provided with a password to take the
psp01 assessment
and if they take it within 14 days and
are unsuccessful we'll be granted a
second attempt as part of our validated
learning experience we provide a
30-minute learning review
a one-hour coaching session and access
to future courses at a 30 discount
[Applause]
[Music]
you