The question is, why do so few
Scrum Masters progress to the PSN two
or the PSN three certification?
And ultimately it's
because they don't care, right?
They didn't do it in order to
become better Scrum Masters
or to understand the depth
and breadth of being a Scrum Master.
Quite a lot of people do it
because they've either been told to do it,
right? Their
company has said,
go take this class.
Or
they took the class
in order to get a certificate.
I always know who those people are,
because the first thing they ask is,
"what happens with the exam?
What happens with the assessment?"
You know that that's all they care about.
They want the certificate
for a job interview or for
their professional development or
whatever it is their company's doing.
And those are ultimately not people.
They don't care.
I read this blog post once.
It was absolutely fantastic.
And it basically started with this phrase.
"If you're reading this, you're already
in the top 10% of all software engineers",
And what the author was getting at was
that there are so few people doing jobs
and work that they actually care about,
that they actually love,
that they're willing
to invest additional time,
perhaps outside of work,
in going and reading content,
on finding out what's going on,
on interacting with other people in
their profession
and learning more about it.
They just, I'm done with work.
We're done. I'll pick
it up tomorrow.
And I'm only going to do these
with stuff within work time.
And that's not
necessarily the type of person
that is looking to launch
their career in a particular direction,
that is looking to help
and benefit a bunch of people working
towards a common goal.
If you're interested
in those things, you're going to spend
the time to go listen to some podcasts
outside of work,
or during your commute.
Instead of watching
movies during your commute,
you're going to be listening to podcasts
and reading blog posts and learning more,
maybe perhaps reading some Agile books.
And those are the folks
that actually progressed to PSM2 and PSM3
because they're actually
interested in the content,
they're interested
in the topic, they're interested
in helping other people,
particularly for the PSM, right?
Because that's the
Scrum Masters accountability
is the effectiveness
of the team and the generation of value
within the context of the organization.
So how do they learn those
new things? How do they figure
out what it is they need to do?
one of my favorite expressions actually
from a good friend of mine,
David Starr, who now works
for Microsoft in the US, and he said,
what do violinists
and martial artists have in common?"
That was his question.
And you're kind
of like, well, I don't know.
Those seem like very different things.
But the answer is "they practice",
right?
That's how they get good
at what they do, is they practice.
When do we practice?
When do we get to practice our craft?
You tend to spend all day
at work fulfilling your craft.
Where's the time that you
spend on making your craft better,
on studying new ways of doing things,
of perhaps practicing some
of those things?
That's the type of person
that transitions to PSM-II and perhaps PSM-III,
right? Somebody
who's really interested
in diving deep, learning more,
and helping other people get better
at what they do by thinking
about how can they help
themselves be better at what they do.
Thanks for watching the video.
If you enjoyed it, please like,
follow and subscribe.
I always reply to comments
and if you want to have a chat about this please book a coffee with me through https://nkdagility.com