okay looks like we are online today in
my office hours I'm going to talk a
little bit about a new program that I
have for training as well as something
that I talked with Daniel Vacanti with
it the professional scrum with Kanban
class that we just had on Monday Tuesday
called continuous forecasting that can
help our software engineering team
during their daily scrum and part of
sprint planning to figure out more about
what's going on to you in a minute
naked agility is available for DevOps
and agile training and consultant
contact us for a free consultation
okay so um the things that I want to
talk about first off I'm here to answer
questions
every Wednesday I'm at 6 p.m. BST
British summer time I'm going to be
trying to keep to that schedule at 6
o'clock on Wednesdays we'll see how well
that goes I shared it deliberately so
that it didn't fit on top of any classes
that I was doing but hopefully it will
be ok
if you have any questions please put
them if you're talking if you're here
life watching life please add them to
the chat stream I should be able to see
chats as you add them they might be a
little bit of a delay but I should be
able to see them if you want me to
answer a question um next week Wednesday
6 p.m. then please ask the question
anyway and I'll get to it in whatever
the next weekly second is I keep are a
bunch of stickies here with the the
questions that I've been asked and what
what we're going to talk about and if
you have a question that you don't want
anybody to know that you've asked so you
want to do an anonymous question then
you can use this link right here and
fill out a form just one text box it
doesn't ask for any identification and
off you go
so that will be awesome remember as well
the easiest way to get to the schedule
for this is to use YouTube so you go to
my channel on YouTube which you will
find by just searching for Nick agility
on YouTube no problem at all
you might be wondering why I look a
little bit weird you might see my lovely
covert cut
and which isn't even even I think I've
not even got it even this was my first
attempt at a haircut for myself I was
looking more and more like Lemony
Snicket from a series of unfortunate
events so I decided that there there
needed to be some cottage
unfortunately the cut was not super
successful so you can have a nice laugh
in fact if I do a little spin is just as
bad at the back and oh my goodness me I
just saw the back for the first time and
yeah okey-dokey
so my wife will hopefully be fixing that
at some point so the things that I want
to talk about and I've been teaching all
of my classes virtually we've done two
PSFS
professional scrum foundations so far
professional agile leadership and
professional scrum master which I did
for a program at wiggling in Oslo as
well as a professional scrum with Kanban
that I taught on Monday Tuesday there so
and we're kind of getting spun up on the
ideas around how do we deliver classes
virtually and I've got my set up
everybody seems to have their own set up
which is fine if whatever works for each
individual trainer and their students
I've been using Microsoft teams to
manage that and it's been working really
well because you know teams doesn't just
have you know you're on a call and then
you have breakout rooms it has
persistence and it has files it has
permissions it has a way for me to share
and interact with students on a
long-term basis and what I've been doing
and when you add a event to team
everybody in the team is invited if
you're added to the team later you get
invited so it's really handy for me as a
trainer I can just add people and to the
team and then they get all of the the
things they need to figure out how to
join the class I had to get in so what
I've been doing is kind of the week
before the class I
doing a tech check so that's been sent
out and we've gone over how to connect
two teams correctly because there is
more than one way to connect two teams
if you just click a meeting link and
you're probably coming in as an
unauthenticated user which means you
have very restricted permissions you can
participate in the meeting but you can't
access any of the other assets in the
organization which makes perfect sense
and however when I'm running the class
we use multiple channels for breakout
rooms we upload files we have
applications and tabs that give the
students some extra information or some
extra interactivity so we need students
to come in as an authenticated user and
depending on how they're doing that it
depends on how much of a struggle that
is and usually it's perfectly fine if
you're somebody who gives me to add the
email address that is your corporate
identity same as you would log in to
office 365 in your company then and you
will just have a completely seamless
experience using you use your corporate
login and I don't have to have any login
details at all just your email address
you accept the invitation and then
you're able to come in so that works
works really well you effectively just
log in in the same way that you would if
you were if you were coming in from AK
to one of your own corporate systems so
that works great the other option is
people use a Microsoft account so they
already have an outlook.com or xbox comm
or a hot meal and address that they've
had for many years they can give me that
they log in with their credentials and I
don't need to store any credential still
they'll log in with them and that's fine
and then the third one is and you still
need a Microsoft account to actually try
to get onto our Google and the Google
meet at the other day and you have to
provide Google credentials so I have an
email address that's enabled for Google
even though it's not a Google email
address and you can do the same thing
with Microsoft so you can take any email
address that's not a corporate identity
and not currently a Microsoft identity
so it could be you know your your gmail
account or Yahoo or AOL or whatever that
is and if I add that email address you
when you go to log in and claim the the
identity will be asked to follow some
steps to enable that it's usually pretty
straightforward but it sometimes just
takes a little bit of explaining and so
we do a tech check the week before and
it's probably 30 minutes depending on
the level of knowledge that users
already have with teams but I've not had
any problems so far teaching all the
classes the other thing that we go
through is mural and we use a tool
called mural which is a digital
whiteboarding tool and it works pretty
well it has its own idiosyncrasies just
like any tool out there and there's
mural as well as mural and there's a
couple of other tools out there that
folks women using whatever works and as
long as I like to be able to provide the
output so that the students can continue
to go and view the work that was done on
those services and so I download the
files upload them to the team and then
students can continue to get access
which is pretty good the other thing
that I've been doing as well as the tech
check before is something that I'm
called I'm kind of calling reification
where we're going to work together to
solidify some of the ideas and so I've
only built it as an error at the moment
two weeks after the class and ultimately
ultimately
effectively when you when you takes
class from scrum de-torque through
myself you get two attempts whatever
assessments you get at the end
assessments while not being valuable to
identify somebody else's skill level it
might be useful in understanding your
own skill level and what are the areas
where you might want to go read up and
figure out so the idea is that students
get two weeks to take the assessment and
if they fail they get another attempt
but only if they take it within two
weeks so the idea is my reification
session which is just let's let's
discuss the things you don't know or
that you've tried to do some things in
your organization what what are the
problems that you've hit and just spend
an hour hitting on whatever questions
that folks from that particular class
have so that's a new experiment that I'm
running to see if we can't add value
there and I think that would be sounds
like I just think it's gonna be a lot of
fun it's a very easy value add and in
the circumstance of we're all at home
anyway and I've been booking in over
lunchtime UK time so I would do you know
be conscious of other people's time
zones so if I'm teaching in PST at
Pacific time then I'm not going to book
it at lunch side my time because you'd
still be in bed but I'm going to do that
so I might experiment with some
additional engagements with students
after the class and but hopefully this
will work out and then we'll be able to
add a bunch more so that comes to and
the thing that I was going to talk about
which is continuous or casting um so
that's the only thing on my list today
it was something that came up during the
professional scrum with Kanban and it's
the idea that in in the scrum guide
there is nothing which says you have to
plan your whole sprint it says that you
have to have enough of a plan coming out
of your
and sprint planning to get started
that's all you need you need enough of a
plan to get started remember the team is
going to inspect their progress towards
their sprint goal every 24 hours at the
daily scrum and they're going to adapt
that plan as the goal so maybe we don't
need to plan the whole sprint and figure
out what all the tasks are maybe we just
need to start with a smaller plan
something you know the next couple of
days worth of work and then we're going
to build on that as we go I would maybe
take the current day plus two more same
as we use with planning the in the
product backlog and that will allow you
to to dynamically understand what you
can do and and maybe pull extra things
into your backlog maybe push some things
out depending on how things are going
and do that dynamically now one of the
tools to help with that and it's my
belief and that professional scrum teams
use the the the metrics from the Kanban
guide for scrum teams so they're going
to be using throughput they're going to
be using cycle time they're going to be
using work and process and they're going
to be using and work item aging those
are the four metrics that every
professional scrum team should be
collecting and if you're collecting that
data you would be able very easily to do
a for example Monte Carlo simulation I
think I have just an example and I'm
slight with a picture of a Monte Carlo
simulation from Daniels two-way
did that work yes it did oh let me just
put
you
that you want to add to this section I
am happy to take any questions and I see
that there at least I can't see and any
questions coming in on the channels let
me see if there's anything in the
anonymous there is not anything new in
the anonymous feedback either and I
think this will pick up once I get on a
regular schedule but hopefully you find
this useful to talk about continuous
forecasting and the ideas around having
a reification and a tech check for my
training so if you are looking for
training you can go to naked agility
comm that's where I list all of my
training classes and all the classes I'm
running at the moment are at scrum
dot-org accredited classes and so the
the official classes from scrammed and
org with assessments so please go there
and have a look if you want a private
class obviously we're not doing on-site
classes just now we can't really go
anywhere but we are doing at live
virtual classrooms I'm teaching a PSK
not PSK
professional scrum foundations class m
in dublin next week and then in
Pleasanton California the week after so
if you want private classes we can
deliver private classes pretty much
anywhere in the world in any timezone
and we just may need some preparation if
it's a crazy time zone I have one coming
up in New Zealand so that's going to be
a very tiring maybe experience or at
least it's gonna feel like I've get jet
lag for a couple of days as we figure
that out so please get in touch and
obviously if you want to ask your
question anonymously you can use this
link here on the screen and please
subscribe to our channel so that you
know when we go live and when we're
talking about things okay thank you very
much
naked agility is available for DevOps
and agile training and consultant
contact us for a free consultation