what what is Scrum scrum is a social
technology
that allows groups of people to organize
around a common purpose
it's specifically designed to work in
complex space and that may be a bit of a
weird term so complex is when you know
less at the beginning then you
understand while doing it right so
usually the things that you do are
unrepeatable
um you're doing different things all the
time stuff you've never done before
whenever there's a there's a huge
variation in how long you think it's
going to take and how long it actually
takes that's complex and scrum is
specifically designed to operate in that
in that space or at least the edges of
that space