when we're engaging with
customers especially new customers one
of the things we we we try and be 100%
clear
on is that we're not going to solve your
problem all of the messes all of the
issues are yours to
fix but what we can
do is we can um help you see the problem
s and keep a little bit of focus on
those problems so that you can solve
them right we're we're we're bringing
the Torches so that we can see what's
going on shine a light in those those
dirty Corners where are the under the
rug where we've been sweeping uh um the
dust right and point at that and say
look we need we need to resolve this
this is causing you problems this is
slowing you down this is costing you
money right and help those organizations
um Get Better by helping them figure out
like what are your options quite often I
I think it's it's really
interesting how
many
organizations and
Engineers I'm going to include engineers
in this because I think it's true there
too um
we tend to not get a lot of
training right you don't I don't see
organizations sending their Engineers on
coding courses I don't see them sending
them on product courses I don't see them
sending them on API courses I don't see
them sending them on security courses I
don't see them sending they don't they
don't do that so almost everyone of your
engineers is self-taught
right and when you're self-taught
you learn something within the bounds of
what you looked at and we stop looking
when we find an answer right it's like
when you're looking for your keys in
your house right if you've lost your
keys and you're looking for them you
don't find your keys and then keep
looking right you don't find them and go
I think I'll look a little bit more in
case I find more keys No I found them so
I'm going to stop looking right so
they're always in the last place you
look and that same is true for knowledge
when we find an answer most of us stop
looking and use that answer but perhaps
there are five better
answers perhaps there are five
progressively better answers that we
could be finding and that's the value of
bringing in sometimes somebody from the
outside to look at what it is you're
doing and how you can be more effective
at it is that experience knowledge and
experience I've been doing devops
probably the best way to describe it
doing devops before it was since before
it was called devops was called
application life cycle management uh
before then and I've I've been looking
at that for for 20 years um I've been a
software engineer for 20 years I've been
a a a scrum coach and consultant for 10
years seeing what all of these
organizations out there are doing and
seeing the things that work for them and
the things that don't cuz not every
organization does everything well they
might do some stuff well and other stuff
not so much right um means that we can
bring a whole bunch of
ideas have you thought about this have
you looked over
here here's a tool that you could use to
get you started in the
space Oh if that tool doesn't work for
you here's the type of tool you're
looking for right and that provokes
people to go look for Alternatives look
for other ways to do things look for
Solutions and perhaps they'll find their
own ones that are even better than the
ones that we came up with but that
process is something that you and your
people have to do so when you're
engaging um as for devops we're going to
help you understand where you are right
now um help work with you to understand
what direction you want to
go and help you keep moving in that
direction but it's you and your people
that have to do the work because it's
you and your people that have to learn
the things institutionally you know that
um institutional knowledge that an
organization gets that when you bring in
new people although they come in with
their own ideas they learn that
institutional knowledge you want that
institutional knowledge to be moving in
that direction right the the the weight
of progress is in the direction that you
want to go which is
not building up a whole bunch
of refinement and work you've not done
it's doing those things and doing it
properly and not actually doing things
well well and we can help you keep
progress in those directions