hello welcome to another episode of
agile actually my name is Simon rindle
professional scrum trainer agile coach
entrepreneur author uh with me is my
friend and colleague Martin Henwood
hello Martin how you doing hey Simon
how's it going also professional scrum
trainer camand trainer entrepreneur
coach MVP of Microsoft uh yeah and all
all around good chap
mostly mostly okay you're human right we
all have all right moving swiftly on uh
this episode we were thinking about
stuff that was going down in the world
and we thought it would be interesting
to discuss ethics and
Agility uh ethics being uh moral
principle of doing the right thing so
the understanding the difference between
right and wrong wrong and acting on it
and Agility being the whole movement
like all of it where Frameworks whatever
the industry that is become agile
helping organizations deliver better
value more
quickly is it possible for an
organization to be agile and
unethical have there ever been examples
of organizations behaving in an
unethical
way are there consequences to organiz
ations doing that um
discuss um what's your thoughts
Martin I I think it's a very um I think
it's a very gnarly issue because there
are loads of things
that people believe to
be
ethical that aren't or maybe maybe maybe
I'm wrong in the way I'm phrasing that
maybe there are just lots of people who
don't understand ethic that's possibly
possibly possibly what it could be
because I I think there's there's doing
things unethically and not understanding
that you're being unethical and then
there's deliberately doing something
unethical that you know is unethical
Okay so we've got conscious and
unconscious ethical Behavior yeah I'd
also like to call out that you use the
term Nar in the context of complex as
opposed to Nar as in cool um oh I did
not know I had another I was thinking
Nali in um certain uh subcultures means
really cool okay was not aware of that
that's age thing I'm not sure well I
think I'm older than you so yeah thanks
for that
um all right so do you think most
businesses operate with a moral
compass oh not sure I like that word
most
well I'm putting some uh well should do
you want me to Rattle through the
businesses that have at one time or
another executed a poor or ambiguous
moral choice that I'm aware
of sure I could probably maybe I could
add to that list or maybe I'm just
thinking of the same companies as you
are yeah okay um so Ford with their
Pinto release they consciously released
a car that would probably cause deaths
um the Ford Mundo pulled to the left
under heavy breaking uh Rena with the
Bonnet catch that would fly up
okay um how about Exon right we really
want to like this will get everybody uh
running for covers uh really dangerous
one Exxon had evidence that the oil
industry would cause climate change in
1970 and pay
to suppress the information and
discredit the
information
yep
I Y there is climate change Exon one of
the biggest o companies knew about it
actionably invested in misinformation
around
it yep I'm pretty sure the tobacco
companies can be put on that list as
well for the same same style of action
yeah at a certain point they became
aware
that smoking wasn't so good for you
right yep gone with the adverts that
dentist put out that smoking was good
for you and doctors that helped you with
your asthma
right um how about this um diabetes and
sugar addiction kills three times more
people than smoking in
America and it's heavily regulated in a
way that promotes
it corn syrup is
in everything everything
us
um what about uh zoom's changing of its
uh user policy that if you continue to
use zoom you agree for it to sample some
of
your right that was the the update was
that um they would be able to consume
all of use have their AI consume all of
that content to learn off your your
conscience
interesting well here's here's a here's
a personal beef of mine I got autobanned
from playing Call of Duty by installing
a new
mouse so Activision have banned my
profile from playing Call of Duty
because I installed Logitech Suite of
gsync
and it's on a ban list and so my my
account got banned which means I'm not
able to use a product not not for
cheating but Logitech uh Activision
don't tell you that you can't use that
or corsair's IQ or a couple of other
things and they known false positives
but because they're making so much money
they're not adopting their Ricochet
system and they just autoban people it's
it's a thing is that ethical take
someone's money and then ban
them yep that's
bad um
so what about boing what about
boing uh
boing um
deliberately made a business choice to
focus on shipping rather than
quality are you talking about the 737
Max 737 Max is definitely so allegedly
allegedly we have to use that term
otherwise we'll be bankrupt um I this is
a I'm I'm very keen on Aviation um the I
think the ethical challenge is Boeing
very much knew the behaviors of the 737
Max and they made a particular feature
optional and didn't educate about it
you'll find the airlines that suffered
those crashes did not educate their air
crew properly on the operation of the
equipment uh yes however they we're not
told that there was a change to the
operation equipment um yeah allegedly so
yeah the there's there's it's it's
dubious ground right yep yep absolutely
do you launch a product that is
potentially
dangerous well we don't have all the
facts so um the Activision one I know is
true and you can't see me because you've
done it to me that's personal I didn't
cheat you banned me what's wrong wrong
um what about
meta um meta's harvesting of data from
since they bought WhatsApp well also
harvesting of data into C Cambridge
analytics as well right wow that's well
that's proven right because they paid
the fine yeah yeah yeah okay so U let's
stop before we end up being in some yeah
big trouble so that that's stuff that we
know about that we're picking up from
papers or personal
experience it's very easy for companies
either consciously or unconsciously to
behave in a pretty shoddy
way do you think they intended to do all
this stuff or is it some Curious happen
stance rush to go to
live I think it I think it depends from
which perspective you look at it I I I
do
believe
in all of those circumstances that we've
talked about if there was indeed
wrongdoing that takes care of our
allegedly right if there was indeed
wrongdoing somebody knew about it
somebody
understood the problem and the
ramifications and either chose not to
act or
chose to act in a way that had that
negative outcome
right what would drive that motivation
I'm trying to lean here into the the
whole curiosity with positive intent
because I don't think anybody gets out
of well the majority of people don't get
out of bed to just kind of break the
world right you're you're turning up to
work to do your thing and we're talking
about major corporations we're not
talking about you know organized crime
or anything because obviously there's
there's there's real intent there to
harm people um just make loads of money
um so with these major corporations what
could possibly influence somebody to
make a decision like that what what
would drive
them people tend to behave how they're
measured right so if somebody is under
significant pressure to deliver
something they
may cut
Corners um they
may falsify data there's been enough
number of cases especially in the
medical world where data on the the the
the the ramifications of of drugs either
um sweeping side effects under the
carpet or um making a drug look like it
works when it doesn't by fudging the
data and because people are put under a
lot of pressure to deliver something
yeah yeah
so it's what I'm hearing is that it's a
financial impact comperative right
because medicines in particular are
horrendously expensive to come up with a
new one yeah so and that that pressure
to deliver that's that's what got um
cyberpunk 277
right did you hear about that game yeah
the game uh that had that that um issue
so there's an interesting example with
cyberp Punk
277 perhaps not ethical but an example
of releasing a product too
because of that that Financial
imperative and there's documented
evidence on YouTube of developers
showing what the flaws were product were
desperate to hit a particular release
date and it it didn't it wasn't working
so well sometimes there's a lot of money
on their line right that that they're
going to start losing a lot of money if
they aren't able to actually release the
product um and and those ramifications
put people under a lot of pressure um I
imagine for examp example that was the
the driving factor for Zoom at the start
of the pandemic right where they they
deliberately
made I don't know if I have to say
allegedly for that one allegedly made
changes in the product in order to
increase the stability and scalability
of the product but reduce users
security um and not to tell users and to
actively um I don't know how to describe
it what is it when you create a
situation where it looks like it's doing
the thing but it's not doing the thing
masking masking masking the fact that
they they had done it um the the
endtoend encryption and you still had
the green light even though they turned
the encryption service on off
behind the scenes in order to support
more users because I think for
encryption you lose about 40% of your
performance right with encryption on so
that gave them that boost but instead of
making it transparent and clear uh to
the users that that's what they were
doing you know and for the reason right
um it was kind of all hidden um which is
unethical okay
um is it possible
to work in a professional agile
way and be
unethical I
don't
remember reading anything
in the agile
Manifesto that
guarantees
ethics it focuses largely on teams
collaborating and delivering value to
the
customer so defining your Market
segment uh your target audience and your
customer could allow some ambiguous
behavior and you could apply all the
principles of the ago Manifesto in an
unethical industry so let's push it to
the extreme um fishing centers they're
huge right there's organizations around
the world that um massively Target
fishing emails fishing texts you know
the WhatsApp scams the
um they they blanket hundreds of
millions billions of people and they
need a very low bite rate to actually
make themselves profitable that's that's
how the crime Works y um they're
amazingly responsive right every time
you know they the the in yeah they're
they're they're it iterating almost un
real time on the the the the copy the
opens the links the security people are
uh blocking their stuff and they're
continuously iterating I don't know how
many emails I get with fake remittance
advice or as a company right you get
fake remittance advice you get all all
these things that some of them look like
legitimate emails like somebody just
asking you question but even if they're
just fishing for you to click a link and
validate that the email is actually a
real email it's still a fishing attempt
right yeah yeah and then there's uh your
Amazon account's going to be closed is
the latest one that's heading my inbox
um uh
your security software subscriptions out
of date um you know your could send that
out for your your your Microsoft
security subscription and you're going
to hit a large body of people who who
are like that could be me right yeah
yeah yeah and you just need that little
bit of uncertainty so billing has
expired yeah yeah you're going to lose
everything um so what we're saying is
that you can apply the product aspects
of
agility in any context at
all and so really is up to you driving
the product
process to choose to act in an ethical
way or not and I know in the in the PSM
course for instance we explore an an
ethical issue where you misrepresent
what can be done at a certain amount of
time yeah yep um which is ethical and we
tease that out in the psm3 assessment as
well so
that need for uh awareness
of ethical behaviors there there's
nothing in the the guide books the
Frameworks the rules of agile that says
you need
to do do good for the world right well
sure and I think it's it's definitely
interesting so I have
um my my MVP my Microsoft most valuable
professional comes with an
Ethics guide like uh uh you you agree to
comply by these these epics as part of
this this
award um but I think I I do remember I
do remember a time uh me many many years
ago I think I was on the job
maybe was it my second second
gig um 2001 2002 around that time and I
was working for as shows my age as a new
media
agency right before uh just after the
dot bubble burst um and I was asked I
had a um so I was probably
22 and I was asked to um create an
application that took in a list of uh
first name surname and Company um and
generated guest at what their email
might be based on comp common company
formats um and then emailed those emails
with a you know in those days you could
really do the opened right because there
wasn't so much security around it um to
to to find people's email addresses I
was that's one of the things I was asked
to do um at the company I was at and did
you do no I ref I refused to do it
absolutely abjectly refused to do it and
I kind
of
I I I I lied about why I didn't want to
do
it so I didn't want to do it because I
thought it was unethical that's why I
didn't want to do it but at 22 I don't
think I had the balls to say I don't
want to do this because it's unethical
yeah because if I say that it implies
that I think the other person's being
unethical right Jud yeah yeah that could
that could be that could be an
accusation and it was the the Sales
Direct that was asking me to do
it but what I did
see which I guess kind of didn't really
get around that but um I I think I was a
BCS member British computer Society M
and the British computer Society also
comes with a with an Ethics ethics guide
I think my membership had expired at
this point right but I claimed that my
my my contract my membership of the BCS
was based on compliance with a set of
rules and I said that this this would
break that set of rules so I wouldn't be
able to do it um so that's a
really good practical
tip is regardless of your organization
like if if you're a a computer person is
there a computer organization like the
British computer society that has that
code of ethics I know as professional
scrum trainers we've got a code of
ethics as an MVP you've got the code of
ethics if you do any coaching training
there's coaching ethics from the ICF if
you do facilitation stuff there's ethics
there
is whatever your profession is there
will probably be a professional body
that can offer you a code of
conduct to help you negotiate your way
through the moral
mace yeah because I not
everybody
I'm just I'm thinking that's why I
paused not not not
everybody has the same ethical
boundaries I think well there's there's
some there's some grounds that is very
personal right and we see that um being
played out in society like you uh
there's
very strong issues that they generate
really really strong response and some
of it's supported by the media some of
sure but some of it's just just some of
it some of it's supported by by other
things that people ascribe to that they
feel that other some things are
encroaching we're trying to avoid saying
you know religion and various bits and
Bobs right but are things that are
antagonistic what's societal Norm versus
my group norms and how how how do they
mush together and what do I what what do
I follow and what do I try and impose
upon others right person personal Ms
personal beliefs right
yeah however they come about right yeah
it's it's like how do how do you well
it's up to you how you balance that um
obviously you'll make a choice when you
join and work for certain corporations
that work with certain
industries um I know some people would
choose not to work with
tobacco for instance energy companies
um defense manufacturers other things
like that like there the people will say
no I'm not going to go and work with
them gambling is another one so some
people some people won won't work with
with gambling companies uh cannabis
companies in the states struggle uh with
their cash flow because they're many of
the credit card companies many of the
banks won't because it's federally I
think it was I don't know if it is just
now but last time I
was
exploring those ethical ideas or at
least Aon in news it was federally
illegal so none of the federal banks
would touch it but state-based it was
legal but the banks have to operate
across Federal boundaries and they had
all they they couldn't they couldn't so
they had all this cash on premises so
they were getting robbed right because
everybody knew oh they've got all this
cash and they can't because they can't
take cards so it has to be cash and then
they can't go put it in the bank because
their business can't do that so they've
got all this cash on the premises and
they were getting robbed so that's
that's
almost they're doing it for ethical
reasons they're their own personal
ethical reasons and causing an unethical
situation which is yeah it's the the
Curious conundrum you get when you have
you know legal ju the position that's
you know let's not go into yeah yeah
don't don't yeah we're not going to go
dancing down that rat hole
um um so we can be ethical how we behave
we can behave towards each other
ethically and be working on a product
that is arguably unethical by someone
else's standards there are
some grounds that some people would
argue that for instance working in a
fishing company uh not as in fishing for
fish but as in the fraudulent Fishing
Company um is the right thing to do
because often they're in disadvantaged
Nations it's a way for them to provide
for their
families uh it's that or sta so it's an
ethical choice they either do that or
the family staff so for them it's better
that they work for that you know that
that ethical choice to them it might
appear cut and dried to us that it's not
on but to them
them it's a way of stopping their loved
ones go hungry right yeah I think I
think I've always had a strong ethical
Compass of what I will and won't
do um that comes a little bit from from
Asbergers right folks with Asbergers
tend to be very it's it's it's either
true or it's not it's either FAL it's
true it's right or it's wrong right um
and I think that has set me in good
stead but also got me in a lot of
trouble as well
because I don't think refusing to do
that work when I was 22 inured me to
that company right no and that's an
interesting thing is that if something's
challenging your code of
ethics is it okay to
walk and I would suggest if something is
really against your code of ethics or
your
values the ethical and right thing for
you to do is to walk yeah and that way
you m at least you maintain truth to
yourself yeah well and it but it also
depends on whether like you might not
walk from the whole company but you
might just walk from that particular
situation yeah right cuz it might not be
a company ethics thing it might be a
specific situation ethics uh for that
particular company I feel like um it was
it was the whole thing I just didn't see
it from where I was if that makes sense
MH that it it wasn't wasn't an
unusual thing to happen um but also it
was the time 2001
2002 people didn't really necessarily
understand
not everybody especially if you weren't
an IT person right didn't necessarily
understand that that that ethical in the
software space because software's not
really been around that long I mean it
has been around what 70 or 80 years
right um
but everybody in the world needing to
understand software and the choices and
the implications is a relatively new
thing well um
having access to mass
data
having concerns like privacy like before
if you if you wanted to growing up I'm
not sure whether this thing growing up
in
Australia everybody had their name and
phone number listed in the phone
book yep because if you want to Define
someone you went to the phone book right
yep whereas now you actively work to
make sure
sure not in the phone
book and register it with in the UK
there's a telephone preference service
where you can register it and make sure
that your electoral role it's
acknowledged so that finance companies
know you're on the Electoral role but no
one else can find it out Y and it's
interesting the Electronic Frontier
Foundation they've been around since
before the internet was a big thing so
mid 90s the eff have been fighting for
trying to get balance on the internet
and to maintain some Fidel
but um how do we maintain the signal so
that it's greater than the
noise yeah I don't know is is the answer
I see a lot of
noise um and especially on on on social
media right
because I don't know I don't know I
don't know why that I think it's because
people are hidden as well people feel
like they can be unethical when there's
nobody there to judge
them that nobody knows who they are
right oh you've just triggered to me you
know how I think in memes and metaphors
right um two things popped up the the
classic XK CD uh someone is wrong on the
internet y there's the the comic where
you just look at that through your
favorite search engine it'll come up
like bang XKCD someone's wrong on the
internet and it's like I'm just
correcting somebody's wrong on the
internet and uh the other one is I think
because Mike Tyson who said it uh social
media created this space where people
thought they could talk nonsense without
getting a punch in the head yeah yeah
yeah you know something to somebody's
face and you say something so horrendous
that they could give you a punch in the
face so you you you there was that built
in res what people say that that
prevented you from from from doing that
people's faces but then on the internet
where it's a free-for-all and nobody
knows who you are and you can create a
fake account um it's it's very easy to
say things with no ramifications
whatsoever so what do people say when
there's no ramifications
whatsoever this is the what was it when
Microsoft put the AI bot up a few years
ago that it happened twice so the first
time they they they they built an AI bot
they connected it to Twitter and within
a few hours the bot became misogynistic
racist and aggressive and they had to
turn it off um and then they tried again
I think a couple of years later they
they'd work been working on these
filters for for a couple of years um and
they tried it again and it took 24 hours
this time to become racist misogynistic
and aggressive it was it was it was
threatening to come around and kill
people um within 24 hours and it's it ai
ai is not
AI
like it's a funny thing to say but a AI
that we have is not like AI in the
movies right AI in the movies is
artificial intelligence AI that we have
just now is um a an
interpretive system it's collecting all
of the data that exists within a
particular topic and then rationalizing
that down to what are the patterns in
that data and reproducing those patterns
right so it's it's it's a trained
suggestion engine it's not it's it's not
a yeah if if you suddenly think of
Terminator and a self-aware intelligent
identity walking around doing stuff or
I'm I'm really old and and there was a
great BBC science fiction program called
Blake seven and there was a super
cool yeah yeah talks about Blake seven
yeah yeah so go and look at up it was
brilliant it was really well done um but
there was this superc computer called
orac which was this uh perspect box with
some lights in it and it was self-aware
right it was fully intelligent you
know Ziggy from uh Quantum
Leap I'll take your away for it missed
that one uh but yeah but that's why not
it's it's modeling right it's yeah it's
modeling so if you plug it into Twitter
the AI will reflect the sentiment on
Twitter so it became a racist
misogynistic horrible person right
because that's how people are act there
are there are people who are being nice
on Twitter but the majority of stuff on
Twitter is people being nasty to each
other with no repercussions imagine it
if they did it now when a lot of the
checks and balances have been taken out
of X as it is now
known yeah I I and I
think if the thing I always think about
like the moral and ethical part right
should they be taking those checks and
balances out the the the the the the
part that I find more
interesting is
that H
humans also do some of what AI does
current current
AI is not doing what humans do but what
AIS are doing humans also do we we we
collect a bunch of information we uh uh
surf it for patterns pull out the things
that patterns that we connect with and
then that becomes part of ourselves
which is why we lazy load right we lazy
load and we generalize well it's it's
it's ultimately why uh magically we're
all we're always born into our religion
right that's the the the the thing where
the data we're absorbing
as we're growing up is the thing that
creates that that mental mindset that
we're in
therefore we're we're we're always in
the perfect religion for us because
that's the one we've been taught and
it's the same thing if if if you're
engaging with um a bunch
of nasty mean
people you're going to start talking and
acting in a nasty mean way well it's
that tribal drive right and if we yeah
okay so we we as humans have a desire to
be part of a group if we're surrounded
in a group that are behaving in a poor
way how do we become self-aware that
it's
poor and what do we do about the
situation so then this comes back to
ethics being subjective right the the
the what's what's one
person's bad
thing is another
person's it's fine
thing probably not not best words to use
but but there there's some general
trends
of of
what uh really poor behavior is and this
is where I you know reflect on asimov's
laws right yeah Mo most people
I probably feel comfortable with that
statement most
people are physically
upset when are physically affected in a
negative
manner when they
see another human or even another
animal being subjected to some kind of
pain right yep Mo most people are are
are upset with that and
even animal you you could see that in
the animal kingdom with each other as
well right they're they're usually
hunting to eat they're not yeah they
don't play with their food right yeah um
well except cats but they're Psychopaths
um yeah well this this is like cats and
humans are the only ones that torture
other things right yeah so that that
there
is inherent
moral and ethical rout sub
routines in humans that are triggered by
by those things that's probably part of
how animals survive right Humanity
survives is because we have helped each
other what was the the there was a a
lady she was a um
Anthropologist and she was asked I don't
remember any of the names for this but
she was asked
um what was the
first indication that humans when when
when did humans become not animals but
uh uh uh sentient what was the first
sign of
sentients and it was a
uh a repaired broken
bone oh tools no so this is this is this
is yeah this is when we actually
look after a weak person right so when
we actually looking after a weak person
taking care of somebody till they're
they're bone had healed and then they
were able to be productive again and
that was
her moment that that that that's that's
what they're looking for when they look
back in in in history um for whether
this group
was sentent or not right so um I chall I
wouldn't say sentient but I'd say
civilized I'm the wrong words yeah so I
I'd say civilization that that was the
point that yeah the first say of
civilization you're right that's that's
that's exactly the phrase that I would
that I was trying to get to but couldn't
yeah thank you um so really if we're
thinking about it is basically that
first law of azimov which is um a robot
may not injure a human being or through
in action allow a human being to come to
harm so basically if we use that as the
ultimate
imperator that is the ethical boundary
but then immediately we're hit with the
Escape Clause of what if you're in
defense of your own and that is where
the military come into play because they
sure but
they're you know that's that's the in
extremist that's the straw man argument
right but dayto day most of us don't
have to go around and MIM or injure or
no not until theoc through we'll be fine
no so okay we're all good till the
zombie apocalypse yeah [__] just has
to be any form of Apocalypse right yeah
so um well we found out through coid in
the UK that the first consequence of
Apocalypse is we run out of toilet
paper second consequence is I can't buy
a webcam that was the second consequence
of of Co yeah yeah I can't buy a chip
cuz uh for my graphics card cuz
everyone's crypto
mining everybody's crypto mining from
home yeah I think I think that that
that that
core moral and ethical code although for
some people it appears to be broken
right but in general for that core maybe
some people have overridden it they
still have it but they've overridden it
yeah um and some people definitely don't
have it that's for sure there psychop
that is
just statistically statistically a very
it's an extreme outlier they're beyond
the three standard deviations they're
the you know serial killers get a lot of
publicity because they're so rare right
yeah yeah than and yeah uh but the the
the beyond that people humans have an
inbuilt moral and ethical Compass which
means that if if if
somebody this is why you get
whistleblowers right people people are
making are making
decisions that go
against their moral and ethical and it's
learned or imposed Behavior yeah that's
overriding their
inbuilt and it's that sense of Do no
harm right and I think that's the
essence of the first law is we do no
harm we don't make the situation worse
for others now occasionally we will be
in a
system where that whole system is built
to take
advantage and at what point is the
checkout you know because ultimately
social
systems require some transactions some
people are going to come off better some
going to come off worse at what point do
you check out of the
system
yeah but also at at at what
point
do do the
rules imposed upon
people the system that's created
right um impose unreasonable constraints
so we we
create there's two forms of this right
one is one is obvious it's it's the law
right we create
systems to
impose and I'm using impose Loosely mhm
threat of punishment right so it's an
imposition to impose certain
behaviors yeah yeah Bas on societal Norm
right so yeah depending upon your
country that there's different policing
models to be very philosophical about it
and you know in a lot of the western
world it's policing by consent um where
they they're just a reminder some of
them um yeah okay Rat Hole Rat Hole Rat
Hole yeah yeah Rat Hole police by
consent versus police by enforcement
yeah
um there some social Ms or boundaries
they could be laws there could be some
social Ms or behavior codes um that's
the way our Tri RS um that that's like
my my MVP code of conduct or the BCS
conduct or the scrum.org C code of
conduct these are all um um they're not
expected I think the the the core thing
with those those types of things those
codes of conduct is that they're not
expected to be
broken right yeah like the doctor's
hypocritic o right just be the default
even if we didn't ask you anything even
if we didn't tell you about it we don't
expect you to do any of those things
yeah it's like here here table Stakes
don't be a dick yeah cuz I I I I I read
a lot of these codes of conduct and I'm
like yeah why would anybody do those
things just seems like a no-brainer that
that that you wouldn't you wouldn't do
those things but you know some of them
some of them are a little bit more
strict than others right um especially
when you that oh well that's probably a
rat hole as well
imposed
um how how what's the
word imposed speech right or
imposed uh uh ideas that you're you're
it's not necessarily A that core thing
but you're kind of forced to do that
thing there there's a few things like
that I've seen in codes of conduct
um that that maybe are starting to get
to that edge of that moral and ethical
is it ethical to to impose thought
on I'm using air quotes for thought but
impose thought on on on on other people
but um I guess pendulums right swinging
lots of different ways but I think
there's boundaries right and otherwise
we're going to go off on another segue
and start talking about the world of
Brave new world uh
1984 new speak you know the impos
thought and I couldn't help it but this
the way my weird brain works and you
know random connections firing off as
soon as you said policing by consent
policing by order you know good police
straight in my head Judge Dread walks
in yeah that and that that's that's
that's that ultim ultimate policing by
enforcement right yeah that you have
some some kind of societal this is the
whole side topic but you have some kind
of societal thing that changes which in
the Judge Dread Universe it's a it's ma
it's mass
unemployment because mechanisms are
taking over all of the jobs so there are
no jobs for people so if everybody's
sitting around not doing anything um you
end up with listless behaviors right
because people have no outlet for what I
want to do uh and then things can very
quickly get out of control and then you
need stronger enforcement of the rules
right that's and which ties into another
fantasy Universe because all the judges
are clients
um anyway all right so um just real as
back towards so ethics and Agility so
we' we've had a a wide rambling
discussion there have been evidence of
Corporations behaving unethically there
is clear evidence of people behaving
unethically some of it legally some of
it just not very nice y some of it
alleged some of it
demonstrated uh agility in its core when
we look at the manifesto for agile
software development there is an implied
ethics in it but you can be agile and
apply it in an unethical fashion for
instance um fraudulent industry such as
skimming fishing scams like that um well
there might even be perfectly legal
industries that a certain group of
individuals believe is unethical right
and that's contextual and up to for
debate and that's why laws changed you
know so um and that's that's fine that's
the whole point of the legal systems is
to uphold well it should be for the
betterment of the the society and what
have you without jumping into that um
mess we not touching that
um so then we thought about that and
flipped it on its head and said well is
it okay for somebody to work in one of
those Industries if it saves their
family and in that instance it may be
ethical for them to behave like that we
then sort of made a segue into personal
ethics what does it mean to be a
civilization
and we thought about when we as a
civilization look after the less
fortunate we become
civilized um and you said that the the
Anthropologist was sorry we forgotten
the name um defined the point of
civilization is when the society
became comfortable and capable of
looking after an individual with a
broken leg and that meant that they
willing to expand the resources to look
after that person for their uh healing
and up until they could then become a
productive member of the group again so
that a civil society will look after
people which will imply an ethical
boundary we then explored professional
organizations and their guides to code
of
conduct and we're then inviting you
wonderful listener to think about what's
your what's your values what's your
ethics what's your boundaries
yeah and and to and to consider how your
ethics your boundaries apply to what
you're actually doing every day and what
are you doing in your organizations who
are you working for what are they doing
and does that fit within within within
your ethical boundaries what have you
been asked to do um and I I would again
tie tie that back to that idea of of the
squirrel burger that you mentioned right
um of ask asking asking
people to say and do things that they're
not capable of saying and doing if that
makes
sense ask asking people to commit to
something that's impossible for them to
deliver
yeah
um which
is a really important thing for agility
well professional agility um for the
professional cand professional scrum
that we
teach making sure that you have time and
space to reflect so that you have the
capacity to observe yourself and to make
sure that you're honoring your code of
ethics if you're practicing both of
those either of those being able to use
the force of the scrum values Focus
openness respect courage and commitment
Do no harm do good um be a be a positive
influence uence on society in general
and
then what's what's the step so
interesting say you suddenly realize
you're in a bit of a dilemma and you're
in a bit of a a moral
maze what would you recommend for
someone if they suddenly realize they
come to the Epiphany that perhaps
something they're doing is not quite
good wow yeah what to
do
um
depends on what it is right it depends
on where what what what line is it that
you feel that you're
Crossing um perhap Perhaps Perhaps
Perhaps you need to walk into your local
police station right that could be an
extreme case of of I I need to I need to
do something I need to raise raise this
um but perhaps it's just
uh like I was asked to do one ethical
unethical thing out of a bunch of things
that I was doing and I just refused to
do the things that I didn't think were
were ethical and voiced that I felt that
they were unethical right yeah yeah um
that that could be enough for the person
suggesting it to go oh oh actually
you're right that's probably not a good
idea right sometimes people do things
unethically because they don't realize
or they haven't thought through or or
whatever we all have dumb ideas right um
people jump offs onto trampolines right
people have people have uh uh dumb ideas
so perhaps just chatting about it with a
friend see what somebody else thinks do
two people think it's unethical or is it
just one so right that that very
practical first step is have a chat to
someone and just
validate yeah valid validate whether it
is or it isn't before you go to the
police station just check with someone
else before you go there yeah and you
you probably you you can probably assume
that it's unethical if you're if you're
asked to it in the phrase of don't tell
anybody else
but right I want you to do this thing
that's probably a good indication that
there's something fishy going on
yeah so check with someone else yep give
yourself time and space to think about
stuff
build your own set of
values uh if in doubt use the scrum
values until you build your
own yep double check that your
organization's values are aligned with
yours and that you're working in
Industry that you support and can
comfortable live
with um and
just be be mindful right yeah always be
consider
ing the eth ethical ramifications of
what it is you're doing and are you are
you still on the right path are you
still doing the right thing are you
still um able able to live with yourself
for the things that you're doing or are
you going to be up all night worrying
about making choices that you've made
right and this is an important point is
that the I think it was the engineer who
wrote the code for the VW masking of
emissions yes that's my favorite
favorite
one D and the manager
both wenton right yep the first he was
the first person so I'm going to Cave at
that one a little bit Simon um he was
the first person to go to prison but he
was also the lowest level person to go
to prison so probably had the cheapest
lawyers right so there's that as
well you're not telling me that um
there's a two-tier system in society
where rich people get away with stuff
because they can pay for better law you
can afford more expensive uh lawy ERS
then you have a greater chance of not
being punished right I mean that's just
a little bit of reality there that
really shouldn't be there but it is um
the the quality wise right quality of
the service um but yeah the the the
person who wrote the the lead developer
who wrote the code um for for Volkswagen
in the diesel Scandal was the first
person who went to prison we we as
software
Engineers have a moral and ethical
responsibility to do the right
thing and I didn't
know is not a defense for a moral and
ethical ramification yeah nor is I was
just following instructions or orders
yeah I was just following orders is not
a defense uh for doing something morally
and ethically
wrong and you know it's wrong if
someone's going to get
hurt and if you have to ask that
question is it morally and ethically
wrong probably probably probably want to
want to consider it right so I just need
to carate that thing about someone's
going to get hurt there are certain
industries that that's what you're doing
so yeah yeah yeah there are certain
industries where where where where
that's that's that's the outcome
yeah ultimately it's up to you
and make the world a better place right
it's in your gift so you can be agile
you can be ethical
do know har ethics there is an overlap
um we need to be ethical regardless of
our
process and we wish you every
success with your businesses and look
forward to hearing our next
discussion on agel actually and if you
have any interesting ethical quandaries
that you can
share oh
yeah yeah share us your ideas share us
your feedback link like subscribe all
that cool stuff and we'll see you next
time thank you very
much thanks
man