there's a there's a there's a quote um
there's no such thing as an agile
transformation it's a cultural
transformation and I agree with the part
that says there's no such thing as an
agile transformation that's that's agile
transformation digital transformation
whatever transformation you want to call
it it's it's it's not really a thing but
I also disagree that it's a cultural
transformation
culture is not something you can change
it's not something you can affect
directly the culture is an outcome of
the way you do
things the
system and the way the system engages
people and people interact with the
system results in the
behaviors that create the culture in
your organization so the easiest way to
think about it is culture is just a
shadow in the world wall
right so if you're if you want to change
the shadow in the wall do you try and
change the Shadow or do you change
you right you change your position you
change your uh uh shape and then the
shadow on the wall
changes so if you want to make changes
to your
organization if you want to change the
way people act in your organization if
you want to to modify the culture of
your organization you don't actually
focus on those things those are not the
things you change those are the
outcome you focus on the system that
your organization has what are the rules
what are the procedures what are the
practices what are the way you measure
people within your organization what are
the principles upon which people make
decisions in your organization when the
rules don't fit those are the
things
that changing will affect the way your
organization runs the way it functions
and the way people act within your
organization which is your
organizational culture so you can't
really affect how people act affect
effect effect well there my dad's
spinning on that one but um if you want
to change the way uh people behave in
your organization you're going to have
to focus on the system change the system
itself and tweak the system make changes
maybe it's small changes maybe it needs
large changes to the system and then
monitor the outcomes which is the
culture and the way people act and the
behaviors that you see in your
organization and then keep
Shifting the system to get the result
that you want so you need to focus on
that system you can't focus on the
culture because you can't change culture
if you want to have a discussion about
your unique needs or situation then
please book a call or visit us at naked
agility
docomo have our immersive and
traditional public classes on our
website and we'd love to hear from you