what is empiricism and why is it so
critical
yeah I think I think in in empiricism
so what is empiricism that is a great
question so empiricism is
um effectively inspecting and adapting
we hear that we hear that a lot in in
the agile space and empiricism is we we
need to something happens
we need to be able to see what happened
right we we we will look at the data
that's the transparency piece right we
can see what's going on really what's
going on not vanity metrics not all of
that [ __ ] right we can actually see
what's going on
and then we're going to we're actually
going to look at it so it's not good
enough just to have the transparency you
have to go look right you have to go and
analyze the data you know all those
reports that you create that you know
nobody ever looks at they're all crap
right you want to be actually what data
do you need in order to make different
decisions so we have the data the
transparency right or or what's going on
look at it and then we change the way we
do things we change something right and
that could be
um lots of different inspect and adapt
Loops there's a bunch of inspecting
adapt Loops for example baked into scrum
that's why they call it an empirical
process right it's implementing a number
of different uh inspect and adapt Loops
at one of those Loops is the the daily
right you've got a Sprint backlog your
Sprint backlog represents your
transparency of the present what's going
on just now and then every day you're
adapting inspecting and adapting
that backlog continually adapting that
plan towards completion of the Sprints
um you've also got the Sprint review
right continually adapting the product
backlog and the product goal towards
whatever Direction you're going that way
you're able to kind of steer in
different directions as you close those
feedback loops
and then you get the Retro which is the
feedback loop for the process itself our
working agreement right our definition
of workflow and every at the end of
every Sprint we're going to get together
and figure out what happened during the
Sprint and how can we change this to
make our lives in the next Sprint a
little bit better or my Our Lives five
Sprints down the line a little bit
better
so there's three inspect and adapt Loops
just in that part of the process and the
entire Sprint is another inspect and
adapt Loop your customer right the the
stakeholders are engaging in that
inspect and adapt process at the end of
every single Sprint they can see what
you've done and can decide whether they
want to invest in another Sprint right
do I am I getting enough value or is
there enough potential value that it's
worth me spending money for another
Sprint or are we done
right perhaps it was a bad idea right
we're quite early in the process and we
we had a cool idea but it doesn't turn
out it's it's it's very good or perhaps
uh um we're going in slightly the wrong
direction and they need to Twitch it
over somewhere else pivot right uh at
the end of the the Sprint and figure out
where we're going next
that's the real power of inspect and
adapt and that's why
um organizations that have
large hierarchies and the people that
are making decisions are too far away
from this actual work that's going on
and aren't able to respond quickly
enough to the market right because
either your mark your Market is either a
commercial market right your business is
doing business with other people or
potentially for a product your Market is
inside of the organization right it's
another part of the business that is
delivering something and as their needs
change or the market needs change you
need to continually adapt the features
that you're creating the direction that
you're going what you're supporting in
order to best meet those needs because
they're serving some some other Market
as well that's constantly changing so
that's why we need those
feedback Clips that's why we need
empiricism because we actually don't
know where we're going we might know
what we want to what we think up front
we want to create for this product
right but
what about who we're providing that
product for is their capability business
Direction stagnant or is it constantly
changing what about what they're those
people are creating their outputs for is
that stagnant or constantly changing and
how quickly can we close those feedback
loops that's really what agile is all
about
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility