the first thing they're going to get is
the ability to start putting into
practice immediately so you come on
session one and you're going to get
homework basically things you need to do
it's not stuff that it's not like school
homework where you're given exercises to
do it's all of the exercises are aimed
at doing things in your real
organization and finding out where the
issues are finding out where that is so
you can bring it back to the group bring
it back to the class so we can get
together on that but you don't have to
wait till the end of the class to start
doing it you can do it right from week
one you're going to get some real value
you're going to find some real things
about your organization
we always say scrum doesn't solve your
problems it shows you where your
problems are to help you solve them so
we're doing that right at the start but
it doesn't mean in a traditional class
you learn this with with us for two days
and therefore you go and find your
problems afterwards so some of us some
trainers will say hey get in touch with
with your problems but
people tend not to is what I've noticed
it'd be great if they did actually but
in this they're bringing their problems
back so they're not on their own so
effectively we're going with a hive mind
solution to help them solve their
problems rather than make them feel on
their own
that's absolutely huge because it means
they're getting into a more of a
community of practice way of thinking so
many organizations already have scrum
Master community of practice or product
growing a community of practice but if
they don't they need somebody to set
them up somebody like a scrum Master for
example so they can go and do that and
that goes on throughout so every every
week you've got the opportunity to try
something new come back and learn and
learn in a safer environment so you're
bringing in these unsafe nasty work
environment where you know it's
yeah like I said if we're all in a
perfect world you'd probably not be
coming on to the scrum class in the
first place because you'd already know
it all and the organization would
already be doing it so it would bring in
that dirty stuff back into the clean
world of the classroom where we can be
safe try things come up with ideas talk
it through come up with Concepts and
then apply it back so it's a real mix of
coaching and training so it's not just a
classroom experience there's this
opportunity that to mix those two things
it would also give you this opportunity
of a brain's trust imagine if you are
the very first scrum master in your
organization to ever come and learn
scrum and there isn't a community of
practice here I've got a cohort of
people I'm going along with on my
journey that I'm doing difficult things
with actually and sharing that
experience and with shared experiences
and shared hardships we build bonds and
those bonds I imagine will go well
beyond these the situation certainly
when I've ever worked in a cohort I
always find out I'm still in touch with
those people years later
you also have this weird thing of not
having to take two days out of the the
office to come to a class now we are
asking for an actual larger commitment
in terms of more out of the office time
but it's much more manageable it's one
afternoon a week it's not two big days
and a big chunk when all sorts of things
could happen back at the office that
then become distractions while you're
trying to learn and you have to go and
deal with things during the class time
so you miss things
half a day a week is much more
manageable and it allows you to get into
that thing without having to have this
big headache how do I have to sort all
of these weird things out
and I had to say it but things just like
going to pick the kids up from school
become a big drag situation and an
online class when it's a couple of days
you don't necessarily have that because
we can work around it
I think the biggest Advantage for the
people coming on the class
while this the certification is the same
it leads to the psm1 certification
however you choose the PSM modern class
and the two-day experience is an awesome
class we've refined it we've done it
well and
this gives you that little bit of extra
that it's really hard to do in a two-day
class space to learn
space to learn is essential and it
there's a lot of content there's a lot
of cognitive burden on coming onto a
two-day class
by the nature of it this allows you to
take it in a chunk
try it for real take it to that deeper
learning level by applying the learning
immediately bring it back Loop through
it again effectively in that space as
well so we end up with multiple Loops of
learning we'll end up with real
application so as a PSM
that's been through this program as a
sorry as a scrum master has been through
this program you get this deeper
learning this deeper understanding that
makes you more confident and what I see
with a lot of new scrum Masters when
they come on the class and at the
beginning of their Journey
they typically have the hardest problems
to solve in their career right at the
start when they've got the least
experience and the least knowledge to be
able to deal with it that's the nature
of it as you get better the team's also
got better therefore you don't need it
the organizations also evolved therefore
they don't need quite so much of you
this gives you that confidence that you
have been able to do this in the real
world and you have had that support net
so when the support net scales back when
you finish the class you've got more
confidence in your own ability and of
course
will that get you a better job who knows
but certainly your confidence will shine
shine through when you're talking to
those people about that job