so the question was why why would I
encourage people to follow a
certification path in their career
Journey
um
and I I would say for the same reason
that people go to university for the
same people that the reason people do
any course it gets your foot in the door
um certifications themselves
have no value
how many of you have ever had to pull
out your University degree right 10
years after you've graduated from
University you don't maybe your first
couple of jobs you had to I I had to
pull out my University degree when I
applied for my H-1B to go work in the US
uh
um and they actually didn't like it they
didn't like it I had to I had to
contribute to two years of my
professional experience to make up the
year that the US degrees have more than
my degree that I took but it all worked
out but that that's why you have those
things right is somebody wants somebody
wants to
um validate your knowledge it doesn't
mean you have skills right skills and
application of learning is different
from just amassing knowledge but kind of
at a minimum for certain roles you
should have knowledge right
um at the very least if you're going to
be working on a scrum team you should
probably have read the scrum guide
if I was an employer how do I validate
that you've read the scrum guide well I
could I could sit and interview the
thousand people that apply and ask them
have you read the scrum guide or I could
just put in the in the in the job spec
uh psm1
right and if you can pass the psm1
you've read the scrum guide it would be
very difficult to pass the psm1 if
you've not read the scrum guide so
there's a minimum bar there's a litmus
test there's a quick check that an
employer can do to whittle down the
Thousand candidates to the 200
candidates that I've actually read the
scrum guide because we want somebody who
can work on a scrum team and so taking
that
assessment
um it that that that's why it's valuable
from a professional career perspective
um external professional career
perspective like somebody looking at you
but internal professional career
perspective it's about validated
learning
right
um how if I take if I take a course
um and there's no assessment at the end
um how do I know I understood what was
the intent for me to understand from the
course
well I don't right I just have to well I
didn't pay attention for half of it and
I forgot the other 60 and now
um
I'm I'm I've done the course so I should
be able to go do the job but that's not
really how it works right our memories
don't work that way our understanding
doesn't work that way so taking and
that's why I really like the way that
scrum.org do the validated learning that
you get you effectively get two attempts
to take the assessment right
so when you at the end of the class
um everybody gets a token to take the
assessment and if they take it within 14
days you get a free second one if you
fail if you pass well you passed right
but in both cases you get your results
broken down by category with a
percentage and you're able to look at
that and say well
um I didn't know I had a low score I
passed but I had a low score in this
area so perhaps I should study this
material and the thing you get with the
scores on it actually has a link to a
bunch of material to study in that topic
that scrum.org have created and there's
a scrum Master learning path there's a
product owner learning path there's
various learning learning paths and that
additional learning even if
I got a high score in it I want to dive
deeply into that topic because I liked
it how do you know where to start or
where to look here's a place to start so
that validated learning for you and your
career path because the thing
once you get Beyond getting in the door
right the foot in the door that that
gets you to the actual interview is you
still have to demonstrate in the
interview that you actually understand
stuff and there are so many posts on
LinkedIn talking about how
how to validate the the person at the
interview actually understands the thing
that you're talking about and all these
trick questions and you you just need to
know your stuff
and in order to know your stuff you have
to have done the studying absorb the
information and and and understood it
and you don't get that from not
looking at anything not reading the
books not watching the videos not uh
reading the blog posts right of
investing some time and effort in
figuring out what this thing is
um and and
training courses are a great great way
to level set and then what's next I mean
the output of of a scrum.org classes I
think all of them have at least 10 books
here you go here's a bunch of books to
read here's a bunch of additional
content to read each trainer adds more
content into that story as you go and if
you take the time to to go
check it out learn how to do different
things you can you can improve your
career trajectory
um so that you you you get further
quicker right that's that's really what
careers are about
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility