ah so three what are the three key
takeaways to attending the aps class
especially the immersive APS class
um so I think the the first one is that
fundamental understanding of the
underlying principles of uh of scrum and
ethereum practices that make it up right
that that's kind of kind of kind of key
but I guess at a double advantage to
that of the immersive class is that you
can
augment that story with how you're
actually implementing it within your
organization right so you can although
Martin's going to say this is how a
product owner works that's in a box
here's the definition of product owner
from from scrum
um you're then perhaps going to go try
some of those things inside of your
organization and you're gonna be like oh
well this bit sucks and that bit sucks
and we can't do this bit and the
organization says we're not allowed to
do that and then you can come back and
and we can we can tweak it right there's
not one way to do scrum you can tweak it
to figure out
um how it is that it can be most
effective within the context of your
organization so that's really the first
one that that empirical
um understanding of the underlying
principles of of scrum and how they work
um the second one is probably that that
bit that bit at the end the the getting
started right the the
um you know the the the the
getting rid of the the the Klingons that
have come into your process or
um uh you know scraping the Klingons off
the starboard bow if anybody remembers
that
um I may be too old that's what it is
I'm gonna be too old
but uh the the also the the getting
started right lots of teams really
struggle we understand this scrum thing
now
like what what do I do what's next
um and the advantage to the immersive
classes that's happening continuously
throughout the class right rather than
you having a two-filled day or here's a
week of training and then Monday we're
doing something different and we don't
know where to start you get introduced
to a little piece at a time try it
within your organization a little piece
at a time try to try it little piece
little piece little piece
um so that's that's probably the second
key takeaway man what's the third third
one
third superpower
um probably
um learning what is not scrum right that
that
I mentioned like the Klingons the things
that are are built up in our process but
there's also not just institutional
knowledge within our organization
um but institutional knowledge within
our industry of what people think scrum
is so you'll have people who have done
scrum organized other organizations that
also bring their Klingons and Barnacles
right to the story
um and when you mush that all together
you end up with something that perhaps
doesn't look like scrum at all doesn't
have any empiricism doesn't close any
feedback loops doesn't have working
products at the end of every iteration
and that's fairly common right so being
able to clearly understand what is and
is not scrum so that you can choose the
not even if you're doing the core right
um and I think that's that's a huge key
takeaway for
um the aps class
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility