really important part of visualizing
your work when you're doing caman is
having some kind of caman board okay uh
you want to take the way your system
currently operates you want to think
about the things that move across your
board things that will move through your
system and then decide what are the
columns that that needs to move through
now the absolutely most optimal way to
do that would be single piece flow one
item at a time to do in progress and
done but the reality is we don't all
live in that perfect world in fact none
of us do so you're going to have to look
at how your work flows through your
system what are the columns that you
currently have on your board with the
stages of the work and come up with a
board that represents that