so what a question was what are the red
flags
to look for with wearing an agile
consultant
I think
the biggest red flags
for me
um are
not not not not engaging in the
community not being part of
um some
some some group or Community or effort
where they're sharing their ideas with
others they're having ideas of others
shared with them and working in that
kind of Melting Pot there's nothing
nothing better than being part of a an
agile community and which I'm part part
of a few and seeing something and you
immediately get piled on for saying
something so ridiculous
that
um
it's not really people aren't
deliberately piling on you right because
they're they're agile it's just you know
you you send them a message and all of
them are writing a response at the same
time because you've poked at something
that that that maybe wasn't the best
thing to pull cat and and that gives you
I don't know what the right word is is
it is it is it humility for for
you're not always going to say the right
thing you're not always going to be able
to do the right thing you're you're
going to say stupid stuff
and you have to be able to take being
called on saying stupid stuff
and sometimes it's okay to say stupid
stuff because if you don't say what
you're thinking if you don't feel safe
enough to say what you're thinking
um how would you possibly
be able to learn
that there might be a different way of
thinking and I think that's that's one
of the key things because I there's so
many consultants are not
part of any agile Community they just
have that Echo chamber of their
organization or their consultancy and
there's not anything more information
coming in
from outside that
um having having discourse
right being able to articulate
the the the the the the the Core
Concepts in agile so I'm thinking
empiricism
I'm thinking uh lean
um I'm you need to be able to
articulate them in a way
that they are able to be understood by
the other person within the context of
that other person rather than just
regurgitating something from the scrum
guide say that says well XYZ right
um
you need to be able to say
well you know the scrum guide says this
because it's trying to achieve this idea
if you can achieve this idea in a
different way inside of your
organization then maybe that's okay
being able to articulate those things
I think that's that's key so that's just
a fundamental lack of knowledge right
that's that's really it I think I think
it's actually true in in in all
consultancies
but I'm going to be very specific here
because otherwise I'm going to piss off
everybody right but you there's a
difference between a boutique
consultancy which specializes in a
particular topic
hires people who are experts known
experts in that particular topic and
encourages them to become better experts
in that particular topic
and our our butts in seats
Contracting
consultancy
who are really only interested in how
much money they can make out of the
customer
so they they get into this vicious cycle
right this is the thing to watch out for
in in in in consultancies as you get
into this vicious cycle of
um
in order to stay afloat we need to win
more business right we're the
Consultants say we need to win more
business because we've got people that
are that are in the company that need
the work
and then you you have experts and you
have all of these high ideals with the
customer so lots of customers buy your
stuff and suddenly you don't have enough
people on the bench to service the gigs
that are coming in right the gigs in
your pipeline so then you have to go
find people who can do those gigs but we
can't wait for those people we need them
now
so we're taking the people that are
available not the people that are right
for that gig they're not bringing in
people because their Knowledge and
Skills they're bringing in people
because of their availability
um and and then you get into that
vicious cycle of then now we've get more
people
and uh they roll off a gig onto the
bench and we need to sell more to get
more stuff rather than
I mean we it's it's even more
it's even worse for an agile consultancy
not to do this but having a lean
Outlook right you don't take on more
work than you can handle
um you you limit your work in process so
that you're playing the long game not
the short game of Revenue extraction but
the long game of value creation and
building relationships with your
customers
um and not pissing them off and then we
have to get new customers
so for me those are the big
the two big pieces is the actual
individuals and the knowledge and
capability that they have to understand
agile articulator explain it and and
work with it and work with other people
in the agile space
and that bigger consultancy model
um of the the I call it the death spiral
right because there's there's no way out
of that if all you're focused on is I I
need bots in uh uh Revenue extraction
mode then
you're not gonna
you're not gonna you're not gonna serve
your customers right
for me that's the two big things