I got introduced to cban uh by Daniel
Vante and Steve Porter uh when I did the
the the participated in the first uh
professional uh scrum with cban class uh
back in
2018 late 17 early
18 and I didn't fundamentally understand
at the time the value of of this
different way of thinking of this um
observational tool I think it's quite
important to understand that Canan is
not a system itself that's why uh uh Pro
Canan and the
cban guide talks about it as a strategy
it's a strategy for understanding your
existing system and then actively
managing the flow of work through that
existing system
and we talked about it in that context
within the context of a scrum team and
how we can manage actively manage the
flow of work within the system use the
cambam metric to augment our existing
perhaps awesome scrum process in order
to really understand the predictability
that we're getting and increase that
predictability for the business because
lot lots of teams do struggle
uh with their ability to to to deliver
they struggle with getting to the end of
the Sprint and having working product um
they struggle with um consistently
getting working product they struggle
with the con the quantity of working
product um and
that creates fear in the business
because the business are paying a lot of
money to get stuff and they feel like
they're getting that stuff in fits and
starts in an unpredictable way right
they feel like it's not what they asked
for it doesn't cost what they thought it
would and it's not delivered when they
thought it would and part of that is
because they they can't see what's going
on they can't we're we're not giving
we're not giving them any information
the standard scrum team is not giving
the business any information to reassure
them they're not doing transparency
right they're not increasing the
transparency to a level where the people
viewing who need to understand actually
understand what's going on and that
creates that fear that means that we
want to have more control right when we
fear something isn't working out when we
fear that um our money isn't being spent
well we want to take more control of
that thing and that's the knee-jerk
regression that we get from a lot of
teams in organizations when a lot of
teams move towards scrum because they
take away
uh uh some of the the the the tools for
measuring productivity from the teams
right um because in agile we don't
measure productivity they take that
stuff away but then they don't replace
it with anything and because they don't
replace it with anything transparency
drops fear increases and then we want to
go back to the old way so a caman
strategy and this is this is something
that I've learned really over the last
five years of work working with Daniel
Vante and the the campan guide and uh
Pro caman is that the only way to be
successful is to use a caman strategy
because we need to understand our
predictability we needs to understand
and actively manage the flow of work
through the system and we are not going
to be successful if we don't do that so
I I recommend a cand strategy for any
team
doing anything in any context that's
right any team doing anything in any
context if you're a marketing team
delivering marketing contents if you're
a um a software team delivering software
and you're using scrum you're a software
team using safe you're a software team
using something else that you made up
yourself or you're a management team
managing portfolio or I don't know I'm
trying to think of other things if you
work in a Factory and you're delivering
stuff you should be using a camand
strategy in all of those contexts that
is the metrics you need in order to then
be successful right because those
metrics create transparency transparency
allows you to make better decisions and
ask more interesting questions and those
interesting questions and better
decisions result in more effective flow
or stop doing the thing that you thought
of um and that's why caman is so
important to the strategy for every team
building anything in any company if you
want to have a discussion about your
unique needs or situation then please
book a call or visit us at naked agility
tocom uh we also have our immersive and
traditional public classes on our
website and we'd love to hear from you