so what the question is what should be
way more popular in in agile
than it is today
and I think it's
the opposite of tools
so the main the main focus of agile
coaches agile consultants and people
actually trying to do Agile
um seems to be tools right the focus is
on the tools but the tools aren't how
you
figure out how to solve problems in a
complex environment because in a complex
environment you might need different
tools every time you do something you
might need a different practice a
different capability a different an
emergent process right
so the thing that I think is missing
is that focus on principles right
because the principles are the thing
that are underlying everything and
helping you make
choices that fit within the direction
that you want to go of of your
organization and the way you want to do
things and the tools are just something
that supports those
ideas right those those practice those
those
[Music]
um
principles
so I think the the big lack of focus is
on the underlying principles that
support the good decision making that
results in great organizations great
teams and great products and it's just
not there
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility