one of the common myths in scrum is that
since we're doing agile we don't need no
planning um and that is just utter
garbage scrum for example is all about
planning we have Sprint planning we have
refinement which is a type of planning
we have uh daily scrum which is about
planning the next 24 hours we have a
review where we riew what happened based
on the plan and adapt the plan going
forward into the future it's it's all
about planning it's all about getting
things right it's not about planning
upfront it's not about
spending too much time upfront planning
okay but there's a phrase which is often
misinterpreted which is we should do
just enough planning we should do just
enough right if we do too much planning
and we plan a bunch of stuff that we end
up not doing because it gets taken out
of the out of the backlog then that was
waste maybe that was okay waste maybe we
needed to do that planning in order to
find out other stuff and have that thing
removed or maybe that was a little bit
too much was is there a way that we
could have learned the same thing that
we learned doing that planning doing
something a little bit less
and the converse of that is if you are
building I'm trying to think what you
could be building that needs lots of
let's say you're working on
Windows and you're one of 2 and a half
th000 software Engineers how many teams
is that metric assloads of teams right
if you you're that many teams working on
one product then you're going to need to
plan
right you're going to need to understand
what's happening going out into the
future you're going to need to
coordinate across hundreds of teams on
Direction and strategy I mean most of
that in scrum is done through
communication right Vision product goal
Sprint goal right you've got that
communication chain how do we all get
behind the same thing but we're trying
to
have as
light a plan upfront as possible within
our
context so even even if I was working on
the Windows team I would probably have a
a road map I'm probably going to have a
road map for my current six months if
you're not familiar with how how
Microsoft product teams have they've
created their own scaling framework
around what they need and their business
um it's often called the season-based
model cuz they do they talk about the
spring update and the fall update for
their really big products U many of
their products do continuous delivery
but they're talking about long-term view
of what it is they're trying to achieve
and that's that's about 6 months and
they look three seasons ahead so they're
looking 18 months out they have an 18
month plan and I'm using air quotes
because it's probably pretty vague right
if you're looking looking at that third
season out things are really big right
you might have um uh uh uh uh themes
rather than individual things you're
going to deliver you might be looking at
what are the investment opportunities
what's happening in the market where do
we need to to get ahead of the of the
competition going over the next 18
months and that generates these big
theme
buckets of work that many hundreds of
teams might work in um to to actually
you know make progress towards those big
themes but you're looking that far out
you're planning that far out you know um
probably what your goal your product
goal if if they call I don't think they
call it that but whatever their their
theme for uh their primary theme for us
each of the seasons they probably know
what they're going to be 18 months out
for the season that we're in you know
we're probably got backlog items and
actual things we're going to tactically
deliver for the next three four maybe
five Sprints
maybe and then in the next bucket we
maybe have you know here's some Sprint
goals we might tackle here's some
product goals we might look at um in
that next seasonal bucket and then the
season after after
that we we don't have any of those
detailed just what's the big theme and
you can you can see how they did that
they they did a uh one recently uh I'm
saying recently in The Last 5 Years
right uh recently that was called the
creators update so when they when they
were talking to us the general public
about the products they talked about the
creators update we're going to invest in
opportunities to make our systems and
products and services better for
creators that was an organization wide
uh theme that kind of spawned out of the
windows team but think of all the things
that impacts not only does that impact
on Windows the operating system right
but what about offices impact most
people interact with the operating
system through off office so if you're
to hey fever if you're talking about um
pen support right you've got the the the
the actual pen touching the screen on
the surface and the number of levels of
capability that it has in that world
you've got so that's that's hardware
that's the surface hardware and perhaps
thirdparty vendor Hardware collaborating
with then you've got the application
that you're actually is interpreting
those signals so that could be
Microsoft's applications it could be
office it could be third party software
and then you've got the underlying
operating system which is providing
support for the I think it used to be
250 6 uh levels of pressure and now it's
uh 1024 at least uh uh levels of
pressure that you can put on the pen in
order to to to get that you know I'm
drawing on the page type of type of feel
and that
requires collaboration looking forward
into the future what do we need what are
we trying to achieve all of those
strategic things are happening we just
probably don't store them in a Gant
chart thanks for watching the video If
you enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked
agility