the the hypothetical question
was what does a poor scrum team look
like
and unfortunately that's how well it
depends answer as well right because
it's not it's not the things the team
well there are some things that I would
almost always categorically put in the
not good category but sometimes most of
the time it's the
the outcomes
that are bad so for example a poor scrum
team might be
um you've got some lead developer who's
always imposing their will on everybody
else in the team doesn't listen to what
everybody else says and expects
everybody to just do what he tells them
to do
there's there's a there's that and I
would just say that's just not a team
right does not necessarily need the
scrum part it's just not a team
um or my favorite favorite example of a
dysfunctional scrum behavior that I use
a lot is actually the a dysfunctional
product owner
um and during a Sprint review
the customer is a little bit the
stakeholders are a little bit irate
because they didn't get something they
the way they want it
and they demanded of the the scrum team
why did you build it that way
and what you would expect to see in a
healthy scrum team
is that the product owner would be then
standing in front of the stakeholders
um
defending or apologizing for whatever
the problem was
and asking how would you like it to be
different how what could we do
differently in order to be able to
support what you need right or we're not
going to do it that way because that's
not the direction of the product but
it's the product owners
responsibility to to to make that stand
but that's not what happened in the case
that I'm thinking of the product owner
turned to the development team and said
yeah why did you build it that way
basically totally passing passing the
buck to the development team
and saying it's your fault that you
didn't understand what the customer said
and I translated for you
and you didn't build it the way I said
that's just
what what the hell right
that
that's not there's no trust there
there's no respect there there's no
commitment there there's no openness
there
pretty much totally divested of the
scrum values
and they weren't doing very good scrum
either
so I think there's a myriad of examples
of what what does a bad scrum team look
like and there's actually very few
examples of what does a good scrum team
look like because
there Patrick lisione one of the things
that that he said is that that great
teams
are such a
Force multiplier for companies
because they're so rare right it's
actually really hard to create great
teams because most organizations set you
up for failure
the the the the the
a policy be used used to have in in
Microsoft years ago under Steve Baumer
was that every manager had to stack rank
every one of their direct reports every
year
and at the end of that year based on the
stack rank the bottom 10 were out of the
team
if you were out of the team out of out
of a team three times in a row you wrote
the company
so what's the incentive for people to
work together
right isn't that an incentive for them
to try and stab each other in the back
what was the incentive for for you as a
as a leader
to build a great team
well I can't build a great team because
I'm going to lose 10 every year so I
need mostly a great team and some cannon
fodder that are going to get lost right
and how does that make the cannon father
feel or the rest of the people in the
team feel it just totally depresses the
ability for the organization to create
value
because
mediocre teams or bad teams don't build
great products amazing teams build
amazing products great teams built great
products
so you need to have an environment
within which teams are able to to be
like that and that that's not about
imposing
processes and tools on them even even
scrum you don't impose it on a team they
need to choose it
um it means not focusing on everybody
have the most comprehensive
documentation ever right you need that's
not going to help and you need to not
focus on on on contracts contracts don't
solve your problems contracts are just
working agreements
right they're a working agreement
between two companies so they don't deal
each other over so that they have an
agreement on how we're going to work
and as soon as you start enshrining ways
of working like ways of people working
what you're going to deliver how you're
going to deliver in the contract you're
starting to constrain the ability for
the teams to choose a way of working
that best suits
what they discover when they're doing
the work
so I think
it's easy to see how organizations
fail
to deliver value because they're not
actually focused on value they're
they're focused on treating uh these
teams that are meant to be generating
value as a cost center rather than a
Value Center
and that's what results in in poor
quality teams in unhappy people and
shitty products