and that's what brings us to the biggest
cut of all which was
the weight orders ready in 30 seconds
not 30 minutes
mecca we look at each other one night
you thinking what i'm thinking we're
gonna have to tear down rebuild reconfig
rethink the whole dang thing we're
talking about shutting down a thriving
business for months people are going to
think we're crazy
we were crazy
and you were going to love how we did it
dick you got to tell him tennis court
okay he brings me up to this tennis
court and he's drawn this line the exact
dimensions of our kitchen sink on the
right extruder on the left
bagging and hood bush okay garnish
garnish this is uh burger finish got it
and then this is burger slide
we could just move those okay we'll do
mixer soft drinks okay we bring out our
whole staff and we have them go through
the motions making pretend burgers and
fries
all right steve anticipate that you got
to keep the tray level
okay and dick is running around with
this stick marking where all the
equipment should be tuck in
tony are you going to skip the pickles
when we're really doing it they do it
over and over hashing it out
choreographing it like some crazy burger
ballet going on over there
yes
no
everybody stop stop garnish one garnish
two you've got pickles you've got onions
it's a goddamn hamburger come on clear
off let's clear it off
it's time for the pink chalk
and then rip your orange
see see all this open space here now
we've rearranged the fry situation so
now this stage left the deep fryer
stayed right
again
that's great
come on guys they're pretty tied up here
watch it
it's the timing of the lazy susan
those are finished burgers you can't
hold it
i still think there's a third version
what do you want to move i want to move
everything back to stage left please
[Music]
i guess i guess look let's assume our
battle station okay
finally after about six hours of this
we get it just right it's a symphony of
efficiency not a wasted motion
good form jasper
[Music]
put your back into it seth
and pickles and pickle and
mustard we take the layout to a builder
custom build the kitchen to our exact
specs
the speed d system is born the world's
first ever system to deliver food fast
it is totally revolutionary and a
complete disaster why opening down cars
pull up onto the lot and they start
honking immediately because no car hop
comes up you place your order we try to
explain to them the walk-up window and
they are uh bewildered no they're
furious what do you mean i gotta get out
of my car most of them just cuss us out
and drive off and the few that stay are
met as heck because they're eating off
paper and they've got to discard their
own trash why you're doing great you're
doing great yeah we won't be coming out
to the car but you can just come on up
welcome to mcdonald's we may have
underestimated the learning curve so by
five o'clock dick is calculating how
much it's gonna cost to go back to
driving but i am not ready to throw in
the towel i go back to our old hollywood
days i think to myself we gotta go big
with this we gotta put on a shout out so
i say dick i wanna throw a grand
reopening uh gala premiere that would
put louis b mayer vuitton so we ran a
bunch of spotlights same ones we used to
haul around in the columbia day to get
sparklers a juggler for the kitties it
is an event people show up in droves
and then
the flies they must have been drawn by
all the lights millions of them it was
like a scene out of exodus the pharaoh
would have released the israelites