the question is what will you learn on
the PSM course
that's a great question I think there's
really two there's two main things that
you're gonna you're gonna learn on the
PSM course
that they Advanced PSM
um and the first one is uh and this is
for most people
that they've been doing this scrum
Master thing wrong
they've been focusing on the wrong
things it's not their fault quite often
they come in as a and I know many scrum
Masters that come in as a jira admin
right and that that then they become the
scrum Master through being a beard Euro
admin and we kind of go back to our
default state right so we want to be
that jira admin because it's fun right
that's why you became well maybe
not so much fun in Europe but um you
became a uh that was your your thing
that you thought was fun
um
but the the that realization that
there's even more things that you need
to be looking at in fact the the jira
admin is something that should solve
itself right give give everybody on the
team admin rights to jira and let them
let them let them do it I know that
sounds crazy for to to authoritarians
but it that's pushing responsibility
down the organization teach the people
how to do the thing and then let them
get on with it and that leaves the scrum
Master free to focus on other things
what are the services that the scrum
Master is providing to the team what are
the services that the scrum Master is
providing to the product owner and
what's the services that the scrum
Master is providing to the organization
and I think that's those those two to
the services the product order and
services to the organization are quite
often often missing and the services to
the team uh constitutes I was what's the
the age-old ones are you know protecting
the team
right uh uh why do you need to protect
the team can't they protect themselves
don't that doesn't the team have the
skills and knowledge and capability to
be able to say no to a customer right
that's what's missing not you don't need
to protect them
um or or doing the admin right updating
the tickets team can update their own
damn tickets you don't have to do that
um and and if you have to do it it's
like um
uh uh uh it's I I sometimes liken it to
to uh if you have if you have kids
and they've they've got an untidy room
you don't tidy it up for them
right because if you tidy it up for them
they'll always rely on you to tidy it up
and it will never be tidy unless you do
it
whereas if they have to do it and they
have to deal with the the the the the
the
maybe they'll take that plate down to
the kitchen because they know they'll
have to tidy it up later and it will be
nasty if they leave it if they just
slide it under the bed and leave it
right you know that bug you just kind of
slide
under the bed so you don't have to you
don't have to deal with it but if you
have to deal with it later and you have
to deal with the Fallout of it and talk
to the customer and why is it not fixed
and you have to do all of those things
you're more likely to go well I don't
really want that so maybe I should just
fix it I know it's I don't like doing it
but I'll just do it and that that that I
don't like the parenting analogy but I
think it works in that small
circumstance that you're trying to
enable a group of people
to
um be better at what they do to take
accountability for the things that
they're creating to deal with their own
stuff so that you can then focus on the
higher level uh uh uh things and
capabilities that that we want so that
the the improve the team's capabilities
improve the product owners capability to
deliver value to the business and
improve the businesses capability to
engage and interact with the team and
perhaps deal with organizational
impediments as well which is which is
very difficult to do especially from
where people think the scrum Master sits
um so that opening out of the scrum
master and being able to to
do greater things I think
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility