so scrum scrum doesn't solve problems it
reveals them how and why is that
valuable
um there's a there's a there's a there's
an old um adage that can can Weber used
to used to say all the time
and scrums like a mirror
oh it gives you a way of doing things
and if you can't do it that way
why that's your mirror right what is the
thing because it doesn't sound
unreasonable
right there's no there's nothing
unreasonable in scrum
you you have a group of people who are
working together towards a common goal
right they're a team working together
towards a common goal you you give them
some work
they take a piece of that work
they build that work and they deliver
that work
you take the feedback from people using
and inform the next thing that you build
and you keep going around that Loop
right
why why is that so hard for organization
it it seems like a no-brainer right we
we do it all the time how did your your
kids learn to walk they fell over a lot
and they kept picking themselves up and
kept trying they would see other people
doing those things right they could see
other people doing those things the
walking I want to do that uh for for my
daughter
um we bought squeaky shoes I don't know
if you've ever seen these squeaky shoes
that's basically shoes with a squeaker
in it and that when you walk it goes
and she loved that noise so she learned
to walk it nine months with those shoes
on and she was running down concrete
concourses on holiday
um with those shoes
and it's just just you
that that that
mirror that other people are doing it
you have some incentive to do it and
then uh you get you get the outcome
right most organizations move to
adopting scrum because they're
struggling to deliver
right they've failed in some way to
achieve the desirable outcome and people
are like oh this sucks why is this
taking so long why are we building the
wrong thing how do we build the right
thing and somebody's like well there's
this agile thing that people are talking
about they seem to be talking about
these short feedback loops delivering
more value maximizing that amount of oh
that sounds like a good idea let's do
that and then you go to try and do it in
your organization and suddenly all these
mirrors pop up and say you you know you
go to try a simplest one ever you go to
try and ship your product to production
and what what what happens the mirror
pops up and it's you can't ship to
production I'm sorry you have to fill
out these 14 forms
and you have to fill them out
minimum six weeks in advance before you
do a deployment there you go
well there's something we need to fix
right that's that's the first thing we
need to fix that that's an example I
used to work at Merrill Lynch uh and and
that's exactly if we didn't submit all
the paperwork six weeks before a
deployment it was considered an
emergency deployment and every emergency
deployment got a black mark against your
name against like uh in the hierarchy of
departments and if you get too many
black marks at a particular level
um then you know leadership comes down
to slap people around and and say why
why are you why are you doing this
um and the group that I worked for
because we were trying to do ideal
delivery we were doing continuous
delivery right so we were maybe shipping
twice a day
um we we had the more black marks than
any other part of the organization I
think it was somebody said it as we had
more black marks than the whole rest of
the organization combined
right because we were just
we're generating two or three of them a
day and that was just my products there
were other products in our in our group
as well
so so so that
then disincentivizes people to do the
right thing right why is the rest of the
organization not doing continuous
delivery well because they're not
willing to just go yeah whatever your
black marks right they didn't have
strong enough leadership who says to the
rest of the organization no this is fine
we're okay with this level of black
marks this is perfectly acceptable and
we're getting the value we need this is
okay
and and why did that exist why does that
black mark system exist it's it's
organizational cropped right our
organizations build up
a whole bunch of
um rules I'm gonna call them rules they
build up a whole bunch of rules because
they did something it worked well and
they wanted to enshrine that in the way
they do things so that they continue to
do well
and that idea worked fantastically when
we existed in slow-moving markets right
and you'll see the organizations with
the most bureaucracy are the
organizations that have traditionally
existed in the slowest moving markets
right governments right always had lots
of high levels of bureaucracy and rules
and procedures Banks right banks have
been around for well I think the First
Bank was was it not Royal Bank of
Scotland 250 years there's still an
organization still exists can you
imagine having 250 years of these rules
and procedures I worked with kongsberg
in Norway that's a 200 year old mining
company that found diamonds and then got
into everything right they have all
these rules so for example at Merrill
Lynch I had a rule that the software
that I create had to be tested to make
sure that it didn't interfere with the
trading desk software if it was
installed on the trading desk
but the software I was building was for
a small group of people in a call center
who were calling people and had nothing
to not even in the same
league as the trading desk folks so this
piece of software would never be
installed over there but yet I had to
spend six months in testing an
assessment to validate that that was
true even though it was of no relevance
whatsoever
that's a rule that's applied across an
entire organization for a very small
group now risk mitigation right if that
software was installed on the trading
desk and it interfered with it maybe
that's hundreds and hundreds of millions
of dollars worth of risk to the
organization so they applied across the
board but there needs to be a
reasonableness test right needs to be a
reasonable this text
across all of the the the
organization's rules so challenge that's
scrum's job is to challenge those rules
it pops up that mirror and says no you
should be able to do this you should be
able to do continuous delivery you
should be able to have an ordered
backlog that's just a list of stuff that
you need to do with the most important
thing at the top you should be able to
say product owner here's the product you
own it you make the decisions if you
can't do that there's a problem for
leadership
right that pops up that mirror
immediately we've got to fix this so
um the the whole purpose of scrum is not
to solve your problems for you it's to
highlight that you have them in the
first place
right it's a little trigger mechanism
that you can't do the short feedback
loop you can't deliver stuff into
production you can't get working
products you can't you can't you can't
you can't right that's that's I don't
know what to call that is that the art
of the negative I don't know like you
you I work with so many organizations
where
um
here's here's here's how I would expect
conversation to go
right um
we need to do this
we can't do this okay
how we can't do it that way but you if
you did this and you did that then you
would be able to do it this way or let's
pull in that compliance person that we
need to sign off on this so we can make
this change
because it's a business need right we
need to be able to ship more quickly
whereas what really happens in
organizations is you go oh we need to be
able to do this and the other person
goes nope you can't do that
that's the end of the conversation
how is that supporting the business
right
the the the whole purpose for every
Department in your organization's
existence is to support the business
making money
anything that's inhibiting the business
making money is getting in the way and
you need those mirrors
right devops
pops up those mirrors scrum pops up
those mirrors damn man pops up those
mirrors these are all tools to help you
see what's wrong because the way we do
things is the thing that's getting in
the way of actually delivering value
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility