I work with many Enterprise
organizations that use Azure devops and
many of them do things that either
reduce the effectiveness of the features
or break them entirely I asked Dan Helm
the principal product manager for aure
devops what the top four issues were and
this is the
[Music]
result hi I'm Martin hinwood owner and
principal consultant naked agility I'm a
professional scrum trainer with
scrum.org a professional camand trainer
with Pro caman and I've been a Microsoft
MVP in GitHub and Azure devops for 15
[Music]
years as your devops in its current
Incarnation was built for agile teams by
agile teams the Azure devops product
team transition to Agile around 2013 and
they moved almost overnight from a
2-year delivery schedule to one of 3
weeks as of the time I recorded this
video they have completed 235 Sprints
and delivered 235 times to production in
this new
model this was not always the case and
many of the tools features and
capabilities which persist assist from
the visual studio team system days of
the product are much more relevant for
companies that are not using agile
practices when Microsoft created team
Foundation server back in 2006 the
intent was to create a connected
experience for all of the tools and
capabilities that an engineering team
would use the idea was to create a
holistic connected experience from
idation all the way through to delivery
with full traceability of how and why
things were added however back in 2006
Microsoft found this to be at odds with
the organization's General Outlook and
they ended up with a very Microsoft
Technology only focused
system fast forward to 2001 and the move
to the cloud and suddenly those
limitations were much more prominent and
needed to be fixed there's a fantastic
paper from buck hudies director of
engineering for aure devops on this and
I'll put a link in the comments
below as Microsoft transformed TFS to
become a cloud product it also addressed
many of the Microsoft Centric issues
that it held back its adoption the tool
started to reflect the original Dream
and the idea of 1es or one engineering
system was
born the intent of 1es as with the
original team system was to reduce the
complexity of product delivery by
ensuring that everybody working a
product knew where their stuff was work
items builds releas these environments
and
more today as your devop supports any
technology from any stack and has
enabled that one yes dream however as
with all products users use them in many
ways that were not envisaged by their
creators but with something as
complicated as a your devops there are a
number of things that users do that go
against the very intent and paradigms of
the tool
itself I'll show you the top four issues
that give the Azure devops team
palpitations so the first item that has
the assured devops product team pulling
their hair out is same level hierarchy
creating a hierarchy of work items that
happen to be exactly the same level so
let's take a look at what that looks
like I'm going to show a simple example
and then we'll go make a customization
and show show a more complicated example
so here I have uh my product uh backlog
um I've got my product backlog items uh
I have under here a a t a task which is
a sub item uh so I can quite easily go
in here and add a new item um I'm going
to call it a child and I'm going to add
a task uh task to uh click okay you can
see I uh suck at
that and now I have two uh uh tasks
underneath this item but what I've done
over here is I have added uh product
back plug items as children of product
backlog items so it is represented on
this board and I should be able to can I
still move this around oh I can still
move H this around here but when I go to
try and grab one of these items I can
order it inside of the context oh and
there I've managed to break it uh this
is this is why this is a problem uh so
work item uh 40 52 C be ordered because
it's appearent in the same
category so if I hit refresh it'll have
gone back to where it
was there we go um so I I was just
trying to order within this category and
it jumped out and that was the problem
if I go and try and order it over here I
will immediately get that error that's
the one I was going to show you um and
now I I can't do anything with that
until I uh refresh and it will go back
underneath because it has a parent child
relationship ship you can't order that
hierarchy I cannot reorder these backlog
items within the context of anything
other than this backlog item and in fact
when I move it to the bottom there it's
might pop out I might is it going to pop
out what if I put this one here see it's
not not doing oh there we go I managed
to uh pop it pop it out there um it's
very easy to do when you have this set
up this is not how aure devops is
designed to work at all um so this one's
a a fairly obvious example of of when
this is broken uh but let's go take a
look at what we can do uh to make it a a
little bit less obvious more complicated
solution what so what I'm going to do is
I'm going to go into the
process and I am going to um I've got
feature disabled let's see what am I
going to do uh let's let's create a new
backlog item um we're going to call it
uh okr we're going to call it okr just
for fun um and what I'm going to do I'm
going to make it another color so that
it doesn't look like it's on the same
level okay so I've added this new item I
just wanted the default one right so now
I have an okr here oh I don't like that
um oh well The Tick's fine okay so I'm
going to go over to backlog
levels and I'm going to edit this
backlog level and I'm going to add okrs
on the same back oh I could do it with
risk as well oo that would be lovely so
I'm going to add H this in here now I
have okrs and risk at the same level as
this backlog um if you're going to have
work items at the same level that's fine
but it should always be a flat list so
now that's all saved if I go back and
I'm going to refresh
this okay so now on this backlog I can
click new work item and I will have all
of those options I've got um okr risk
bug I have lots of different things so
let's uh ok
R1 add to top OK R2 that's just so that
we remember what we were creating um and
I'm going to do risk and this is risk
one and risk
two okay so this all works great and I
should be able to order these Within
uh my backlog because my backlog is an
ordered list of work all of the things
on my backlog should be Tim limited
things that are going to be
delivered but now I've got um some
different things on here now okrs I can
imagine being a Time limited thing that
we're going to deliver and then they'll
disappear risks we don't really deliver
risks so they should probably never be
on a backlog uh but loads of people will
what they will try and do is they'll go
oh I want this
risk to be a child of what did we do
here uh Let's do let's do this one again
just to make it even more dysfunctional
uh we're going to create a new item and
I create that as a a child I'm going to
add that risk in as your devops will let
you do it as your devops has a the
underlying work item tracking system
didn't used to have these Adu planning
tools on top and you could do whatever
you wanted with whatever work item type
under the covers however now I've got
risk as a child of the product backlog
item and I might even think oh can I
even order that oh no I managed to break
it already you can see as soon as you
start doing uh um some of these things
it's going to get even well it only goes
up or down I can do that oh it it starts
to work really weird there's loads of
considerations in here the product team
can't take care of everything and you
can even see that it's not doing an
ordered list um as part of this these
items should not oh and it's even doing
very starting to do very weird stuff now
let me refresh that
again you should not have items that are
at the same level in the backlog as a
parent child relationship with each
other it's perfectly okay uh to have
different items at the same level so I
might have a bunch of bugs on my boards
that are going to be managed in here
here along with everything else and I
can order them with the rest of my work
that makes perfect sense but please try
and avoid having parent child
relationships at the same backlog level
and you'll see at the backlog level here
I have three items at other backlog lels
you might only have one item the easy
way around this is to just have one item
uh but if you do have bugs on the
backlog you'll also have bugs please
don't do this
the second thing that has the Azure
devops team pulling their hair out is
blocked columns or really any temporary
State
column the expectation for the states on
a work item is that every work item will
move through all of those
States if you create a temporary State
there's a number of process things that
become a problem but in reporting you're
going to have columns on your board
which not all work should pass through
let me show you what I mean so let me
switch to my board here for my
backlog those of you that are cand
minded might have noticed that I forgot
to mention whip
limits if you have uh one of these
temporary State columns like a blocked
column you are effectively hiding whip
whip goes over to a different field alth
the way is a different colum although
it's actually in that other column that
it has to go back to and lots of teams
you not deliberately but they hide that
whip over there so they can have more
things in progress cuz this blocked
thing doesn't count that's not how it's
supposed to work the blocked things
still
count
and here I have a customized board so I
have new approved um options develop
validate and done every work item on my
board is expected to move through all of
these
states uh the the item in new will be
approved by the product owner the item
that's approved by the product owner
will become an option for the team um
the team will then start working uh
during their Sprint and then they'll
pull things in to develop it it will go
from develop to develop done because
they've completed the development work
and then it will wait wait in this done
uh develop dun column as a wait State
until whoever's doing the validation
perhaps the same people are able to pull
that uh uh item into validate um and
then once the validation has been
successful they're going to drop it into
done that would be the common flow for
all of the work flowing across this
board let me make a little customization
this is the most common one uh that
people add I'm going to
add a blocked
column um now my first problem is what
state is it blocked in
which of these states is it blocked in
it's either blocked in the approved
State the new state the approved State
or the impr progress State uh whichever
one I
pick that might be weird so let me show
you let's say um blocked stuff is kind
of outside it's not really in progress
cuz it's blocked but maybe it was in
progress when we blocked it maybe it was
approved from we blocked it how do we
know what state it's supposed to go back
to let me just stick it in the new state
I'm going to have blocked items on the
left hand side of the board there so now
I've got an item in develop here it
becomes blocked so I'm going to move it
into
blocked and now well actually I think I
messed that up it's still in approved
wow it's gone to approved what did I do
wrong uh columns blocked ah I only
changed bug so if I change that to new
it's actually not going to let is it
going to let me do that
but that item disappears lovely jubly
let's move another item in there you can
see I'm already starting to run into
weird issues now I've put this item in
the blocked column um it becomes
unblocked uh where do I put it which
column does it go to well I can't
remember so I'm going to open the item
I'm going to go to the history and I'm
going to see it was approved and then
push back to new so so now it it was in
approved um so then it becomes an option
uh the team starts working on it and it
gets blocked
again so then we go to unblock it and we
go in we look at the details and now
it's gone from uh new to approved to new
to approved to
new
okay but we had it in develop so we put
it back in develop open it up
well that's H Madness is it in it is it
actually in progress it is in progress
see I am running into lots of issues
already so I'm going
to uh I maybe need to refresh my
board there we go and then I'm going to
open up the work item I'm going to go
back to here and there we go now we can
see everything that's going on so it
went from it went to new then to approve
then to new then to approve then to in
progress then to new then into in
progress but in actual fact under the
covers uh you'll see the board column uh
was blocked not blocked blocked not
blocked right oh we could mitigate this
there are some of you out there
screaming well what I would do is I
would go into my
process and I would go into
my uh put a backlog item I'd go into
States and I'd add like a core state for
this
item but now we have exactly the same
problem where should this blocked column
go in the core states is it blocked in
progress or is it blocked
proposed if it's blocked proposed and it
was in progress we're taking it out of
in progress into proposed if it's
blocked proposed and we put the blocked
column in progress then we're moving it
from proposed to in
progress this is madness this is going
to cause loads of issues this is true
whether you've got a blocked column
uh I don't know what else might you have
um on hold um any sort of intermittent
state that could appear in any column of
your board what is a much more effective
idea I'm going to remove that nasty
nasty blocked column a much more
effective idea is we create a tag for
blocked if I add a new uh blocked tag
boom save
that and now I can very easily see that
this item was blocked and approved I can
see that this item was
blocked in develop and it is very clear
which column they were blocked in how
they were well maybe not how they were
blocked you need to ask some questions
but I know that was blocked in developed
so I might ask different questions from
it's blocked and approved and when I
want to remove blocked I can very easily
just go remove the tag hit save and now
that item is no longer marked as blocked
now I was able to achieve that uh with
an extra uh annotation here a tag color
blocked his bright red R so that it is
obvious on the board but tagging is a
great way to Mark blocked in addition
that will support other plugins
certainly plugins that I like to use I
have actionable agile uh metrics for uh
predictability around here so there's
the actionable agile um tool which gives
you much better graphs on what's going
on with your data it's just loaded the
sample data but if I load the Azure data
I can load the board history uh go grab
that scrum team I think we were on scrum
Team 2 um and I can
go
I've probably not chosen a board we're
going to load backlog items there we go
it's lit up it's going to go load that
data 34 work items um and I have some
stuff that's changed behind the scenes
uh so I'm going to go take that in
progress State and stick it on here
that's where I want those two items to
exist so now I can model uh this on the
board um it might not have anything
useful on the board because um this is
demo environment uh but if something is
blocked in here you will see the blocked
time in days popping up um and that will
use the blocked um tag and it will not
use a blocked column cand teams should
not ever have blocked columns um that
creates a lot of dysfunctional behaviors
so please try and avoid having a blocked
column and instead opt for a Blog tag
with a highlight don't use blocked
columns or any uh temporary State
columns on your board and certainly
don't add it to work items and force
everybody to have
them the third thing that makes the
Azure devops team's toes
curl is too many work item
States now work item States exist at a
much lower level in Azure devops than
team choice so when we were looking at
changing columns on a board adding more
columns removing columns that gives
individual teams within the context of a
project lots of flexibility and how they
want to work what they want to report on
what their workflow is and what they
want to see but lots of organizations
are
incredibly uh uh
authoritarian on the way that they do
this and they mandate a bunch of states
for everybody so here I've got an
example I've got a a project here um a
bunch of States has been added and I'm
going to go to my board and suddenly
you'll see this is this is going to be a
problem the column configurations are
not correct cuz those columns don't
exist somebody's messed with them and I
need to fix it uh so oh that's the howto
fix it I don't want that I just want to
fix it correct it now and it's going to
pop up that board and now I had my
original approved options develop
validate done and now I've got a bunch
of crazy things in the middle so let's
have a look at what we've
got
okay these are the columns the minimum
set of columns I'm now more or less
forced to use as a team so if I go into
my admin and I create a new team
teams new
team scrum team
three create that I probably need to set
some stuff up so I'll do it now let from
Team
three have I got my iteration yes I've
got a default iteration path let's who
where what Sprint are we on I can't
remember the dates but let's put
six let's do
that and we have area paths okay we're
all good so
now I click on boards and I go to my
scrum team 3 board this will be the
default board that every team that uses
this project will get it's massive it's
not only does it barely fit on the
screen in fact it doesn't fit on the
screen I've got to scroll to get let me
zoom out there we go now I've got
everything on the screen at 50% um not
only that uh but adding items to the to
the board
um moving them across you can see that
it's going to take H time to move them
across all of these states are on that
work item it's just an absolute mess now
I can as a team member go in and say uh
I don't want
feedback I don't want
review we're going to have we don't want
design and I don't want initiation we're
going to have new uh uh well is approval
and approved new
approved um and then we're going to have
only one state in so we're going to have
develop uh
um there's a lot of columns in here
let's get rid of that in
progress uh pre-production uat so we're
going to have
this
oh column has two items in it the design
column I can't get rid of oh joy so let
me put these
back go and uh I want to remove remove
design remove initiation remove remove
remove feedback remove approval I've got
approved develop validate remove in
progress pre there that's a little bit
more manageable a little bit more
manageable but now although I can move
work items through these states you can
see that it added the pre-production
state on there but here it's just
develop and validate but if I go into my
States and somebody moves a work item to
one of the states that doesn't exist on
my board my work item disappears you
need to have all of those States in
order to be able to see all the work
items you could do some mitigating
around making sure that you have queries
that show work items that are in states
that you're not using but it just
overloads the team it overloads um the
it doesn't overload the tool you can see
the tool renders it just fine but how do
you find the stuff you're looking for
how do you know what state it's supposed
to be in how do you uh move things
through that state and if I now add a
bug onto this board
um which the bug only has uh two states
you can see it's in approved it's now in
New it's now in New New uat
done oh that's that's the bug new and
done it makes it more difficult for
teams it makes it more difficult for
administrators it makes it more
difficult for
collaboration please don't use too many
states the fourth thing uh that gets in
the way of aure devops is too many work
item types like
why do we need more than a few work item
types it's really common I see this a
lot with customers um I know the Azure
devops team talk about this one a lot it
causes a lot of performance issues um
but too many work item types like what
do we need them for I've got I've got an
example here um of too many work I'm
work item types so here's uh my back
clog and this back clog has 1 two 3 four
five different work item types here here
technical debt Sprint goal okr user
story and hypothesis um I don't know why
you would want this many work item types
all it creates is additional choices
that are a little bit difficult to to
change you you can just change work item
type that is
possible um but why why have so many I I
don't understand it myself I'm going to
show you what I mean if I open up the
project here um and I have
seen I've made this one um but I have
seen uh projects that have this this
many uh work item types I've seen
application change requests compliance
task dependency all of these things I
have seen um perhaps not kitchen sink I
haven't seen kitchen sink um but that's
what it feels like something sometimes
we're going to put everything including
the kitchen sink in here and it serves
to
confuse um and confound people if you
remember some of the previous things we
talked about was um uh a hierarchy at
the same backlog level so now I've got
hypothesis okr Sprint gos technical debt
and user story at the same level so now
I can go in here and say well this is my
user story and uh let say my Sprint goal
I'm going to add that user story as a
child of that
item um and I'm going to add um
let's and I'm going to add
that as a
parent that
one
and this seems to make perfect logical
sense right I've got some okrs uh that
I'm trying to achieve I'm going to have
this is my goal this Sprint which is to
achieve that okr and then I have user
stories when you have multiple items at
the same level it's definitely much more
likely that this is going to occur uh uh
within a a project or product um and it
just gets confusing because now we can
no longer order those items like you saw
before um we can no longer do other
things with these items uh also you can
see here I've got items at different
levels so here I've got feature has
application feature product goal
research item and epic has epic which is
the default initiative and I added
Kitchen syn in there just for fun um and
then there's a whole bunch of here that
are not associated with any particular
backlog so it's okay to have a few extra
work item types you might add something
like um risk to to to to to your backlog
but if it's if we're talking about
pieces of work um especially things like
a hypothesis or an okr that might make
better sense as a field on your standard
work item right the I I could add a new
field in here for the type of user story
and have uh this is this is
a an epic this is a Fe this is a a a use
case this is a user story right um
rather than user story being the type I
prefer to have product backlog item and
then add those types to it right how am
I breaking down these different uh work
items because I want to do something
different with them much more effective
to use a field um and then you never
need to change type from one type to
another type so what I want you def
itely want you to do when you're
thinking about
whether you should add a new work item
type is is the reason that you need it
painful enough that you have to have it
um Can it just be a tag applied
to a work item that would be the most
optimal fastest quickest easiest
cheapest least invasive uh way to do
that next do we need to have a field on
the work item cuz maybe we want to
report on it um don't just put add
fields and report on it because somebody
says they want to report on it um I I
get this a lot awful lot in
organizations where they want to add
custom custom work item types add custom
Fields add custom States because they
want to report on it my first question
is always what different choices are you
going to make based on these reports
what reports are they going to appear in
and what different choices is the
business or the team going to make based
on that data if they can't answer that
question I I probably not going to
create that work item type I'm not going
to add that extra field there needs to
be a reason for it to be there because
it's more to manage it's more to support
it's more for people to do it leads to
more confusion which means you need more
training how do people know what all of
these work item types and extra fuels
and extra states are for what they're
supposed to be for are they using them
correctly who's checking that these
things are all being used correct this
is just a maintenance nightmare it just
doesn't make sense to use too many work
item states don't put the kitchen sink
in that
list that was the top four rookie
mistakes in Azure devops that make the
product team's toes curl if you are
finding that you have any of these types
of issues in your environment the
agility can help you or we can help you
find somebody who can don't wait the
longer you leave these types of issues
in place the more expensive it can be to
fix get in touch in the comments
[Music]
below