when scrum
Masters
don't have an
understanding of
both the the
philosophies theories and practices
within the context of the
team and an understanding of what the
team does every
day the
impact on those teams and those
organizations is
profound they're not going to
improve right if if you took
uh if you you had a coach for a soccer
team that didn't understand soccer had
never played
soccer how
effective would they
be at coaching that team in the
processes and practices that you need
now
immediately a bunch of folks are
thinking but Ted lasso did
it you got to remember Ted lasso is a
fictional character and that fictional
character runs off a script and the
script works because plot so he's a good
coach because and successful coach sorry
because
plot right not because it would work in
the real
world every
almost
every
successful
coach for a sports
team
understands
fundamentally how that sport
works the
training the specific training
techniques that need to be done in order
to
maximize the capability of that team
right if they
don't they have sub
coaches right that
help for a specific thing like I think
in American football you have an
offensive coach and a defensive coach
and then you probably have an overall
coach and the overall coach might have a
different skill set from the offensive
and defensive coachies
right but they have a fundamental
understanding of the sport its rules uh
the the training techniques the types of
muscles that are used by the team and
how they can train those muscles to be
as effective as possible how they
prevent injury all of those sporty
things and that's what we're talking
about when we talk about uh competence
of of scrum Masters they need to
understand if they're a scrum Master for
an engineering team they need to
understand all the engineering team
things that they the team needs to be
able to learn
practice uh do change in order to become
more effective and if that's not there
they won't change if you have somebody
who is
just a um professional
coach right and perhaps taking a two-day
scrum Master
Class
typically what you will
see is very little actual Improvement in
the team's ability to deliver product
they might be better at engaging with
each
other but are they actually better at
delivering product because that is what
your business cares about they want
product they want working usable product
that solves business problems that's
what we're here for that's what we're
paid for that's the outcome they want to
improve have these scrum Masters
actually improved
that is is that what we're measuring at
all the lack of basic
skills around scrum
Masters results in an
organization's
continued um status quo which is likely
an inability to deliver which is why
they brought in scrum Masters in the
first place because building software is
hard building building products that
don't exist yet is
hard are we making the right bets are we
um using the right philosophies in how
we build our product how we design our
features how we get our features in
front of our customers how we engage
with the rest of the
Business Without understanding all of
those things we're not we're not going
to be able to help the team be effective
we're going to have them I don't know
I'm being factious B sitting doing some
Lego team building exercises and perhaps
building a bridge with spaghetti and
straws right which which sure might be
great for for for a team building
exercise like Myers Briggs right I've
done some Myers Briggs exercises with uh
uh teams I've worked on for
organizations I've worked with and it's
a great team building exercise um but
it's of no value for delivery
there's only so much you can help a
team from the context of the
[Music]
team working together more
effectively but there's a massive
difference you can make by improving
their
knowledge right it's like it's like in
lean you you can you can make a certain
amount of um impact by looking at
reducing
batch
size right if you make the work items
smaller you're going to you're going to
improve the
flow but your biggest bang for your buck
is probably limiting
whip right that's where the highest
percentages a scrum Master helping a
team the biggest bang for your buck is
that scrum Master being able to teach
the team new skills and capabilities
that enable it to be more effective
enable it to build better products to
test more effectively have higher
quality these are the skills the primary
skills that you want your scrum Master
to have knowledge and
competence so that they can help the
team once all of those are awesome
perhaps at the same time right but once
all of those are awesome
and the biggest bang for our buck then
becomes because the team is already
awesome at engineering they have the
best devops practices they can they have
the best architectures they can in their
product they have the most effective uh
Engineering
Systems then if we enable the team to
collaborate more effectively we'll get
more stuff right that that's a small
percentage of the overall if
Effectiveness and we get that from
competence so organizations are
suffering because they don't have scrum
Masters that fundamentally understand
the work that needs to be done and how
to enable that work to be more effective