one of the things that a new product
owner needs to understand is that
there's a lot of their job which is
about
marketing you're going to be marketing
the the vision that you have in your
product to the people doing the work to
the people consuming the work and to the
people paying for the work might be
different people they have to buy into
your story they have to engage with what
it is you're trying to to do and
ultimately they need to engage
emotionally with that story that's what
marketing is all about is how do you
enable people to engage emotionally with
what it is you're trying to do so that
they're following with anticipation what
it is that you're trying to do that's
how you get people engaged in your story
one of the the key issues I see in
organizations is the Great difficulty
that product owners especially new
product owners find in getting your
stakeholders to turn up for your Sprint
reviews right and often times it's hard
even if they do turn up to get them to
provide you with feedback right you ask
them for feedback and all you can hear
is tumble weeds rolling through the
desert right you're trying to engage
them and they're just not getting there
and that's to me a marketing issue they
don't understand the value of what
you're showing them they're not
emotionally engaged in what you're
showing them if they were emotionally
engaged they'd be desperate to sneak
into that Co that discussion and provide
that feedback provide you with more
information and that is part of
marketing you need to figure that out
how do you get into that story we talk
about it in the professional scrum
product owner only a little bit I talk
about it more than the course whereare
does so um I like I I like this topic um
but also we talk about it a little bit
more in depth in the advanced product
owner because we start talking about the
Visionary and the collaborator and the
different aspects of the product owner
and that's where it starts to matter a
little bit more when you get a little
bit more advanced but marketing is that
piece that enables you to sell your
story and your conversation to the other
people that are involved in your product
and maximize the value that you're
delivering because all the people
funneling providing input to your funnel
that results in your product backlog
that results in the value that you're
delivering as you release to customers
everybody's following the same funnel
rather than buffing buffing against it
um with friction because they're all
going in different directions is your
leadership of your organization are your
members of your team are your customers
all aligned in where you're going and
what you're trying to
achieve that's your job as a product
owner to figure that out if you find it
hard to enable this engagement with your
your your stakeholders and get them into
your Sprint reviews my team at n agility
can help perfect your ability to do that
or we can find somebody who can help you
don't let these sorts of issues inhibit
your ability to deliver value that lack
of feedback at the review kind of sucks
use the links in the description to get
help as soon as you can