why do I think the advanced pspo is a
perfect fit for entrepreneurs because it
focuses on the things that that
entrepreneurs need to think about and
maybe sometimes they don't
um
are are what are you focused on what
what type of
um product owner right or are you
looking to be
um what are the the facets of the
product owner that you need to reflect
in order to have a successful product in
a successful business quite often people
believe that they just have to be the
Steve Jobs type right and focus on focus
on uh Innovation and doing something
different
but that that maybe doesn't is that
going to alienate your existing
customers that are just looking for
refinements and the features that they
already have is that going to alienate
your your development teams who feel
like we're always reaching for the new
thing and never finishing the thing that
we've got is that going to
um
you know if you just focus on one of
those uh facets of the the product or
stancies of the product owner then
you're missing out on a whole bunch of
other other things that need to need to
be done you need balance right and I
think that's really the core uh focus of
the the advanced product owner is not
just to say
you know yeah you might be in this
category where do you feel you are
because we do have that conversation
right where would you put yourself in in
these six stances of the product owner
that we're going to talk about in the
class but also and talk about each of
those stance season what they're missing
from those dances because quite often
product owners do a little bit of that
thing right the the the we talk a lot in
the class about hypothesis driven
engineering right you don't necessarily
although data informs but doesn't
control the choices you make you need to
get that data and how do you get that
data and how do you decide whether the
feature that you're creating is actually
valuable like what numbers are you
trying to shift and how are you going to
measure it so that that whole holistic
Focus across the product across your
your your your customers not just in
Innovation but in customer focus in
collaboration in doing deals with people
right how do you get collaboratively
create those those most amazing products
and that for me is the value of the
advanced product owner
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility