so in my view uh poly immersive learning
experience has a lot of fantastic
benefits but when speaking about three
the most important ones so first one we
are in the complex world right so we
obviously don't know what we don't know
we have some knowledge about risks and
ambiguities what will most likely happen
is that when you will go back to your
environment you will see oh some of the
things don't work as expected or the the
outcome is not the one that I was hoping
for so every your every assignment
brings this opportunity that you learn
okay it did not work you come back
so it's a fantastic learning feedback
loop because you can go back for
additional coaching feedback from the
trainer you may you may share your
findings with other participants
um and you will have some Inspirations
what to do when moving forward
uh second benefit that I can think of
is about time so as I as I already
mentioned
um I believe some of the students simply
need time to digest to think to reflect
it's a natural in my in my view it's a
natural feeling you simply need this
retrospective time for yourself and in
this way in immersive class way you have
regular time for reflection you have
more time for digesting the whole
content and this format brings you
regular opportunities to ask more
questions when you are ready
last but not least the problem very
typical for many students I'm amazed
with the class A lot of learnings a lot
of tools but I came back and well I
forgot I did not have time right and
with this format we are holding you
accountable we are helping you with that
because every every module has an
assignment a small experiment that you
are supposed to conduct in your
professional environment
and thanks to that you can hold yourself
accountable and after the whole Learning
Journey you will have a set of a few
maybe even several experiments conducted
in your professional environment it
might be for you a great opportunity to
create habits of experimentation and
learning through that in your
organization