[Music]
oh my name's Martin Intuit I'm a
professional scum trainer with scrum the
dark as well as a Microsoft MVP I'm here
in Scotland and my good friend Jim is
over in where are you Jim I'm in the
United States in the Midwest
Midwest Ohio Ohio okay so that's if
there's a delay or there's a problem
that might be because of the internet
isn't this about that well this is kind
of just after lunch in the US yeah it's
three o'clock my time here everybody's
know Netflix yet probably within the
hour or so so I am interested in the
question that you had for me the other
day could you give me that you remember
what it was yeah so I got a call from a
colleague of mine who is on the agile
journey let's say and his current
struggle is from a technical perspective
so he has a number of development teams
and his his developers just don't
they're not thinking in an agile manner
they are not validating and getting good
feedback from customers and frankly to
be honest the biggest thing is they just
don't seem to really care about bad
quality going out the door or not
meeting the customers needs and these
are internal customers and a corporation
but you know he was asking me how would
you train development team members on
agile and scrum and that was really
where I reached out to you because my
expertise is more around product
ownership and scrum mastery than it is
working you know in teaching development
skills yeah I don't think this is an
evolved
no problem but I'm curious to hear what
you think yeah I was I was literally
just thinking that I was thinking that
it doesn't sound like a development
skill problem
I find that in engineers tend to be
reasonably smart people um and the
reason you might have a problem is
because they're they're disengaged from
work so just like you would expect a
product owner or scrum master to step up
and um maybe being a little bit I don't
know what the word is blunt maybe step
up and do their job I also suspect an
engineering team to step up and do
theirs but if they're disengaged with
the work that tends to be a cultural
problem yeah and that's really where my
comments to him when is you know we can
do technical practices we can teach TDD
we can do pair programming and mob
programming sessions and we can talk
about you know iterative design and
emergent design and all that but really
it seems like how do you get people to
care and how do you get them to care
about quality and have some pride in
workmanship pride and craftsmanship and
the interesting thing about that is
their business is very manufacturing
focused so they are used to delivering
end products like tangible goods to
customers so I think there's some
interesting analogies there around
caring about quality and customer
feedback and you know kind of that that
aspect of software craftsmanship is
definitely a difficult one because if
you do have people the are technically
competent it's it's always possible that
you don't but if you do have people that
are technically come
and then it comes down to the the X the
intrinsic motivations rather than
extrinsic motivations and you'll be
familiar with Dan Pink's book drive and
talking about autonomy mastery and
purpose and that's usually where I would
start for an engineering team is um look
at what are they lacking in those three
things right yeah that's good
I could I've spent quite a bit at a time
with some of these teams so I think I
could take a few guesses but I mean it
would be presumptuous of me to know at
the individual level but I think at the
high level their autonomy is probably
not great in their per their sense of
purpose is probably a pretty low the
thing I don't know the dimension I don't
know is their mastery because I know
that you know here the the feeling of I
need a two pair program with experience
out and developers to teach them skills
so I think there's two aspects to it I
think there's a technical concern that
they're not great developers and then I
think mindset can people to care how do
you teach people do
think
soles and Keith doesn't mind their work
yeah exactly you were breaking up a
little bit there it wasn't too bad I
think it was an internet issue that's
just the world we live in
yeah and I'm sure I'm sure it'll be in
fine as we go ya know I've noticed a few
things have happened recently and that's
that I decided I wanted another webcam
because I have I have another monitor
over here and when I'm looking at this
monitor it looks like I'm not looking at
you yeah and I went to by having to buy
a webcam
yeah and there aren't any left no no
hair clippers either oh yeah this is
this is terrible this is the worst mine
has been in years
yeah my wife's been complaining quite a
lot but we just don't have Clippers
she's got a pair of scissors but I don't
know if I want to let her have a goal
with a pair of scissors yeah interesting
stop yeah you know who's still got
Clippers in stock I bet two pet stores
nice stores stores yeah that's a good
point
I was at a pet store over the weekend
and then they had a whole shelf load of
Clippers so yeah it is interesting I
read an interesting article which I
guess is part meant for the type of work
that we do in floor as to why there's so
many shortages and the article was
talking about the the the flow of goods
has more than one channel so for example
for toilet paper which is currently
substantially missing from shelves and
lots of there are companies that make
commercial grade toilet paper and those
don't make it onto the supermarket
shelves and we're no longer using
commercial grade
toilet paper those distribution channels
are empty you know they've got all the
toilet paper but nobody to use them and
the the EM was it the opposite of
commercial the public consumer consumer
is looking for thank you the consumer
chains are getting overloaded because of
just that switch so there everybody's
making the same amount of toilet paper
we're just using it differently yeah I
think this is akin to like the nineteen
forties where new markets are gonna pop
up so things that were used to dispose
of we're now gonna be like what can we
use this for and then so there's gonna
be this use of byproducts and it'll be
really interesting to see if we kind of
kick off this second self-sustaining
generation this of you know being
self-sufficient and eating what you grow
and and using the most of everything and
this could be an amazing shift away from
rampant consumerism but it's funny I did
a consumer products company last year
and I feel that right now there is the
data science experiment going on in
every retail store in the world which is
two things
it's buying patterns it's so what are
people buying first in times of hysteria
I am more intrigued by the products that
are left on the shelves so what is the
last bag of pretzels bought what is the
last jar of peanut butter
what is the last type of toilet paper to
be grabbed and what would influence
those decisions and do companies and
retailers care or what a date of
scientists and I'm not a data scientist
say you know you can't make any
decisions during a time like this
because it's unprecedented and it's not
significant from a data perspective
because of the hysteria an impulse
nature of things I don't know but to me
it's always shocking to be like look at
all the ketchups
why is that one ketchup left and all the
other ones are gone like what does that
tell that producers in a few
images from people taking pictures in
supermarkets of the vegan aisle in the
supermarket and everything's still there
I did think that was I noticed it in my
local supermarket as well and that all
of the the meat replacement goods were
where all the shelves were fully stocked
and it's funny I did have some recently
and it's pretty tasty it's just not the
go-to that people think of when we when
we go shopping yeah yeah yeah I think
again and I don't want to get to like
Phyllis it if you think about which of
your principles will be the last to go
and which ones are the first to go so I
I have a friend who's a vegan or was a
vegan and it's like I don't care I'm
eating meat right now because I need
protein and there there are amassing
meat so they quickly let that principle
go out of for many reasons fear Asteria
impulse etcetera but it just is it's
very telling in my opinion I agree and
it depends how how long this goes on for
both of those things you know what's the
last what's your last principle to go as
well as and whether the data science is
going to have an impact whether changes
significant changes need to be made to
the the distribution pipeline and I
think there are some people I've been
reading some articles people talking
about everything changing and that it
will just be different from from now on
but then it hasn't been that different
in Asia where they've been through
something like this before they still
have rampant consumerism they still have
and they probably just wears masks you
see that uh a lot and even just people
wear them anyway when they're out and I
think it is it's going to be interesting
how how long this goes on for what's
going to change because um we've got an
expectation in the UK from our our what
was he called the the health person in
chief the chief scientist behind some of
the decisions they're making and he says
is six to twelve months yeah we're going
to be in some kind of restricted set up
they've already said that the schools
here I don't know what it's been like
for you guys but the schools here aren't
going back till after the summer
holidays so that's August before the
schools go back at the at the earliest
and I guess they'll reassess then and
see what's going on but homeschooling is
something that seems to be happening a
lot in some places have have their act
together for schools doing some kind of
distance learning and other places
they're just emailing some homework and
hoping people do it yeah you know I I
had a conversation the other day with a
family member and she was like you know
man wouldn't this be I've been great
when we were kids and I said no because
we'd be bored like when I hear kids
today
just want to smack a website there you
have no board in 2020 but
would be different back than like how
would
even
if I was in
maybe
working through the drive-through
homework assignments and bring them home
redeliver them but
available now that
and exist five
one year
so yeah it's it's unprecedented so to
bring it back to what you and I do for a
safety yeah say if we talk about
principles what principles do you think
are even more important now and that
team should focus on and and really
spend a lot of time working to
strengthen given this new I'm calling it
our new Wow
our way of working so give it our new
Wow what's more important than ever
before I would I would think I'm coming
back to to some of the the scrum values
probably makes sense for for me and I
think it's gonna be really hard to get
and teams to have the same level of
commitment to each other that they can
have in person when you can poke the
other person you know that other person
is there when you can't see somebody
you've you've said you'll do something
for is the same level of commitment
going to going to be going to be a
parent and how do we create that same
level of commitment
I'm just hoping teams are not thinking
that they only need to talk during the
daily scrum yeah somebody a scrum master
or asked me the other day hey does it
feel that you like we have more meetings
now and I got thinking it does and it is
as I look at my calendar and I have a
number of quick 1520's
let's say discuss this technical problem
or discuss this plan or do this where
those conversations would have happened
organically in the off and a drive-by
you know like walking up to goal having
a what
if we had to go third-person we just now
you see I'm gonna schedule time to make
sure you're in the WebEx camera and able
to you know miss so it does feel like
there's more of a schedule nature to
work it's interesting though you talk
about like I think what I heard you
talking about was follow-up like
committing like delivery commitments to
each other a lot of times lately where I
have forgotten owed somebody something
pretty small because I just get
destroyed I don't I'm not as focused as
I was before in the office and I didn't
have all my tools and trappings
available to keep me focused on the work
at hand so I find it easier for little
things to slip through but and the flip
side of that is more attitude now and
I'm like yeah I think I can you know
give me two minutes I'm gonna run to the
to the kitchen fine I'll be right back
and I can do that you know at work me
being distracted Thanks yeah I I agree
and I think especially with everybody
off everybody are the schools being off
and people's kids being at home there
can't be the same expectation of
commitment from folks anyway yeah I
think it's going to be very difficult to
find to find that level of commitment
yeah do the metrics change at all or do
you think that the metrics that
leadership and the organization cares
about is gonna change if this persists
for months and months it depends if if
leadership are focused on yeah I'm gonna
use a bad phrase I don't like using it
the metrics they should be rather the
metrics they shouldn't then I don't
think the the shoot
change we should be looking at fart for
engineering teams or any teams building
some kind of product or some kind of
output then we should be looking at
value delivery are we getting the most
valuable thing it doesn't really matter
whether people spend 12 hours a day or
two hours a day if we're getting enough
value that we as an organization and our
customers are happy with the output that
we're getting then then or sorry the
output I used the wrong word again the
outcomes that we're getting then it's
irrelevant how much people actually work
right but I think and again I'm making
some leaps here is an organization that
has a really good track record of
measuring outcomes and value could
easily say hey we're getting the same or
greater value delivered than we used to
but think about a company or
organization who had what their value
was and they were only measuring output
in activities like hours billed or lines
of code written my fear is they are
going to over index even more so and
over focus on getting every drop of
orange juice out of that out of that
fruit and say I have to squeeze harder
and how to and say well hey you're
getting what you've always gotten you
know so you should be happy with you
know we have lower costs probably and
we're getting the same but just to say
that we have to know what the same was
yeah so a company that didn't do the
hard work early to figure out how to
measure and track value delivery doesn't
have a baseline
yeah I totally get that
and I think that it's gonna be very
difficult for those those companies to
figure out what what they're going to do
and I have I have a slight inkling that
those companies will just die I I've got
a feeling that and as they realize that
from their perspective they're not
getting their return on investment
because they
investment is based on quantity of work
not quality of work so they feel that
they are not getting the return on
investment they divest themselves of
employees in order to how many how many
employees in the last how many people
signed on in the that's British
expression what's it called when you
register for as unemployed in the US
there's a name for it I can remember the
USA's we called signing on here fire
file if I oh yeah I'll file for yeah
yeah um Ted over 10 million people have
filed in the last two weeks in the US
and it's it's not in as high a
percentage of that as that here in the
UK mainly because the government is
paying eighty percent of people's
salaries you know for companies to stay
in business and not not go out of
business but I think companies that are
focused solely on the bottom line solely
on profit so Leon's that squeezed
squeezing more juice out I think I think
they're gonna go they're gonna go bust
they're gonna they're gonna break yeah
and III I think there are exceptions but
I think that's what will happen there's
two really interesting things I that I
see one is people are being extra
sensitive to expecting less like I see
people expecting less so it'll be
interesting to see if this how far this
goes if that correlates to people's take
on the workplace and measuring and
caring about the right things but the
other thing and completely different is
if I think about some of the really good
people that I work with over the years
and I'm like why are you still here you
know you seem to hate your job you don't
seem to like this company
no yeah but I'm comfortable you know
I've been coming to this building every
day for twelve years and I've been
working with the same people but imagine
if you take all of that comfort away and
everybody starts working remotely even
most
to the time well then changing your
employer is just as simple as changing
which VPN you log into and what your
email address is in your workplace the
people you interact with the building
your commute none of that matters so
what you might see is a higher
propensity for people to switch
employers to ones that value the right
things or seem to value them more
because it's the barrier to switches is
greatly diminish that time limit it's as
as people either switched to employers
who actually care rather than pretend to
care um or start their own businesses to
fill a gap in the market and care and
hire people who care maybe maybe this
could be a big push for the purely
capitalistic focused organizations who
are going to struggle if they're though
there was a big push and towards a lean
but in the wrong way
you know III ever I have a horrible
story about how lean was implemented
Lean Six Sigma if you're familiar with
the term Lean Six Sigma was implemented
in an organization that I worked with
and where the IT support department did
you know Six Sigma training they got a
six sigma consultant turn they spent
three months doing this figuring out
what they were going to do and then they
implemented it and what the implemented
was shadow masks on their workstations
where their coffee cup goes at the end
of the day where their keyboard goes at
the end of the day where their mouse
goes at the end of the day and my
question was yeah that see that face
you've got that's the exact face I had
when they were presenting presenting
their awesomeness that they'd managed to
do in this Six Sigma world
and and for me they just completely
missed the point they missed the point
so they were they were focusing on you
know that that part of lean where you
would maybe optimize your workspace and
because maybe the consultant came out of
a manufacturing world and they're
talking around it in a manufacturing
world it was in fact a manufacturing
company so it there's a little bit of
synergy there that would be that that
level of expertise and but somebody on
in IT the physical world is not their
world and my first question was can I
find files on the file server quicker no
that can I create a support ticket
quicker can I find out what's going on
quicker and I think that missing missing
the point is happening quite a lot in
our industry it's why people talk about
all agile is dead or scrum is dead it's
not that it's dead people have just used
the terms and features incorrectly I
know that's I'm trying not to be
religious about it it's it's it might
work just fine but they're they've
they've messed with the name or
implemented it in a way that doesn't
necessarily provide them with the value
that they were looking for and then they
complain that the thing doesn't work
when in fact it's the implementation
that doesn't work and then backing off
and not inspecting and adapting is the
complete untag Anette antagonistic
opposite of agility yeah yeah that's a
lot to impact but something tells me
that that company read or attended some
work by Poul acres with two second lean
which is a great room
box is a great YouTube channel and a
great company and a lot of those little
kind of workspace hacks come from his
world what end to second lien is what
can you do in your day to save two
seconds like how can you optimize you
them so if you create two little Mark's
in your lunchroom and this is where the
salt shaker goes and this is where the
pepper shaker goes that might save two
seconds but then when we encourage
people to say how can you say two
seconds they end up saying well I found
this thing that can save 30 minutes or I
found this thing that can save five
hours so it's really about getting
people thinking about waste and seeing
the value in the 5s is one of which is
you know sorting and standardize this
works there's value in that as far as
building habits I think some of the
philosophy is if we help people get good
at organizing and see organizing as a
way to reduce waste they will figure out
how to store files on a file server more
efficiently yep but I think so many
times people stop at the easy stuff and
they don't do the hard work to say okay
great you figured out where my keyboard
could set on my desk but what are we
doing about that big giant problem in
you know the IT world or that big
database problem that we have over there
and it's making that leap from the
mindset of agility to the hard work and
practice of agility I agree and that's
the the thing that I see time and again
in organizations and it doesn't matter
whether you call it lean whether you
call it a jewel or scrum or Kanban or
DevOps it doesn't matter what you call
it the same fundamental goal is there
and is often often missed no I know you
don't come from our DevOps background
you're correct
yeah well yes and now my background
before I got into the world of advil was
all infrastructure so client-server
cloud network all that so I touch with
DevOps a little bit so I have a systems
background not a development background
but I'd say more kind of my background
was always in building high-performing
teams and knowing that my special power
- skill wasn't in always doing the work
but it was motivating inspiring and
helping others do their best work and
that's kind of the world I live in the
most cool so what what what does it be
you're working on just I'm so right now
I'm an agile coach and scrum master and
trainer for insight so I do a lot of
different things but I am primarily a
working scrum master an agile coach on a
product line at a large company here in
the United States so I'm working with
development teams and other scrum
masters who get really really important
work done tech very technical work and
it's really stretched my skills it's
taught me a lot that this engagement has
taught me a lot about myself about what
I'm good at what I'm not good at it and
how it's really helped me figure out how
to help build high-performing teams have
you run any of the scrum to dark classes
remotely yet so I am leading our very
first one in the company in April we're
gonna do a PSM live virtual it is April
vapor later this month the the tic-tock
tic-tock trust me I feel a little bit of
stress and anxiety there but I'm very
excited to though and then I'm going to
be copilot on more than likely on the
PSF live virtual and a poly I might be
leading a poly
live virtual
so I I have a pally in two weeks so I'm
doing a poly in the Edinburgh timezone
yeah public poly I have to to normal
people and one PST coming so normally I
don't know how difficult that will be
for my first live virtual classroom
escapade so it's going to be interesting
I attended a workshop last week and was
Todd's workshop and and he did it was me
as a PST and a bunch of normal people we
were from his some of his classes who
were just exploring things and they went
through a workshop so some good
learnings there in figuring out not only
how to run the workshop but how to
maintain the engagement levels that was
that was really good I really enjoyed
that but I've got the I'm jumping in
I've literally got I've got next week
free and then I jump into Polly Monday
Tuesday then the next Monday Tuesday PSF
next Monday Tuesday PSF next Monday
choose the PSM so it's gonna be a little
bit full-on at least I don't have them
all in the same week luckily the to
private PSFS that I'm doing and luckily
the customer said um you know we we want
to do we want to do it private which is
good and we want to do it Monday
Tuesday's because they have deployments
on a Saturday there there that's quite
every Saturday so they want they wanted
to front-load the week rather than back
load the week so that that helped me out
a little bit as well it meant they
didn't want to in the same week which
was a good idea yeah give me some time
to prep in between and optimize things a
little bit
but yeah I'm looking forward to that as
well you'll have to fill me in after
after the first one because we're
experimenting with for half-day sessions
go guys I just feel like it's gonna be
exhausting for both the instructors and
the students to do phase and and I have
never been successful in keeping
someone's attention electronically for
more than three to four hours yep but I
also know that there's pros and cons to
that approach the other thing I'm
curious are you gonna have a facilitator
or somebody who's supporting you from a
logistic standpoint so you can focus on
teaching so right now no I don't have
anybody who's gonna be helping me out so
I'm gonna be doing it all which is where
I'm thinking about the tools that I'm
going to use obviously well obviously
obviously for us maybe but that mural
has been seems to be a useful useful -
yeah I had in the workshop last week it
worked really well I've seen bits and
pieces over before and I think everybody
all the other trainers have been using
it to facilitate their workshops so much
so that I thinks Kramden are going to be
bringing out some templates
I think there's already templates
available for the PSM PSM and PSN - I
believe have templates so I think that
that will that will help a lot even if
it's just giving everybody a jump start
and then some stuffs pre-prepared and we
can just implement those templates but
also the the the the the video
conferencing tool and they were going to
be using I think is important as well I
had planned to use zoom and the reason I
plan to use zoom is it's good breakout
rooms but the museum has some
significant issues right now not
everybody's happy using zoom based on
the security concerns that have come out
in the last little while well it's all
we
the case once when you're when you're a
little player nobody cares and you
become a big player and everybody
everybody cares and I think the the yeah
I'm not particularly bothered about
leakage personally if that makes sense
like if if some part of my video goes
out and people get a hold of it CAA okay
whatever that's that's okay but I think
it's more the concern of students in the
class so I'm definitely running the PSFS
in Microsoft teams which is secure or at
least doesn't have any known biggest
holes in it but it does then require
everybody to authenticate um but also
that's the thing that makes it more
difficult to set up and manage initially
but it is the thing that negates the
problem that people have with the that
you can just jump in yeah you know we're
doing a lot of tool reviews as well and
it's funny because right is this thing
hit I had done a presentation around the
relationship of tools with agility and
it was very you know there is a certain
amount of premonition there because I
said tools do not make you agile but
they can absolutely enhance your daily
and getting good at tools and the
application of tools will should be
something you focus on in value but then
even even more interesting I think and
I'm curious if you agree with this as as
we go as we develop more and more mature
skills our tooling has to change so I
thought back to there's two analogies I
use one is when I just started a golf
when I was a kid my I just used a pair
of hand-me-down golf clubs and they were
okay and but then when my skills got to
a certain point the tools became a
limiting factor so then I went and I
bought a nice set of off-the-shelf golf
yelps and my game progressed and then
some point I needed custom lights
because I was growing I was a teenager
and so our tools had to evolve with our
skill set and then also I'm kind of an
amateur woodworker and if you walk into
a master woodworkers shop who's been
doing it for 10,000 hours or more they
might have a single hand plane that's a
$300 hand plane that serves one very
special purpose that they pull out twice
a year but it is the perfect tool to
deliver a very high quality product and
there's no there's no better replacement
tool but then there's a certain amount
of vanity in that tool and you could say
well could you get the same outcome with
a cheap tool from one of the big-box
retailers and you might be able to but I
just find it so funny with lately the
focus on tools in the last few weeks not
funny is in you know negative but just
interesting in how tooling is becoming
an amplifier for agility I agree and I'm
gonna have to turn this light on because
this light just automatically went off
because nobody walked around for 20
minutes so give me one sec sure there we
go that feels a little better I can
actually everybody can see me now as
well and I can see yeah yeah and see
what I have
i I've set up a studio in here so I have
a camcorder linked in to do the
whiteboard so if I need to draw
something on the whiteboard when I'm
doing calls and stuff I have to light
boxes up here cuz lights important
especially on video I think it's
difficult to see what's going on yeah no
I agree I my my wife thought I was crazy
about a year ago when I made sure that
all the light bulbs that I bought in my
home office for the same temperature
which is not where I am right now but
because I didn't want to have color
correction issues you can have all that
stuff so I had a pretty obsessive around
the lighting and make sure I got all the
same brand all the same temperature so
that I I had a better quality lighting
setup yeah and I've been I've been
playing around with it like last week I
had Daniel Vacanti on to have a
discussion and we had air core problems
from Daniel because I wasn't now I've
got headphones inspect and adapt you
just got to figure it out this is new to
me as well I've been learning how to use
new tools like will be s studio for
streaming and setting up the different
thing that I can even do like if we have
a problem
we can go on please stand by while I go
fix something or whatever yeah it's been
it's been fun and how to how to get
scape which you're on into here that was
craziness there's lots of bender lbs so
Skype is the only video conferencing
tool that I found that has a special
feature called NDI a so Skype is
actually if I go to my desktop picture
I'm in the middle and you can see you're
on skype there that's my two skype
windows so that lack of focus one and
the this one and but that's not what's
happening and in here okay so Skype is
dreaming all of the different feed video
feeds that it's got locally so that
means that I'm hooking in to this n di
stream and putting your display here but
I can if two or three people were
calling in and I can bring them all in
and move them around and it was very
complicated to set up I'm quite happy
that I managed to get it I think it was
complicated for me maybe I don't know it
was it's it's been a lot of work trying
to figure out these things get it get it
good and I think it's a is it's part of
the fun it's something else to focus on
and that's the thing that I found in our
what do you call it whoa you new world
while I'm working you we have work here
and isn't it n well new way of working
okay yeah there we go you know in our
new way of working all of all of all of
the work and conferences that I had
just disappeared not quite overnight
over there over the period of a week or
so so then we had to reevaluate and
figure out what to do and the I think
the stream for where we that are would
you call it funnel for where we get work
in the new model is substantially
different it's it's maybe different
people who would see and come to online
training then would come to in-person
training although there's probably a lot
of overlap as well but there are some
people who just I don't care if it's not
in person
um and I think doing doing these
recording videos getting content out
there and there is in this format that
people would use if they were coming to
engage with you and I think is is part
of that that new model we are we're
inspecting and adapting already yeah
well one thing I've been thinking about
is how does this change the training
landscape because think about if you're
a remote learner and you're in Omaha
Nebraska here in the United States in
the Midwest and you don't have any local
you know quote-unquote experts or very
few so you're looking at well where am I
going to travel to and it's like now you
don't have trouble anywhere you can go
get trained and come on by Daniel come
to you you could go get trained in Azure
DevOps from our natural would I mean so
you you now have are a worldwide
consumer and I feel that the trainer
expertise and the quality of the
training becomes paramount now because
we've minimized and eliminated the
barriers to immediacy and location you
know so to me that's provided to me it's
great because I think I put on a very
good high quality learning session but I
think that you know for many and I'm not
saying I'm like somehow I'm elite
trainer because trust me I'm not but I
like to think that there
or like I want that class because that's
a gym class instead of well that's just
that I'm just going to gym class because
he happens to be in the same city or
state that I'm in which that'll always
be a part of it but I want to build a
reputation for my classes being of such
a high quality that they're sobbed out
and I think I think that that's actually
one of the problems that I've been
having and doing classes in Scotland and
and that's that I am much more known
outside of Scotland than inside of
Scotland having you know I I worked for
three years from 2010 to 2013 in Seattle
doing DevOps and agile consulting across
I don't know I think I did sixty
different states which is quite a lot
and many of my customers were in San
Diego in the surrounding area and as
eight hour time difference from here and
I do a lot of training in in Oslo so in
in the in the UK I up until recently
have never really gotten much work
mainly cuz folks that just didn't know I
was here didn't didn't see my content
didn't didn't loop in that circle I
guess but and it's interesting because
one of the other PS T's in the UK had
been training over in Edinburgh as well
and um it's it's when people come to my
class many of the people that come to my
class were flying in come to my class I
got very few people who were were Eddie
robeast
well maybe very few probably one of one
of those Scottish phrases for you know
about half and about half of the people
that were coming to my class were flying
in and I think that's that's just due to
me going to other places around the
world and doing conferences they are
like I didn't do a lot of conferences in
the UK I did conferences in the you
in Europe my customers were US and
Europe check n yeah but now with
Bertrand you should care
so the the poly that I'm doing in a
couple of weeks I just had to two folks
from Germany sign up and I did a poly in
Germany in fact I did a poly in Germany
the weekend before they closed that hole
of lights so luckily it wasn't later
than that and I think that um you know
there were people who maybe wanted to
come that couldn't so then they booked
into the Edinburgh one yeah that's good
hey you just said something that I have
to ask about you said folks folks I
struggle yes as a trainer I get my hand
slapped occasionally and I do it to
myself for six you guys I use you guys
it's just a collective it's the group is
folks your preferred nomenclature for so
last that long
no to be honest guys is my preferred
Norma culture that's what I default to
that's what I I me nights three years of
training consulting around the us guys
is they go to and just like it
interesting act I prefer to focus on
intent then on the actual works so when
I say guys I'm being all inclusive but I
am being very conscious of that and I've
switched to folks but it is very I'm
getting better at folks and telling guys
but I'm doing folks or everyone or
something else just to be to be more
conscious of it because I think while it
doesn't matter to some people it does
matter to others so I think it's an
important thing to take note off and but
it's just like I are we the one that
always got me were
and people saying oh shoot or dagnabbit
or I don't know some curse words
although we would say swear word in the
UK but some curse word and that they've
made up in order to not say a real curse
word yeah and from my perspective the
intent is still there if I stub my toe
and say die ignite I'm still swearing
because that was my intent even though I
used words that aren't normal swear
words and so I read for me it's the same
with guys and folks if I say folks but I
mean guys then I'm being disingenuous
and that's the bit you should get
slapped down for but if I say guys and
mean mean folks then III wouldn't like
to get slapped down for that but yeah
you know words words matter and if
you've read the scrum guide yeah well no
words matter or it matter a lot I think
it's definitely something I've tried to
focus on yeah I have to
my grandmother famously has a
replacement word for every swear word
and I'm like why do you do that we I
know what you mean it's just like what
you said so I'm curious because there
might be somebody out there who says
wait what the heck word Jim and Martin's
supposed to be talking about today did
did you what were we supposed to be
talking about he said it is riffing on
the list and I had fashioned ilysm and I
had conflicting priorities that were the
two things that are analysts and we we
should spend about 20 minutes talking
about professionalism and then we
tangent T how many minutes I'm
unprofessional and my two priorities are
chocolate and puzzles and board games
lit so that's three well Jess can I did
a puzzle a thousand-piece puzzle that
was kind of fun and we collaborated on
that and we've been playing some board
I have a I have a group um the the meets
on Sunday and we've been meeting on
discord and I played games for nine
hours on Sunday that's awesome yeah I've
been aware of discord for years but I
would tell you that for years I was
probably one of a hundred people in my
circle that knew about it and now I have
people like have you checked out on a
discord channel have you checked your
channel and it's like it overnight it
went mainstream it seems like I've got
like twenty discord channels that I'm a
member of knows yeah getting ridiculous
it's almost getting overwhelming so I do
have a couple thoughts about
professionalism and competing priorities
the interesting thing about priorities
and I'm curious what you think is there
is no such thing as the plural of
priorities he you only can have one
priority and I this is now went into my
teaching especially around product
ownership is you know what is your
priority oh I have five priorities no
you have one and you know anyone who has
ever why I have two priorities you know
I want to go to the gym and and workout
tonight and I also want to go binge that
new show on Netflix well whichever one
you do first that's what you prioritize
you might do both things but whichever
one you did first is actually what you
prioritize okay so this is an
interesting one because I bring it up in
my classes quite a lot okay and I have
the same feeling as you however the
majority of the time when I'm teaching
scrum classes I'm teaching non-native
English speakers and in most that I've
found so far other languages it is
plural it just means a dirt bike
priorities just means ordered for for
them so
you know I sometimes I have a it's
interesting for me the things that are
different across those cultures and
languages yeah yeah I I think firm it
and that's how I use it in my in my
teaching is the difference between
priority and order and I say we might do
things in a specific order that is out a
priority so in that example I might go
to the gym first and then go home and
watch Netflix because that's the most
logical order
maybe the gym is on my way home from the
office and it would be dumb of me to go
home watch a television show and then
drive back to the gym that that might be
dumb it's a good thought exercise to
understand the difference between
priority and order and how those things
relate especially when we're like
delivering value and building features I
mean and again I hate to come back to
zoom but if did you know and I guess
this is not fact but this is opinion but
the opinion I've heard is that zooms
number one delight er from a feature
perspective was their virtual
backgrounds that the the number one
thing that customers really touted as
why they choose yeah your average person
the number one reason that the the
feature they loved in the zoom platform
was the fun virtual backgrounds so guess
what you see every other company
prioritizing now they're they're pushing
out virtual backgrounds and virtual
green screens
it wasn't the stability or security the
platform yeah obviously it wasn't the
breakout rooms you know your average
just you know a user didn't care about
recovery rooms now we as trainers did
yeah we care about the rooms yeah but
but think about it if you look at a
prioritization model of like des
lighters and parity and which which
features a user cares about sometimes
it's surprising I totally agree in its
it's the struggle of a product owner to
make a decision between
[Music]
Ling and long-term sustainable value and
sometimes you might have to prioritize
the bling because you know we need to
compete with em other platforms and if
that's what users value then we have to
deliver what users value and but we also
have to look at not spending all of our
time just delivering things that users
value otherwise I so I've got I got a
just a little story around that the and
you've probably heard me - you've
probably heard me tell before and but
it's the the azure DevOps team at
Microsoft ten years ago were
significantly behind the curve and
behind the curve is an expression that I
think M actually makes a lot makes a lot
of sense it's one of those odd ones that
actually makes a lot of sense because
they they were building features at for
users which means users were asking them
for stuff and then they were building it
in next release it just so happened that
they had the two-year lag time so that
really ends up being a four year lag
time and in the enterprise world that
was fine cuz Enterprise didn't really
give a crap yeah for year like okay
whatever that same is all of our
software we can adopt things that
quickly I get a customer that took
nearly four years to move from server
based source control to distribute or
controller but and that that am unable
to deliver quickly and building stuff
for users that were that they were
asking for it
meant that you're a follower you were
following what people want to do and one
of the things that the the phoned was
that they had the ended up building up
too much technical debt because they
were purely following leading because
technical debt doesn't matter if you're
a follower
it really doesn't matter yeah and if
you're making a lot of money off
following you can just build up
technical debt and we'll just whatever
but the they spend concerted effort they
their goal of their their product unit
manager which was Brian Harry at the
time was to get ahead of the curve how
we need to build stuff for the early
adopters so that by the time the
majority of people come along we already
have that feature in the product we are
the ones leading the industry not
following and they invested a lifetime
in working and I yeah okay can I react
to that a little bit because you just
you're touching on is that that are just
hitting home for me I left the company
that I had that I was out for a number
of years because they refused to try and
get ahead of the curve that I used to
joke that their product backlog was to
send me links to our competitors
websites and say we want what they have
i it just rocked me to my core just
bothered me that that is what they
considered innovation was well this is
what our competitors are succeeding with
yep so that's what we need to build and
I'm like yeah they have that idea a year
and a half ago it's gonna take us a year
to do it and then in a year-and-a-half
they'll be that far to be onto something
else yeah and I hate it when my the
owners my company would go to
conferences because I knew I hated it I
look at their counter I'm like oh my god
they're going to Vegas I can't wait to
see what's gonna happen in my backlog of
work when they get back sure enough come
back from Vegas I get a calendar invite
that says highly important
and they'd be like okay this is what we
just heard about this is what
everybody's doing this what we have to
do I'm like I've known about that I've
been other people in telling you and for
a year ago and you know so that's one
reaction as I lived that nightmare for
six years and then Nigel Thoreau I think
just wrote an article one of our fellow
PS T's in a very amazing thought leader
about you know disruptive innovators and
innovators and these different companies
you know that sometimes can find
themselves with different products or
services and different quadrants so some
of their some of their work is is even
truly innovative other work is achieving
parity with competition and then and
again I'm sure I'm preaching to the
choir here but you know in my training I
talk a lot about features and features
that became that went from the lighters
to now just maintaining the status quo
like would anybody butter an automobile
without a backup camera no the
interesting thing about features is as
soon as you build one in and it becomes
ubiquitous meaning it's it's everywhere
and just becomes you know a part of the
standard package you can never take it
away it's very very hard to take it away
but it's you have to be very careful
with what you build because every
feature you build is a feature you have
to maintain and extend and worry about
from a stability and security standpoint
and you know there's a quote out there
and I forget who to attribute it to but
he said that a product is not done when
you can't Jam one more feature into it a
product is done when you can't take
anything away from it and still have it
be desired and wanted by customers yeah
and I love that idea and because that's
agile principle number 10 simplicity you
know so I I talked about and especially
my in my training on both sides both the
product owner site and on the the
product side lean inventory control
you want to have as few things in your
backlog as possible but it still be a
backlog I know you want as few things in
your product as possible and it still be
a product yeah so they and I'm in your
school of thought on this but there is
how we're kind of on topic cuz we're
talking about competing priorities
there's another coach in the same
organization I'm in that feels that the
product owners backlog should be as big
as possible yeah like her dream back or
a thousand items oh that's a small
backlog and I'm like no no absolutely
not how did you have folks how can you
rationalize and prioritize an order
4,000 items and even 400 like I don't
know if it's if there's not a perfect
number but something tells me it's not
you know what I thought of right there
when you said how do I manage 4,000
items same way you manage 4,000 people
hierarchy need more higher alright you
need more layers you need more more
distance between the ideas and the
realities for everybody else I'm being
so cut out right now there is an idea of
a funnel like let's dump as many things
into that funnel as possible so let's
consider many things but to me the most
important thing a product owner can do
is take something new look at it
rationalize it and then say no we're not
going to do that but if you just say
well I'm gonna we might do that someday
and I'm gonna put it in the corner over
there you you just enhanced your anxiety
around stuff yep you have a packrat
mentality a hoarder mentality so I
preach a more minimal and I hate the
word preach there sorry I'm trying to
break myself of that habit but I suggest
a more minimal approach kind of like a
Marie Kondo approach to tidying up our
things so that we can focus on less know
but know them deeper and hopefully that
leads to more
value being delivered I just don't think
you can find that Neal and the haystack
of 4,000 items but if you have put the
time in to get good at rationalizing
things and only have a you know a much
smaller number to review you might be
able to have a grasp on your product and
your market and your customers better
yeah and I totally agree with that I I
got a I got a workshop from um David
Starr who's a very good friend I didn't
Seattle I don't know you know David
David's awesome and he he wrote a
workshop that he provide uh he had a
family emergency and I had to take over
a gig of heads I think I was pretty much
just the first PST he met and after he
found out the bad news that he had to
deal with and so I took took on this
this gig so he provided some workshops
and things around it but the workshop
was a requirements gathering workshop
and effectively it's got some stuff
around it but effectively what you do is
you take a bunch of people who are going
to be working on backlog and you take
some screen from the application that
they've already worked on before and you
get them to create user stories based on
you know their their hindsight of
knowledge that they've got knowing
everything that's going on yeah and so
the III talk about user stories and I
talk about scenarios so given the way in
thence walk through all of that with
them show them what good ones look like
and then get them to work on breaking
this down it usually takes like an hour
and a half for them to do that but then
at the end of that they have a very
intricate set of backlog and behaviors
that represent the work that the new had
to go in to building that thing that
make sense yeah so then we put that put
that to the site
take something out of your back look
some item in your backlog something
usually with a UI because it's just
easier for people to understand and
interact with and put that put that user
story on the board now do the same thing
and they've they've now realized the
amount of detail that they had to go
into to describe the thing they've done
in the past and I had I did it with a
group where we had engineers architects
bees we had business folks we had the
the the entire PMO office there and we
did that exercise and halfway through
the second exercise the the head of
product management stopped the whole
workshop and and he said that this does
we fundamentally are not ready to go
into this level to even understand what
these things are and that to me was a
was a shocking realization for a company
to realize that they didn't have the
fundamental understanding nor ability to
create an order backlog and that was
with with 20 people in the room focused
on doing just that task yeah I don't
know if I where I stole this idea from
or heard about it or or if I just came
up with it but I have had teams in the
past kind of do what I call retroactive
refinement so go back and refine an
estimate something you've already done
like what you just described and with
now with the benefit of hindsight what
would we know and they're like oh well
we would do this and we would ask us to
made it like this and we would use that
exercise to create anchor stories so
that we would post on the wall in our
team space and say you know what
remember when we were refine this retro
actively we all said this is what a five
looks like and this is the level of
to the tasks that it spawned and it's
fun and then we have a new item off our
backlog that everybody says we don't
understand this very well we're like
okay but which of those things does it
look like like oh well it's a lot like
that thing okay that's probably a good
starting point to think about what what
did we need to think about to do that
thing we probably need to think about
the same things to do this new thing so
I love that workshop the other thing
that when you were talking it kind of
made me think about was this idea of
like a backlog snake which was an
exercise that I've done at a number of
clients where I took their backlog and I
printed it out you know sometimes
hundreds of items and I arranged a
conference room in such a way that all
these tables form like kind of like this
snake shape and I put my designated I
had this kind of fun stuffed animal at
one end of the of the table and it was
the snake's head and then I had the tail
of the snake at the other end and I said
okay now take everything and it the most
important thing goes at the head and the
least important thing goes at the tail
and they were able to order and
prioritize hundreds and hundreds of
items by just laying them all out on on
these tables so the things at the end
became the most important the things at
the end at the other hand became the
least important and then what the
product owner was able to do is like
they were able to go about midway
through and be like from this point on
all these things just throw away we
don't even need them we'll never get to
him let's just focus on these hundred
things and we we drastically trimmed the
product backlog in mass as a team as it
actually is a whole group of teams and
was it it wasn't perfect and there was
price and things we tossed away that we
had two that came back but that's
another one of the things that I I teach
is if something is really important
it'll come back yeah you're not gonna
forget about that amazing that you want
to build but if it never comes back have
you heard of a tool called email amnesty
no so they have it was a plugin for for
Outlook or people that have ridiculous
numbers of unread items in their inbox I
know people that have 25,000 plus unread
items and their their their inbox and
what you know amnesty did was it scammed
through your entire inbox and for each
unread email that you had or each person
that you had an unread email from it
created an email to them attached all of
the unread emails and said in the body
I'm declaring an email amnesty I have
too much crap in my inbox and please
send back to me things that you think
are still important and then it sends it
out and it China I don't know how much
of a tool it did for for for collecting
responses but it meant that you know
probably more than 50 percent of your
emails are gonna bounce yeah and then
you have a bunch of emails that somebody
gets 10 things and they go well these
two things are still important the rest
I don't care about anymore
so suddenly I paired down that list and
I've encouraged organizations to do that
with their backlog items you know
declare our backlog amnesty you've get
25,000 things in your backlog you can't
get to 25,000 things said send them back
and see what comes your way yeah yeah
that's I launched a in activity at a
client that was kind of a mixture of
that it wasn't really amnesty but it was
this massive Kaizen event around getting
our backlog under control and I started
to dub it a mixture of the Marie Kondo
method and the debt snowball method from
Dave Ramsey I don't know are you
familiar with either of those two names
Marie Kondo with Marie Kondo she says
you should only have five board games is
that what she says
it's probably zero you joy and I'm like
well all these bring them joy no in a
nutshell really what it is is is we took
this giant backlog and we dispatched of
a whole bunch of it right away
just because it was old and the product
owner could easily go through and know
what was valuable and what could just be
deleted so we did that then with what
was left we met when and met with all
the stakeholders and we said you know
what is the value of this we're going
through it and this was kind of the
organization step of the backlog but the
Marie Kondo method you know of tidying
up our backlog and we explained I got on
my soapbox like 25 times gave the same
little mini speech to this different
stakeholders 25 times and said here's
why it's important for you to let go of
some things because if you want this
you've got to let go of this because
this is the crushing weight of the
backlog warrants why we're not getting
anything done so we were able to get the
a lot of stakeholders say you know what
you're right we don't need that anymore
the windows past for that etc focus on
these two or three things we did that 15
20 25 times then we apply Dave Ramsey's
model of the debt snowball which is
sometimes kind of productive and you got
to be careful with it but it's doing
small things first so we were able to
get a whole bunch of small things done
which then allowed us to do less contact
switching more focus on the bigger
things so we might have done some less
valuable work early but it was it paid
us back in less context switching in
time and focus and that's kind of this
this snowball thing of paying off your
small bills so that you can then put big
lumps of sum and big payments down on
your really big bills and the
organization loved it
but but it took a while to get it done
but man it just led to all types of
phenomenal conversations about that
you and priorities and competing
priorities and all these things that we
talk about every day it's super
difficult III find that product owners
really struggle to have any kind of
reasonable priority or good
understanding of the product backlog or
even to be able to be empowered to do
that and I think that's that's that's an
organizational issue it comes from the
the hierarchical tailor istic practices
that we're used to and backing off from
those ideas is is really difficult have
you have you seen the the I I do M I did
our session a little while ago I guess
what did I call it the tyranny of
Taylorism and how to spot agile bs yes
that one I did and I'm seeing your
content yeah yeah so the the that that
piece at the start where I talk about
where Taylorism came from is something
that I I do in almost all of my classes
maybe not a PSF but a poly and a PSM I
always cover that because I I think that
too many too many folks dismiss this
waterfall thing that they've heard of
yeah they talk about it as waterfall
which is where those big backlogs that
are difficult to prioritize come from
because we have to have a list of
everything before we start and we have
to spend six months in analysis before
we do anything that that that's maybe an
exaggeration but depends on the
organization that you're working with
and and bringing that down to you know I
just need to two weeks work for the team
I need a big team busy for a couple of
weeks and then that will give me a
couple of weeks to come up with more
stuff to keep that team busy and getting
that yeah that that balance is really
important
I'm glad you enjoyed that that I'm
session that I did I did I really liked
it I love this thought of or not the
thought but the understanding the
history of Taylorism and how it
influences modern-day thinking and the
relationship with Gant and other
contemporaries about you know how work
used to get done in this idea of there
being one best way to do something well
that does something better that this is
something we fight against every day
yeah no such thing as best practice on
y'all have to quit practices for the
situation at hand that's right only a
generally useful practice that works in
some context exactly exactly so we know
we have been we have been rambling for
an hour and 20 minutes so I think it's
probably good idea to to wrap it up
sure so if you could just do you have
anything you're working on next you have
any public classes anything you want so
yeah I do have some public classes
couple will be out on the scrum ador'd
site their home cities are Columbus and
st. Louis right now please go take a
look at those I am about to launch a
website called no boring no boring
retros dot-com and even though no boring
retros is the the title because that's
something I'm very very passionate about
it's just gonna kind of serve as a
portal for all of my content so my
podcast appearances things like this
just my random thoughts but there will
be kind of a big section of the site
dedicated of retrospectives and all that
because I am a big believer in the power
of retrospectives so yeah look for that
and then I also love for people to
connect with me on LinkedIn I mean
that's kind of how I stay in touch with
my colleagues and my students right or
wrong I'm not a great social media maven
so LinkedIn is
kind of the the preferred way to get in
touch with me well I managed to get
LinkedIn streaming-enabled on my account
so this was going out live on LinkedIn
so you'll be able to go tag that that I
don't know how you do that and even
write bit I don't think you can figure
it out yeah that the LinkedIn streaming
is super new so it's a little bit
difficult to find stuff after the fact
the other platforms are a little bit
easier because they're more mature but
that's awesome we'll definitely look
forward to to that and I think in in in
that vein and if anybody has any
feedback review of how we organize this
how we set it up maybe just the audio or
it could be how much of a plan we had
for the this sprint which was not very
much we had a very loose plan how much
we got off topic maybe you like that
maybe you didn't um it would be really
useful to get to get feedback on that
and hopefully Jim and I will have maybe
a retro and maybe we we do this again at
some point laughs - cool well love our
chats thanks for coming
coming on Jim yeah thanks for having me
cool well hopefully see you next time
all right
[Music]