how do you know how effective your
organization is at improving
value in order to do that you need to
understand your organizational
capability and part of that is
understanding your ability to innovate
evidence-based management has some key
example metrics that you might use
within the context of monitoring your
ability to innovate if you're building
software products you might be looking
at your active branches number of active
branches you might be looking at
technical debt on any product you might
be looking at Innovation rate percentage
of time you spend innovating rather than
struggling with complexity but there are
plenty of other metrics that you might
choose from in that space um you need to
understand how effective your
organization is at improving value