so uh the kanban workshop is from uh
procamban.org
it's called the the APK applying
professional kanban
um and it's uh
really it's it's 16 hours of a deep
exploration of the
strategy that is devops
um so there there are other things out
there that are actual software processes
right
um but the core of kanban is this
strategy that allows you to
um or meta process that allows you to
monitor any existing process doesn't
matter what it is right your existing
process could be scrum your existing
process could be we've made it up as we
go along or your existing process could
be uh Maurice or ssadm or whatever thing
your organization's doing
the
kanban strategy would allow you to
observe and record what's going on in
that process you're effectively
monitoring the flow of work through that
system thus then you're looking at the
data right enabling you uh to
continually make tweaks and changes to
the system in order to optimize that
flow of value right so that's that's
that's that's really about that delivery
piece how quickly are we able to take an
idea that we get and get it
all the way into or all the way into
production potentially so that our our
customers can use it but it will model
any system I think that's that's the key
piece for me
um is the the it models any system and
any part of any system right so even if
you had a a team that's just looking at
you know their view or their area of
control is uh from when the product
owner gives them a feature of the
business gives them a feature to to to
when they've sent it off to the
operations team right that could be that
could be one view so you're looking at
the cycle time across these two points
doing the report item aging controlling
your whip in it at that level but your
business could be looking at a much
higher level right instead of individual
pieces of value that a teams
working on going through the system your
business could look at all of the
Endeavors that are underway and what is
there from when they come up to it from
when it's actually delivered and what is
their throughput what is their cycle
time what's their current whip what's
the capability of the organization and
this is especially true in in things
like Professional Services right where
you get gigs coming through and you're
trying to service them with the people
that you've got and you don't want to
end up in that death spiral of you know
we've got more people so we need more
gigs and then we've got more gigs so we
need more people and you end up in a
spiral of reduction in quality because
you've got to hire people because you
need them not because they're the right
people to hire
um and that's true for big organizations
as well so so this allows you to model
the flow of value through any two points
um and really improve the way you work
because you're able to monitor what's
going on and that's that's what the the
APK applying professional Kombat is all
about so whether whether you're a team
right and you're looking to improve your
your engineering excellence and shorten
the cycle time get value through your
system quicker or you're doing scrum
you want to improve
throughput in your system or you're a
leadership team and you're looking at
the work that's underway across multiple
teams it it really doesn't matter what
the system is this is the tool that you
need uh to monitor the data analysis
that you need to monitor not just the
flow value through the system but then
look forward into the future and do
probabilistic forecasting on what's
coming up next how long do we think
things are going to take and How likely
is that to happen right if we're
thinking in bets
and really looking at the the data from
what we've delivered in the past if we
have a stable system right you need a
stable system first then we can start
looking out into the future using using
effectively some of the same tools that
that when you see them talking about the
weather on TV right
um there there they say that on on
Thursday at three o'clock it's going to
rain right that's their their their
prediction and then it'll have a
percentage likelihood of that to happen
and let's say it's 85 sure that's going
to happen
what they've done and for them it's much
more complicated than what we were
talking about much more complicated
they've got these really complex models
that model the weather in whatever area
you're in right and they feed the data
from hist all of history that they've
got Plus what's currently happening in
the weather and they feed it into this
model and then they run the simulation
thousands and thousands and thousands of
times and what percentage of those
simulations does it rain at three
o'clock on Thursday well 68 of the
simulations it rains at three o'clock on
Thursday well it might rain at three
o'clock on Thursday right it's 65 if
that's the number of simulation 65 sure
it will rain at three o'clock on
Thursday and that's the same thing that
we can do with our engineering processes
right we can look at
um what are historical delivery
um on average for example
um 85 of the time that's on average
that's the wrong Edward but 85 percent
of the time uh we deliver work in our
team uh let's say six days or less
so I'm 85 sure that any piece of work we
take on will be delivered in eight days
or less right so we can make that a
forecast looking into the future and put
it into a simulation and for that we
normally use a Monte Carlo
feed some data in run it 10 000 times
what's the chances of you delivering 10
things in the next Sprint 20 things 30
things what's the percentage likelihood
that's going to happen and then you can
have real conversations with your
stakeholders not about what you will and
What You Won't Do but what is the
likelihood of certain outcomes happening
with the clear understanding that there
is also no matter how
um high in the the percentiles you go
right you never get to a hundred percent
you can get to the 99th percentile right
but you can never get to 100 so there's
always a chance that something wouldn't
happen and that's a key learning outcome
for engaging with stakeholders for the
stakeholders and the teams communicating
with them that we want to be talking in
percentages we want to be talking about
probabilities
um with our with our stakeholders for
whatever it is we're doing How likely
are things to be successful just like
businesses have always done
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility