yeah I don't see you're saying I'm the
CTO at great calm
so after the Lord evaluation of
differences from training options we
selected Martin because I think he'd
bring daily perspective they very close
to what I call the weaker engineer the
dragon troublemakers and he brings a
great perspective that's close to the
makers scrum training session which is
what I thought about a lot you know
everything else about making sure the
great days of the builders are
successful in doing their best work and
I think Martin does a great job in
connecting with them
so we decided to train everybody because
it is critical to baseline understanding
of scrum in the organization what I
expected every shop is that you start
with following the standard framework
and use one and you create a variation
facts we should create a normal and
expecting
it's just that in an organization where
you have a lot of new people joining the
organization everybody bring their own
flavor and understanding of what's come
and agile means and it creates more
dissonance so we come to create
by the feedback that they received for
training from all the lab students and
then maybe process and so dad I think it
resonates in everybody that margin is
very close to the makers in the village
and that shows and how he teaches a
class and that's pretty consistent
feedback
the ICMS value in the organizational
change backlog that comes out of the
training it is the team getting us would
we need to change in relationship
reorganization and big initiative makes
my mother to bots to expectation after
the training is my expecting the
organization should change its senior
levels which is what the organization
macron is about and the other is that
individual team should be sure are
talking to different that are one that
is one individual folder
my belief is that this training in the
air hoist that father would help us
improve our on to true coat and crumbs
off both just delivery ie getting the
shipment out of the door gate laces how
the world is only not more feature from
strategy for customers but also to put
in turns off the needle of the business
metric that reason the only thing I
reading but you know when I first took
the password margin few years ago at my
previous game I personally took the
class and I was very impressed because
again I think I am still an engineer at
hide and connected me so that hole cut
God in the name of modern among the
candidate Cheney and I'm glad that the
feedback I've gotten so far it's very
consistent from the team great job but
Monahan great job from our team left
naked Martin to come here