the question is are there any scrum
courses that teach you how to scale um
and the answer is no there's not there's
not any scrum courses that teach you how
to scale but there are scrum courses
that help you understand the tools and
techniques that you can use to build
your own scaling framework that's
probably the best way to describe it um
um every
successful um organization that I've
seen operating at scale um I've worked
with organizations with uh 600 people
working on one product I've worked with
organizations um that have 4 and a half
thousand people working on one product
uh these are all scaling situations
those are Mega scaling situations for
most organizations you're probably
looking at at um just two or three or
maybe four or five scrum teams working
together delivering value but they have
to deliver it together I'm working on an
engagement right now uh where we've got
about 13 teams working together on one
common outcome um and how do you how do
you scale that and the answer is that
there is no prescribed way to scale you
have to find a way that works for your
organization
uh so the course that that that we have
H scaled professional scrum scaling
professional scrum um is uh from
scrum.org and it focuses on a a little
bit around a framework right but that's
a tiny tiny tiny tiny tiny part of this
course right um the the Nexus framework
uh what that we talk about is not really
much more than scrum and it talks about
3 to nine teams is working together on
one outcome uh but what it does heavily
focus on um the the course focuses on
about 50 different practices that you
can use to help you build your own
scaling framework just like scrum is not
a method for delivering software scrum
is a framework around which you can
build your own method for delivering
software in the same way Nexus is not a
method for delivering software it's a
framework a scaffolding so that we make
sure that we're not missing something as
we continue to build and iterate on our
own framework what practices are going
to work for you in building uh uh your
your your scaling framework for your
your teams in your organization um and
please do not start with everything in
the kitchen sink
that's a bad place to start you want to
start small what's the smallest thing we
can improve and change um and then
what's the next thing after that what's
the next thing after that to make things
a little bit better and you'll build a
framework that's suited specifically for
the product specifically for the the the
the organization that you're in that
entity of of of your organization um
so that's a lot of work right the the
scaling class that we have is not going
to teach you how to install a scaling
framework in your organization it's
going to teach you the
foundations of you being able to build
your own scaling framework that fits
your organization like a glove um I
think that is the best way
to enable
scaling um there's a little bit of a
Kickstart there's some things that
that's definitely very common uh if
you're if you're interested the two
things uh that you really need to focus
on is uh dependency management that's
the killer for most organizations so we
spend a ton of time uh talking about and
dealing with dependency management and
the other one is
alignment alignment between your your
product the organization and the people
right you need alignment there that
things smoothly flow through that system
if the architecture is different from
the way you organize the people the
architecture of your product is
different from the way you organize the
people it's going to generate friction
so the the the tools and techniques that
we deliver in the course about 50
different practices we might not talk
about all of them but there's 50
different practices in the pot um are
all there to help you figure out how to
best scale your product and your teams
for your
organization thanks for watching the
video If you enjoyed it please like
follow And subscribe I always reply to
comments and if you want to have a chat
about this or anything else agile scrum
or devops then please book a coffee with
me through naked
agility