so one of the questions I often get is
how how do we potentially as delivery
managers how do we balance the
difference between speed and
stability right when you're under
pressure for tight tight
deadlights and I'd assert that there's a
there's there's a fundamental problem
with the
question and that's that we're under
tight why are we under tight deadlines
we tend to be cuz let's be honest
most
deadlines
exist because people don't believe you
can meet them that's why a deadline this
this is the ridiculous thing about about
about
deadlines so there are some deadlines
which are they're not even real
deadlines that that are coming the
external deadlines right so let's say
you've got a a a a business you're
something within the context of let's
say a regulated thing something's
regulated by the government the
government brings in a new
rule and your software does not
currently comply with that rule and the
government says by this date if you
don't have compliance we're going to
start finding you x amount of money for
every day that you're not compliant
right that that for many businesses
they would decide that that's just an
absolute deadline but the reality is
that's not even an absolute deadline
either we can pay the fine right we can
pay the fine how much is it going to
cost to build a
feature how long is it going to
take and what are the
implications of trying to
push for that feature to come out faster
than we are able to deliver that feature
right
people are going to start tripping over
their feet if we start pushing them too
hard they're going to fall in their face
and if they fall in their face the
software is going to fall in its vase
what's the impact of that on our brand
and our business and is it worth the
fine normally the find's a lot smaller
than the cost implications of going too
fast
so longterm you're probably not wanting
to pay all those fines right but
shortterm
you need to build the feature in the
right way with the right capabilities um
with the right level of quality
otherwise you're going to start
eroding your customers's confidence in
your product you're going to start
eroding the the the the brand awareness
the your brand of your company this this
is not okay right it's not okay to ship
poor quality um unstable product under
any almost any circumstances the only
circumstance I can think
even even even so the circumstance I
think about is our company will go out
of business next week if we don't have
this feature I think that's totally
arbitrary but I've heard I've heard that
one but if we ship that feature and we
have that feature but it doesn't work
properly and it's buggy is that actually
going to help us right is that actually
going to help us stay in business I I I
would be jub as to as to that maybe we
can try and hide it a good example of of
that being successful is is zoom during
the pandemic right they and they they
they succeeded I actually don't
understand why they didn't get more crap
for it but what they what they what they
did was when the pandemic happened and
everybody started working from home
their user base massively multiplied
right very very quickly massively
multiplied and what they found was that
they couldn't they just could their
systems could not support that number of
users but if you start capping users
right and saying to people no we can't
have another user on the system they're
going to go somewhere else they're going
to go to your competitors they're going
to go to teams they're going to go to
WebEx they're going to go to somebody
else so you don't want to do that right
good business practice is sorry what
good that's one of those could be either
way um moral and ethical business
practice would have you either cap the
number of users until you can um
increase capacity and bring on bring on
more more people bring on more
capability right but Zoom chose a
different route they decided that
maintaining that user curve and
supporting it was more important so they
started
systematically building features more
quickly at lower quality they started
ignoring security concerns cuz security
is a lot of your cost right for building
stuff validating and checking so let's
not let's cut all of that and then we
can we can build more stuff and they
deliberately turned off
encryption so Zoom one of zoom's selling
points was end to endend encryption of
of Cs but into encryption adds about 40%
load I I'm just ballparking that I'm
sure there's all sorts of variations
there but 40% load so they can
immediately have 40% more users stable
on the system by turning off
encryption but they didn't want to turn
off encryption and tell their users they
were turning off encryption because that
was a huge selling point for the product
having encryption and what would
existing users do if they were told that
it was encrypted so there was a little
green light in the corner of zoom and it
was the encryption light and it would go
green uh when the communication was
encrypted they turned off the encryption
but they changed the code so the light
continued to be green right that's
that's that's a reduction in quality
that's a massive massive business risk
and they were caught and that had a
massive impact to to their brand
awareness and a massive impact to their
business there are still companies today
that have zoom blocked as a product
within their organizational Network that
they will not allow it to be used and
it's because of
that moral and ethical decision that was
made at senior levels of that
organization to to reduce quality reduce
stability of of features that users
expected to work effectively they did
they were even worse they kind of lied
it's kind of like the the Volkswagen
Scandal a little bit right and except I
don't think anybody died but
don't reduce
quality in order to ship features
quicker it has an impact and it has
because we're building complex systems
it often has an impact you're not
expecting it often pushes you into a
corner and you're then left with those
moral and ethical decisions and you have
to go a particular way one's going to
suck and one's going to be nefarious and
quite often we as humans pick the
nefarious one because it's easier
cheaper more manageable in order to do
that so how do you strike a balance
between speed and
stability stability is more important
than speed much much much more important
than speed stability and quality is much
more important to than speed pay the
fine if you have to pay the fine but do
things well and do things properly