in um evidence-based management we talk
about multiple areas of um of focus we
talk about multiple uh key value areas
and one of those key value areas which
is really important and most
organizations and teams forget about is
unrealized value right they're just as
important all four of them are as
important as each other but because this
is the one that's often forgotten about
um unrealized value
is features you don't have maybe
features you know you need to have but
you haven't shipped yet maybe there's
features that you don't know you should
have and all of those things are driven
by Mark by the market right and when I'm
talking about Market um you could
picture in your head one of two things
if you deliver to customers general
public it's a commercial product then
your Market might be external to your
organization if you deliver inside of
your organization than the market is
inside of your organization right so so
that's what I mean when I say Market the
the thing the driving forces for what
your product needs to do right whether
you fit the market people are going to
use it people are using the features
people are engaging with the the things
that you're doing people care about what
you're building right that's that's all
part of that that market story so um
unrealized
value means that you don't know you
don't know necessarily what you need to
build or even if you think you know what
you need to build it's based on
assumptions and you don't know what's
actually going to provide market value
right was actually value only happens
when you get it in front of real users
everything before that is an assumption
we can try and validate our assumptions
we can try and weed out uh bad
assumptions right bad features things
that we don't think oh yeah we've done
it on paper and it doesn't look like
it's going going to work but the reality
is that until you get something that you
think is going to provide value in front
of real users you don't know whether
it's going to provide value like if you
were bu if you were renovating a house
right are people actually going to buy
it and are they actually going to pay
the price that you think they're going
to pay if you have a keen understanding
of what people are looking for if you
have a keen understanding of the market
um if you have a keen understanding yeah
of who's going to who's going to turn up
and and and potential buyers then you
can tailor the build of your product
towards those potential buyers and make
it more appealing for them rather than
less appealing right so if you're if
you're renovating a a a house and you're
you're going for a a family of four
right two kids H don't concrete Over the
Garden right because the kids want to
play in the grass the kids want to kick
a ball about a a a back large back
garden with lots of grass looks
appealing to a family of four right but
if you've got a a one person house with
a garden you want that or or a couple
right a childless couple you you you
want that to be as easy maintenance as
possible because they might want to sit
out in it but they don't want to spend a
lot of time maintaining it those are the
things that you're thinking about with
your products as well who's going to be
using our products what do they want to
do now what do they want to do in the
future how can we get different users
who who could we get in so that there's
more people using our product what
features do we have to build to bring in
net new users to our systems in order to
um maximize our value
right our product provides more value if
it serves more users either through a
commercial relationship or through an
internal providing value inside of the
organization so that unrealized value
piece is that story and how we engage
with it we don't know whether things are
going to be successful even if we have
the coolest idea ever so we want to
break that down I'm a firm believer in
hypothesis driven practices from a from
a product management perspective you
have you have a you have a a a a belief
right that a features going to add value
to the product as a product manager as a
as a as a leader in the business as a
CEO right I want this feature but we
need to break that down what's your
hypothesis right if we build this
feature what do you think is going to
happen we're going to have more users
okay well how many more users do you
think you're going to have right you
turn it into a hypothesis um if we build
this feature we think we'll get 10% more
users okay what's the
smallest thing from this feature that we
can
builds in order to start validating that
hypothesis well we think this is the
most valuable piece well let's let's
build that and see how many users we get
how many new users come to our platform
because we built this smaller thing and
maybe that's only a few days work to
build that smaller thing to test the
market to test the hypothesis right I I
what was the the um a great example of
this which is a little bit a little bit
orthagonal is
Dropbox right when when Dropbox um
somebody came up with the idea for
Dropbox I can't remember the dude's name
but he came up with the idea for Dropbox
but his investors didn't believe that
anybody would want that so he couldn't
get investors nobody would invest in his
product so he needed to demonstrate
that people wanted to buy his product so
they created a pretty cool video it's
probably not pretty cool now but Dropbox
is pretty old a pretty cool video that
that demonstrated the features in a in a
like selling to a sales video and they
put up the video on the on a website
with a text box for your email
address put your email address in here
if you're interested in this product and
then they spent some money marketing it
and and they got millions of signatures
millions of people put in their email
address and that was the evidence that
they used to go to the investors to get
them to invest and they got their
funding uh uh to start building the
product that's an example of we have an
assumption we think people want this
product we're going to create a
hypothesis we're going to get lots of as
a that's my crappy hypothesis we're
going to get lots of people if if if we
build this product and then how do we
test well here's one way to test whether
people are interested in it and we
didn't even have to build the product to
do it so validating those hypotheses at
every stage and that requires especially
once you built your product and you're
starting to add new features you're
going to be using feature Flags you're
going to be using uh uh continuous
delivery to get those features in front
of real users as quickly as possible to
gather feedback gather Telemetry on
whether whether and how people are using
those products um
so your deployment frequency is a huge
part of that story because that is the
minimum length your feedback loop can be
right so if you deploy once every two
weeks you you can't get feedback shorter
than every two weeks right you're going
to deploy to
production at the end of the two weeks
you've then got to recognize a Telemetry
and then you got to get it back into
your story of delivery and you so
usually usually it's twice your
deployment frequency for most things
it's twice your deployment frequency so
if you do twoe deployments your feedback
lo as four weeks um getting into
production customer feedback analyze it
get it into your backlog product team
picks it up the shortest that can really
realistically be is twice your your
frequency so if you're deploying to
production continuously if every commit
ends up in production it minimizes that
part of the feedback loop and everything
else is people and people are much
easier to figure out how do we get this
done more quickly than systems because
systems take a lot of work for that