the question is what's the best scrum
advice I've ever received
and
I think we it's the same advice we
actually see all the time although on on
social media although in varying degrees
of upsettedness with scrum and
Frameworks and stuff
and you'll see there's a lot of
movements out there to move away from
a Dogma that I feel like didn't really
exist except in
crappy people anyway right this this
Dogma that oh you're not you're not
doing scrum unless you're standing up or
you're not doing scrum unless you're
doing user stories or
um if you don't do exactly 15 minutes
for your daily scrum and it must be in
person then you're not doing scrum all
of that stuff I think has always been
[ __ ] it's not really it's not really
scrum it's not really agile it's not
really in keeping with that story and
people kind of latch on to that idea of
uh in the footnotes of scrum of the
scrum guide it does say that scrum as
defined in here is immutable and
implementing part of it is fine right
but
um it's not scrum if you only Implement
part of it and
people latch onto that so I think the
main advice is not to be dogmatic to be
pragmatic
and I feel like you could you you need
to be dogmatic in education right
because you're telling somebody how
something works right this thing is
defined this way here is how it works
does it matter that they use it
differently when they actually go and
use it in their company no are they
getting valued yes then we're cool right
are they doing all of it no are they
still getting value yes then it's great
um you don't need to be following every
little thing
um to to me that's successful and it's
actually something something that I
think the scrum guide scroll struggles
with because people complain when it
tells you it's to
structured into uh detailed and then
they complain when it doesn't tell you
how to solve your problems right oh the
scrum guide's not enough of course it's
not enough nothing's enough
um you need to come up with the
strategies and that I think is that that
core piece of advice that I see
consistent advice that I see from almost
everybody who knows what they're talking
about on the internet and whether it's
scrum agile lean cap doesn't matter what
it is the advice is almost always the
same
um the actual framework the actual tools
that you use are just tools they don't
matter
people and interactions over processes
and tools processes and tools are
valuable use them when they're effective
for you adapt them when they're not
ditch them when they're bad right that's
it that's that's the only advice you
need to be
um more agile
um but I would also caveat that I'm
going to caveat that because how do you
know something doesn't work for you if
you haven't done it right there's also
that idea that sometimes especially when
we're learning right and that could be
learning I'm in a classroom or learning
I'm trying to figure out how this thing
works is perhaps you want to do it the
way it says on the box
and then go I tried it this and this
stuff doesn't work we need to adapt this
we need to adapt that just like a recipe
and that's what I try and where the way
I try and phrase it
you know a recipe book
is not there for you to just follow
verbatim
because you will find that after you've
made the recipe verbatim once right you
follow the instructions you'll find it's
not quite to your taste maybe you like a
little bit more salt or you like a
little bit more paprika or you like to
put something else in it that is yours
so you take that recipe and you adapt it
and make it yours and create your own
recipe for what it is that you're doing
and that is the power of agile That's
The Power of
um flexibility of adaptive iterative
incremental and empirical processes
right use what works ditch what doesn't
look at the data see what's going on
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility