so the Sprint planning uh Workshop that
we have is delivered over multiple
sessions because we want you to be able
to have a chance to practice what we're
talking about right it's designed to be
run with a single organization
and we're going to start off by having
having a workshop where we we figure out
what Sprint planning is and what it
means to your organization that's kind
of the first part so we'll have a lot of
learnings in that part a lot of
exercises working through those those
ideas and hopefully solid outcome of
what do you want Sprint planning to be
within your Arc and then we're going to
to help you through your first few
Sprint plannings right uh so so somebody
there to to facilitate that Sprint
planning help coach you through it
um help get the most out of it
um and perhaps give a bunch of feedback
and debrief those those things what
happened during that event so that we
can make it better and over time what we
would expect to see is that you take
over all of that at work in running it
and making it effective and you make it
even more your own uh by adapting it to
what you what you need and having
it emerge over time right it's going to
keep changing keep emerging and as you
learn more about what you need what you
get from it and how you can leverage it
to make your business more successful
um
the the Sprint planning workshop can be
um delivered digitally or in person it
actually depends on how you work there's
no point in me coming to you in person
and delivering you and teaching you to
deliver this Workshop in person if
you're going to be doing it virtually
right uh so pick whatever format makes
sense for the way you work uh because
that's where you're going to get the
most learnings because the the learnings
that you get if I'm delivering digitally
um I'm going to be using tools
techniques and practices that work well
digitally and you can also bring those
tools and techniques uh into that that
story
um as for formats
um it's going to be uh um probably one
or two uh learning learning active
working learning sessions that we do
um and then probably two or three uh uh
uh coaching sessions through an actual
your real uh uh Sprint uh planning event
so that you can
um get practice right and have more
questions and find out what's going on
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility