okay so this presentation
is being uh recorded
hi my name's martin henshawwit
i'm the owner at naked agility with
martin henchwood i'm a
professional scrum trainer with
scrum.org
i'm a microsoft mvp and i've been
delivering software
for 20 years and working with
organizational change for over 10 years
and i'd like to thank william for this
opportunity to talk
about story points and velocity
uh this session is an experimental topic
for me i'm hoping
that you that are attending can
help me tell a better story in the
future so i'll be looking for
feedback at the end please feel free to
ask
any questions in the chat uh
jessica will hopefully uh be able to
moderate that
uh jessica is a fluent spanish speaker
um so if there are any confusions
about what i'm saying feel free to
message her in the chat
you can also in the um
the team's ui you can actually turn on
live captions it will only do it
currently in english
but you can do it and maybe that's uh
helpful so you just click
at the ellipse on the center of the
screen
um and turn on
live captions so i've got it turned on
on that machine up
there for us at the end of the
presentation
i'm going to provide a link to the
um and you can also find me
on linkedin and i have lots of other
presentation that i've recorded and
published on
nakedagility.tv
so i see we've got a few more people so
let's
um see how we do for uh some
participation
what i'm going to do is i'm going to put
the link
in the chat so that everybody
can find it let me put the link
in the chat so you don't have to type it
uh so i have
posted this link in the chat it is case
sensitive
so if you're typing it into a browser um
please do so carefully
and i'm just waiting to see uh who is
able to
make it on there we go i've got a couple
of people
i have awesome i have visiting penguin
visiting crab and visiting pig awesome
so um what i'd like you to do
is i'm going to put a a timer for two
minutes but if you see there's an
outline
on the top right of the mural um and you
should be able to click
uh measuring progress and that will take
you to
uh oh thank you visiting penguin is
following me um i will summon
everybody to this uh uh summon everybody
there we go
so what i'd i'd like to do uh first
is a little exercise where um
i'd like you to tell me what techniques
you have used uh to measure
progress within a sprint and maybe other
techniques
that you've heard of as well and i'd
like to create a sticky for each
method so i'm actually i'm just going to
put a timer on for two minutes so we
don't spend
at too long doing things
but i'd like you to create as many
stickies as you can within that
measuring
progress uh box so i'm gonna give you
that
two minute timer which is now one minute
45.
and i'll maybe start it off oh that's a
good point if you don't know how to
create a sticky
using this tool uh you double click
anywhere on the screen
and it will just create one absolutely
there we go so there's
a visiting pig is creating one
and visiting uh bird which is jessica
um is having it go as well so you just
double click anywhere
and type in yep burn down
is definitely a tool that i've seen uh
teams use
any other tools
so for the sake of the recording i'm
gonna bring this
over to the share uh there's about a
minute left
burn down chart burn up what about
metrics what about points of data what
sort of
other ways are there to measure is it
just burn down what do you plot on a
burn down
number of defects i like that one that's
that's one i've seen before
uh let's see
work until meeting the sprint goal user
stories closed by day
cool
nobody has mentioned story points
remaining story points that's a good one
so the story points must be a metric
inside of that
okay work in process thank you very much
whoever that was uh so we have a number
of things
that that folks have entered uh burn
down chart
uh work work until meeting the sprint
goal
um so i'm not sure how you're measuring
that or what data points you're using
with that i guess you would maybe look
at story points remaining maybe
or stories remaining or items remaining
uh we've got burn up
work in process user stories closed by
day
a number of defects created that can
definitely be a good measure but is
generally a measure of
quality rather than progress but um
they are all uh good measures so the
ones that i was
two that are i was surprised
were not on there our story points uh
and velocity are the two most
common ways it was implied in at least
one of the
the post-its uh so that does uh make
sense
so the the most popular uh method
for um doing that is story points and
velocity
and really story points and velocity are
are not they're not actually part of
scrum
uh there are a number of things that we
collectively
believe are required to do scrum and
these have been
perpetuated by a long-running
perseverance of trainers to the
to the training teaching to the lowest
common denominator
and trying to keep things as simple as
possible story points and velocity are
easy to understand they're easy to
implement they're easy to follow
um i would like to assert that they
don't provide as much value as
folks think they do um
there's a kind of a general consensus in
the trainer community
that folks that attend scrum training
are not smart enough to do anything else
and i would like to disagree i think
they are smart enough to do something
else
and whenever i teach scrum training i
always use different measures that we're
going to talk about
a little bit later i'm sure some of you
have already guessed
uh what i'm talking about but if you go
and have a look in the scrum guide you
can see i've i've
collected a couple of screenshots for
both velocity and story points neither
of which
are mentioned in scrum guide uh but
neither is burn down
neither is user story neither is
original estimate
bug count or actual versus completed
errors none of these things are
mentioned
in the scrum guide
i would say it's okay for a team to
start with story points and velocity
i've seen many teams get value out of
that
there are many things that change when a
team moves from traditional
project management practices of the past
to more
empirical practices of the present and
sometimes we
kind of need to pick our battles at one
such battle is that of story points and
velocity
and all of the other gubbins that goes
around with it that's maybe a very
british expression uh
gubbins is just all the other stuff
like if you're going to do story pines
and velocity you probably have some kind
of burn down you maybe have some kind of
burn up
um those kind of artifacts are part of
that
perhaps we do this because we need to
appease
other parts of the organization that are
not yet ready for change
uh perhaps we have to distance ourselves
from
data because we have uh
a traditional persecution
of the team by using
data of the past and that's that
original estimate versus actuals that i
see all the time
in organizations and we need to get
better at estimating by closing
closing that gap uh between original and
actuals
and it's just just not really tenable
while story points and velocity can be a
good starting point
they are not a good long-term
story um i'm not saying that there's no
value
in story points or planning poker that's
what this
uh team here is doing a little bit of
planning poker
um when a team is just starting out they
kind of do need to keep things
a little bit simple and iterate towards
better outcomes
we often start from typical traditional
practices and planning poker
is definitely a good learning point
stories
points use rough sizing as a way to
analyze work and break it down
because really the scores the the
numbers
that we get the points that we come up
with for stories
they're just made up like we always used
to they're a
a relative uh rough sizing thing
that allows us and enables our team
to get a shared understanding of the
work
it's about generating conversations
of understanding what we don't know that
other team members do know
and being able to come to a shared
understanding shared learning of what
those things are
and and that's awesome that's exactly
what we want
uh to achieve but i would assert that
we don't need to use those numbers
after that exercise that is definitely a
good exercise to have
but the story points and velocity um are
not super useful
because agile teams try to use story
points
and velocity for future predictability
uh to gain that level of predictability
and it's it's a total
fallacy uh that that is a valid thing
um while it would be okay for a team to
use it for a while if an agile team is
still
using velocity and story points
after uh they have 20 or 30 sprints
under their belt then i would have
serious concerns
about their ability
their ability to adapt uh to change
and their sincerity towards that change
in general
um teams using story points just don't
understand their work or its nature
this is what i mean by immaturity and
not
that something that's a sign of maturity
uh the opposite of that that's what i
mean by being an immature thing we just
don't
understand our work enough uh to have a
concrete measure
indeed uh the scrum team using story
points really has
at no constant consistent
reference points and they're just
shooting in the dark same as they were
before
this is very common and i believe it to
be an organizational dysfunction we pick
story points because of that
organizational immaturity and while they
have
in doing planning poker and
understanding those things
gained additional understanding of the
goals
of what those things are that we're
trying to achieve
what it is we're going to do they still
don't have an understanding of the
predictability
and thus they have no confidence in
their predictions
they may have false confidence but it's
not actual confidence
in their predictions we need
some concrete uh data
uh that we can use it to build
trust with our stakeholders that we know
what we're talking about at all
otherwise they may just take their money
elsewhere
and then we don't have additional work
we we need that level
of confidence so the traditional method
for
uh improving that level of confidence
is confidence is uh to
focus on that velocity
fluctuation and try and improve
uh that velocity fluctuation uh sorry
improve it
improves the team's position and have a
more
stable velocity so what i would like to
do
is there is a second question uh
here in the fluctuating velocity section
so if you click
fluctuating velocity on the right i will
summon
everybody i'm only going to put two
minutes i know it says three
uh but i'm going to put two minutes on
there and i'm going to ask that you
create a post-it
for everything that you could do with a
team
to help them improve their velocity
stabilize it maybe make it bigger plus
make it more consistent
so i know there's a few people following
me but i'm just going to zoom in so i
can
read that a little bit better because it
was rather small
so work on commitment and optimistically
view
refinement now trying to put that reduce
waste yep
couldn't we uh restrict the team's
holidays
that's usually a good way to to have
more consistency
i'm just joking with that one
there's about 40 seconds left hit them
i don't know who was typing that but
that was visiting sea lion
let's let's wall up the team make them
work harder
focus on one thing instead of many
that's kind of getting to the
to the to the crux of it
focus on the sprint goal fixing
technical debt
that's definitely something we're going
to do
collaborative refinement a very powerful
technique
these are all really good techniques uh
i would be
concerned with focusing too much on
reducing
waste uh waste is
the elimination of waste is a lean
technique that applies
mostly to uh understood
work uh because we want to remove all
waste from the process like if we were
building a set of cars
uh um we're we've got a production line
and we want to eliminate
all waste waste in a creative endeavor
or things that look like waste in a
creative diver
are actually the thing that gives us
that little bit of friction
uh that creativeness of the development
team of building
uh interesting and powerful products uh
so i i like reducing waste
i just would be uh careful
with that technique i would reduce
technical debt that's a way to reduce
waste reducing rework
um have built testing
into the process rather than test after
which a lot of teams do
that will reduce waste as well so there
are definitely things we can do
to reduce waste but the reality is
if i can change that there we go your
velocity is
is going to fluctuate that is
just a fundamental uh reality
of uh the way we work velocity was a way
to kind of assert
that confidence with a plot of our
delivered story points
along with some clever calculations like
maybe uh
the mean or the mean of the worst three
and we assert that we're likely to
deliver about
20 story points this is such a wholly
improbable assumption that the vast
majority of scrum teams talk about
carryover points and quiz me on how to
represent that
do you re-estimate and stick it on the
backlog or did you just go straight into
the next sprint and do you chop it up
and do you get points for the stuff
you've just done in the previous sprint
even though you didn't finish it these
are all questions
that make visible
make transparent a fundamental problem
with the idea of story points and
velocity
in the first place scrum teams have been
basing their confidence
level that they talk to stakeholders
about
based on just an agreed consensus
that can't be compared between teams
can't be looked at
across an organization and it's
susceptible
to any sort of gaming you would like and
it's just made up in the team's
estimation room
so if you have a different person doing
the work
than was involved in estimating maybe
because there was some vacation time
and somebody who was critical to
creating
the understanding that we got during
refinement
is now they're off while when we go to
take this story
they're not available then um
it's going to take much longer than we
thought it was maybe some critical skill
is missing
maybe some critical insight is missing
we've shared our understanding as much
as possible but
we just don't have the confidence level
that we thought we did so we end up with
carryovers we end up with things
spilling over
into the next sprint in a way that is
untenable
i got this quote uh off at daniel
vicanti's
at twitter he actually gave me another
quote that i'm not going to use because
it's very rude
uh but he says uh he used to say that
story points set the agile industry back
10 years
and he was wrong they set the industry
back 20 years
we have been scrum has been around for
25 years the agile manifesto
was signed nearly 20 years ago and we're
still
talking about uh story points
and velocity as a concrete measure for
teams
and it is just not acceptable
anymore we need to create
uh a world in which we have a
more suitable set of measures that we
can
actually use to understand
our work understand how the team is go
doing and understand how changes that
that team makes or that the organization
makes
impacts on that work we need something
that when you game the system it
produces a different result
instead of gaming the system by oh we'll
just call that a
ten pointer instead of a five pointer
and we've doubled the amount of work
that we did
and we want people to be gaming the
system in a way
that benefits the process that reduces
uh the time it takes for us to deliver
things
and there are some very key practices
around that
uh they are well known i'm not going to
be
uh i'm not opening a a magic box
um but we need to be actively
managing items in progress
actively managing the items that we're
working on
and the way to do that is definitely to
visualize
your work um understand
where what stage things are at and if
you will have seen a kanban style board
before
where work itself moves across rather
than
a storyboard where the work
is stationary and items of work
flow across so the what is stationary on
this
uh board the what is flowing uh
across during the sprint and and we
maybe have some
at stages along the way that work has to
flow through
in order to get to at the end get to
production
uh but you can see a limiting uh working
process by having
a a total whip limit that's divided
into the individual columns kanban has
no requirement
to have uh individual columns with whip
limits however
if you are going to have columns within
that process then they should have what
plummets beetle you don't have to
but we need to also record our cycle
time we need to understand how
long things are in process for
how long does it take from when the the
team that owns that kanban
owns that part of the process when they
decide that work has started
until they decide that work has finished
uh we can use our work in process
and plot that uh on a on a graph called
a cumulative flow
graph and cumulative flow is very scary
to look at when you
first see it but it actually gives you
an
indication of the predictability
that you're having so you can see this
particular
cumulative flow that you see there which
is a little bit small but
can i zoom in
oh i think i can using there we go
uh this particular cumulative flow is
uh showing each of the different columns
that we had
and sorry was there a question
there's just some background noise it's
okay everybody's muted now that's
awesome so uh
that these lines on the cumulative flow
are wavy
i.e not straight is an indication of a
lack of predictability
the more predictability you have in the
system the
straighter those lines are and then
it's easy to see once those lines are a
little bit straighter
if they're diverging your working
process is increasing
if they're coming together then your
working process
is reducing ideally what you want to see
is parallel lines but that's almost
never going to
happen in the real world but that's the
the goal
that you're aiming for as you uh
do certain things in your process you
can see the impact that they have on
your predictability
this graph is indicative of the
predictability
of the team and that these lines are
waving around all over the place
is a indication that they're not being
very predictable
unzoom that there we go so working pro
cycle time and working process are two
really powerful
at measures throughput um is
a measure of items of work
per unit of time so you can use any unit
of time
you like if you're sprinting it's
probably
a two-week sprint so how many
pieces of work were you able to deliver
in two weeks and it does not care about
size it very deliberately doesn't care
about size which is the difference
between
throughput and velocity velocity usually
cares about the size or complexity of
items because you're applying story
points
throughput ignores that because then
gaming the system will be the team
reducing the size of the items by
breaking them down or making them
simpler
and and things that are smaller are
going to go through this process
a lot quicker because smaller things are
easier to do so if we half the size
of all of the things that we're working
on we're going to half the amount of
work
that we have to do therefore we will
half the amount of time
it takes to go through the system
therefore each item
will get delivered more quickly um
so that's it's i'm fine with the team
gaming that metric but throughput um
allows us to tell an interesting
uh story but there's one more metric
that we really need to understand
that helps us have more interesting
conversations
during our existing uh agile events
maybe you're doing scrum
maybe you're doing other uh processes
maybe you've made up your
own uh very powerful process empirical
process control system that works for
you
um and that is work item aging
we have to understand how old things are
and how close they are to our
uh uh likelihood of completing them
in order to see whether we need to go
deal with something now
is this getting so old it's been in
there so long
that it's likely not to me then me be
delivered by the end of the sprint
that may be something that we want to
focus on as a team that we maybe want to
swarm
around so it allows us to have some of
those more interesting conversations
so in order to use flow in a scrum
context
i i'm a professional scrum trainer my
recommendation
is uh to use scrum as your scaffolding
for
project management and then flow to flow
techniques to manage your work that
would be my general recommendation
but flow in a scrum process those core
practices
are that defining and visualizing your
work
limiting the working process we have to
measure it and then
actively managing those items and the
actively managing
is uh super important there you're not
actively managing if you're just
ignoring stuff and letting it flow
through the sprint you need to actually
go decide whether you need to do
something extra whether you need to
change what you're doing
inside of that process and inspecting
and adapting
your workflow you need to constantly
make changes to your workflow
see how it affects the data one of the
things that i mentioned which is the
most common
uh uh thing that we talk about in
any flow techniques is reducing batch
size
making batches smaller will help us
deliver things more quickly
so i would like to um
do another little exercise in
mural so i have let's
where did i put it in
the mural nope that's not what i wanted
to do it's a tab that's already there
there it is um in the mural there's a
third exercise in number three batches
in scrum
uh and three people are following me let
me just summon
everyone and then i'll not i'll not zoom
so i get nine people following me now
what i'd like you to do is create a
sticky for everything that you think is
a batch
in scrum what are what are batches in
this scrum world so i'm gonna i'm gonna
put two minutes on the time box your
smart group should be able to do this in
two minutes
um and we need to come up with a list of
those batches so think of things that
you would be counted by actually
deliverable definitely
uh a thing that is a batch
what what would you call that in the
scrum world
we can have that as an additional sticky
next to it oh the increment
okay yes definitely the increment is a
batch
thank you for for making that clearer i
was not 100
on that for those uh there are nine
people here
there are how many participants are
there
in the there are 12 participants
in the call in the chat you should be
able to see
a link for the
mural i'm gonna post it again i see uh
marty has also posted it again
because folks that are new in will not
see it but i will post it again so folks
can get in
thank you uh marty for that that's very
useful
as we get pbis in the sprint backlog
so are you saying that the sprint
backlog is a batch or that the pbis
are a batch or both maybe you need two
stickies
i would count them as two separate
things
does anybody else like would like to add
a few things to this list sprint backlog
yes thank you very much
visiting visiting dragon bracket the
sea lion awesome
is there any um
anybody else going to add something
there's 25 seconds left
retrospective commitments
perfect thank you visiting c-line i'm
going to add a couple as well
um i'm going to say pbis
product backlog items whether you call
them uh
stories or
our requirements whatever you call those
things
um so we've got uh the sprint backlog
pbis uh the increment uh
retro next actions these are all uh uh
batches in scrum and one of the things
that we
try and uh do once we start
looking at our flow techniques
is we start reducing the batch size for
as many things as possible
so we want to reduce the size of our
pbis the things from our product backlog
that we're taking through
on average um i see scrum teams taking
on
maybe 8 to 12 things per sprint
that's just a vague average from my
experience
um but teams that monitor flow
have that go up to 70 or 80 things
because they're making each of those
pieces of value
much smaller which means they flow much
more quickly
through the system and once you have a
flow based system you can start looking
at
how you can break down that batch
of the increment are you doing
continuous delivery
are you using devops practices to
continuously deliver your product to
production
and what engineering practices do you
use to make sure that you
always have a good product to be able to
ship
to production uh so once you have that
you can then start flowing work
across the sprint boundary because we
always have working software we're
always shipping
every commit to source control in a
continuous delivery world
ends up in production therefore
um we have the engineering practices in
place
to hide things that are not finished yet
maybe we're using feature flags
and still ship to production we can then
have a piece of work that well we didn't
quite finish it in this sprint but we're
going to finish it in the next print and
it just
flows right across the sprint boundary
then scrum becomes
that container for planning and
flow management techniques are used for
delivery
and that's very powerful we're using
flow in our production line
but we're using a two-week iterative
cycle for our cognitive uh ideation and
planning
cycle that's that's uh really powerful
so then at the individual events in
scrum we can
actually have different completely
different conversations
when we're at our our daily scrum
we're not necessarily focused on the
individual anymore
what did i do to to
what did i do yesterday what am i doing
today what am i
going to do tomorrow yeah anything
that's blocking me
we're looking at things on the board and
saying
why is this thing not moving why is it
here so long
oh this one's not been here that long
but this one's been here really long so
let's focus on this one instead
um what can we do to move this item
forward to get it closer to the end of
that
process and things like going right to
left on the board
help with that because you've got a pool
process you're not pushing work through
this process
it's being pulled from the right uh from
from the left to the right yeah
pooled uh i don't think i've got my
terminology quite right there but i
think you know what i mean and it allows
us to
to really have better conversations
about that work
and the thing that allows us to see uh
when things have been sitting too long
uh measuring
measuring latency what one easy way to
do it
it says they're right the date on the
back of the cards i've seen
dot voting uh so you just put every day
put a dot on the card and the cards with
the most dots that are still in progress
are the things you want to focus on
uh jessica really liked that idea
of sticking a a banana peel to the item
and the
browner the banana peel the longer it's
been sitting there you don't want it
sitting there
too long or it'll start to smell um
but one of the things that we often use
and the
graph that we use uh there is a is a
um histogram with whip limits
um and the green is uh you can see the
the 50 70 85 95 i'm going to talk about
competent
confidence levels in the next slide but
that's effectively
uh green is things are flowing awesome
at half of the things that we do end up
in that green bit
uh 70 of the things we do end up
in the light green 85 percent end up
in the yellow and 95 of things
are done within the orange so if
something's in the
red it is likely that it will not
be finished by the end of the sprint if
something's in the orange
it's could be a con it's a definitely a
concern
if something's in the yellow it's going
to be a concern
so you can see that progression and this
particular graph they're calculating it
per column
you can do it just overall which is what
i'm going to show you
next so we use the cycle times
scatter plot so we plot all of those
cycle times that we calculate how long
things are going to take
uh on the vertical axis here
uh so that is number of days so you can
see
uh seven days 10 days 12 days
at 16 days all the way up to 30 days
to deliver something and then along the
bottom is the
the date that it was finished and you
can see that some of the items have uh
uh maybe you can
maybe need to zoom in for that have a
four in them how many items
uh uh were in that four oh sorry four
items were
were in that particular point in time
the horizontal dotted lines with the 50
75 85 and 95
are um calculated
that 50 of all the items
displayed on this graph are below that
50 line
75 percent of all the items are below
the 78 line 85
same as you go up and the prediction on
the left
is the seven days 50 of all the things
we do based on this data will be
delivered in seven days
but if you go all the way up to 85 it's
16 days
so we can say for sure for this
particular team
that 85 of the time
anything we bring into their sprint is
finished in 16 days or less
anything
that's a really powerful measure that's
a concrete
statistical measure there is some leeway
there there is some space for
for concern but 85 is pretty
pretty sure remember we're
working on creative work so more is
unknown than known so if we get a
a 16 day uh
85 percent then that's pretty good but i
would ask a question
i would ask if we're on a two-week
sprint is 16 days
okay and in fact it's not it's too slow
so we can use those flow metrics in
different
events within our uh
scrum in order to understand them a
little bit better
so we can use work item aging in our
daily scrum to understand where we need
to focus our time
uh we can use cycle time in our retro
retrospective to understand
uh how things went during the sprint
are we able to increase our
confidence level that we're giving to
our stakeholders
what does that confidence level look
like what can we do to improve it we can
look at that
that data there the cycle time
we can use our work in process during
the daily scrum
to understand uh how things are
are flowing again part of that uh aging
data as well
but also during our retro are are what
do our whip limits make sense
uh is work flowing well through the
system do we need to do
something about it and potentially at
the review as well
talking to our stakeholders get more
credibility with your stakeholders
and you can also use throughput during
sprint planning our throughput
is a concrete indication of
what's happened in the past so we're
able to
use that to understand what we might
potentially be able to do
in the future it's a lot more it has a
much higher degree of accuracy
than velocity because
we will have been able over a period of
time to improve our predictability
which is not possible using velocity and
story points
so we would use throughput during our
planning our review
and our our retro so this
data will help us understand
those things help us manage that work
help us have uh build trust with our
stakeholders
by making uh uh
that story of data and when things will
be done
a lot more at credible uh
as a good quote you can definitely
have a read of that later it's long but
it's basically
half your batch size things will get
delivered faster
um half and again things will get
delivered faster again
if you want to research at some stuff on
this
topic uh i've put some notes up there at
little's law
queuing theory continuous delivery no
estimates
and there is a guide from scrum.org that
is an addendum to the scrum guide called
the kanban guide for scrum teams
about how you implement flow techniques
within the empirical control system
which is
scrum and that can be very powerful
so in the minute i have left
i would like to open up for both
questions
and feedback um if you want you can
unmute to ask questions i would also
love
uh for you to put feedback in
the mural things in this talk you were
happy with
things uh you thought were meh and
things that you didn't like
as well as um anything that you think i
can do to improve the talk
um also questions does anybody have any
questions
yeah hi martin uh here are
the the draw on speaking the drum guest
what about what do you think about
putting some metrics related more than
you're talking about incomes about
throughput but
what do you recommend to a team that
want to begin to focus on outcome or an
output
more than more than only predictability
about
uh if what they are really really
what they are uh producing what is the
real impact to the customer
or so yeah and i think that that's yeah
that that's an awesome question
um so just to to paraphrase that so that
i make sure i've got it right
and the these metrics are awesome
for uh monitoring delivery and improving
delivery but that doesn't we could still
be delivering a
pile of crap to our customers um how do
we
monitor value that we're delivering to
our customers
is that
your questions yeah yeah is it yeah just
stopping the delivering crap yeah
yeah something that doesn't deliver crap
deliver more value um
yeah that that's your measure no um so
uh
i talk about i i have i teach class uh
called the the professional scrum with
ux user experience
and what it really is is how to uh how
to
what data do we use to optimize value
and there's no concrete measures for
that
i could i would actually point you a
little bit at the
um ebm evidence-based management guide
from scrum.org they have a bunch of
starter measures that are very generic
uh that are good for measuring change
within your organization and are you
improving and are you having happy
customers because happy customers
happy customers happy employees always
good
um but also for
every single idea that your product
owner has
and they need to along with the scrum
team
understand what they're trying to
achieve with it what behavior
in your customers are you trying to
change what are you trying to improve
how are you going to measure that so
it's specific to each
backlog item it's part of that what that
you're delivering
so how you're going to measure that and
then actually measure it
so telemetry is your friend there
are people actually using the feature
that you built
and are they using it in the way you
expect is it creating that changing
behavior for the users
that you expect so you have to be able
to model the existing behavior and then
see the change
i i usually use app insights application
insights
uh for that works on any any tech any
platform
and it allows you to not only collect
the base
data you know like some of the google
analytics stuff plus the server-side
stuff
um but also add your own
custom metrics that are about how your
application functions how that
particular feature works
and and and monitor that data is your
friend
honestly data's your friend customers
lie
remember that customers lie data
generally doesn't although
you can read it badly um so definitely
good
thank you for that question did i answer
it
yeah i was re i i i was writing yeah
yeah thank you martin agree with the
lies of
our customers or yes
what was it uh henry ford said if uh
if if he'd listened to customers he
would have created faster horses
rather than the motor car um
any other questions
so if there's not any other questions i
saw a couple of folks
left there's probably other talks to go
to
let me skip to the last slide where i
have a lovely
uh link which i just noticed has
uh o's and zeros
uh without a good font so that is a
oos2020
ie 2020 a aos 2020
at dash velocity and and that will get
you
this copy of the presentation
um you'll be able to view it online and
the recording
i guess will go up at some point thank
you very much for coming
thank you marin you're welcome please
feel free
hook me up on linkedin
i will gracias
thank you martin my pleasure
oh it's coffee break that means i could
have kept going
you