one of the seven deadly sins of agile is
sloth and this manifests in a number of
number of different ways with with teams
with
organizations uh with leadership all
over the place um one of the most common
um elements is just not bothering our
bothering our ARS actually doing the
things um that that that we say we're
going to do right we say we're doing
agile but we don't deliver working
product at the end of the Sprint we say
we're doing agile um but we have long
convoluted deployment processes which
are not in control of the developers we
say we're doing agile um but we don't
have an ordered backlog right all of
these things
are places where we say we're doing
something but really we're just kind of
lazy and line through our teeth in order
to not have to do the work perhaps it's
because somebody in leadership in the
organization has decided that thou shalt
do Agile and your product is not
particularly suited to that model
because it was built in a in a
traditional maybe it's got Mainframe and
all kinds of crazy stuff in there maybe
there are other reasons why it's not
viable within the the the confines the
structure of of of your organization the
system that you're in um but I would
much rather teams and people were honest
and
transparent with their companies and
their organizations about what they they
can and cannot do what isn't is not
agile um I really like there's a great
article
um called uh detecting agile BS uh from
the US Department of Defense and if you
search for it you will find
uh a great little workflow on it it's my
one of my favorite uh uh things that I
use in organizations so here are uh six
sloths uh things that organizations kind
of say they do um or pretend that
they're agile but they don't actually do
these things uh and this I think these
are great uh so first one is our teams
delivering working software to real
users every iteration including the
first and Gathering feedback that's like
that's like the first thing that's
almost agile in a nutshell are we coming
up with ideas getting those ideas in
front of customers and getting that
feedback if you're not doing that sloth
right you're you're you're you're not
able to get things done uh the second
one and because this is Department of
Defense right uh is there a product
Charter laying down the mission
strategic goals and do all members of
the team
understand how they contribute right
that's absolutely key if how can we
expect people within the context of our
of our product of our teams of our uh
organization to make good decisions
about what it is uh that they need to do
if they they they they don't have all
the information they need right we're
we're hiring smart clever people and
then we're not empowering them
to do the things that they need to do
right we're not we're just not
empowering them um and that that's
that's part of we need to communicate
with them and if you don't communicate
with them sloth if you don't actually do
those things you're you're you're being
lazy right just do it uh third one is
feedback uh from users turned into
concrete work items um on Sprint
timeline shorter than one month right so
are you getting uh things in front of
your customers at least once per month
um and
those that that that shouldn't be that
hard right it shouldn't be that hard to
engage uh with your with your with your
customers get parts of your product in
front of your customers and then get
them to tell you what they think of it
right Gathering feedback from from from
those users that shouldn't be that hard
and if you're not doing it sloth cuz
it's not that hard you're just being
lazy uh uh one that I I already
mentioned a little bit H is the full
ecosystem of your project agile I.E
agile programming teams followed by
linear bureaucratic deployments is a
failure right why do you have linear
bureaucratic deployments after your
adual team have done the work yeah we
might be able to make working product in
two weeks but how long does it take
before that increment that two weeks
worth of work actually gets in front of
real users so that you can CL close
those feedback loops break down those
assumptions validate what it is that
you're creating that it is actually
value and and if that's too
long that's it's not agile if you look
at the agile Manifesto you you it
says ideally a shorter time frame but
only a few months uh between having an
IDE and getting it into into production
um that should be uh the case and then
the the the fifth one are teams
empowered to change their requirements
based on feedback the the people doing
the work should be able to change and
adapt the requirements that they're
creating in the system the things that
they're building we want to build more
of the right things and less of the
wrong things we want to maximize the
amount of work not done all of those
things require the people doing the work
to be able to delete add or change
things from the backlog as needed based
on those interactions that we've already
talked about with the customer and if
you're not doing that sloth right why
are you not doing that why is somebody
not addressing the problems of why you
can't do that if your organization is
saying we want to do Agile year we want
to get all the benefits oh but you you
can't change your requirements you have
to do everything that here's the 300
things we need you to do that's
fundamentally not agile welcome changing
requirements even late in development
these are just fundamental uh uh
principles of agility and then the last
one on the Department of Defense you
know not well known for being an agile
organization but um the last one on
their list is are teams empowered to
change their process based on what they
learn so not only changing the work that
they're doing but changing the way that
they're doing the work and why aren't
your teams empowered to do that well
because people more senior can't be
bothered with that they just want to buy
agile from some vendor install it and
then everybody just does it that way
that's that's not fundamentally how
agile Works agile is about the emergent
practices The Continuous change
emergence and adaption of our processes
practices and tools in order to be able
to maximize the value delivered to the
customer the stakeholder which maybe the
business themselves right and without
those abilities we can't do that that I
I I feel like these six things
absolutely impit omey that's not a
word are sloth right if you're not able
to do all of these things you're not
really that interested in moving towards
agility you're really not that
interested in doing those things it's
it's lazy it's inept get off your ass
and fix it
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked
agility