one defines quality the other defines
scope acceptance criteria and definition
of done are not the same thing and
confusing them leads to missed
expectations hidden risks and broken
trusts acceptance criteria defines the
specific conditions for a particular
backlog item did we meet this specific
need did we cover this particular case
but the definition of done that's the
organizational quality baseline it
applies to everything it's the minimum
standard every increment must meet
security telemetry testing deployment
readiness regulatory compliance it's not
negotiable it's not optional it's not
story specific at Naked Agility we clear
up this confusion so your teams can move
fast without cutting corners and your
customers get reliable consistent
outcomes still mixing up acceptance
criteria and done let's build clarity
that scales