so good reasons to do a pspoa class
would be that you are a product manager
or you're in product management and you
want to understand how to incorporate
and do Agile in that story uh works
great if you've if you are a product
owner and you want to increase your
skills or if you do no scrum whatsoever
and all you're interested in is that
product matter agile product management
piece how do I become more collaborative
how do I become more effective at
responding to change what are all the
things that I need to consider in that a
world of product management in order to
deliver the most effective product for
my business