Engineering excellence isn't about
perfection, right? A a lot of
teams and organizations especially
especially um organizations with more
than more than one team try
they they have this ethos. Oh, we're
going to move to a new way of doing
things and I want to understand all of
the facets of that before we move. I
want to understand all of the choices
we're going to make. I want to
understand why we're making all those
choices. I want to understand I want to
make a a a big plan of of what we're
going to do. And and that's
not reality. That's not how
when you actually start implementing
things. And this is true for for for
implementing things with people,
implementing things in systems,
implementing things in software.
The needs that you discover are
different than the needs that you
thought of right at the beginning. So
there's not a huge amount of value in
planning out all the things at the start
only to have that planet destroyed. So
we still need planning. Absolutely. I'm
not saying shoot from the hip and make
stuff up. That's definitely not what I'm
saying. Um, the plan itself, that every
little detail is the the the the the
irrelevant part. I think there was a was
I think it was a US president from years
ago. Um, might have been a general or a
US president, might have been Eisenhower
said, um, plans are irrelevant. Planning
is everything. I think it was a World
War II thing, right? It's it's about the
planning, the discussions, the what do
we think's going to happen? What do we
want to try and do? What what are our
options when these different things
happen? Um and discussing them and
disseminating that information,
but the plan itself um the plan itself
is is is irrelevant. I think isn't there
a Sunzu? Maybe
no plan survives contact with the enemy,
right? As soon as you start doing
something in your organization, as soon
as you start following the plan, it's
irrelevant, right? The first step, the
feedback from that first step in your
plan and probably destroys the entire
plan. So if if if your goal is to move
towards engineering excellence, it's
it's not about perfection. It's about
instilling
those ideas,
modern software engineering ideas of
continuous, right? Usually you stick
continuous in front of everything.
Continuous delivery, continuous quality,
um continuous adaptation, continuous
learning. It it's that that continuous
or emergent nature that the things
you're going to need, the knowledge
you're going to have to learn, the
things you're going to find out are
going to emerge over time. So we need to
create a system within which that
emergent knowledge
adapts the system as it goes to what is
happening. So that so that we end up
getting um um delivering working
products. Um getting high quality output
and although the goal is not agility um
being fast and nimble and delivering for
your customers is right and that that
that can be a definition of of of
agility for sure. So there are loads of
tools and capabilities
practices that are known
to to enable this. And every time I I
work with a lot of customers and we talk
about some of these practices. I was
talking um yesterday about trunkbased
development
and the customer came back with five or
six reasons why trunkbased development
wouldn't work for them, right? Or or we
couldn't do it that fast, but you know,
it could be this long.
And my immediate response was, well, why
are those things blocking your ability
to do that modern engineering practice?
Where did those things come from
and how do you fix them? Right? That's
that's and some of it could be a
long-term fix. We've caused some legacy
products and it's going to take time to
to get to that to get to that point.
Right? If you're currently manually
building out your your infrastructure
for your products, if you're currently
um doing manual portions in your build
process, right? It's not a automated
CI/CD process. It's it's there's
stuff somebody has to go do in between
in different spots in order to make it
make it work. Then it can be really
daunting
to have this idea of well, we're we're
going to do trunkbased development.
We're going to have a a a topic branch
spin-off. It's only going to exist for a
few hours. It's going to have a full
environment. We're going to run all our
tests and then it's going to going to
come into main in a few hours. How is
that even possible, right? Because of
the frictions that are that are holding
us back. If if but if we want fast
feedback,
right, then we we have to get to our
customers as quickly as possible with
high quality, right? not delivering them
crap because then they'll just the
feedback will be it's crap, right? We
want to deliver high quality usable
working product on a continuous as
quickly as possible, as often as
possible basis. And for that, we're
going to we're going to we're going to
need to have clean code,
right? You can't you can't do this with
poor quality code. And you might be
starting with poor quality code. So
there's something to go work on. you you
need observability in the way you do
things and you you you may not have
observability today. You may not have
telemetry coming through your product.
You may not have those things built in
that allow you to see what's going on.
um you know the the the the
knowledge that you gain on how users are
using your system but also what's
happening in your system while users are
using it. It can be invaluable, right?
Um you you've effectively got
brittle
I'm going to say poorly architected, but
I don't mean that as as as a direct
criticism. maybe atrophied
code. It It's not usually a deliberate
effort. We want to build bad code and we
want to build bad products and we're bad
people because we built bad products.
It's it's that's not what we're talking
about. It's something that happens
slowly over time. It's like it's a
drift. It's like it's like when you um
oh when your tires on your car are not
aligned properly, when the tracking is
not aligned properly, right? It's maybe
it's just a little bit out. Maybe it's
just a a degree. That could be quite a
lot actually. Maybe it's just a fraction
of a degree out. And that means the wear
on your tires
is unnatural, right? And you maybe have
to replace your tires more often. So,
it's costing you more money. And you're
trying to figure out why is this costing
me more money? Well, and it's £100 a
tire and you're doing that every every
let's say every year you're having to
replace these tires. You're like, what
what's going on?
But if you paid £40 to get the tracking
aligned, then we don't have that
problem. Maybe our tires last a lot
longer. Maybe they last 50,000 mi and
someone that's actually a lot for tires.
Maybe they last 20,000 mi instead of
5,000 mi, right? So So that's that's the
type of thing we're talking about. How
how do we fix the tracking on our on our
software, right? Well, we we we need
clean code. We need observability. We
need CI/CD
right ideas. We need to to automatically
build our product. We need automated
testing. Um we need to test as much as
possible. This is that whole idea that
fixing the tracking is the idea of of
also shifting left. Um you might have
heard that terminology, but shift left
is about moving things as close to the
developers writing the code to figuring
out that it doesn't work. I I always use
the example of the Azure DevOps team
because they started with a massive
legacy product. Um,
very low I'm going to say low code
quality. I think they probably agree
with that. Not great code quality. Um,
and and very poor testing capability.
Most of the testing was longunning
system tests like things like Selenium
tests today, but they had their own
system. And that's just not not good
enough anymore cuz they take too long to
run. It takes too long to find out for
the developer to find out that they've
broken something. And if it takes too
long, they've lost the context. And if
they've lost the context, they have to
relearn that context. And that's a
massive cognitive effort that could have
been used to work on other things,
right? So we want fast tests and they
were I think they were either 48 or 72
hours to run their full test suite
against the the the the stuff they were
building as your DevOps. Um not in Azure
DevOps actually as your DevOps being
building building that product and they
spent a bunch of effort. It took four
years because they're doing a little bit
at a time, right? They're paying back a
little bit of that friction every
sprint. And over four years, which I
think is 80 sprints. They did three week
sprints, so you can probably figure it
out. Um, but over those 80 sprints, they
they paid back a little bit of time and
they went from 48 to 72 hours to find
out whether they'd broken anything to
three and a half minutes.
So a developer
can run the entire
test suite for for the product in three
and a half minutes on their local
workstation. And that includes having a
full environment running to be able to
run those those types of not just the
the fast unit tests, but that includes
some some integration tests as well. And
that
is what makes things better. That's what
makes things faster. the the quicker
shortening the feedback loops. This is
this is what it's all this is the
fundamental premise of DevOps of agile
is shortening the shortening the
feedback loops. DevOps is about
shortening the feedback loops in
engineering. Agile is about shortening
the feedback loops in business. Right?
Um, so if you want your teams to build
better and deliver faster,
you need to start with engineering
excellence.