[Music]
my name is Martin Henshaw wit and I
created the azure DevOps migration tools
you can find them on the visual studio
marketplace if you search under Azure
DevOps you will find the tools we're
actually up to about 50,000 migrations
just over 50,000 migrations migration
sessions per month this in the last 30
days we've migrated 340 thousand work
items with 2.6 million revisions using
the tool so that's that's pretty pretty
huge I do want to stress the warning
that you can see here on the page the
tool is not designed for novices it is
developed by and far as your DevOps
consultants who have helped lots of
folks do migrations around the world and
you're welcome to have a have a go this
video is going to try and explain how to
get started with the tool we've updated
it a lot in the last year in fact two
years since the last video we've merged
a lot of the different tools together as
well as enabled syncing for for work
item migrations so if you do a migration
and then somebody happens to have
changed a bunch of work items in the old
system between you starting the
migration and finishing you can have it
go and pull those additional changes
across as well so it's kind of pseudo
syncing it's not syncing between two
systems but syncing from one system to
the other system I get a lot of
questions around what versions of azure
DevOps does it support and everything
that the object model API does so that's
TFS 2013 plus it does mostly work
against older versions of TF
but the official support is TFS 2013 and
onwards all the way up as your DevOps
and yes you can go from Azure DevOps to
as your DevOps as your DevOps to TFS TFS
to your DevOps
pretty much whatever you want and so let
me pop over there's a documentation
available on github and it has a lot
more detail on how the Tool Works so if
you click through to the documentation
and you will go to this page and I know
and here you'll see detailed
documentation about what the processors
that are available are and the
processors are the thing that does the
work so the node structures migration
processor will move your areas and
iterations across the work item
migration context will migrate your work
items links revisions attachments and
hopefully if we can get it organized
it's not working right now the HTML
field embedded images as well and it
will also fix the git commits as a
number of other and tools that are
available at work item delete this is
deliberately crippled so that you don't
accidentally delete a whole bunch of
stuff you will meet the code to be able
to run this one but you can delete any
number of work items and an update ur so
instead of migration from one system to
another if you just want to run a bunch
of changes against an existing project
then you can do that so for example you
might have an added a new field and you
want to migrate data from one field to
another field or you might want to split
data from one field into two fields
that's so that work item update will
allow you to run against an existing
project work item query migrator well
obviously migrate your queries across so
it will take them just need to make sure
that it will skip any queries where the
fields don't match up so you need to be
aware of that
the fields in the new location need to
match and the fields in the old location
otherwise it with error right there is
also a a migrator for the teams I think
it's actually not on this list yet but
it will migrate the create teams and
migrate all of the settings for those
teams across or as much as possible at
the moment there are a bunch of tools
around migrating at test cases and so
sweets and plans you have to migrate the
variables first then the configurations
and then you run our plans and sweets at
migration which will pull that across so
you do not migrate test cases using this
tool you have to use the work item
migration context to migrate the test
cases but do not migrate the test plans
and test Suites work items across at the
same time otherwise you'll end up with a
bunch of duplicate items that's about it
for the general processors we have a
number of field Maps I did mention that
if you're either working against a
single team project your migration for
one to another you may want to use some
field maps and this is good if your
source and target projects have
different processes you may want to use
this or if you're updating changing the
process and an existing project and you
want to map data from one field to
another and so there's just a field to
field map and field to field multi map
so it's a list if you've got a field or
a list in it it'll map data from one to
another field marriage and put two
fields together in a particular format
blanket so you don't want to migrate a
particular field that field to tag
that's you can convert any number of
fields from your source system to tags
in your target system that's good for a
bunch of fields that are not available
in a target system you don't want to add
them to the target system and for
example if you're simplifying a process
you can run the field tag to save some
of that data while not adding to the
Lord of a number of fields field value
map so that's just a value mapper and
then we've filled value to tag so if
there's a set of values you can have
them two tags a reg X field mapper so
that's pretty useful for example I got
this for a customer who had their
version format in 2016 - in a text field
and they wanted to set it in a drop-down
list one with 16 in the other one with
the two and so the reg X field map will
let you do that and then for many
organizations that have been in TFS for
a long time they have a problem where
all of their area paths their area tree
hierarchy is reflective of their product
or organizational hierarchy rather than
the team's hierarchy which is how the
new system prefers things to work you
don't have to do that would prefer
things to work so if you want to map all
of that tree into tags so we'll take
each node and build a tag and attach it
to the work items and you can do that
so it'll map area paths to tags so if
you had an idea path that was seven deep
you would end up with seven tags one for
each of the things just allows your way
to categorize that and save that work I
note that we don't migrate any code
using this tool there are no good
options for TFB C team foundation
version control the original TFS version
control system and there is the TFS
integration tools which is not supported
there's a number of other tools out
there as well and I would recommend
doing the using git TFS a tool to
migrate your TF BC code into M git repos
that's what I would recommend get out of
TF BC moving to get get is really easy
to migrate you just clone the repo from
the source location and push it to the
target location that it just works out
of the box and we do I did mention
earlier that those are while we are
processing work items if the git repo
has been moved across first then the
tool will it fix up the the git commit
links on the fly so in as your DevOps
and TFS you can link from I get commit
to a work item by tagging it
so hash 1:21 will link work quite work
item 1:21 and and you can link to pull
requests so your pull request links will
disappear because we can't migrate pull
requests but your git commit links will
be fixed on the work item site so it
will not be fixed in the comment of the
commit because it's it's a totally
different exercise to go to go do that
but when the work item is created and
the links are added and it will go and
see if it can find the git repo in the
new location if it can find the get repo
in the new location it will fix your
link so that it points to the right
commit and I note that there is a way in
the tool to map and your get repos if
you've renamed them and if they're the
same name then that's super easy you
don't need to do any any mapping and it
will just find it and you can run this
and after using the fixed commit a fixed
git commit obsolete
processor so you can run it on its own
and but it's better to run it as part of
the whole thing builds and releases
don't get migrated automatically and you
will need to export and import each of
your builds each of your releases and
and then all of the secrets that are
part of that will need to be read and
that's just an exercise in going through
them all and doing that there's not a
good way to do that I if you are open to
working on that you could
very easily build a processor that could
do that we just haven't had the occasion
to do that yet I know aren't
contributing we are happy to take any
contributions that you have as long as
they're relevant for everybody rather
than just for your organization and
there is no official support for the
azure DevOps migration tools
apart from community support because
this is an open source project and I am
happy to help folks out if they're
having trouble and if you have
significant trouble and then that may be
something that's more related to a
consulting engagement rather than just
at me pointing out where where where the
configuration needs to be customized and
ultimately if it's gonna take me an hour
to solve the problem then I'm good maybe
help you right and if it's going to take
three days to solve the problem then we
might like to have a conversation and
there are other contributors to the
project who are also happy to help
there are many conf users we've had over
40 contributors go look up any
contributor you want have them help you
out we're going to add some more
recommendations here so that you've got
somewhere to start and I'm definitely
got two more folks that are going to end
up on that list very very quickly so let
me jump into how you use and interact
for the tool the first thing I recommend
and I do a lot of migrations between
Azure DevOps and Azure DevOps and that's
mainly for customers that have sold part
of their organization or and they want
to merge many team projects into one
project or they want to split a project
into more than one project that's that
works as well so the easiest way to do
that is to run the tool on a machine
that has access to both environments you
want to migrate to so I don't generally
recommend running it on your local
machine
mainly because
your local machine gets turned off at
the end of the day and you want to go
home and migrations might take a lot
longer than that
so I recommend and especially if all of
your target and source environments are
in Azure that you create in Azure and a
dev test lab and the reason I suggest
the dev test lab is because it can
automatically turn the machines off and
on as needed so I'm just gonna create a
new dev test lab so create that so I'm
going to leave auto shutdown enabled you
want to use the location and of your
both hopefully both your source on the
target are in the same location and if
not I recommend creating this in the
same data center as your target
environment because we're going to be
doing a lot more communicating with the
target environment than we are with the
source environment because we just load
all the work items and then run against
the target and so in order to see where
that is if you open up your organization
go to organization settings and you will
see on the overview page the region and
this one is in West Europe so I'm going
to create that in West Europe which is
my default because that's where I am
right now I'm gonna create that okay
okay
once your azure DevOps that lab has been
created you need to create a machine
inside that a virtual machine I'm going
to add a virtual machine and I've had a
lot of trouble with the Windows 10
versions of if so if I type in
I've had a lot of problems with the the
on Windows 10 at once they basically had
not been starting I don't know if that's
fixed so I'm not gonna do that just now
so I'm just gonna pick Visual Studio to
a nineteen enterprise on Windows Server
2019 so I migration I'm just gonna put
in a password well I can do that have to
look for that later so let me copy that
into notepad so I don't have to show you
all of my passwords there we go you are
quite welcome to steal back because I
woke up deleted this machine at the end
of the video I'm not gonna use the
standard e3 because it is tiny I'm gonna
map that too and I want at least four
processors there's four processors 16
Giga RAM so a d4 sp3 I'm generally I
have the auto off set true so that at
the end of every every day like maybe 7
o'clock every day the machine turns off
and shuts down when I do the actual
migration I'll turn that off and then
I'll go turn it back on again and after
the migration is completed so I'm gonna
use premium SSDs as well so this would
be an expensive machine if it was
running for a long period of time and
I'm not gonna setup any of this because
sometimes it doesn't work so well and
I'm going to create that machine
okay so once your machine has been
created and it's running
we just need to log into it so let me do
that
there's my password that we set up yes
okay so now that we are into the machine
and I will still give it a few seconds
before I try and start clicking stuff
for it to get organized no we do not
want it to be discoverable thank you
very much it will start a bunch of
default stuff that I'm not really that
interested in let me get rid of that
there we go
okay so I have visual studio I have all
the bits I need installed unfortunately
I have to use IE because it is server so
the first thing I want to do is I need
to install the tool from chocolaty
whatever's so first thing I'm going to
do is install chocolaty this is very
easy to do copy the script open
PowerShell in admin mode oh well that's
paste in my password there we go
yes although access now I've got it and
that will install chocolaty on my
machine
chocolate is a package manager so it's
basically going to handle the install
and uninstall of the tools so that's it
all set up so if I validate that it's
working there we go so working okay so
now if I go back to the first page so in
order to install our tools there's your
DevOps migration tools we just need to
type
yes yes always all artists into the clan
line and that will go and download the
bits needed to install it including any
dependencies which there shouldn't
actually be any dependencies which is
pretty good because we're running on a
machine with fields to do installed
there we go it's all been installed so
now you will find in your C Drive
there's a tools folder in that tools
folder there's a VST s sync migration
folder so if I go in there you'll see
there's loads of files but the main one
is the migration dot exe so we're gonna
call migration DXE in order to set this
all up so let me kill ye because we
don't need to IE anymore let me show you
what's going on and then we'll move some
stuff to a folder that makes it easier
for us to see so tools migration and
does a lot of a lot of stuff in there
the first thing we need to do is create
a template at migration file so if you
run there we go oh let's go one back
migration exe and we type in it
it will create a simple work item
tracking based file so if I go up here I
may need to refresh configuration here
so let me let's open a new folder and
pop that just onto the temporary storage
there we go you
there we go so we have our JSON file
there now this file is just work items
so if I just do top work films here we
go
and we can take a look at the conflict
file and see what is what so this is the
first time visual studio has been
started on this machine so it may take a
minute or so I guess while we're waiting
I can open a notepad and we can take a
look while it's loading so what I've
done is I've created our default file
I'm gonna go through some of the options
in the files so that you can um see what
is in here now maybe later
you like the dark theme okay that's the
first thing is it has a version this
matches the version of the to at least
the first two digits of the version and
its purpose is to make sure we don't
accidentally run a car an old con fake
against the new version of the tool and
see if there's a new version of the tool
and it changes a major version check for
any different season maybe update this
the two will not run if you're using an
older version of the config file but it
might just be a case of changing not
three four four and then everything's
good ah telemetry trace is by default
set to false really don't don't turn
this on this can be used for some debug
scenarios and it will push all of the
telemetry out to application insights so
you don't want to do that by default and
the the base set of metrics are sent to
a pin sites so we'll say how many work
items have been processed how long
they're taking
exceptions those kind of things are
passed to up insights if you enable the
trace then every thing that you see
going past on the command line screen
will also be sent to a pin site so you
don't want to do that unless you you're
working with one of the consultants who
has access to app insights and you want
to UM have a have a discussion around
some of the telemetry or try something
push some things out ah this was a
workaround for the azure DevOps team
breaking the api's should by default we
set to false we just haven't removed it
yet and then the two really important
things are the source and the target so
source and target both are the same
format and you've got the collection so
what is the URL of the collection that
you're connecting to so that could be
the TFS connection URL or the azure
DevOps connection URL or the name of the
project inside of that it goes under
name and the reflected work item ID
field name is the name of the field that
you've added to that project into the
process where we're going to store the
reflective work item ID now if it's TFS
you get to set the whole thing if it
says your dev ops when you create a new
field you only get to set this bit on
the end and it used to be if you've
added this to an older process it will
be processed name dot and but if you go
add one just now to Azure DevOps it will
be custom don't um I don't know why they
changed it or how that's meant to be
documented but it just is you can use
there is a tool to export processes that
you can use even the the inherited
processes you can export that and then
go look at what the fields been called
but generally it's one of those two
things
it's either whatever you've said it as
if you're in TFS if you have an XML
process in
your DevOps then it will be the same and
if you have an inherited process and
it's an old process then it might be
called my process name dot reflected
work item ID if not it's if it's newer
it's just custom oh so you may just need
there's only three possibilities so you
could just do trial and error and the
tool will check to make sure that what
you've typed in there is valid so that's
pretty good
the field maps is empty you don't need
to add any field maps by default the
tool will map same field name to same
field name or same field ref to same
field ref if you want to change any of
the data on the fly on the way across
then you would need to setup field maps
but this is just the easy setup and work
item type definition now does not need
to contain anything it can be empty but
if you have for example in the source if
you're using user story and in the
target you're using for a backlog item
then you would fill those differences
out in here otherwise it will just
process and all the existing ones and I
mentioned before the the git repo
mapping so if you need to map get people
names from old name to new name a new
location then that would be in here as
well again in this case it is null so
then we come to the processors there are
two processors oh let's go to the color
coded version now we get to the
processors and there are two processors
set up here for us to see the first one
is the node structure migration config
this will migrate your areas and
iteration paths across you can set base
paths if you want to filter that but
please note that if you try and save a
work item when you're doing the work
item migration to an idiopathic
not exist there will be an error
generated and the thing will bomb out
the area paths need to exist so what I
normally do is just set this to empty
you don't need to have any base paths at
all and it will just migrate all of your
work items if there are no bats all of
your area and iteration passes there are
no base paths present there is one
feature on here and actually needs to be
consistent across all of the processors
that you run if you're going to use it
and that's prefix project two nodes
which means that it is going to if you
had a team project one and you were
migrating it into team project to and
you wanted team project two to have an
area path of team project one with all
of the team project one area paths
underneath it then it would do that this
is a feature for if you're merging team
projects so if I have team project one
two three and four that are all merging
into team project five team project five
will have root area paths of team
project one two three and four under
that of the work items all the data and
so that you're not just merging it
together into a big mess and you can
take some action afterwards to clean it
up and figure out what are those dupes
and all that kind of thing
generally you want their set to OFF
unless you're doing a team project
marriage and even then you need to make
that choice all right so this one needs
nord structures needs to be run first in
order to have that work you've then got
a work item migration config the work
item migration config that sets up the
migration for the work items processors
are set to false by default so nothing
will happen if you run it I generally
run them one at a time
to make sure everything's good so you
can set that enabled to true and and
then there's a number of things that you
might want to have so first off you've
got the prefix project two nodes again
set to false it must be consistent
across the project you've got so got the
update created date and
they created by in most cases this
should be set to true which is why
that's the default and if you're having
a problem because you are a particular
version of TFS that does not allow you
to edit the created date or created by
you can turn these to false
update source reflected ID it should be
set to false it's set to true or a
little fix that the default should be
false this will actually also go and
edit the source work item with the
reflected work item ID of the new
location we're doing away with this
feature because there's no point in
editing the the source if there's
another way to do it and I figured out
another way to do it if you're replaying
revisions you do not need build field
table so if you're just doing a tip
migration then you want to set this to
true and it will build a field of all
build a table of all the existing fields
in the source work item and save it into
the comments of the new york item so
that you can at least go and search for
any old data that might not have been
migrated across into fields and then
there's a signature which you can set to
or false we'll probably get rid of this
but it's set to false just now so that
brings us to the replay revisions replay
revisions will either replay each of the
changes made to a work item if it's set
to true or it will just take the latest
tip of the work item if set to false if
you're doing a sync
ie there's been changes made since the
last revision change and it actually
filters the list based on and the exact
date time of the save so you'll have
maybe ten revisions and the first thing
as it does is it looks at the target
work item and takes out all of the
identical updated dates and times out of
the the list and then picks the top one
if we play revisions are set to false
and we plays them if it's set to true so
that's
just that's how that part works and the
way it knows which work items the Lord
is you have a query bit and generally
you can't have more than 20,000 work
items as the result of a query so you
may need to stage this if you have more
than 20,000 work items and you never
want to migrate test Suites and plants
there may be other work item types that
you don't want to migrate so you can add
them to that not enlist and what I
generally do is I focus the initial
migration on the open work items so the
ones where closed date is not set to
anything and then I will rerun it again
with the opposite being true with cause
date populated to fill out all the the
closed items that way people can move
over and start working in the new system
and everything's hunky-dory and there's
the order bit from the query I usually
do change date and so that it goes from
latest change date to oldest so the most
recently touched work items are updated
first and then it gets into the past
where it's less likely to cause a
problem and then while it's migrating
each work item there are a number of
features that one is the link migrator
but by default should be true and this
will attempt to add all of the existing
links so it's going to add all of the
different link types
apart from pull request links because we
can't migrate pull requests and this
will migrate all of the attachments you
can you will need to pass it a temporary
folder for the working path where it's
going to download and upload the
attachments the default should suffice
on 99% of systems it will clean up
itself afterwards there may be some
things left over when it can't delete
folders because files are still in use
but it will generally clean up after
itself and then the fix HTML attachment
that links is for in HTML fields you can
paste an image that image has an
absolute path
to the file and that will not work in
the new system when the old system was
offline unfortunately that's not working
just now we have some authentication
issues with that but what it's supposed
to do is pool basically download each of
the attachments add it as an attachment
to the work items you'll have extra
attachments and then insert the the
replace they let fix the links for you
again it doesn't doesn't work just now
we've got authentication issues with
that communication we'll get it fixed at
some point there's a number of people
who are who are looking at that you
occasionally get errors just
communicating towards your DevOps and if
you're migrating 30,000 work items with
a hundred revisions each and a bunch of
attachments and links you're going to be
hitting the usurer DevOps API is pretty
heavily you're probably going to get
slowed down and occasionally that system
will glitch it's on the Internet
it could be for any reason between your
your environments and so there's a reach
automatic retry and it will wait if it
gets our 503 which is a server
unavailable exception it will wait for
one second then retry then wait for two
seconds and retry all the way up to 5
seconds and then retry and if it fills
out the fifth attempt it the tool will
stop cool so that's what it is i don't
recommend making that number that much
higher but if you said 215 the last one
will be waiting 15 seconds and then we
trying as well this is a really
important one filter work items that
already exist in the target there is a
mutually exclusive nature here that I
need to mention so what it will do is it
will M using the same query bit okay
it's going to load the source work items
load the target work items and
remove any target work items from the
source list that already exists and so
if you're trying to sync things that
have been changed that are newer that
will not work because it will filter
them all out because they already exist
by default you want this set to true
because if you're migrating 30,000 work
items and it got cheese after 5,000 you
don't want to skip or have to Lord and
skip over each of those 5,000 work items
so that will filter those out and so I
recommend getting a full run with this
enabled and then using a date based
query so see if your close date and I
would do a full migration and then do
cheat me spell it right change date and
have that set to greater than date of
migration so let's say it was 2019 1016
because we start the migration yesterday
it's finished and now I want to rerun
anything that was changed after we
started the migration and you would need
to start with the date of the migration
because you can't put tines in there and
that that will work super awesome and
then it will just go and pull the 300
work items that were changed yesterday
and today and Rioch date them and but
you would need to change this to false
so that you can migrate and it will skip
anything that doesn't need any changes
but it will need to do a bunch of stuff
around that which is why you want this
generally set true okay that was a brief
overview of the azure DevOps migration
tools let me know if you have any issues
on github create an issue on github and
somebody will help you
[Music]