there's a myth in scrum that you spend
more time talking than doing I see this
quite a lot people talking usually
people are using old school terminology
when you hear them talking about that
you hear them talking about ceremonies
right rather than events and one of the
main reasons why scrum doesn't call the
the activity the events ceremonies is
because it's ceremonies we get together
and nothing happens it's a ceremony it's
something we do that's perhaps the same
every time and there's no actual outcome
to a ceremony apart from maybe people
have some jollies and they feel good
right um the reason scrum calls them
events and also not meetings the reason
they're called events is something's
supposed to to happen
there every single one of the scrum
events serves
empiricism that's their purpose right
you're going to inspect something and
adapt
something if you're not
adapting there's no point in being there
there's no point in having it there's no
point in doing it their purpose is to
adapt so for example at your Sprint
planning you're inspecting your product
backlog and your product goal and you're
adapting your Sprint back clog in your
Sprint goal you that emerges through
that con perhaps through that
conversation right but at the end of
your Sprint planning you should have a
Sprint
goal you should have selected backlog
items what do the developers think best
serves work working towards the product
goal and you should have some kind of a
starter plan to complete them if those
three things don't exist at the end of
Sprint planning there was no point in
having it that's what it's there for so
that we understand what it is we're
going to take into the next Sprint so
that we can communicate that perhaps
with other people what's our goal for
this Sprint what are we trying to
achieve how do you get the stakeholders
to actually turn up for the Sprint
review well you have to give them
something that they're interested in
coming and Fe providing feedback on
that's your Sprint goal right and that's
just one of the events in scrum every
sing your daily scrum it's only 15
minutes how does that add up to a
boatload of meetings at most 15 minutes
per day where the team gets together and
plans the next 24 hours that's its
purpose you're inspecting your exist
Sprint back
clog and you're adapting that Sprint
back clog based on what you learned in
the last 24 hours you might have learned
some stuff from actually working on the
product what can and cannot be done you
might have uh uh gained more information
and insight from other stakeholders and
collaborating with the business and
doing analysis on what it is you're
going to work on that means that
something that you've got in the Sprint
needs to be taken out because it's no
longer viable or something else needs to
be brought in in because it becomes part
of that that story of what it is you're
trying to achieve that
Sprint that's your daily
scrum right it's not an elaborate status
event it's not a time that you're
wasting it's where you're maintaining
the transparency that is required to be
able to inspect and adapt you're serving
empiricism and all of the scrum events
serve empiricism thanks for watching the
video if you would enjoyed it please
like follow And subscribe I always reply
to comments and if you want to have a
chat about this or anything else agile
scrum or devops then please book a
coffee with me through naked
agility