[Music]
most product
owners or people that have been given
the role or accountability of product
owner don't really comprehend the the
the bread of the product owner role and
it's generally sold to them or told to
them as being focused on um creating a
product backlog and making the team work
through it um and that's a very small
part of of a product owner um a product
owner is really an agile product manager
right they're a product manager that has
a bunch of additional skills and
understandings um that that are
encapsulated a little bit in the
accountability of the product owner in
scrum um and it it's really important
that um product
owners understand the breadth of the
possibilities of the product owner role
what it is they're supposed to be
looking at um and I I I find that the
quite often Mo most people who come to a
product owner class um realize that they
don't want to be product owners because
it's a lot bigger role with more actual
accountability um than they really
realized that it was it it was in the
first place um so a product owner is
accountable for spending the
money right that a product owner is
accountable for that if you even if as a
product owner you only have control over
ordering that product backlog right
maybe you can't even delete stuff from
the product backlog maybe you can't add
new stuff that you come up with yourself
but you're just ordering that product
backlog then you're controlling the
budget you're deciding when we deliver
each piece of functionality um and that
that's that's really powerful if you can
then gain the ability to remove and add
things to the product backlog you're
then going to be hopefully more
effectively spending that budget um and
for a product owner that that means a
lot of things right what what do you
think a product owner in order to
maximize the value of the work done
right so we're going to put stuff in the
product backlog team's going to work
through it maximize the value of that
work um what do we need to look at what
information do we need and what what
controls and levers do we need to be
able to have those conversations because
it's it's not just about focusing on the
backlog and the team it's not just about
being a a funnel for the the um requests
from the organization right it's about
making decisions it's about placing bets
it's about looking at probabilities of
what's what do we think is the most
effective uh uh thing to work on what's
going to produce the most value now um
for the organization or the most
long-term value depending on your your
your timelines and topics that you're
you're thinking of delivering in the
product so as a product owner you really
need to be looking out into the future
you need to be looking at what's
happening in the business what's the
trend in the market how do I um get to
where I need to be in order that instead
of me looking at my competitors and
saying oo that's cool functionality we
should add that that they're looking at
my features and they want to add and
follow my Trend that I'm setting for
features and capabilities in the market
effectively shifting your product from
following the market to Leading the
market and in order to do that you need
a clear picture of of a lot of
information you need access to levers
within the organization to be able to um
change what you're working on based on
those needs and that understanding right
what's the next bet what's the next uh
uh hypothesis that you have for
something that you think is going to
provide value and can you invest in it
and that takes a lot of building
relationships understanding uh uh the
the the business in the market that lots
of people don't don't understand as part
of the product owner role so if you want
to be a product owner just coming to a
training class is not going to help you
be the best product owner okay but a
training class is going to help broaden
the scope of your understanding of what
that role is and what are the different
tools and techniques that you can at
least start with to start investing in
some of those areas that perhaps you're
missing that the value of coming to a
product owner class if you want to have
a discussion about your unique needs or
situation then please book a call or
visit us at naked agility tocom uh we
also have our immersive and traditional
public classes on our website and we'd
love to hear from you