a a blog post that I read years ago and
it started with the phrase if you're
reading this you're already in the top
10% and that's because there's only a
small number of uh people that actually
focus on continuous learning that
actually try new things all the time
that are actually reading up on
different techniques and different
topics they don't have to be new they
can just be new to you they can be older
things that you're going and figuring
out crossing the chasm was written in
the 80s right what are the things that
you're reading how do you enable
yourself to be in the top 10% because
that's how you maximize your chances of
getting the best gigs right is you need
to be in the top 10% and if all you need
to do to do that is read some blog posts
every week maybe a couple of books a
month that's not a high bar