the question is how is technology like
AI changing the world that we work in
and I think this we're kind of on the
cusp of one of one of those big uh
revolutionary rather than evolutionary
changes in the way way that we work
um AI isn't going to
um
do your job for you right but AI is a
very powerful tool as a sidekick or
co-pilot for you as uh somebody who's
doing doing things right
um for example I I use it quite a lot
when I want to come up with ideas on a
particular topic and I'll ask it to
generate some ideas on a particular
topic it will make the ideas and then
I'm going to go write stuff around those
ideas but it makes me much more
effective I don't know if you've ever
sat and stared at a blank page for ages
trying to figure out how do I start or
you get to a bit of your your your your
thing that you're trying to talk about
and you're like ah ah how do I how do I
go from here and you can effectively
take what you've written so far feed it
into a chat GTP and see what might be
next and it will come up with something
for you and they may come up with
something that's crap right it's totally
uh totally might do that but then you
are still the author right you're still
the one in control it's just the
co-pilot making suggestions for you and
it hopefully will twig twig that that
memory or that that thing you want to
talk about
and I do find it particularly useful
once I've written something to say oh
and create me a lead for LinkedIn
for this for this for this post and it
will go create uh those those things for
you it's it's really quick to to get
started and do things so to tie that
back to that idea of how it will change
the way we work it it will make us
um more productive and more capable
right as an individual
who adopts some of these AI tools we
become more capable at our jobs we
become more productive at our jobs we're
able to do more things more quickly
um less wasted time right you should you
should never again have to uh copy stuff
from one spreadsheet to another or uh
create uh forms in in you know you want
to take a spreadsheet and you want to
analyze the data AI will will build the
the bits for you and then you can then
write your analysis around it all of
these productivity tools are going to
um mean that you as somebody who adopts
AI are going to be far more effective
um at your job than your colleagues who
do not
um so I would say adopt AI bring it into
the way you're working as soon as you
possibly can even if you're just
tinkering with it uh go go get a course
on uh prompt prompt engineering or uh
find some stuff content to absorb and
figure out how you might use this
technology in your job because it is
going to revolutionize uh the way we we
work and hopefully for organizations
that adopt it wholesale it's going to
revolutionize their ability to compete
in the markets that they compete in by
them being able to adapt to changing
changing demands of the market much more
quickly than their competitors this is a
tool it's going to help us enormously in
figuring stuff out and that's how it's
going to change the way that we work
it's going to change every Vestige of it
and get on board or be left behind
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility