[Music]
this workshop is for practitioners that
are interested in starting a career as a
scrum master existing scrum masters
agile coaches and consultants
trying to improve their use of scrap
the professional scrum master is an
engaging enjoyable learning experience
where students gain a deep understanding
of scrum theory and principles
scrum master accountabilities and why
each element of the scrum framework is
important
our training is delivered as an
interactive activity-based course over
half-day sessions using microsoft teams
and mural
between sessions we provide additional
reading writing and watching activities
to maximize the learning opportunities
and complement the classroom experience
after the conclusion of the class we
provide access to a community of peers
and continued access to the trainer
through office hours quarterly catch-ups
and constant engagement
to maximize validated learning all
students are provided with a password to
take psm one assessment and if they take
it within 14 days and are unsuccessful
they will be granted a second attempt
[Music]