question is where is consensus valuable
where does it kill great product
development
and I think that's that's a that's a
really interesting topic consensus just
means general agreement
right that everybody generally agrees
and sometimes
getting to agreement is the Right Way
Forward
but also
conversely sometimes making a decision
is is is the right answer
but trying to split that
and figure out how
in what circumstances you want to make a
decision based on consensus and what
circumstance you want to make a decision
based on you know we're making a
decision and we're going this direction
it's something that is
um very much at the heart of of the
complexity being a product owner right
if you think about the product owner as
a as a mini CEO or an entrepreneur right
um we're we're perhaps operating
in a in a highly Dynamic highly volatile
Market
and things can change quite quick
and sometimes if we want to take
advantage of opportunities that are
floating by
we need to just make a decision and go
for it and as long as we're oh what
what's the I usually an organization is
generally an organization is willing to
make a financial bet on seven percent
success right that's that's the general
it's a good bet if it's 70 as a success
it's a bad benefits it's less than that
but people that are entrepreneurs
tend to accept a much higher degree of
risk than that 70 right there there that
70 is like bricks and mortar
organization that that's that's that's
uh what they look at and other Financial
departments
but for an entrepreneur you you see an
opportunity
and you have a you have a gut feel right
and usually it's not really a gut feel
right it's based on your experience and
the data that you've got and you're
making a call but yes I'm going to
invest in this in this in this idea
um
but if you've familiar with
startups
um
50 of all startups fail in the first
year
and 70 of the rest fail in the first
five years
so you've actually got a really small
chance of success from being an
entrepreneur
so to be that entrepreneur you have to
be continually
making making decisions trying stuff
failing making stuff trying to stop
failing what was the what's the the bad
Edison quote I know it's a bad quote he
didn't I don't know I'm sure he 100 said
this but the the cut the consensus quote
right that is probably wrong is that um
he said uh I didn't figure out how to
make a light bulb I found 99 ways you
can make light but right because it took
a hundred tries at something to get that
one thing that worked 99 things
um so so that that's the mind of the
entrepreneur that's the difference
between a a big organization CEO and an
entrepreneur is the amount of risk
they're willing to accept
in in in the Endeavors that they're
trying to trying to achieve yeah look at
Elon Musk buying Twitter right that's uh
that's a really high high risk of
potential failure but if you disrupt
enough and change enough and keep
changing until you get to those ideas
that's that entrepreneurial mindset
so that that in the product owner as an
entrepreneur can work at the small scale
as well as the the bigger scale if you
look in the the scrum guide right
um it's quite explicitly says Everybody
Must uh respect
um the the product order right the the
product owners decisions that they made
and part of that is because sometimes we
have to move quickly that's one
sometimes we just have to try stuff even
if we're not 100 sure it's going to be
successful so you might be making a
decision to try something even though
lots of other people think it's a bad
idea right
um and
that that's that's that's where
you you have that piece of it's it's not
about consensus it's about just making
the decision and moving forward
but on the other side of that you've got
the times when you when you do want to
get consensus
um because it's very difficult
to it's very difficult to do stuff
when the people that you need help from
to do stuff
believe you're wrong right if they
believe you're wrong
they're not gonna help
right or entrepreneurs kind of sidestep
that by
um
building a group of people around them
that are supportive of their vision
so that when they do have to make
decisions that people are like really
we're gonna go that way
oh you know uh uh Leslie the the CEO the
entrepreneur Leslie's like yeah this is
the way we're going they're like okay we
trust you we're gonna we're gonna move
forward and go anyway right that's how
they get support for that so you've got
people that support you so that's not
really consensus but it kind of is it's
that other type of consensus where it's
lead consensus right
but you have another type of consensus
where you you and this is more
facilitation idea of of of of consensus
or at least convergence right it doesn't
have to be consensus but it's
convergence and that facilitation idea
and I don't mean just a facilitator
right this could be the product owner
this could be the scrum Master this
could be a team member this could be in
a video you're you're
trying to
um um brainstorm ideas for your family
vacation right it doesn't doesn't matter
what it what it is but you have this
this uh um initial expansion of ideas
right when you ask a group of people how
might we solve this problem
we're gonna generate hopefully right
lots and lots and lots and lots of ideas
so we get this big buildup of idea and
then you want to get to what's the thing
we're gonna try what's the thing we're
gonna do
but there might have been 15 different
options
how do we not only get to the thing we
want to try
but gain
a moratorium of consensus so that
everybody's behind the thing because if
people aren't behind something it ain't
gonna happen no matter how how awesome
it is it's not gonna happen if the
people are not are not behind it that's
that's why that's why I feel a lot of
projects fail is that that there's no
attempt to get people behind it they're
just told what to do so you end up with
those I don't know if you remember and
the old old traditional days you had
death march projects and a death march
project is where every single person
that's working on it knows that it's not
gonna work right they know in their
bones that it's not gonna work so what
happens it doesn't work right but
somebody thinks it will work and keeps
going towards it spending the money but
nothing happens you want to avoid that
and I think the the the this this
building to consensus is getting
everybody behind the idea even if they
don't necessarily think it's the best
idea right that's that's for me is
building consensus around that that
story so this this
to get back to the original question
right where is consensus valuable and
where does it kill a great product
development it doesn't it's always
valuable but how you achieve it is
different depending on your circumstance
if you're the CEO you gain consensus by
creating an environment where everybody
trusts your decisions they're far
they're willing to go along with and are
happy with your decisions because they
know the chances of you being successful
are fairly High because you've built a
level of trust with them that's
consensus through leadership but then
you've got also got consensus through
um collaboration right we're
collaborating together as a group
um we want to generate this is usually
on the macro scale the the CEO is making
the decisions on the big on the on the
macro scale and then on the micro scale
you've got lots of little decisions that
have to be made by the team lots of
things to try lots of things to do and
you need those ideas and then consensus
and you have to navigate that growing
zone in the middle right that's usually
what it's called the drone zone where
where stuff's just you know nobody
agrees on anything and you have to as a
good facilitator
even the CEO has to do this has to
figure out we're going to generate a
bunch of ideas and then I have to get it
down to what it is we're going to try
that everybody's willing to get behind
I've had more census behind so that it
moves forward and it has the possibility
of being successful
so I think I think consensus is
absolutely imperative
to all aspects of product development
but there are different routes to
achieving it depending on the
circumstance right you might have fast
moving stuff where you have to make
decisions and people trust you
but how do you build that trust in the
first place well you have to do all this
other stuff to gain consensus in the
other way that people I you know you get
them behind it because you get them to
agree to be behind it even if they don't
think it's the best idea and then oh wow
that was successful you just gained
credibility to then make a decision and
have people people support it
so I think um
it is absolutely imperative but it's
also important
um
to think about
I really recommend there's a book
um Mike Voss book
um called Never split the difference
right
um and I think that's our that's a
fantastic
um story about
how you create that
where are we going
without needing to have a bunch of
people that are unhappy with the outcome
right so the way I think his his little
description is that
um whether you're negotiating because
it's all a negotiation right
collaboration whether you're negotiating
with uh terrorists for hostage release
or you're negotiating with at bedtime
for kids right it doesn't matter the
same rules and techniques apply right
you're trying to get that consensus that
yes this is the right way forward yes
you should go to bed now but if they're
unhappy you know they'll go into their
bedroom and they'll go under the covers
and get the flashlight out and they'll
read their book anyway right or or
whatever whatever it is they'll try to
uh get get not do the thing
so building that consensus is absolutely
imperative but I really recommend never
split difference I recommend uh um
looking at facilitation techniques for
navigating that growing zone to get
consensus and also another awesome book
thinking in bits for those entrepreneurs
uh right you you Building Products is
like playing poker right you don't have
all of the information all the time but
you still have to make decisions so how
do you navigate that data analysis and
then make the best decision possible
based on the information that you have
and being consensus along the way
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility