so the initial response to the immersive
learning has been
incredibly positive almost every single
pair I can't think of anybody I've
spoken to that have said uh well that
sounds like it sucks I'd rather do a
two-day class or nobody said that
everybody
detests uh at the full today uh
full-time two-day workshop I I don't
know I don't know why we kept doing it
for so long actually I do know why we
kept doing it for so long it's because
we insisted on trainers going on site to
do it which means that you have to do it
in a short period of time because the
company that you work for doesn't want
to pay for me in a hotel for six weeks
uh and all all the stuff that that
entails in order to be able to deliver a
six week Workshop right
um so we need to compress it into a
short period of time now in the virtual
space we're free to experiment with
different formats different ways of
engaging with students and it's really
resonating with the people
um that are thinking about taking the
class or or wanting to be part of it and
we've already had uh customers express
interest we've had customers buy onto
especially the pspo has been hugely
popular because they're really
interested in that continuous
development right that conversation that
you have over a longer period of time so
that you're not just
here's a bunch of content
bye that's it that's that's a two-day
class right this is this is uh more
here's here's a bunch of here's a little
bit of content
and here's something to try in your
business
go try it come back next week and let's
have a chat about it how did you get on
how did it work what happened and that
piece
businesses especially small to
medium-sized businesses
really see that Value Extra Value that
they get for it
for really not that much extra cost
right
um it's it's spreading that out over a
longer period of Time closing those
feedback loops uh getting people really
embedded embedding those ideas not oh my
favorite expression
um
that actually uh uh uh uh one of my good
friends Jim uh mentioned is that
um a job as a trainer is to plant seeds
right seeds of ideas that are then going
to grow into something
and one of the problems with the two-day
format is you're planting a whole bunch
of seeds and you don't know what's going
to grow and nobody's coming back to
water those seeds or care for them right
that's just self-service you've seeds
are on your own figuring out how to how
to how to expand that whereas this
format is the gardeners coming back
tending all of the the different plants
the different seeds you know if these
plants in this area aren't getting
enough water they can spend more time on
that and that really gets those thought
processes going I'm really looking
forward to to these immersive classes
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility