when when you're you're migrating data
around in as your devops there are a
100,000 things that can go wrong uh
there's some really big things that
people run
into um if you're
using the Azure
devops data migration service um that
Microsoft provides to take your whole
collection up um big things are we're on
an older version of TFS that's not
supported that's one um I I did one
recently and discovered during the the
discovery that the customer still had
visual Source safe right so we had to do
a visual Source safe import first visual
Source safe I think went end of life in
2005 maybe 2005 so it was stuff that
been around for a long time um so we had
to bring that in first and then because
if you don't bring it in first first and
you try and upgrade your TFS first um
the vsss import is was only supported up
to TFS
2015 because after that it's 10 years
after vsss was end of life so Microsoft
stopped having that functionality in TFS
so if you don't bring it in before that
you can't bring it in not with full
history and all of the the the things
they discontinued those tools so you
that one of the most most common issues
that people run into when they're doing
migrations is doing things in the wrong
order um and that's over a variety of
different contexts if you push up to as
your devops and you've done things in
the wrong order uh you might have want
to do process template changes you want
to do them on Prem before you push them
up you might want to bring in other
source control stuff you need to do that
before you take it up um you might want
to move from
tfvc Team Foundation Version Control to
get you probably want to do that before
you move up but you can probably get
away with it that one you can probably
get away with um but if you the the
probably the biggest one this is the one
that's um there's there's absolutely no
way back from W I guess the vsss
stuff as well but the one that is
absolutely no way back from is is is
account account
alignment okay
this is this is just mental so the way
TFS
does
identity is TFS has an identity and it
wraps whatever the actual identity is so
in the old days this was either a workg
group account if you're familiar with
Windows authentication it's either a
work group account or it was an active
directory account right so the issue is
that if you take a work group and then
move it into a domain joint environment
and convert it to a domain joined but
the accounts don't match up right so TFS
will automatically when you move between
environments it will try and find the
account that matches the one that
already exists and just swap out the the
bit inside of the TFS identity but if it
can't find it it and it's already added
to the systems it will create a new
identity so you'll end up with two TFS
identities so if you've got Bob in your
company and Bob has the old TFS identity
and the new TFS identity when he logs
into TFS and he searches for show me all
work that's assigned to me he won't find
anything because it's assigned to Old
Bob not new Bob old identity Bob not new
identity Bob um and that's an order of
operations issue um and it's really hard
in active directory and a your active
directory because quite often there's
groups and things that that add people
into Services before you want them to be
added and then you end up with this
problem so as your devops kind of
combats that a little bit that when you
move stuff around because even even once
you're in is your devops you can move
from tenant a to tenant B right um so
you're Microsoft inra tenant identity
management can be swapped out and it
does the same thing right but it's going
to ask you here's a list of all the
users that we couldn't match up do you
want to match them up and if you click
that skip button at the bottom which if
you have somebody who doesn't know what
they're doing people are apt to do I I
find so many times things go wrong
because people click the skip button
because they think they know what it
says or they don't care what it says or
they just want to do it or it's not
their job or whatever reason and there
is no way going back to the old way
because now you've got those both those
identities exist and there's no way to
merge those identities so if you want
everything to
align uh uh uh through through your
upgrade process then all of those things
need to be taken into account probably
the absolute worst case of
that having to be
managed um was years ago I Microsoft
sold a part of their business to another
company so we had to get it we had to
get all of this work right the the TFS
environment from inside of Microsoft to
inside of this other company
but as you can imagine with with with
legal and compliance and all kinds of
things it wasn't that easy and when you
work within a company you take
dependencies on lots of things that
maybe your company owns but then you
sell this thing and you're not selling
these things that you're taking a
dependency on so how do you how do you
get it out so I think we had seven I
think we had
seven migrations that we had to do with
this single environment um so there was
there was three
outgoing
one outside neither environment and then
three incoming into the new company and
at each of those levels there was
different validation different scripts
different things that had to be run
against those environments to ensure
that we don't lose anything and we don't
get anything we're not supposed to and
all of those kind of things and it was
absolutely horrendous nightmare of
convoluted legal ease right to get it to
get it all done um but the the biggest
issue was that maintaining those
identities all the way through cuz the
people were going as well and they
wanted all of the identities to match up
on the other side so you have to ensure
that you map all of the identities
correctly all the way through um so that
when you get to the other side people
open it up and go oh there's all my
stuff rather than oh where's all my
stuff gone right and then they have to
go find it and they have to go create
custom queries and all kinds of stuff to
to it's just a pain in the but
um
so those are some of the some of the bad
things that can happen identity
management that's that's there's a lot
of gotchas in there um database size Mo
moving up to a your devops the size of
the database and what's in there and how
you clean it up that's that's a bunch of
gotches in there if your company which
you should know developers are apt to do
um you might find that your TFS
environment has been around for a really
long time
and it didn't used to be run by your
operations team with control right it
maybe used to be run by the developers
before it was handed off to operations
before they knew that in the old
days operations often thought that
anything that developers did was
nonproduction
right even though all the code is an
organizational asset and we're storing
it in there the bill
environments and build agents are all
organizational assets because we can't
deliver our product if we don't have it
they were all considered not production
so developers could have the keys to
everything and do everything for so many
companies like that
um and the problem is that because they
can do whatever they want they go oh
there's the new beta version of TFS oh
it's supported by Microsoft so we'll
install that but it's mostly supported
by Microsoft right so I've had
environment
where it's a major Enterprise company
but in the midsts of time of that
environment it's had a beta version of
TFS deployed that was maybe supported
right way back in 10 years ago um but it
causes knock on errors because there
were a couple of things that weren't
taken care of that mean it can function
the way it is but it ain't going to is
your devops without fixing all of those
things so um there's those types of
things if your server is old enough
there's all sorts of buggy ass things
from TFS
2010 that they fixed in 2012 that if
you're servers old enough to have been
in 2010 and us these tfvc the team
Foundation version Oh there's just a
whole nightmare of stuff left over that
you have to go you have to go fix you
have to go fix it before you can go to
the go to the cloud so that's uh you can
have half committed stuff um because you
had to do two commits back in the to do
a rename but nobody told anybody and
there was no error
message so in service pack one they
brought in the error message and then in
2012 they fixed it but there's still a
bunch of stuff in there um that's that's
messed up oh so so many if you imagine a
product that's been around for 18 years
no not quite 18 years 16 where are we
was was created in 2005 shipped in
2006 man that's a long time right nearly
20 nearly two years off 20 18 18 years
right my mouth sucks 18 years of
engineering work has gone into this
product 18 years of different people
working on it 18 years of Forgotten
stuff 18 years of bodies being buried
underneath uh uh some of the the classes
and methods
and the stuff the stuff that doesn't
work the way you want it to so
those are probably where the biggest uh
difficulties are um the easy stuff the
stuff that can go right man i' like I
did mention the the migration up to
Azure devops and this was really early
on in Azure devops that took um took
less than an hour I mean this this was a
a government agency in the UK um it was
a council
so not government government but local
government and we we we ran the we
installed the latest version of TFS um
everything went fine we ran the tool
against it it said everything was good
so the database was I think a few a a
couple of gig tiny so we just sequenced
the d pack did a dry run up into as your
devops that took about 15 minutes to
less than 15 minutes and it was there
they looked at the dry run they thought
oh this looks awesome this is perfect
everything's where it's supposed to be
we see all the stuff uh we we trust
Microsoft and throw an error if right so
they were just reasonable reasonable
folks um so we just went okay would do
you want to just do the production one
then or do you want to wait and validate
it some more and they're like no just
just run the production one so we run
the production one and we're done turn
off
TFS that's that's one headache off their
plate one headache off um their there
their local admins plate oh hold on we
need to we need to go back to what's the
worst the
absolute most appalling issue with TFS
SL Azure devops server so running it on
Prem especially if you're if your
developers are running it this will be
done
right if your operations team's running
it I guarantee you it's wrong and that's
backup
so most operations teams want to use
their standardized tools so they just
see a SQL server and they want to plug
their standard Backup Tool into Aur
devop and suck out the data store it
tape off site right if they're doing
that that does not guarantee a
restore the problem with systems like
TFS it's not really a problem with TFS
it's a problem with having people that
don't know what they're doing running it
or that don't care running it right um
it's actually the same issue is for
SharePoint and a lot of other systems
but you have multiple data physical
databases inside of the system right so
when it
runs updates you could have an update
that's straddles multiple databases so
in tf's case you've got a configuration
database and then you've got a bunch of
collection databases so you can have
like an identity update for example will
hit the collection and the configuration
database and the configuration database
is small so that bit will be done really
quickly and then it needs to complete on
the
um the other one but they run it as a
transaction it's absolutely possible
to the point in time of your
backup that it's completed and committed
on one database and not completed on the
other one so we'll roll back because the
transaction has across multiple
databases and this one's finished and
it's moving on to this one and the
transaction allows you to roll back the
whole thing but not if you restore a
backup without that transaction being
his existence right mid transaction so
there are things that you're supposed to
do that are all documented by Microsoft
to enable you to do marked transaction
logs so you actually put a mark you you
use the transaction system to put a mark
across uh uh like a bookmark across all
of the databases and then you back so it
the transaction completes all of the
other transactions are completed this
transaction completes and has this Mark
and it might be at different time stamps
across the different databases right and
then you back up that Mark and then when
you restore that Mark it's exactly the
right point but most people don't do
that and they validate things by we'll
do a trial restore it's totally possible
that that restore will work probably in
most circumstances that restore will
work but you know what Murphy says
what's if the worst thing could happen
it will happen at the worst possible
time right so in an actual disaster when
you need to recover your database that's
the time when you'll hit that
transaction log and if you hit that you
are not going to be able to restore your
databases and you're going to have to
call up Microsoft and they're going to
have to have an engineer log into your
servers and
run scripts to fix the databases and
then because they've run scripts to fix
the databases that's another thing that
can end up being a future problem when
you go to move to is your devops um and
something in the database is not quite
right when they do the validation and
and it fails the the import so
um my advice is never ever let an
operations team run TFS that's that's
that's my advice if you have to let an
operations team run TFS um ensure that
they must use the TFS documented backup
procedures not their own stuff that
won't work and might end up with with
you in the in the hole
um yeah so that's that's the big one 90%
of the time things go perfectly fine
right upgrading TFS super easy it used
to be an absolute nightmare but the aure
devops team did a bunch of work to
validate everything check everything and
that's part of their ethos right so if
you run it it will tell you here's a
problem here's how you fix it you fix it
it runs and it runs you can do the
upgrade
totally cool they're super easy but when
something isn't right that's when you
need that that
expertise um to go what is the problem
how do I fix it where does it come from
the documentation awesome but there's
still those those things that slip
through the cracks so that that's really
the things there's a lot of things that
can go wrong and a lot of things that
can go wrong that are really important
but
99.9% of the time everything's going to
be fine um you're going to be able to
upgrade you're going to be able to
migrate and everything's going to going
to go go great