there's a number of migration services
that we we offer um they're kind of
related as two sets of of tools there's
there's Martin as your devops migration
tools which is uh on GitHub and
available for people to use but we help
people use it we do it for customers um
when they don't want to learn it
themselves so that's the um more
targeted migration tool so I want to
move I want to stuff I want to merge
stuff
um so that's that's that's that actual
moving individual work items around
that's what I want to do then then
that's our one of our services the other
one is a kind of managed import into
Azure devops uh Microsoft have a tool
called the Azure devops data migration
tool and that data migration tool takes
the whole thing so you might have a if
you're with how TFS I I always call on
Prem TFS and the server as your devops
just to avoid confusion right I know
they renamed the server to as your
devops but it as your devops server and
as your devops service and it's just
confusing TFS right so TFS has multiple
databases hanging off off it um and
those databases are the things that you
take and put up to to as your devop so
if you have 500 projects in one database
you're taking the whole thing thing but
you can't just take it because there are
things you could do to your TFS that are
not allowed in as your devops um there
are things that could have happened over
the years to your TFS that are not
allowed in as your devops and there are
things yeah I think I'm going to double
down on things you could have changed in
TFS that you're not allowed to do in as
your devot like increase the max
attachment size is one um there's loads
of them so Microsoft provide a bunch of
tools to validate your environment to
make sure it will work before you migr
it up and it has to meet the validation
before it will go to a your devop but
how do you do that you have to get onto
the latest version then you have to run
the tools then you have to fix all of
the stuff that it highlights and then
you've got to go so we provide a
managed um service for moving your
entire on Prem asure devop TFS
environment um code repos builds um
everything up to as your
devops um or we also provide a service
where you want to move pieces of things
within that context around and
consolidate and change process template
and you know we want to move from scrum
to Agile or our bespoke one to Agile or
our scrum one to our bespoke one all of
those if you want to do things peace
meal we can help with that if you want
to do the whole thing we help you manage
that process up to the C