one of the seven signs of the agile
apocalypse are plagues um and there are
a number of plagues but one that really
uh um kills my goat is uh tools and
process becoming sacrosanct within the
team that's a plague on agile and
Agility you can't be agile you can't
have agility if you're not willing to
continuously adapt and have your
processes practices and tools emerge
over time if you're stuck on one thing
or you're forcing people to use one way
of doing
something that I'm afraid is one of the
seven signs of the agile apocalypse
plagues thanks for watching the video If
you enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a with me through naked
agility