can your product pass the done test good
done isn't aspirational It's objective
It's measurable A strong definition of
done means the increment is tested
deployed monitored gathering telemetry
Validating or diminishing a real
business hypothesis It's not about tasks
being finished It's about outcomes being
real It's about delivering something
that works that's safe that's valuable
and that you can learn from immediately
At Naked Agility we help teams set
realworld benchmarks for excellence
because raising the bar on done raises
everything else with it Quality agility
trust time to
value Ready to define your done and
raise the bar on quality let's build
your future proof standard