so the question is do teams really
understand the power of applying scrum
professionally
this is a really hard one because I I
or contentious one because I don't think
that most teams I've ever worked with at
like professionals they act like
amateurs
um and that's not necessarily their
fault there's not a not a not a blame
there
um it's just how companies expect they
don't seem to
expect us to be professionals and do the
right thing they want us to do their
thing at whatever speed they want us to
do it at which means that we are as
Engineers as a software engineer for
many years we're encouraged to do things
the easy fast cheap way
not the right way
and that encourages unprofessional
behavior it supports unprofessional
behavior
so most most teams don't necessarily
understand what what professional
Behavior looks like even even to the
level of
um I worked with an organization a few
years ago and we did an exercise on what
requirements should look like
for the engineering team to take them on
so this was this was not the engineering
teams themselves this was the the
product management group
um and we did this exercise where where
I I love it get everybody in a room uh
break them into groups cross-functional
groups and then they have to take some
user interface from their product and
break down what the requirements they
would have liked to have
with hindsight right so they they build
these lovely detailed requirements and
how much detail and all the questions
they had to go ask and the stuff they
didn't know and they built all this
they're like holy moly that's a lot of
stuff
and then we started the second part of
the exercise which was take something
off their backlog that they don't that
they have right now that they haven't
built yet and do the same thing for it
right so they're they're trying to build
out these requirements and the head of
product management stopped us
stopped the whole whole whole workshop
and basically said that him and his team
um were not set up to be able
to do this just we're we're not
fundamentally capable
of creating and working with you to
build requirements of this level of
detail that we obviously now see this is
what you needed in the first place right
that we've never given you before
but we're not set up to do it that's
like a a moment of realization
that that professionalism is up here and
your capacity to deliver is down here
right this is where we need to be this
is where a professional product
management group is interacting
collaboratively with the team figuring
out what it is they need working up
front getting ahead of the the the curve
of the things that the teams need so
that everything's ready at the right
time and they just weren't ready for
that
and and I think that's that's true in
lots of parts of organizations not just
on teams and scrum teams and one of the
purposes of scrum
is to to make those things transparent
right you've got to try and do these
things that you're working one of the
minimum professional things that a team
any team if you have a software team
they absolutely should be able to create
usable working product every iteration
including the first that is production
ready
right that's like minimum bar for scrum
if you're not doing that if you don't
have that at the end of the Sprint
potentially shippable not ship
potentially shippable right it you're
not doing scrum yet you're just
fundamentally not at the level of
transparency that you need for a
professional scrum team and so many
teams look at that and go holy crap
we're so far away from that it's it's
it's it's it's insane
right that that is a hard place to be
and it's a hard realization not just for
the team because as the team tries to
get there they're going to realize all
the things they don't have right oh but
we don't we can't create production
ready because we've got a third party
testing team that comes in and and does
testing so how do we know that stuff
how do we know what they're going to
come up with or we submit it to oh what
did we used to do at Merrill Lynch
PWC it's also some company we used to
submit all of our websites to that would
then do a third-party penetration test
and we had no idea what tools they used
to do those painter they call it just
the pen testing cost 15 grand to do a
pen test and you would get an output of
stuff you need to go fix well it wasn't
done right the product that you created
wasn't at done wasn't ready wasn't
shippable quality because you you don't
understand those tools that they're
using you don't understand those
additional checks and you need to
so I I think
the power of applying scrum
professionally is understanding what it
takes to be professionals and create
have a professional work ethic where
we're creating something that our
customers can use that they can get
value from that they that they value
right
um and more most uh teams don't really
understand that until they start
and then they start to understand what
they don't know start to add more
capabilities in there and they
eventually get to to being professional
teams
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility