one of the five things that I would
teach a new product owner is about
Vision value and validation one of the
common things that happen in
organizations as they start to move from
focusing on Project delivery to focusing
on product management is that they um
they take out all of the things that you
think of as traditional project manager
M right that you think of as traditional
project management like the the the
milestones
and dates and Gant charts and project
plans we we take out those things cuz
they're not agile but
then most organizations don't replace
them with anything and you end up with
this vacuum in the Middle where we're
not going to do any planning we're not
going to do any forecasting we're not
going to really understand what it is
we're doing we're not going to explain
to people what it is they need to do
we're not going we're just instead of
giving them the plan we're just going to
say here's the product get on with it
and then we expect magic to happen and
that is an absolute recipe for disaster
don't do that right what you need to do
is you need to fill that vacuum and as a
new product owner this is the key part
for you to understand as well as for you
to be able to engage communicate to
other people in the organization up up
down sideways whatever it is do you
understand the vision of your product do
you understand what it's trying to
achieve if you don't that's step number
one figure out um what the what the
value is in your product what's the
vision right what is it you're trying to
achieve where you going what's your
North Star right once you figured out
that once you figured out that and you
can communicate it right you have to
learn to speak in front of people and
engage people in that story because you
need to engage them in that story then
you need to think about the value that
you're going to deliver are the things
that you're delivering in the product
actually
serving that Vision are they working
towards that Vision what is it that
you're trying to to to achieve and then
you need to think about validation how
are you going to check
that you're actually making progress
towards those key ideas that you're
actually making progress towards your
vision with the value that you're is the
value you're delivering even value at
all you might think it's value but do
your customers do your stakeholders do
the people who are using it think that
it's value right so that's this is this
is a a a a a key major thing that we
talk about in the professional scrum
product owner class we dive even deeper
in the advanced product owner class but
ultimately that Vision value and
validation is what's supposed to fill
that product management vacuum that
occurs when we make that
transition from project management
towards product management and that that
doesn't mean that there are no project
managers anymore that is absolutely not
the case project management um is not
being deleted uh from our of working it
just becomes one of the tools the focus
is the product we want to deliver a
product we want to deliver the most
successful most valuable product that
maximizes the value Creation in our
organization right rather than focusing
on the project which you can be on time
on budget with the features that we
asked for and still be unsuccessful
right and from a project manager's
perspective from a projects perspective
we can still be successful and not have
delivered any value that's why that
transition that focus and that's why
when you take away those pillars that
project management uses you need to
replace it with something else and the
answer is Vision value and validation if
you find it hard to
identify how you can enable Vision value
and validation within your organization
my team at naked agility can help you or
help you find somebody who can help you
don't let these sorts of issues inhibit
your ability to deliver value and
maximize the value Creation in your
organization use the links in the
description to seek guidance as soon as
you can