not every shiny object deserves your
attention or your budget but that's not
how it feels when the next big thing is
lighting up in your inbox everybody's
talking about it your team wants to try
it a competitor just shipped something
with it and suddenly it's your job to
decide if it's a risk not to adopt
it but here's the truth chasing hype
without rigor drains more than time it
burns your team's energy it clutters
your architecture and it kills trust
when the new shiny thing doesn't pan out
at Naked Agility we help CTO's build
discipline into their tech choices that
means frameworks for evaluation ROI
strategic alignment team capability fit
not just can we do it but should we do
it and is it the right time we help you
make emerging tech assessments part of
your systems of work structured
repeatable and defensible because good
leadership isn't about jumping on trends
it's about knowing why you're saying yes
or no and when you've got that clarity
you stop reacting and start leading