so the question is how big is the gap
between an average developer and a great
agile developer
I think there's two parts to that but
the main part that I think is really
important
is
um
I read a blog post years ago and I was
sitting reading it and the first
sentence it started with so it was about
this topic right what makes great
developers how what's learning all of
these kind of things and the first
sentence was if you're reading this
you're already in the top 10 percent
and that was what it said of the first
sentence
because so few people
are really engaged and care about the
work that they do
that they're willing to go invest and
investigate and figure out and solve and
try stuff and feel and pick themselves
up and try again right and this is true
regardless of whether we're talking
about our our skills in uh with people
with process right so that those those
are those agile group of group of skills
or product management or whatever it is
and but it also in the the the the the
technical right in the detail in the
weeds and how you actually do the work
that you do every day that is irrelevant
to the to the system with it which we're
working
and I think that is the fundamental
difference between somebody who is
average at doing their work and somebody
who is great at doing the work is
willingless to learn willingness to
adapt willingness to try things
investing your your own time and making
yourself better right
um one of my favorite folk in the world
uh David Starr who originally created
the the aps applying professional scrum
class back in the day and he had this a
a thing that he always said
um
what's
what do
martial artists and musicians have in
common
right what the martial artists and
musicians have in common and they're so
different that people are usually like
well I I don't know what do they have in
common they practice
why don't we when do we get practice
when when do we come off actually
performing right at the concert making
the production code and when do we get
the time to to practice
when we get things to try different
things to try new things that's actually
for me I feel like one of the the the
powers of training classes not
maybe the way not not the PowerPoint
training classes where you you basically
fall asleep and your brain dribbles out
your ears watching a PowerPoint
presentation
um but what I I try and do is bring in
some of the ideas of of flipped learning
right so I provide you with effectively
here's the content I'm going to teach
you in day one right go read it
if you read it
I don't need to tell you it we can then
talk about it and practice it in the
live session where we are together
because everybody reads at a different
pace everybody learns at a different
pace
perhaps you could spend some time
reading that content and then
we're gonna we're gonna answer the
questions we're going to dive into the
Nuance we're going to figure out how
that works we're going to do some
exercises so that we can maybe practice
some things that's the value of all
being together not in you know reading
some content of uh off of a slide so I
think that that that learning interest
in learning
is what makes it really powerful and I
do have a customer that leverages this
um and they actually provide their
developers everybody in their company
they provide everybody in their company
with a budget of about five thousand
Euros a year
for training
and you spend it how you like
it's up to you what training classes you
want to book what you want to learn
Perhaps Perhaps you just want to go do a
NLP class because you aren't very good
at that stuff and you want to understand
it better perhaps you do some cognitive
behavioral therapy uh classes because
that's what you feel you're lacking you
can pretty much do anything you want
with that budget I'm sure they might
frown if you wanted to go on a paper
airplane making class but
um the idea is that you know you as an
individual know
um what you don't know right kind of you
know what you don't understand you know
what you need to figure out and the
person best suited to direct the
learning that you need as yourself it
also has the huge benefit that it's
opt-in right it's self-service so the
worst type of uh um learning is mandated
in forced learning
um people generally don't pay attention
don't care as much
um and don't participate but if they
pick it themselves they're generally
more eager more engaged and that that's
the difference between the average
developer and the great agile developer
is engagement is practice is focus
that's what it is
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility