so the question is what makes a truly
great scrum master
and I think that's a very very difficult
question to answer because
it's very
circumstantial right it depends on the
organization the team you could have
somebody who's a great scrum Master for
this team at this organization and
they're not so great at the next gig
they go to right because the the team is
different the organizational culture is
different the things they were the fits
not right
so I think one thing that makes a great
scrum Master is having a good fit with
the team which is why it's important
that the to be honest that the the team
selects the scrum Master rather than the
scrum Master being selected for them
which is why you normally see great
scrum Master as being promoted as the
wrong word but promoted within uh within
the team I.E the team selects this
person as somebody who can deal with our
stuff that we as a team trust to deal
with our stuff
um and
they need to really focus beyond the
team
because in general the biggest problems
that a team Focus are not problems of
the team's own making right there's
there's most
uh um teams of people doing work know
very well what they do well and what
they don't do well even if they don't
admit it to themselves they still know
right and so the scrum Master can focus
for a while on bringing bringing that to
the surface of bringing bringing that
out and helping them understand and what
it is they're doing what the impact is
and but at some point usually very
quickly right within the first year of a
team working together is you start
hitting those organizational impediments
those those things in the organization
that just make it hard to do what it is
we're all trying to do which is provide
value for the organization provide value
for the business provide value for the
customers
and those are all things that are
impediments to our Effectiveness and
some of those things the team can deal
with themselves
but other things take
significant
application of politic I guess I think
I'm using the right word but effectively
politics right but the the act of
politics which I think is politic where
where you're building relationships with
people in the organization
um as a scrum Master you might build
relationships with the head of HR you
might build relationships with the CEO
depending on where how big your
organization is and what it looks like
you're going to build relationships with
people so that they know your level of
competence your understanding of the
work that's underway your understanding
of the way the business operates and
that you're making suggestions to help
the organization be more effective and
then they respect your your opinion they
value at your Council and that you're
able to then affect change inside of the
organization not by doing it yourself
but by helping everybody understand else
understand and some of the things that
might need to change
um and that I think is the difference
between a a a just a scrum Master doing
a job and a great scrum Master is that
willingness to build those relationships
to to
further the organization