when you're implementing a caman
strategy we're effectively creating uh a
pool-based system of
work so
um cban kind of does this there there's
three core practices to caman defining
and visualizing your workflow actively
managing items in that workflow and then
improving that workflow and our
ability to Define and visualize that
workflow as part of creating that caman
system we need to decide what is the
system that we're going to use caman a
caman strategy to monitor right so we
Define generally and you'll see this a
lot with teams as they'll Define columns
if they just stop there it's probably
not a caman system yet right it's not a
cand strategy if they just Define The
Columns and then we're done there's a
little bit more to it than that and some
of the minimum things things uh uh that
you kind of need at a minimum you should
have whip limits right at Absolute
minimum you should have whip limits
those other things we should have but
definitely if you don't have whip limits
definitely not not don't have a cand
system yet
but what we're able to do is we're able
to decide what of the stages that our
work flows through but we also want to
think about what are our weight States
and weight states are places where work
stops because the next thing that needs
to happen the next activity the next
stage in the process is um is full right
there's no no capacity if you think
about um I'm trying to trying to think
of a of a good example good example is
uh if you go to the hospital and you go
to the waiting room and there are no
seats left quite often there'll be a
another
overflow waiting room uh where where
people can go and wait to get into that
that that situation and then the people
running that department in the hospital
are going to be looking at well how many
people end up in this overflow they're
they're all wait they're they're waiting
longer than we expect because
everybody's waiting longer than we
expect and we don't want too many things
in the system perhaps we need to reduce
the number of people that we uh Book on
a particular schedule right in order to
Maxim minimize the amount of time people
wait and maximize the amount of people
we get through the system um and they
well that's more difficult for hospitals
because they have to take into account
people that cancel people that don't
turn up all of those kind of things so
um yeah that's that's fun but this this
idea of um the weight state is really
important so quite often for a stage
let's let's use a really
simple visualization uh where you've got
some kind of analysis Discovery happens
then some sort of development or doing
happens and then some kind of validation
or testing happens and then things are
finished you want to be able to indicate
on your board in your visualization in
your system visualizing your system when
things are complete from the perspective
Ive of analysis right um but they've
we've not yet
started development doing work on it so
if the analysis team just put it into
the development teams and I'm using
teams badly here but the people doing
analysis put it into the backlog of the
people doing development they're
committing to that work on that other
group's BAS behalf right they're putting
it in their system inside of their view
um without permission they're just put
dropping it in there even if they ask
they're they're kind of pushing that
system that's a push system if we want
to create a pool system then the folks
in the stage before so in this case
analysis they want to kind of have an
analysis doing and an analysis done
indication and that analysis done is a
weight State for the the the the the
next stage to look at that list of
things that are done from the previous
stage and then pull them in but it still
counts as time in that previous stage
that way we can see when visually see
when work piles up and see when we need
to do something about it like the
Overflow in the waiting room at the
hospital we want to be able to take
action right we want to actively manage
the items in the workflow which means
we're going to be looking for those
weight States we're going to be looking
for work piling up and you might find if
we're limiting work in process which we
should be in a cband system then if the
the the
development activity has four things
that they can take and the analysis
activity has four things then perhaps
the analysis work stops because they
have four things in done and the
development activity has more things in
progress slash done and we can't take on
anymore and Analysis can't take anymore
cuz their whip is four and they then
stop working and they say
to the system we don't have anything
left to do we we can't start new work
because we don't have room in our
system right and you might think that
well surely they can just take on
something else
but what if they keep doing that and
don't stop and put up the flag and alert
that we've stopped work what if they
just keep going so they keep pulling
work and dropping it into their done
column and their done column just gets
bigger and bigger and bigger and bigger
and perhaps the next stage can't pull
from that list very quickly and it means
that the weight time the amount of total
time in the system for all of those
things that are in that weight state is
getting longer and longer and longer and
it's just waste wouldn't it be better if
though that group in analysis just put
up the red flag and said uh We've
stopped because we've got no more room
in our system the next stage has not
filtered more down what should we do
right now in reality if you're a
engineering team working together
perhaps they go help the next stage down
the r line right maybe they can help out
and help make that FAS faster or perhaps
we need to bring this up as a a bigger
thing for leadership and say we've got
some kind of problem in the system and
we need to change the system in order to
make it more effective so the things
that we bring into the system flow
through the system more quickly so by
creating a pool system um we actually
create a
system within which we can see we can
visually see when we're not when the
system's not flowing properly when the
engine's not working properly it will
back up and it will back up all the way
to a point where we're like okay
everybody in this line of all every
single activity is is effectively
blocked right it's not a blocked thing
but everything is constrained and then
oh this is where it's constrained
because they're still working and
everybody after them has stopped what's
the problem do we not have enough people
here to be able to process the amount of
work that's going on um are we taking on
too much work into the system so it's
flowing through too quickly for this
whatever the constraint is in this area
and we need to figure out what it is and
go fix it so
this Dynamic applies both for a caman
strategy right you want to be looking
for those stages and thinking about how
do we visualize them uh but it also
applies in the the scrum world as well
scrum has a weight State H built in um
because the developers select work
during Sprint planning right so that's
their moment for for pulling work into
the system and then the system runs and
we see what comes out the other end so
we can apply a cband strategy on top of
that as well in addition to uh the work
limited pool system that's implemented
by scrum and add additional work limited
pool systems so that inside of the
system that scrum creates we can break
it up into other activities that in
order allow us to see what's going on in
those activities and where within the
system that's implemented by scrum where
the actual activities are are are
blocked are stuck are constrained that
we need to take action and we need to
fulfill that final part of a cand
strategy uh which is improving the
workflow not just actively managing it
but improving it so we need to go uh
take action and make a change if you're
struggling to create a pool-based system
of work then we can help you we provide
worldcast cran training from Pro caman
as well as Consulting and coaching for
teams trying to implement a caman
strategy if you're a scrum team then we
always recommend bringing in flow
metrics as a complimentary practice and
have cang classes from scrum.org as well