one of the Seven Virtues Of agile is
humility we need to
realize especially product owners and
product managers that the things we
expect to be valuable or the things that
we think are valuable are not always the
things that are actually valuable that
just because it's our idea um and our
thinking doesn't mean um that it's going
to be successful and that's true for the
product owner thinking about ideas and
the product um it's also true for for
developers right people doing the work
thinking that their idea is the best how
do you collaborate as a team do you
collaborate with um
arrogance and I'm always right and
you're always wrong or do you
collaborate with humility here's my idea
and maybe it's a good one maybe maybe
it's not let's discuss right bringing um
modesty and respect for others into the
conversation in agility is going to help
you build trust right build those
empathetic relationships both within the
team within the organization and
Leadership and outwardly towards
customers don't make
assumptions right that's the the the key
risk here is making assumptions um and
also cognitive bias although that's more
difficult to detect in yourself usually
you need somebody else to to to look in
on it to to point it out um but then do
you listen to those people do you
realize that perhaps other people's
perceptions um are are are are important
to our decision making I'm not saying
blindly listen to what other people say
right um I'm saying we need to take that
into consideration so in order in the
product world in the product management
world to
be being H humble having humility we
need to be looking at how people see our
ideas and see our product how they see
us we need to be looking at the data
right there are facts in this story but
you know we can interpret as lies damn
lies and statistics right we can
interpret facts differently but having
those facts to hand how are people using
the features in our product um how are
they engaging how do how do the people
on our teams feel about the way that we
engage in this product world right how
how do the how are employees happy
what's their morale like um having that
data to hand will help us make better
decisions and we need the humility to
look at the results to listen to what
people say and perhaps make a change to
the way we do things because we're not
always right if you are having
difficulty getting the most out of the
Seven Virtues of agility then my team at
naked agility can help you or find a
consultant coach or trainer who can it's
essential for you to find help as soon
as you can and not wait use the links
below to get in touch because you don't
just need agility you need naked agility