one of the harbingers of the agile
apocalypse is famine and famine
manifests in organizations by lacking
something you know PE people teams
groups
leaders products we don't have the
things we need in order to be successful
um and quite often that's because of one
of the other harbingers the the the the
top- down management structure but it's
we we effectively don't have what we
need we're either we're either starved
of trust in our in our teams and our
organization so people can't do the
things that that they need to do because
nobody believes that they'll do it right
they might have uh starved for for money
right quite often in
organizations um you need some somebody
high enough in the organization to
approve the spending of money
but what if that person's high enough in
the organization that they actually
don't give a [ __ ] about the problem
right they actually don't care they're
just looking at their budget and going
it's not in my budget for this year so
no I'm not going to sign off on that
yeah but what's what's the actual real
cost of making that decision what's the
impact on the people doing the work on
the work on the customer of making that
decision it's not in my budget for this
year is not a good answer to that and it
results in that famine we don't have the
stuff we need do the people in your
organization have the training they need
uh I I work with a an organization in in
Spain a couple of organizations in Spain
where every single member of the
organization every employee has their
own budget for training they decide how
they want to spend it if they want to
spend it on some agile training or they
want to group together and buy some
training together or they want to spend
it on Technical Training or on whatever
they want they're able to spend it on
whatever want it's their budget that
they get to spend they're not starved
for things that they need they have the
ability to get the things that they need
how do you do that in your
organization um I'm working with an
organization at the moment that I needed
a piece of software as a a as a
consultant helping this organization in
order to facilitate I needed a license
for a particular piece of software and I
had to go on and request that license I
made that request uh uh two and a half
weeks ago um I escalated it a week ago
there was a little escalation button on
the page where you can uh request it so
I escalated it after a week of nothing
happening and I still don't have a
license for that software I still don't
have access to that thing
what is the cost and impact of that
delay right what is the cost and impact
to the organization of me not being able
to provide the services um that I could
be providing to people inside of the
organization what is the cost of all the
people that I would be providing those
services to that can't get those
Services because there's a fundamental
piece of the puzzle missing there's a
Blocker in the way of actually doing
work so famine is all about those things
that make sure that people don't have
the things they need it's not deliberate
right these policies somebody didn't go
let's make sure people don't have the
stuff they need nobody did that right
they were looking at somebody at a level
who's I I guess we would traditionally
call them Bean counters right the bean
counters are looking the amount of money
something cost and they want to restrict
access to that thing so it doesn't cost
more this could be travel this could be
software this could be training it could
be anything but who are the people that
understand the most about what is needed
in order to maximize the success of the
organization um a great example of this
is uh one of the organizations that I
worked with for training uh they're a
very big manufacturer or car
manufacturer um and they had a a
circumstance in their organization where
uh
machine I I I don't know what the
machine was doing but the machine was
creating something for for the
production line for the cars for the
parts right and it was no longer
operating in a way that it needed to
operate it was too old no matter how
much repair you did it wasn't going to
be able to actually do the things they
had to do a ton of workarounds to make
it actually suit the needs of the
business and that machine really needed
upgrading to the newer version of that
machine that supported more cap cap
ability that had uh uh more just was
able to do more stuff more cheaply more
effectively faster um and the person who
runs the machine did followed the
business procedures and wrote the
business case uh for for wrote business
case for it uh sent it up the chain and
that's it got to somebody who was
looking at their budget and says nope I
don't have $2 million in my budget for
this new machine so scratch it off um
and when they finally figured out that
one of the major problems they had was
this machine was making a defective and
inaccurate Parts uh they found that it
actually cost the organization over a
billion dollars in Lost Revenue in um
having to rework things in fixing stuff
in production if you can imagine if you
have to recall a car a car or a model of
car because something's wrong with it
fundamentally what's that going to cost
you down in the line um but it wasn't in
this Block's budget but do you think
that block had the had the power to
approve well approve a $2 billion or a
billion dollar loss for the comp no no
nobody has that that that power to be
able to do that but they can block the
thing that might result if it's blocked
it might result in that um so what they
did as an organization this particular
organization is they they pushed
responsibility for spending money down
to the people who were best placed to
make the decision um anybody in the
organization no matter how below you are
can approve any needed expense of any
amount for doing your job you might need
to validate it afterwards right you need
to it's almost like a you're you're
pre-approved to expense it but then you
have to write still have to write the
business case you still have to say this
is why we we we bought this this is what
it was for this is what it was needed
this was the impact right you still have
to do all of those due dilcy things but
you're not blocked from solving the
problem what's causing famine in your
organization thanks for watching the
video If you enjoyed it please like
follow And subscribe I always reply to
comments and if you want to have a chat
about this or anything else agile scrum
or devops then please book a coffee with
me through naked
agility