in
order to meet the unique needs of all
the different organizations that we work
with and we've worked with medical
device organizations military
organizations uh all the way through uh
to to internet startups um and web
organizations doesn't whatever the
organization the intrinsic philosophies
of devops are the
same
so but how they're solved within the
context of your organization is
completely unique it will always be
unique in every
organization and although a lot of the
stories sound the same right there's a
lot of stories that you'll hear about
devops and devops implementations that
kind of sound the same the the devil's
in the details right the the the the way
that it's solved the tools that are used
the limitations those bring will be
different in every
organizations um the the value of
engaging with
us is that we're generally going to be
focused on on that big picture right
that state of devops where are we right
now where do we want to go and how do we
maintain progress on that that that that
route so we um do a lot more work at the
start and then there's a lot of work
that has to be done by the people within
the context that are doing it um and we
can help keep progress in a particular
direction we can help engage with them
over the longer ter to to coach them
around some of these gnarly issues that
they run into right you want to solve a
particular problem and you don't
understand how to do it but you need to
try some things and then perhaps get
some advice from somebody who's been
doing it a long time and if you don't
have those skills in your organization
sometimes you need to look outside of
your organization for those additional
skills so because every organization is
unique every solution is unique and we
can't tell you how to solve your
problems but we can tell you about
how other people have solved similar
problems to give you ideas for things to
try
and creating
this philosophy inside of our
organization where we're able to take
little pieces of what works for us
within our context sometimes we need to
adapt our context but keep moving
forward keep adapting to the needs of
the market market and continually
increase our capability to deliver
software within our organization is
where we can help you understand that
direction and how it sits within those
devops philosophies