[Music]
you
hello my name is Martin Henchy wood
I'm the owner at Naked agility in
Glasgow Scotland and I've had a couple
of questions come in from a few Foulke
and I wanted to cover a few of those
things so first off I'm going to be
doing this as often as I can I think
it's important to help people in in this
this time it can be very difficult to
figure out what's going on and get
things done so we're going to going to
look at this so the first thing that I
want to talk about a little bit was
remote working a lot of us are in that
if I probably most of us are in that
space of having to work remotely we're
gonna be working distributed from our
our teams and while we talk about in
scrum and agile in general we talk about
co-located teams the reality is when
these types of circumstances arise and
and even just based on your
organizational context you might work in
an organization that doesn't have
everybody in the same place and it can
make things very difficult so while in
one of the the values of scrum is focus
openness we are trying to have a group
of people who can work together
effectively regardless of the context so
we need to think about the values we
want to have people working together as
closely as possible and obviously in the
current context that closely as possible
is over webcam and using video
conferencing technology so we just have
to figure that out but don't forget to
continuously and
even though we are separated by space
and and only doing videoconferencing we
still need to be able to figure out what
the best way to use the tools that we've
got so don't get stuck on a tool that is
not working for you
make sure you continuously adapt try new
things figure it out I did a web
conference on Wednesday using Microsoft
teams and I found that it wasn't
particularly awesome for for that set up
just in the way that I wanted to do it
it wasn't quite working I'm going to try
some other technologies but I used teams
a lot for other things so I think it's
important when you're remote working to
think about how you interact with other
people are are you interacting with your
teammates enough do they do they know
what you're working on do you know what
they are working on make sure we have
that focus and context to understand
what's going on and what we're doing we
talked about this a lot in the
professional scrum master class I'm
hoping to do some remote PSM once the
the scrum community figures out how best
to achieve that we're gonna try some
stuff and see see if it works I have a
class coming up that I'm going to move
to to remote and we'll see see what
happens
so I think it's also important to think
about taking taking some time that idea
of poo-poo the chain while we're in this
remote state and we're maybe don't have
such laser focus on delivering value
than we had when we were in person high
bandwidth in person and we can still
focus on some of the things that need
our our help so in the the scrum world
particularly in all of product
development the work at
we're doing is really complex and it's
not really suited to that production
line mentality but our DevOps pipeline
is suited to that production line
mentality and if we want to UM take an
idea from our product owner and turn it
into working software we've got that bit
that we can't understand how long it's
going to take because it's it's the
creative endeavor of solving that
cognitive problem so we're going to
solve that problem but then we make a
change to the software we commit that to
our repository and then somehow it goes
off and ends up in production how
quickly does that happen
and how that that is your production
line that's the bit that we want to
shorten and figure out and how to make
as fast as possible and I usually use an
example from Brian Harry who was the
product unit manager for Azure DevOps
and he talked about zero build I think
he called it a zero build an awesome
phrase but he he talked about it as and
if he does our build of the product so
the team creates a version of visual
studio and TFS at the time and then they
ship it to production it has to go
through a whole bunch of or at the time
it had to go through a whole bunch of
checks so there was legal there was
validation though all kinds of steps
along that way and he would look at not
how long it took to get through that
process because there may be things just
now while we're not so good that would
fail so that's going to go back into the
feedback loop so you're not looking at
how long it takes to get your software
out the door because there's some stuff
engineering-wise we need to fix in there
and that's good to disrupt our data but
once we've got that version of the
product in production if we do another
brand new build from exactly the same
version of code that passed all the
checks and
see how long it takes that to go through
the process so that's your zero bill
does zero changes in the code the zero
changes in the platform how long does it
take you to get that into production and
that's your your zero build time that's
what you want to focus on as a
production line as we need to make this
as short as possible we need to reduce
the process and in order to do that you
need to get feedback from every stage
along the way I just found this diagram
on the internet that is enough stages
that I think was valid so you need to
focus on engineering excellence you need
to focus on improving your definition of
done but also focus on team building you
want your team to care that these things
are important it's important to get into
production as quickly as possible
because without feedback we're we may
not be building the right thing I need
to figure out how to do that and or does
that mean to focus on on people and
something I've been looking at recently
is how to use extreme gamification and
to help people understand how to work
together a little bit better some of
those things that I'm trying to get I
get people to look at it is through
board games those are a board game that
I had in mind called pandemic which is a
cooperative game of of saving humanity
from pandemic so it's kind of apt but
one of the things that you see when a
group of people play that game is that
it's very that game is very prone to one
person telling everybody else what to do
which is kind of analogous with software
development so if you can get a team
together for our it's 45 minutes to an
hour to play the game and do a diagnosis
at the end get the team to play the game
together and then talk about who you
know you're observing potentially is a
scrum master and then
have a discussion about the different
interactions that you saw during the
game so you can have that kinda safe
environment where you can run a little
experiment with your team it's fun for
them so they get into it and they forget
that you're running an experiment
because they're getting into the game
and solving the the puzzle that they're
trying to solve but you can you can have
us two observations and usually you'll
find that there's one or two people that
are very loud everybody else follows
along how do you make sure you get
everybody's opinion here'd the people
that are very loud to understand and
that they're maybe being overbearing in
in that conversation so that's part of
that focus and on people and how people
work together and I think cooperative at
fun games are definitely a way to to
help make some of those ideas a little
bit more real so I also got a question
from one of my old friends Ian frame he
was talking about UX in the context of
larger organizations and how do you make
sure that UX is not just an afterthought
now I've worked with the author of lean
UX Jeff on this that we have a class
from scrum that are called the
professional scrum with UX which he
describes as I as an olive branch to the
UX community the US community is off
doing their own thing because they're
getting pushed away by engineering teams
but really the thing that they're doing
is one of the most important parts of
product delivery understanding what your
product is what you're gonna do to solve
the business need how you're going to do
that and how those interactions and
behaviors of users that you're going to
change and I think that's that's so
unbelievably important too
at product owner and building the right
thing story that it it's it's going to
be detrimental to any organization that
is leaving it behind and you need to get
your your UX skills available on the
scrum teams with the people that are
doing the work because they are doing
work as well and I do think there's some
I guess confusion and difficulty around
what happens with long-running work you
might have a bunch of stuff that tastes
longer than Sprint to complete so how do
we deal with that and the reality is we
we have that built in to scrum in scrum
we have something called refinement
which is that work that the team does on
things that are coming up in future
sprints to create the most awesome
ordered backlog possible and so that
everybody on the team fully understands
what is in the backlog that you're
planning on bringing into the sprint by
the time you get to the sprint planning
session so in order to do that you have
to spend a bunch of time refining that
product backlog probably looking out
into the future the recommendation is to
start with about a current sprint plus
two more whatever that means to you that
might be your effective planning horizon
but really you need to plan as far out
as you need to action the things that
you find so if you find you need some
extra information or you need to do some
paper prototyping or you need to get
some some something in front of users in
order to understand better what the need
is you need to know far enough in
advance for you to deal with those
things so how do you do that in this
refinement and so there's a lot of UX
work working with the product owner and
the development team in refinement just
like there's a lot of security work
there there's a lot of architecture
car there's a lot of testing work all of
all of the skills are required in the
scrum team so there's this terminology
that I hear used a lot called dual track
dual track agile dual track scrubs
you'll track UX well whatever you want
to call it people are using lots of
different terminology but the idea
behind dual track is not that there's
two separate streams of work and it's
that there's there's one development
team that moves through different modes
for a particular backlog item so you get
something on your backlog pbi product
backlog item it might be a user story it
might be a requirement whatever you call
it there's something on your backlog and
it probably starts a little bit vague
so we maybe need to do some amount of
discovery work to understand what that
item is to get the team up to speed to
really focus on and how to to bring all
of that together and then that will move
into maybe a combination of discovery
and delivery maybe we're going to figure
out what's the smallest possible thing
that we can build that will help us
understand whether to continue to invest
in that or that we need to build
something else that's that and yep
that's that a discovery versus delivery
work and then maybe you your entire
engineering team dives into delivery for
the period of a sprint
so we deliver a bunch of things and then
we shoot back up into discovery again
where we're going to analyze the data
that we're collecting for that we're
going to look at what our hypothesis was
and whether the features that we've
built have managed to change user
behavior in the way that we expect
create the outcomes that we expect and
then we come up with what are we going
to go do
next to solve that problem so that will
bring us back down into delivery again
so we keep going through that cycle for
a particular idea and that result might
result in many PBIS that are delivered
over multiple Sprint's as we flip
between discovery and delivery and
somewhere in between so the reality is
that things on your backlog and are not
just you I work they're not just
engineering work just like they're not
just coding work not just testing work
not just architecture or security work
and each product backlog item should
represent a unit of value and that unit
of value should include coding testing
security architecture as well as UX as
well so what are the UX ideas you need
to do in there and deciding how much
time you want to spend on UX for a
particular backlog item will depend on
and how unsure you are of whether that
thing will provide value sometimes if
it's just a small simple low-risk thing
I would just go build it and see if it's
useful and if it's a high risk a big
thing then maybe I want to do some paper
prototyping maybe I want to do some
additional investigation work as a
development team around that so it's
important that the entire development
team is involved in that process and in
the the PSU professional scrum with UX
we focus very heavily on team
accountability for UX but there are many
things in UX that you need a significant
amount of expertise to be able to
deliver on you need expedience training
understanding within the UX world of
many years so everybody can't learn all
of that just like everybody can be deep
security expects experts or deep testing
experts are deep pudding
you're going to have deep UX experts but
there are is a certain amount of work
that makes sense for everybody to help
out with so one of the things we focus
on I have one on the wall behind me is
lean UX canvas this is from Jeff's
website this is the second version lanky
is v5 but it says v2 on it but just lean
UX canvas and we focus on this for an
engineering team because it helps them
understand the value and context within
work which they're making decisions
every day on how to build parse the
product and so this is a really
important tool that I think anybody on
an engineering team can learn how to how
to use and utilize but you still need
that deep UX expertise to tackle some of
those harder core things that you might
do so something you should have is all
of the things in your backlog should
include some amount of UX work depending
on the context also we talked about
emergent design just like we talked
about emergent architecture a product
backlog supports emergent architecture
and that idea is that um in sprint one
when you're working towards your first
unit of usable increment your first
piece of working software at the end of
sprint one you're going to probably
spend quite a lot of time on UX just as
you're gonna spend quite a lot of time
on architecture and quite a lot of time
on infrastructure so the amount of value
that you deliver in early Sprint's is
probably going to be quite small
maybe during the sprint you spend during
your first two weeks print you and the
whole team spend four days
working on UX how are we going to build
this what value we get or what user
behaviors we'll be trying to change and
that sets you up for the next couple of
Sprint's where you spend most of your
time in that delivery with a little bit
of discovery before you need to jump
back to food you're spending a lot more
time on discovery so that idea of team
accountability we're all working
together we are all as a team
accountable for users getting the best
experience they can and I think that's
really important focus on those
behaviors that you want to change in
users and it will help you focus your
product backlog as well working with
your product owner while the product
owner is accountable for value delivery
the entire scrum team is responsible and
we are all in it together and if the
product owner is not successful we're
just as much out of a job as they are so
I think that it's important that we all
work together to solve those problems
hopefully that was our youthful at quick
dive into those three things and I
talked a little bit about remote working
and about take taking some time for
engineering excellence team building
doing doing some things around that and
I talked a little bit about integrating
UX into your overall strategy I hope you
found this useful remember the values
and principles of scrum those ideas of
transparency so we can get those
feedback loops is built upon trust and
in order to get trust the scrum
community feels the commitment courage
focus respect and openness or of utmost
importance so if you're trying to make a
decision about how you're going to do
something especially during this crisis
think about how and how will the way
we've decided to do something support
those values the
kick those values to the Carib or are
they going to add to those values and
help us create more trust build
transparency and create feedback loops
if you want to get in touch with me you
have any additional questions please
please do there's my email address my
whatsapp and my Twitter you can get in
touch me on all of those places and I've
done two presentations recently that I
wanted to call out one is an enterprise
evolution that shows that you can -
which is from the the Microsoft story
the story of how the azure DevOps team
of the TFS team went from delivering
every two years in a waterfall manner
towards delivering to production every
three weeks and the improvements that
they made they started back in 2012
delivering only 22 features to
production each year and now they're
delivering over 270 features to
production each year so it's a big
change with the same number of people
and it's about paying back your
technical debt getting better at working
together improving communication lines
and getting all of that sorted last week
I also did a presentation on detecting
agile BS which is from the Department of
Defense article of the same name the
white paper I would definitely recommend
going and reading detecting agile BS and
seeing what's going on there is fairly
awesome article well thank you very much
I hope you found that useful if
anybody's got any questions then please
let me know I don't see any questions
coming in yet that doesn't mean they're
not there it just means my tool might
not have been
very good pulling pulling them out I'm
just going to check and then if there's
no questions
that's folks want answered I might well
I don't see any questions so thank you
very much for having listening to me and
I hope you have a good a good day in a
good weekend okay thank you very much