there are two main reasons to do the EPS
class the first one is getting started
you have a team that doesn't know scrum
uh that once wants to try some of the
things in scrum and needs to learn how
how it's done and the second one is tune
up uh your team's maybe been doing scrum
for a number of years maybe never had
any formal training and you're not sure
whether we're actually doing scrum or
we're doing all are we focusing on the
right things do we are we just making it
up as we go along and we're just doing
waterfall how do we how do we know how
do we get back to roots and the aps is a
great class to kind of level set and
everybody in the group on what
professional scrum looks like and then
you can figure out how does that work
within your organizational context