There are a number of ghosts of Agile
past that plague us and the first one
that I want to talk about is story points.
The person that
originally created the idea
of story points has publicly
apologized for creating them.
That should tell you something
about story points.
But ultimately,
story points have been
with us for a very long time.
In the old, old, old days,
people used to do a lot
of absolute estimation.
So things like hours, right?
We used to figure out exactly
how many hours this thing would take.
This will take 5,000 hours.
And then we would
perhaps measure ourselves
against how many hours it did take.
And in order to kind of move away
from that idea of hours
and absolute estimation,
a lot of teams started talking
about relative estimation
and relative estimation
points in some way.
And that could be t-shirt
sizes I often hear,
but the main one is story points.
Story points have been
with us probably for about,
about 20 years.
They've been plaguing,
they've been haunting teams
for about 20 years.
And story points create a
whole bunch of, wow,
Really difficult things with teams.
So one of them is that you'll often see
or hear teams having a conversation
about how they claim points
for the work that they've done so
that they can push the rest
of the work that they haven't done
into the next sprint.
That's pretty dysfunctional
behavior right?
The point is not the points,
the point is the value
that we're delivering and
that's what we should be focusing on,
not some arbitrary set of points.
We also see teams being measured
or compared across teams based on
their story points.
This team delivers 30
story points per sprint,
this team delivers 20
so this team must be better
than this team and that is utter garbage.
There is no way to compare
story points across teams.
There is no way, there is no
normalization algorithm
that you can use to do that comparison
or create it in some way.
It's just one of those
agile bullshit things
that keeps sticking
around we can't get rid of.
So the the what was the
other thing that story...
Story...
Oh!
I recently engaged with a customer
and they had a team
that was struggling to deliver.
It was actually five
teams working on one product
and they were struggling to deliver.
And I was trying to figure
out what the problem was
and they kept going on
about story points were
the most important thing
for them to progress
and they had to get a
specific number of story points
And this was a professional
services organization.
And I found out that the contract
that they had with the customer,
obviously,
Somebody
on the customer's side
and somebody on their side had decided
that it would be a great idea,
because they've heard
about these story point things,
to put story points into the contract
and they were contracted
for an exact number of story points and
if they were outwith a 15% deviation
from the exact number
of story points then there
were fiscal penalties
for the for the
professional services organization
so you can imagine the raft
of dysfunctional behaviors that resulted
from that.
I used to think story
points were a good thing.
I used to think they were a good thing.
And now I'm a little bit more aligned
with Daniel Vacanti on this.
He's the Kanban, pro Kanban guy.
Story points have set
our industry back 20 years.
Story points are one of the things
that have restricted the ability
for us to adapt to changing circumstances
as we might have because there's
that continuous focus on the numbers,
continuous focus on the work that's done
because story points reflect the work,
not the value, right?
Continuous focus on the work, the butts
on the seats, rather than on the value
that's created.
So I'm a firm believer
in flow metrics moving towards,
They're not the be all and end all,
right? Because we can have awesome flow
and we're delivering tons
of crap into production, but
at least flow is telling
us what's really going on,
right? We're
looking at our cycle time,
we're looking at our work item aging,
we're looking at our throughput,
right?
Those metrics are just based
on historical fact
for what we're delivering.
We can certainly manipulate them
by reducing batch size,
which usually has good outcomes.
And I just find that they're
all round a more useful way of looking
at the data of, and potentially looking
across multiple teams as well
for a whole department,
for a whole organization.
What is it we're able to deliver,
what does that look like?
But ultimately,
moving towards more flow-based metrics
and away from relative size estimation,
I think is a good idea.
And That's why I put story points
in that list of ghosts of Agile past.
And if you are being haunted
by these ghosts of Agile past,
We can help you exercise them
or help you find a coach,
consultant or trainer who can.
Don't let these phantoms undermine
the effectiveness of the value
that you deliver.
And the longer you wait,
the more they're going to haunt
your team's progress.
So send me an email
at martin at nkdagility.com
and we will get you the help you
need to get to the bottom
of it. If you want
to have a discussion about
your unique needs or situation,
then please book a call or visit us
at nakedagility.com.
We also have our immersive
and traditional public classes on
our website and we'd
love to hear from you.