The Scaled Professional Scrum is a hands-on,
activity-based course where students develop
a collection of skills that can be applied
to overcome challenges when scaling Scrum.
Even after achieving success with Scrum, teams
are still limited by the amount of work they
can do and the value they can create. They
need to expand, or scale, to a group of Scrum
Teams working together on the same product.
When doing so, they often encounter common
challenges with cross-team dependencies, self-management,
transparency and accountability.
When introducing heavy-weight scaling methodologies,
teams often find that the added overhead slows
down the teams and distracts from the essence
and benefits of Scrum. Instead, the Nexus
Framework minimally extended the Scrum Framework
to include ways that help solve the dependency
and collaboration challenges of cross-team
work. Since Nexus enhances the foundational
elements of Scrum, it reinforces the benefits
of Scrum while also being familiar to those
that have used Scrum.
The Scaled Professional Scrum™ (SPS) with
Nexus course, builds on the Nexus framework
by introducing complementary practices and
techniques proven to help teams scale. The
course also includes a free attempt at the
globally recognized Scaled Professional Scrum
(SPS) certification exam.
Our training is delivered as an interactive,
activity-based course over half-day sessions
using Microsoft Teams, and Mural. Students
work together in a Nexus to organize and simulate
a scaled product development project. This
case study-based class presents common challenges
in scaling and more than fifty practices for
overcoming them are revealed. Students will
develop an understanding of how to launch,
structure, organize, and manage a large Agile
project using Scrum. They will leave the class
with a toolbox of techniques for identifying
and overcoming common scaling challenges.
Between sessions, we provide additional reading,
writing, and watching activities to maximise
the learning opportunities and complement
the classroom experience.
After the conclusion of the class, we provide
access to a community of peers and continued
access to the trainer through office hours,
quarterly catchups, and constant engagement.
To maximise validated learning, all students
are given a password to take the SPS assessment,
and if they take it within 14 days and are
unsuccessful, they will be granted a second
attempt. As part of our validated learning
experience, we provide a 30-minute learning
review, a 1h coaching session, and access
to future courses at a 30% discount on future
classes.