the EPS
prepares a team for professional scrum
and by really doubling down on those
core fundamentals of of scrum you you
must have working usable product at the
end of every iteration including the
first
if you don't we're we're not at does
there's no agility there if we don't
have working usable products right
because we need to be able to test and
get feedback from that
um what else is really important from
the EPS that
so many one of I think the most powerful
features of the aps which is why it
actually is super effective for existing
teams as well like teams that are
already doing scrum is that level set of
what is and is not scrum
right so quite often in our organization
we pick up scrum we learn scrum we've
been doing scrum for a little bit within
our organization and it picks up a bunch
of barnacles I don't know well I go with
a sailing metaphor yeah let's go with
the ceiling metaphor uh my brother sales
uh he does races across the channel in
the in the UK from from
um England over to France
um I don't I think he's come second once
but you know it's it's these are these
are really really heavy races
um and the the the thing anything that
goes in the water that slows down the
bolt that slows down the stream of water
because he's dragged right and even the
smallest amount of drag can severely
impact over uh over over a race the the
impact of of your place
um and Barnacles are the bane of the of
the of ships not ships sailboats boats
ships
you can tell I'm not an expert sailor
right but
um the the the the Barnacles get on the
side and then they cause cause drag
that's what happens when you've been
doing scrum for a while in your
organization it picks up a bunch of
barnacles right stuff that gets stuck
onto it at some point because
you needed to solve a problem because
your organization didn't do things in a
way that was as effective as it could be
so we have to stick this thing into
scrum maybe that thing was user stories
or story points or maybe that thing was
I don't know we're gonna have a burn
down or it could be some other report
that your organization really really
really wanted so you had to capitulate
for and then it's just kind of stuck
there and maybe it's outlived its
usefulness but we think we as a team
think of it as part of that overall
package because when we say scrum within
our organization
that's what we mean the whole package
including all the Barnacles that we've
we've had attached to our process so the
EPS is a great place uh to come and
scrape off those Barnacles right
um what are the things that are and are
not core to scrum because everything
else is a choice so how do we
disambiguate the choices that we've made
from scrum itself so that perhaps
there's other choices that are maybe
more effective now than they were before
um so there's there's a key one of my
favorite exercises at the end of the
class
um is is where can we I kind of have a
choice and I let teams decide the groups
decide
um but they can either do a kind of
getting started because we're not doing
scrum and we want to figure out how do
we get started doing scrum in our
organization and then there's a kind of
Barnacle Barnacle exercise right which
is uh how do we improve like a like a
little retrospect active on our
implementation of scrum to start at
least identifying the Barnacles that we
have in our scrum process within our
organization and then figuring out how
to how to address them a little bit
right that's a that's a great exercise
and if we do it privately within
organizations there's an additional
exercise that I run which is the people
in the class create an organizational
change backlog like what needs to be in
an organizational change backlog to make
scrum successful or more successful or
valid within our organization
um and really it's an agile
transformation backlog from the people
who are actually doing the work right
what are their problems going to be and
hopefully there's leadership available
who are able to take ownership of that
and take it forward
so we do that mainly in the private
classes not so much in the public ones
right because it doesn't make sense if
you get 20 people from 20 different
companies
that is how the aps effectively prefers
teams to be professional scrum teams
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility