so the question is how critical is a
product owner in developing a great
product backlog if you look at the the
scrum guide then it will be um
absolutely imperative there the one that
decides makes the final decision the
Arbiter of the product backlog
um they they are responsible
um accountable for ordering the product
backlog
um although they can delegate it they're
responsible for the contents of the
product backlog although they can
delegate it
um but they are 100 responsible for
expressing and communicating the vision
and strategy that results in all of
those other things
so if you think about what you might put
in a product backlog you're not going to
know what to put in there unless you
know what direction you're going
um product backlogs can quite often
become just this massive Dumping Ground
of whatever crap anybody asks for at any
point in time and that's not what you
want you want your product backlog to be
uh uh uh uh
um short list a lean
inventory of the work that needs to be
done to maximize your value that you're
going to deliver to your customers which
means if you have 5 000 things in your
product backlog
um You probably don't have a product
owner right you've probably got somebody
who's just dumping stuff in there and if
a customer makes a request they just put
it in there perhaps that's not the right
customer request perhaps we should say
no to that customer request perhaps we
should ask the customer to keep it in
their back pocket because it's not to do
with our current strategy and those
are really the core
critical activities of the product owner
that help us create this lean
directional product backlog that enables
then the engineering team the developers
to select the right things and because
it's all understood it's transparent
it's understood we know what trade-offs
we're making as a developer we know what
trade-offs we're making when we choose
this over that even though this is more
important we know we have to do this
that first and those are the types of
conversations that we can only have if
we have strong product leadership a
strong product owner on our on our
product and who's able to communicate
and express
that strategy and Direction effectively
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility