before you can call yourself an agile
coach you must absolutely must have
worked with a team actually building
some kind of product if you're going to
be working with teams and helping
encourage them to do um more uh more
practices more um higher quality in
their product you really need to
understand and gain credibility from
their perspective of actually doing the
work so if you want to be an agile coach
have you ever worked with a team if you
haven't go join one help them build a
product and learn what it takes to work
on a team thanks for watching the video
If you enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility