the most common thing I hear in the PSM
class is uh but in the real world
um and usually around the point when
we're talking about moral flexibility
and what we talk about in the uh the PSM
is the inflexibility of our moral
obligation to our customer to tell the
truth
and you hear many people in that class
say but in the real world we have to
tell our customer how long it will take
and how much it will cost up front
right and that the moral influx the
flexibility there is that that's a lie
right you just lied to your customer you
sold them a squirrel Burger
um a roadkill burger right it's not what
you just said it was and perhaps they
bought it based on that understanding