so the question is what does a product
owner
do if the team are
incompetent well if it's really that bad
and the team really are incompetent I
would say fire them and get a new team
that's ultimately where I would where I
would go with that now that predisposes
obviously we're going to try our hardest
to engage with that team to to enable
them to have every opportunity to
improve um all of the things that you
would expect to happen right we not
[ __ ] we're not just going to fire
people for no reason uh but the fact
that the question
is the team is
incompetent don't work with incompetent
people don't hire incompetent people
don't keep incompetent people they are
not the people you need in your business
to be successful um amazing teams build
amazing products and amazing teams don't
come from
incompetence um so get rid of those
folks as as quickly as you humanly can
now if it's they don't know something
that they could have known that's not
necessarily incompetence you want to
provide them with training opportunities
you want to provide them with knowledge
opportunities you want to provide them
with um I
yeah I don't know I've never worked with
a a truly I've never actually met
actually that is not true well it's kind
of true kind of not true I was going to
say I've never actually worked with a
truly incompetent team um but I
have but they
were not incompetent in their favor if
that makes sense um so I worked with a a
team in an organization it was a bank
and they had uh um
man I'm trying to think of other teams
yeah plenty of other teams I've worked
with that that that present as
incompetent that actually aren't so this
team that I'm talking about they they
they have I I was a lowly devops
consultant helping uh a part of the
organization transition from what they
were using before into uh Azure devops
TFS at the time and this was Java teams
so at the time if you if you were a Java
team and you had to use TFS you were
already a little bit hostile towards it
right so there that but this particular
team uh didn't want to use Source
control they they believed that it would
slow them down that's their their uh uh
uh comment on um Source control and I
kind of kind of asked them I challenged
them a little bit and said well why do
you think it would slow you down and
they're like well if we need to make
make changes we just just log into the
environment and make the Chang changes
so I asked them about how you know how
do they develop and it's like well we
just log into the the the server the
production server we open up our our IDE
we make changes to the code and we we
publish it right away and I was kind of
like but how do
you how do you do that publish and
they're like well we just click the
publish button and it goes straight into
production so already I'm horrified
right I was horrified already even more
horrified
now and then I asked cuz they have five
servers around the world I said how do
you keep all of those servers in sync
you know how do you make the changes
across all of those servers and they
said that's why there's five of us was
five people on this team each one owned
a server independently and when there
were changes needed to the to the code
um they would they would all log in
independently write their own code in in
their own way on their server in order
to um action those changes so I was I
was even more horrified and then you
find out that it's the realtime banking
transaction system for a multinational
bank and now you don't want to you know
keep your money in a bank anymore and
the those types of teams I they they
they were there was a strategic
incompetence right because they're
they're making sure the bank can never
fire them and when I brought it up with
with Le ERS ship and said that this is a
massive risk to your business they said
we know but if we say anything they'll
leave and then what do we do right so
this this small group of people we're
holding an entire multinational Bank
hostage um for for this this this piece
of software and that's that's not okay
that's that's that goes beyond
incompetence towards Mal levance right
um and that level of Mal malel evance
the
organization this would be my
recommendation the organization needs to
fire that entire group of
people and take their lumps for figuring
out how to resolve the problem right of
actually figuring out the software
getting it out of those servers if those
people are still around they're going to
sabotage that at all costs because it's
their their their property they believe
it's their property they believe they
control it so if you have a truly melant
team definitely fire them if you have an
incompetent team probably probably fire
them but be careful that you're not
reading incompetence into just they
don't know stuff they've never been
told I've worked with teams that don't
understand how Source control works that
they know how branching works but they
didn't know how merging worked cuz
nobody had ever explained it to them um
so teach them as best they can get rid
of the Mal
elevant uh work on the incompetence But
ultimately if if they're that bad get
rid of them thanks for watching the
video If you enjoyed it please like
follow And subscribe I always reply to
comments and if you want to have a chat
about this or anything else agile scrum
or devops then please book a coffee with
me through nak
agility