most scrum
Masters don't realize what's entailed in
being a scrum Master usually that's
because they've just been handed uh the
role by their organization um and
perhaps the role of scrum Master within
their organization is very different
from what I'm talking about with the
accountability of the scrum Master
within the context of scrum uh because
you know 25 years ago when scrum was
created um scrum master was a brand new
term that didn't have any baggage
whereas today it has just amount about
as much baggage if not more than any
other term out there um so as a scrum
master um you do need to
disambiguate the role that your
organization has perhaps the job title
right and all of the different
accountabilities that are included in
that that might be nothing to do with
scrum as well right that's fine
with the
accountability for the scrum Master
within the context of scrum um and that
accountability is for maximizing the
effectiveness of the team um that's
that's that's really the whole thing in
a in a nutshell and in order to do that
there are loads of tools that you need
in your toolbox there's loads of
practices and processes that that can
make sense in that space complimentary
practices to scrum um so there's lots of
things out with scrum that a scrum
Master needs to understand in order to
be be as effective as possible but if
you have a brand new scrum team uh that
have never done scrum before they're
just starting out uh the first thing
that a scrum Master is a is accountable
for is is the knowledge that the team
have their understanding of scrum their
understanding of empiricism the scrum
values teaching those things is really
important for a scrum master and then
once your team gets beyond that
um engaging with not just the team but
the rest of the organization as well
remember the scrum Master not only has
accountabilities for the scrum team but
they have accountabilities for the to
the product owner and accountabilities
to the organization as well so enabling
a team to be as effective as it can has
much wider implications across the
organization um because usually once
you've dealt with the knowledge the
knowledge that the team have about
empiricism about uh uh working product
right and the value contained within
that um it's it's organizational
impediments that get in the way it's
things your organization is doing which
impedes the ability for the team to to
maximize its Effectiveness um and
getting focus on them so building
relationships within the organ
organization understanding the business
processes why they're there and
inevitably how to change them um is
critical role for a critical area of
understanding for the for the for the
scrum master so if you want to be um a
scrum Master you don't have to come to
scrum training but the professional
scrum master and more importantly the
advanced scrum Master Class can really
help you broaden your your understanding
of what is the context of a scrum master
and become the most effective scrum
master that you can be if you want to
have a discussion about your unique
needs or situation then please book a
call or visit us at naked agility decom
uh we also have our immersive and
traditional public classes on our
website and we'd love to hear from you