[Music]
i'm tired of you
i can see hans has got his elmo ready
there
just in case we have some off-topic
conversations i have my elmo
uh
as well
um
so today we're going to be
looking at
how to run a daily scrum or introduction
to daily scrum um we want to have some
conversations around
um that idea of what is the daily scrum
and how it works
while we get started though
and we're going to do a little uh
exercise here um where
i have um five areas for five different
teams and in each of those areas um we
have
seven questions
and next to each of those questions we
have a green tick or a red cross
uh which you should be able to move
around okay
and what i would like it to do is i'm
going to create some breakout rooms i'll
add people manually after because
there's peter as well there goes the
neighborhood now peter's here
um
you're on mute peter
and his microphone is also up
yeah and you've got your microphones up
no i've got i've got a posh microphone
like you ah
porsche microphones are very handy
yeah there we go
dude you're the the comedy relief
so um i was just introducing the the the
um
fast pass exercise at the start so what
i've got is a bunch of statements that
might be true or false
in each of the the boxes and they've got
a ticker across beside them so just
delete the one
that you don't think it is does that
make sense so leaving a ticker across if
you agree with it leave the take if you
disagree with it
leave the cross
not all of them
are true and that all of them are false
and some of them anna and i argued over
so
that that that shows that uh
even even those of us who do it all the
time are going to argue over some of
them and that's okay
uh so
the color coded hexis um because
hex hexagons are the best of guns is the
way i look at it
um i'm gonna put you in two rooms so
room one will be um
frank christian and anna and room two
will be uh buck hans and sean and we'll
just start off there i'll give you
seven minutes
to go around the seven questions
okay um but obviously you don't have to
go around them all and i will sort
everybody else out as they come in so i
clicked to open the rooms if you're
in room one start off at the pink top
left hexagon if you're in room two start
the green bottom left
uh hexagon that has all your questions
in it okay
perfect okay
hey erica how you doing
hi how are you
i'm good
hans is there a pop-up that says go to
going to a room or a button at the top
of your window next to the leave button
which says go to room two maybe
enter room two join room two
it's maybe just taking a second to spin
up
oh
we've got a little bit of reverb
i just muted you there because of some
reverb it it's just still spinning up
i've got a little spinner
um there we go and the only person
that's not made it in his hands
i'm going to click ask to join hands you
should have a little pop-up that says go
to room or a button next to the leave
button
at the top of your screen that says
join room
anything
well what i'll do is i will pop erica
i'll pop you in room two
and then i'll uh
try and sort out try and sort out hands
he's the troublemaker today
so i think you should end up in the room
in a couple of seconds erica
yes
cool
okay
oh yes
hands you have a lot of reverb i'm just
muting you again sorry
let's
try and assign you there
so i've clicked to assign you to another
room
let's see what happens
you should
oh well you need him yes
[Music]
perhaps he's now he's gone
okay he's gone
to another room yeah i put them in i put
them in room room one this time
um
so hopefully that will uh will help i
still i've still got a spinner it's
having trouble moving hands i think hans
is the troublemaker this time
it might be the client he might be on
the web client or he might be on
something that's just not quite
responding properly and i don't know
where that reverb is coming from
um
we have somebody else
i'm ruth how are you doing
no living leaving disappeared
yeah
we're we're we're
we're not pleasant enough
i think sometimes
when people pop in and there's only the
two of us here because we're talking
about what's happening in the breakout
rooms and yeah they think they're alone
and they get together and they leave
they're like is it just me
no it's definitely not just just you
um oh i forgot to put a timer on
because i was dealing with hands so i'm
gonna add
uh probably four minutes they've had
three five six seven probably had about
three minutes what do you think anna
i would say four yeah
yeah yeah so i've added four to timer
that's
what they've got left
room one has finished three questions
so that makes sense
room two is not going in
order but that's okay
they don't like the order then yeah they
just don't like the order
that is fair
so i guess we're looking for differences
here between
rooms well yeah what what what other
contentious issues if everybody agrees
but
data scrum is a time for the developers
to provide a status update crosses
as soon as you hear the word status
there's always a cross in there
uh held at the same time in same place
same time in same place i'm not sure it
says that in the scrum guide
anymore
i think it used to say that
but i think it just says
they might not even see anything anymore
are you having a look
yeah i think it says something but not
as specific as before i believe
i'm going to check
i
quite frequently check the scrum guide
it doesn't mean that i'm going to do
what it says
but i want to know whether i'm i'm
saying the right thing sometimes
yeah to reduce complexity it is held at
the same time and same same place every
working day of the sprint okay well
there we go it does still say that
yeah
yeah it's just to reduce complexity
so i i
yeah
that's okay
we can have a debate about that also
well i think everybody agreed that same
time and same place is a good idea but
then
unfortunately nobody uh uh uh
agreed
well maybe they did scrum master is not
required to attend the daily scrum
and we get two green ticks
for not required
that's good
i don't i don't see any inconsistencies
there with the scrum guide but there's
definitely a little bit of confusion
about the scrum master helps
the developers keep the daily scrum
short
i think they are copying each other
because it's the only one that
well maybe they're just they're just
smart people who are picking the same
answers that could be it
yeah yeah
um
i'm just looking in the scrum guide see
if there's anything to do with
scrum master
helping the developers keep it short i'm
actually just gonna search
for the word short
not because
well for
[Music]
shorter sure
shorter shorter
no
i don't see anything about the scrub
master helping them keep it short
but keep to the time there we go and
keep within the time box
are you at somebody's birthday party
uh yesterday was my my older doctors of
birthday
i can i can i can see that oh
welcome back i think uh uh sean and
erica scared peter off
i think that's what happened
let's hope not
how did you get on frank
well we agreed
i i see that there seems to be a lot of
agreement here yeah yeah well there was
one there was one would help
which was of course a uh topic for
discussion the scrum master helping
the team uh or the developers keeping
the uh
what what did it say what was the
phrasing yep
i'm sorry oh yeah yeah
either help or coach or
[Music]
isn't coaching a form of helping i guess
that would be my
yeah
i i yeah we could definitely debate the
term help
yeah i mean it
i would say in general if i'm working
with a team that would be a pedantic
thing to bring up
but in
in this
case where we're all
uh um
practitioners right we can have we can
have those debate debates but i think it
it definitely comes across as a little
bit petty if we try and have those
debates in front of teams
and they
they start to talk about us as religious
zealots
rather than as uh coaches but yeah
um so i saw room one
um which was frank christian anna it was
only one there was one question that was
the question you didn't seem to answer
or you put the cross on top of the tick
was there a reason for that
christian
yeah i mean um
as we said
i don't think anyone would mind if scrub
master you know started helping a
developer daily scrub short
if they
noticed that it was like an hour every
day
oh but just as a blanket statement it's
uh yeah we were like uh
unsure
about it
yeah and i think i think it it
it's good to keep it short but i i
wouldn't really be
um
i wouldn't i don't think i would be
worried
if
it was taking it was taking longer
than 15 minutes i'm going to talk about
15 minutes for a daily scrum
this is this was the conversation that
anna and i had earlier as well
right there might be more things that we
need to talk about
and that's okay and i think it's always
been very explicit
in the scrum guide that it's not a
problem
solving event
it you might if you identify a problem
and you're like we need to have a chat
about something else after the daily
scrum you can end the daily scrum and
immediately have the same group of
people having a conversation about this
other thing that you need to talk about
that's okay
right because how much planning should
we do
enough right as much as you need and no
more so we need to
uh we need to figure that out as we go
yeah right now in how we are working
that we're all working remotely like uh
having those time books so as strict
even though the scrum master need to
keep an eye on the and and keep those
time boxes um
uh we're working not collocated so
that also brings a little bit of
friction uh by not being able to
communicate
uh all you need are trying to be so fast
and sometimes that's the reason it
becomes a status meeting
so
man that's what i'm inclined to do is
set up a 15-minute meeting and then
immediately afterwards set up another
separate 15-minute meeting
uh with the expectation that you don't
the follow-up meeting is the breakout
because i got fed up with people
in scrum these things saying that martin
i must talk to you about x i'm gonna
have i've got a meeting i've got meeting
after this and two business
um
and just in the ideal world never use it
but then no one has got an excuse to go
i'm sorry i got meeting after this yeah
yeah
yeah and that that that's something that
that does quite often
happen
is that um oh i i i couldn't i couldn't
come to the daily scrum today because
i had this customer meeting
right and i i'm probably on the same
page as back here i would say well well
no
you have a customer meeting either
15 minutes later right
what's the big deal for the customer for
15 minutes but you then get to be part
of the daily scrum you're aware of the
context you're part of creating that
plan
that we need
so
not being involved in that context is
very difficult
um and that's that's something that i
think i've told peter before um maybe
anna
but i i i worked in a scrum team in
australia
from scotland it was awesome fun
um my my uh boss at the time adam cogan
um he'd set it up as an experiment for
how messed up could we make a team and
still be successful was his his
experiment
um so i had me in scotland
uh we had two people three people in
beijing
and two people in sydney australia
so the time zone shift i mean there was
there was eight six hours between me and
beijing
and then another four hours between
beijing and
and sydney
right so it's a massive massive time
shift
so i i had to get up at uh six o'clock
in the morning to do my daily scrum
which was evening for everybody else
right this the australians were just
about to go home
and then i would go back to bed
right because it's like six a.m
but one of the difficulties that we had
was what happens if you're in the
situation this was a consulting
organization you get pulled off that
project to go work for a customer for a
little bit
what happens when you come back to your
team
well now now am i going to be disruptive
by turning up and going hey guys what's
going on
right what are we working on today what
are you working on can i help you with
something oh really we're working on it
like that why can we have a conversation
about this architecture that you've
already had but i wasn't involved in so
i want my input to and now i'm being
disruptive
to the team so we actually had a rule
that if you get pulled off and you have
to come back you have to ask
to rejoin the team
and the team might say you can rejoin at
the next
review in retrospective you know come
for the review stay for the
retrospective stay for the next sprint
planning and then you rejoin the team
that way
because then you're less disruptive
because you're involved in the context
then um or
maybe i was away for short enough time
that i could just slide into the team
or maybe frank the team has decided that
they were more effective without me
uh i don't know that i don't know i'm
not actually they'd probably
message you at some point and say yes we
agreed martin was not not useful for the
team
but i know that did happen
um
but i don't remember whether it was me
that's maybe my faulty memory my wife
says i have the same faulty memory if
it's something negative then you delete
it from your brain
but it definitely happened and it's
perfectly reasonable right there's not a
negative thing in that there's
not everybody is great at working with
every group of people
right there are there are people that i
have worked with in the past that i wish
i had the choice not to work with them
in the past no not you peter wasn't you
it wasn't you peter
uh peter and i worked on a a
an engagement previously in a big
consulting company it was a lot of
fun you have a great yes with uh we've
had with a little bit of history
um
but it's it's it's it's one of those
things that you know not everybody's
compatible and that needs to be okay
because we're all humans
yeah so
will we i think we'll we'll uh jump
straight into this why is your daily
scrum ineffective we're going to use the
output a little bit later or at least i
hope we are
um
peter knows about my timing uh problems
uh
so
i'd like to do a little a little one two
four all
for this so i'm going to give you at one
minute on your own to answer the
question
what are all of the activities
that make your daily scrum ineffective
what makes your daily scrum
ineffective okay so i'm going to put one
minute timer on
for you to silently and on your own
come up with a list of things feel free
to add them to the mural if if you want
rather than writing them down i'm okay
with it with both
um and i will create some rooms with
pairs
how many how many people do we have now
anna
oh
we have nine
nine
so that's four four breakout rooms
no
yes
four breakout rooms but then i'll have
to do something
because there's no pinning i can't
exclude somebody from the random
breakout room generation
so now i have to go oh perfect i like it
when it puts you in a
room with
two other people and then i don't have
to go
rearrange a bunch of stuff there we go
so we're going to do a little uh
we're going to do two minutes in pairs
and then roll straight into four minutes
in two pairs
and what i'd like you to do in each
group is when you go into your pairs
take your lists that you just created
and merge them together
so you end up with one list
and then when you go into the room with
your with two pairs
right you'll be bringing two lists again
two merged lists merge them together
again so we have one list since there's
four rooms we should end up with two
lists at the end and then we come back
to the main room we can merge them
together again okay
uh perfect so i'm gonna click uh open if
everybody's on the mural i'll summon to
that spot
for the exercise where you can put these
things in
what makes your daily scrum ineffective
i'm going to change that from activities
to things all of the
things
that make your daily strum ineffective
oh maybe
they can be
oh yeah
oh it's still still opening
totally totally off into the room
yeah
this is this is where this is the bit
that actually sucks when you're doing a
public
one
because if if one person leaves at this
point
yeah it breaks the road it breaks the
rooms because somebody's in a room on
their own when you do pairs and so what
what i did for a while at the start of
doing these exercises was um there's a
way in teams to lock the meeting
i i don't know where it is now there's a
meeting option to to stop more people
coming in
um and that way you at least
stop people hopping in and hopping out
yeah
but we
you cannot um
um
not avoid people let people live in you
can't avoid people leaving no but you
can avoid people popping in for 30
seconds and then disappearing again just
as you're creating the rooms
but that was really bad when we when we
did the first couple of sessions
um but we did everything people signed
up directly in teams
now with the see i think tolu's
not managed to either make it into the
room or he's gone off to do something
else
but luckily he ended up in a room of
peter and anna as well so
oh i'm going to put that one minute
i'm too busy talking to you anna i
forgot about the timer
when you asked about the number i was
sharing the link in linkedin so
it happened the same
four to one
three to two
three to
two
and i don't think i can do anything
about
tolu i'm going to put him unassigned
so i have a big box in front of front of
your face at the moment anna because
i've got the
reassigned participants window up and i
can't move it because it's a model
dialog box
and some ridiculous
uh um
ux design there
we've seen each other a lot today so no
problem yeah
we spent about three hours
putting this workshop together this
morning so
i think that's uh
what what you need is a box for my face
right that's why
so
time's up hit the submit button
i i try and remember to preset up the
move
and then you just hit the submit button
but again if somebody leaves halfway
then when you hit the submit button
teams goes i couldn't move people and
then you have to go move each person
manually that's that that's a pain in
the butt oh but this has worked nicely
this has worked nicely
i i see there is uh there is people that
uh james uh
uh this reworked such
regularly like yeah like anna or peter
yeah p p peter comes really often anna
comes often
julong i think it's been to everyone
erica came to one and then she's been at
everyone since
um and christian was in my class last
week
so
uh uh he's coming along to see to see
what what what it's all about i guess
what we're what we're talking about
um
but he's he's quite an experienced scrum
master he brought
um
to
he brought his ceo
and his product owner to the pspo
um last week which was a lot of fun was
it last week
i think it was last yes it was last week
it all melts together sometimes
you had a busy last week
last week wasn't so bad because i had a
product owner in the morning and the psm
in the afternoon was cancelled
so i had half days
but then i ended up having lots of
little bits of things
but half days are good for
handling those little bits of things
that you don't normally get to handle
the training's the value
and then there's all the other stuff to
do with the focus not to do with
directly to do with the goal that week
needs to be done they need to be done
right you need to do that you need to do
the customer calls uh you need to do the
because i do a lot of um um 30-minute
training reviews
i like assessment reviews
and then
sometimes people just want to chat
so i get coffees on my schedule
and all kinds of things i actually
missed one earlier i had somebody i
wanted to to meet up with
um earlier but i went out
to get lunch just before and ended up
stuck in traffic and i didn't make it
back in time to
jump on that call swipe the message can
we do tomorrow
so
so then a lot of people
uh
book those uh 30 minutes coffee
um i have it limited to to one coffee
per day
and one so there's a bunch of different
types of sessions
um because i've also got the the if you
take a if you take a training class i do
the one-on-one
on hours consulting basically
um so sometimes people book that as well
and i limit that to one per day so i
don't fill up my whole day with
lots of those things
um but it means i have to i actually
have to book all of the training off of
my calendar all the way into the future
at least three weeks into the future so
that
they don't take book over that time
there is one minute fourteen left
there's one big list in one tiny list
yeah i i was uh i was uh chicken with
what they
what they are writing
wow somebody's put taylorism on the big
list that must be the groom that peter's
in
oh well actually
i guess it could be christian or erica
as well as peter anna
or even gee long i guess it could be
anybody
so
multitasking
people talking too much
yes we have that problem
uh taylorism
waiting their turn only
people are not there to listen too much
focus on what i did yesterday
solutioning
no coherent sprint goal
that's definitely impediment
shared ownership too many people
no no coherent team
that sounds harsh
where are we for time it's just 10
seconds left i'm gonna click the close
button at like five seconds cuz
there's a delay
there we go
i always feel like there's less of a
daily for people coming back but
hey guys
hey
hey jovan geelong
christian peter frank
everybody's back awesome
so we had quite a lot of uh things on
that top list there but not so many
things on the bottom list
we didn't get to the filtering uh
we were asking ourselves well it's a one
two four also do we have to you know put
things together and eliminate
uh stuff here for now
so we get to the elimination
well we is that at the top or the bottom
the top at the top okay
uh
oh cool so room two was at the top we'll
get multitasking taylorism
wait waiting their turn only
is that
what what what's that
that's christian i think
yeah it means having the mentality of
just
i'm just showing up i'm waiting my turn
i'm going to speak and uh you know
you're disengaged the whole time all the
time
maybe even maybe even disengage while
you're speaking yourself
you know
i've heard that
yeah not not actually listening when
you're speaking yourself yeah
just reading the name of the card you
know whatever yeah
yeah too much focus on what i did
yesterday
is
is the daily scrum there to
discuss what we did yesterday
is the purpose of the daily scrub to to
talk about what we did yesterday
yeah
yeah i'm just checking anna where that's
coming from it usually flashes
i'm pretty sure it's frank i just muted
frank sorry frank
was it is it it's gone now nope yes no
no
there was just a weird fuzzy
i believe
oh yeah it's rubbing on your
rubbing on your shirt yep
all right i've heard that before yeah my
my my other one is out of battery so
i'll do like this and no
it won't disturb you sorry it's okay
uh peter
what did your group discuss
i put a long list which i just assembled
i was about to drop it into the mural so
there is the damn mural gun
you think you've not been to one of
these peter
i have been wondering
going into the details
recap all of the meetings from the
previous day your team's too big that
can be an impediment
can't it
i'm sorry i was about to drop this
there's mouse moving around so he's
definitely there
yeah i am i just want to
add a sticky right
oh so if you
if you just click in us in a space
there you go
that's the magic way
yeah deep diving too much too much
chitty chat oh it sounds like we've got
some dips people talking too much
oh where's the chitty chat one
too much chitty chat
um
deep dive
sounds like solutioning
um what i'm gonna make your yours a
little bit bigger
there peter they're very small
not start oh
i removed you from the chat apparently
we'll just delete that one
you got all the power
i tried to remove them but it didn't
work he's still here
uh people on multiple projects arriving
late
and leaving early
yeah that's that that meeting block that
we're talking about not engaging
lack of energy
i've seen if there's well there's
there's too many people
with too big
right
people are multiple projects
tech lead
tech team lead as for update meeting
hijacking the meeting for a status
meeting for the team lead is that what
that is peter yeah the uh ask mr k off
uh not sharing no trust not focusing on
value
traders update on a plan
right these are these are a lot of
things that
i know anna and i see as problems in
team after team after team they're not
uncommon problems to to have having all
of them in one team would be a bit scary
um
but they're all uh
reasonable things
that we see that contribute to the
ineffectiveness
of teams
anna would you like to introduce
uh this exercise the card sort
while i um
put the cards in the right place for us
yeah
um
so right now what uh martin is doing we
have uh some cards
uh and we want you to sort them uh based
on um
if
those cards belong to the purpose of the
daily scrum
or they do not belong to to its purpose
okay
and
how are uh martin are we going to
make group make groups two groups or
three groups what number of groups are
we going i was i was thinking that we
should do
three groups and one of us should
participate in a group to make it up to
three
because we all know two people is a
conversation three people's an argument
and we want people to have have some
some some arguments
um so if i do three rooms but just let
let you fall into our room as well
yeah
then we can do that so i've added i've
added the the
the three layouts to the room so you've
got
um this is about the scrum so we've got
purpose and not the purpose
columns
um and a bunch of cards and some of them
go under purpose and some of them wonder
not the purpose
okay it's pretty much that
straightforward so it's sorting the
cards
into those columns let me just quickly
lock the
background there
because otherwise that will be nasty the
cards
are free to roam um and i've loved the
background so i'm going to start a timer
i'm going to give you five minutes
okay
erica had to leave
oh so if your breakout rooms are broken
she might join later but yeah let me let
me uh
i have to leave soon later i have
another meeting in afternoon i'm here ah
so let me let me do uh two rooms then
yeah and that's inside your room i'm
very happy with that i think yeah yeah
i've got i've got i've got you there as
well
okay i've got you guys that's four and
four
um so just use room one in room two and
it at the end of five minutes i'm going
to leave you in the room for an extra
two minutes uh but i'll uncover the
answers
on the right there so you can then go ch
what i guess what we intended to go in
which uh which room okay and which
column
so i've clicked to open it i'll uh pop
into room one and help them out you're
in room two
anna
okay so people on the stream won't see
anything
uh no they will they will follow me
okay they'll follow me because i'm the
host so that's uh that's okay
there we go everybody's in the
off they go and then i'll i'll join room
one so you might see a little flicker
who has control over um mario i'm gonna
sell
[Music]
so eliminate the me the need for other
meetings i would say that's not the
purpose
correct
and then focuses on this progress toward
the sprint goal i would say that's a
purpose
decision making also
help
check for blockers yeah yeah
all right
review the status of each
of each of ongoing tasks i don't think
so it's not the purpose yeah to the
right who else is with us so
peter and martin and
and christian christian i'm here i'm
just finishing up a burger yeah
i'll start i'll start the argument if
not martin i'm not gonna solve the
subject just for fun yeah and that
pulled out the update status to the
right
where is it update status oh yeah update
the status no oh sorry
yeah no they create focus and improve
sales management i would say so
yeah
actual plan for the next day this could
be a game play so it's for the current
day yeah so
and then review what was accomplished
yesterday check the progression of the
sprint goal i would say purpose correct
i missed what was the last one
[Music]
i do think that is the purpose or like
at least part of the purpose of the data
scrub
is you getting everyone together you're
making a plan and then hopefully you
don't have to have a lot of other
regular meetings
okay i would argue about two two things
i'd argue about and one of those i have
to ask martin the question um
martin when you said the next day
did did you mean the 24-hour period from
this moment forward what did you mean
the
because i i assume that you i assume i
would have read that as the next day
meaning from the current day
yeah so i would i would read that as if
we did it at
8 45 in the morning
the next day is today
we're the rest of today the rest the
rest the day the day because but we
might have our daily scrum
at 4 45 o'clock yeah we might have a 4
45 peter we don't want to keep people
after five
um
so we have four
four five 5 45
and then they're planning
the next day so i think
and if you did it at lunch time
maybe it would be
the next day would be until the next
daily
yeah
24 hours does make sense but it's not
phrased that way anywhere anywhere i've
seen it
and then
so
i think that was a clarification of
titles
and then my question was
and then
i i don't think it's about reviewing the
accomplishments
you know
yeah well
you know where do you come from where do
you go
uh
i suppose
i would argue that there's a moment of
trust that when martin said that he was
going to sort out our devops problem and
get us access to the non-production
environment
but yeah yesterday i'll stand up and
then today when anytime he's going to do
something else
i trust martin i know that he's
accomplished that if i really care i go
look it up
so okay
he doesn't need to tell me he's done
that now here's the word review review
that's the wrong word
it's not about reviewing indeed
so
now if if you know
someone in the security police had
stopped in accomplishing what we wanted
to get done then i would expect him to
say
um didn't do x
i'm going to get that down today or
i can't do it we'll just push it into
next week which isn't she's really just
talking about blockers and things it's
not not a review per se would be my my
opinion there
i i think i agree
so that would mean this
right
it'll be my view
yeah
and i think what christian said
eliminate the need for other meetings i
what i my problem i have a problem with
the word eliminate
i think even in the scrum guide it says
something like that you know developers
will meet whenever it's necessary but at
least you have one
or something to that end
it's not its primary purpose if it
accomplishes that then that's great
we've got a side effect
yeah yeah we've got a byproduct it's
perfect to know what we're doing in the
next 24 hours
i am going to open out the answers
over here
um and i'll just try and bring a copy of
the answers across for you because that
will
because chris christian is correct
on his
okay
so that one eliminates the need for
other meetings is a direct quote from
the scrum guide
so
in the scrum guide it says daily scrum
improve daily scrums improve
communications identify impediments
promote quick decision making and
consequently eliminate the need for
other meetings
okay there you go there you go
all right and then you've given all of
the meetings
yeah it doesn't save all other meetings
right there's still going to be other
things we still have to meet with the
customer we still have to
you know
do refinement we still need to do all of
those things but we want to minimize
the the the number of other meetings
um so there's one
extra one you've oh i should
that's my uh bad let me
there we go
um
so which is the one that you've got on
the left so the one
that you had incorrect on the right hand
side was eliminate the need for other
meetings
right that one there's one on the left
that shouldn't be there
promotes quick decision making creates
focus improves it checks up there we go
yep
checks if we have individual or team
blockers
is uh definitely not the purpose
all right so i'm just going to go back
to the main room and then call everybody
back okay
i
oh these were getting better i had an
audio failure there i had a little
geelong are you still with us
nope too long's not still with us
maybe he is yes
it's so such a nice workshop i don't
want to leave you know so i have no
choice
anna and i spent three hours on it this
morning so
um
yeah so 12 30 to 12 o'clock normally i
have the meeting between one two and
afternoon before it was okay right now
now yeah you'll have you'll have to move
that other meeting
that's
um
so my in in in my room anna we had we
had two
ended up in the wrong place which was
eliminate the need for other meetings
ended up on not the purpose and check if
we have
individual or team blockers ended up on
purpose
yeah in in
in my room the same about the blockers
uh ended up in purpose and also
um
review what was accomplished yesterday
and check the progress of the
springboard those two
yeah because that that that um those
three questions that used to be so
prevalent in the daily scrum what did we
do yesterday
what are we doing today and what's
blocking us
is the reason for those two things
but
those questions
were only ever defined
as a complementary practice to help us
get to the outcome that we want which is
re-planning the next
day's work
yeah and sometimes answering those
questions ended up in a status report
yeah
and and and in fact i i would
think i i would
i would put those questions what did i
do yesterday what am i
doing today
what's blocking me
doesn't sound like very team orientated
questions or very goal orientated
questions
right so i i do
very much prefer looking at the value
in and saying here's a piece of value on
the board
is it progressing is it something we
need to talk about and then all the
people that are involved in delivering
that value can can can talk about it
together or maybe only one person talks
because that's that's
what makes sense for that moment in time
right there's no requirement for
everybody to speak in a daily scrum
magic recipe for the
for the daily scrum uh
it can be very different from one day to
another depending on what the team needs
yep there's no formula
that's going to apply to every daily
scrum
the thing that we're supposed to get out
of it
is a plan for the next 24 hours for the
next day's work
i think as soon as you the formula
you remove the crutch and you make life
harder you're suddenly saying to people
plan some value for me well no no all i
want to do is i did this yesterday i'm
doing this today and i'm blocked by
something that's i can walk away now
where if you say
plan me some value
that's such a much harder question they
have to think about it they have to look
at what what's the things that we're
doing how the impacting what we're
trying to achieve
and figure out what's the best next
thing to do to get value moving across
yeah you're right peter that's hard
yeah you know peter you know what what
i'm doing right now i'm i'm sending the
uh in a team i'm sending people into
breakup rooms to discuss
um i'm not there and they discuss in
between them and then they come back and
they share
so they are the one the ones that need
to to build that plan and i'm not
involved and they need to they don't
need to report to anybody
so
i first it that way they analyze the
data they have and
they come back with with a plan
so
during the stand up
you
divide them in breakout rooms and then
within say five minutes
yeah they come back and they share their
individual plan yeah and they um they uh
then in the main room they come together
uh to a plan they agree on a plan okay
but does that mean that the breakout
sessions or the breakout rooms also
automatically lead to some kind of
cooperation between those yeah yeah yeah
exactly and
it's like when when martin sent you into
two four one oh yeah yeah it's the same
yeah it's the same idea same same
techniques but do you let them decide
themselves no which breakout session
they will join no it's uh i do it
differently every every day
so the the way the way i do it when i'm
creating breakout rooms and it's
actually the easiest way because the
tools support it the best is you just
create random rooms
yeah so it doesn't really matter who's
together
right and that's actually kind of a good
thing and it's kind of why i do random
rooms for every different exercise as
well so even if you did two rounds
of those planning you put people with
different groups of people so you get
different ideas different pollination uh
coming out of it each time
um if you put the same people together
all the time you'll get the same answer
all the time yeah yeah
and it's great having uh the designer of
a team of the team with the backhander
of the can
decide and share so
yeah
having having cross-functional is is is
but do they come up with a joint plan or
a individual plans
uh
they come with with a dream plan about
them well
of course each one has to um uh do
different things but they share it and
they
come to the main burn and share and for
this move here zubachanderson they
decide together so it's like
it's it's an agreement with the team
okay so
so yeah the way the way i think about it
is that you send them out to breakout
rooms they each come up with their plan
they bring it back to the main room and
then you're joining those two plans
right if you get two breakout rooms you
join those two plans together but they
might individually and separately come
up with very different ideas
about how we should proceed
and you get them back together and one
group's like oh yeah we never thought of
that
right and if we were just in the main
room they might not have thought of that
at all they might have only picked one
way because maybe there's
frank do you remember we talked about
before we went um live we were talking
about board games for a little bit yeah
and we talked about pandemic
yeah and you've got that that that hero
that runs the story and tries to
tell everybody i can't remember what
it's called in gaming right there's a
name for that type of person the alpha
player who's trying to tell everybody
else how to do the thing because they
know best how to win
right rather than letting people make
their own decisions discover
mistakes themselves and by doing
breakout rooms
you're effectively isolating that alpha
player
from the other room's discussions
yeah
i i think that's quite an interesting
technique i mean
i would say i'm dying to try it with uh
with a live team but i do it all the
time in in
in courses with groups of
people who are trying to solve solve
problems and come up with idl
very rarely
do i do breakout rooms in a class giving
everybody the same question and you get
four rooms come back with exactly the
same
story
right everybody comes up with different
ways to solve the problem and it starts
another discussion
which is great
uh
i have a question regarding uh the one
on purpose like review what was
accomplished yesterday let's check the
progression of the sprinting goal
uh
i doubted about that and said
like for during the daily we could talk
about the progression of the spreading
goal
if we are on track or not even we are
building a plan we needed to uh make
sure the line is on track towards the
progression of the spreading goal right
yeah and if it if if that card had just
said uh review progress towards the
sprint goal
then then i would definitely have it on
the left
but review what was accomplished
yesterday as the red herring
right that's the bit that negates that
that that that statement and puts it on
the right
it's not about
i i don't really care what was
accomplished yesterday
are we currently and how do we move
forward
is the important discussion
how do we plan what's next
because remember
so julian something something i think to
remember is that um
this is not the only time that the team
ever talk to each other
this is just the defined time for us to
get together and re-plan what's next
i would expect a professional team to be
talking to each other constantly
to be updating each other when they have
problems and oh i'm stuck i'm going to
involve some other team members and see
if anybody can help um and and
collaborate with them if i finish a task
i'm not going to go pull something new
first i'm going to see if anybody on my
team needs some help
right so if we're if we're working in
that collaborative way
then we should be able to keep the daily
focused on the thing that we want which
is what are we going to what's the most
important thing for us to do over the
next
day's work
to get towards our goal
yeah
i i think yeah i know that i know the
the main point for this activity but
personally i still uh
feel the
review what was coming yesterday
and
another one check if we have individual
or team blockers these two
are still something that we could uh
bring up during the daily
i think you can certainly bring it up
yeah right we're definitely not saying
don't bring it up
but not the purpose does that make sense
like if it helps if it serves the team
to help us get to the purpose
do it
if you find that that stops working for
you because what happens a lot is you do
it the same all the time and then you
become mechanical
everybody's just answering the question
like a robot so i can get back to work
and not have to talk with anybody
anymore
right and i don't care what you're
working on and i don't care what i'm
working on either
um so so
keep changing it up keep doing it
differently do breakout rooms if they
make sense if you find people are being
too mechanical switch it up instead of
focusing on
what did i do yesterday have a daily
scrum we're gonna do something different
today we're gonna look at the
work item aging graph uh for our sprint
and we're gonna we're gonna make some
decisions based on that or we're bored
with that we're gonna look at something
else oh we missed some stuff maybe we
should go back to look at that aging
graph or
have lots of experiments do it
differently every time
people get bored real quick when you do
the same
one of the tenets of training from the
back of the room
is different trump's same
right doing things differently
is better more more cognitively
rewarding
than if you do it the same every time
even if you do it differently and then
oh we had a crap daily scrum okay well
it was one
crap daily scrum
right that's okay it's not the end of
the world
that we had one crop daily scrum
so for this activity
we just needed to figure out what's the
purpose but in fact even those
items are not of the
they can still be used during the day
yes
absolutely
except when they inhibit the purpose
because the purpose is the over the
thing we're trying to do
and i do see quite often some of those
things which is why and i added them to
the list because we do sometimes see
those things or sometimes often see
those things inhibiting our ability to
get to the outcome that we're trying to
achieve
with the daily
so we just need to be careful right uh
there are certain things that that we
know work and we know don't but there's
also things that sometimes they work and
sometimes they don't and sometimes they
work for a while and then they stop
working
right i'm pretty sure that the teams i
work with will get
soon bored about the breakout and
breakouts and i will have to figure out
something else
yeah thank you
i'll see you next time see you next time
hopefully hopefully you can rearrange
that other meeting that you have
thank you have a good day bye
so
we have uh how many do we have now we
have sev six people oh well that
actually that actually works out well
for asana because that makes the next
exercise easier
um easier for me
for you because i wouldn't be able to to
split the rooms and do that
yeah you need you need to be a little
bit of a teams breakout room guru to do
to do this one we're gonna we're gonna
do an an impromptu networking
exercise where um we're going to we're
going to break out into pairs
and we should really uh hide those other
uh questions anna we didn't do that
earlier
there we go
i'll just hide it like that there we go
perfect
super simple
and what we're going to do it we're
going to we're going to do
um
well let's
let me create three breakout rooms
because there's six of us
and we'll do pairs
so three breakout rooms hopefully nobody
else leaves in between otherwise
that's
a little bit of the
downside of public events is if i have
you in a in a private or public training
you're trapped because you've paid to be
there
right but if uh
if not then sometimes although
you know i had private ones sometimes
people have emergencies that they have
to drop off for so
it's just less likely
so i'm gonna do impromptu networking
we're gonna do pairs
uh so i've got rooms one two and three
and you can see that i have columns here
with room one room two and room three
the blue the pink and the purple columns
and i'd like you to discuss in your pair
that question so the first question is
what would happen if we don't have a
daily scrum
okay so adding some post-its uh in that
space uh would make sense and answering
that question as a as a pair
at the end of two minutes so you'll have
two minutes to answer the question
and i'm going to
move one person from each pair to the
next room
okay so you'll be with you'll still be
in a pair but it will be another person
and then i'll do it again
for the third question so you'll have
three different pairs within the same
meeting i did say it needs me to do use
my microsoft teams kung fu
uh to make that happen good luck with
that
i i i have done it before with 12 people
successfully i have done it before with
30 people very unsuccessfully
um yeah the more more people the more
complicated it is
so what i'm going to do is i'm going to
open the the room and um one of you will
stay in the existing room and the other
person will move to the next incremental
room or i will completely mess it up
that's the other option that might
happen
i think christian i did it successfully
with your group didn't i
i did yes
that was that was when it did work
successfully
um
but it means i've got a little bit of
homework to do to get it all to organize
right
so
christian is pinned
sean is pinned
and
frank is pinned
okay
and they're starting at one
two three
you literally need a little a little
table of yeah it's kung fu to oh sean's
back
did something happen sean
yeah i couldn't uh it was asking me to
join again
uh at the at the top of your this
meeting window next to the leave button
do you have a go to room button
perfect
thank you you're welcome
yeah he just get kicked out
like a
network snafu
okay
so i have my notes i've got two minutes
on the timer
they're creating their ideas
okay so we have room okay yeah room one
how many rooms do we have three
sunny's here it's unfold
oh yes that's okay it's
if you drop out and then come back in
and then click the button to go to the
room it puts you on hold
okay it's just a it's a characteristic
it's not a bug it's a characteristic of
the
characteristic tool
it's a feature
well it is a bit weird i would rather
everybody went on hold
than they left the meeting which is what
happens in the list so that you get this
little message saying they've lost
access to the chat and then they rejoin
and have access to the chat again but no
history it that bit's annoying
um but they're working on it that's
actually a bug it's not supposed to do
it that way
so 50 seconds left so let me
start up my engine of madness
um so frank
is going to
one
oh that's the
all right this is the people that are
moving christian
is going to two
and sean
is going to three okay
so that will be
three
one
two
i like one that they're right in here
people will at some point
set up something equivalent but quite
possibly only with a subset of the team
that's enough
yep right i'm gonna click the button
[Music]
open out question two
and add two minutes
up peter's going sideways instead of
vertically
i'm waiting for it to all set up and
then i can click the broadcast button
and say move on to question two
yeah so the little broadcast button the
way
teams works very differently completely
differently from zoom from a mechanical
perspective
right what it what it's actually doing
when you create breakout rooms is it's
creating
completely separate independent meetings
in teams so they can actually click the
record button in there they can they can
do all use all of the tools
um and then
when i do a broadcast it just sends a
message to each room
so if i go to my chat
in teams it's got all of the rooms and
all of the messages for all of the
classes so i might do 20 different
breakout rooms for a class
and you end up with room ones all over
the place in room twos it's a bit mental
um
i
yes i can i can see what i i'm
[Music]
thinking i want to do
this
so that they move on to
you
well i'm either that or i'm making life
painful for them
that is also an
option uh
let me get uh
because there's only 14 seconds left
[Laughter]
oh
i don't know if they know that they need
to answer the second question
uh
yeah they've started
so let me i've got to do the assignment
madness again so
frank
is going to room
two
except i've got him listed in room two
so i've completely balls this up
sean
is going to room one
and christian
is going to room three
so the numbers i wrote down
are crap
but
i'm picking i'm picking the right people
so that part is working out
i think people uh join some of these
sessions just to laugh at my
ability to do stuff that's what i think
maybe
maybe that's why i'm here
you're my you're my support
well we have found a bug with this
exercise that people
i didn't seem to explain it properly to
move to the next question
yeah but um we'll see what people did
when they come back maybe they answered
the next question but in the same role i
don't know
maybe it's a little confusing like when
you move to the other uh
to another room you have to skip to
another question so
yeah
well yeah i could have done a better job
of blocking off
and having uh
we knew that this was going to be a
little bit
yeah this is there's an experiment here
for sure
yeah but next time we'll know to have it
like a blind
that goes down and and
stop some editing above yeah
[Music]
oh i can hear my audio problem
is transferring out to
the stream so apologies if you're on the
stream i have an audio problem with
teams i am on a beta version of teams
um and
this week i have had a weird audio noise
that when i do breakout rooms if i go
into a breakout room and come back
it breaks the audio and i get a tone
but if if it happens and anna speaks it
goes away
so okay yeah so we just have to let anna
speak and i'll shut up there we go
i don't know if i
if i would manage to to do this on my
own so
speak please
well i'm going to close the rooms
because i think we've had two minutes in
that team i didn't set a timer because
we were trying to unsnafu them
um but i'll bring them back
oh you're joven
um
it would be so cool if scenes had that
feature like uh three second counter
like
yeah to go back to the main room or like
a zoom zoom zoom mutes you when you come
back to the main room
but i actually find that really annoying
because i i'm a teams user i'm not
expecting to be muted when i go back to
the main room so
um yeah that's kind of uh
what happens a little bit there
so
um
so what
what what happened about
in my explanation
uh that was lost on me yeah cool no they
were progressing downward
and i think i started
deleting the black arrows because you're
like what the hell are these things
doing here
pasting black arrows
i'm sorry about that yeah no it was it
anna and i totally agreed that it was it
was my dysfunction there either not
explaining it properly or not i i should
have had the arrows in it and the arrows
appeared as i moved the thing down that
would have been better but i see it's
it's kind of it's kind of worked out i
can delete the arrows now
um
so anna would you like to debrief
sorry would you like to debrief this one
oh
yeah so
in
room one
about what would happen if we
don't have a daily scrum let's see what
we have in in the three rooms
um
anything that you see that uh
we have a pattern in here
a lot of
sync meetings
slower
slower decision making
less focus
oh
so anything
yep
less alignment
and something that i
really found very interesting was people
will at some point set up
something equivalent but quite possibly
only with a subset of the team
but for the us um
i never thought about that but it was uh
surprisingly true
did it happen to any one of you this
absolutely
okay
yeah clandestine meetings
with
decisions coming from it
that are not shared yes
so should we jump to the next uh
question martin or
uh
i
let's see on the time
i i'm not sure are you what
to the second question
yes i think we have time for that
sorry i was i was i was planning
planning what's next in my head there
so we have here high risk of not
reaching it and lack of pure feedback
um
so this is uh what happens with uh if we
don't focus on the spring goal
do you want to share anything about this
we wrote it
i would say
the first one's obvious and there's not
rich you can't not focusing on it how
long you're going to get there but i
think the other one is slightly more
more interesting
which is
people might say well what about po
feedback
well
if you're not focusing on the goal if
you are focused if you are focusing on
the goal
then you're going to be suddenly saying
about
should this be blue or green
and someone will go off and say to the
product owner do you want this blue or
green at which point you get some
feedback and you do an in sprint
correction
if you're just
plowing along and
doing whatever the hell it is you know
making bottles
them or or not focusing on whatever the
goal is
you know is this red wine or white wine
um
what is the time now
i watched the pub in 15 minutes
um
stay focused
and again i suppose that's about value
focus on the goal i don't know what any
issues are about reaching that goal if
you need to course correction with your
po go off and talk to your po
yeah and i believe that leaves with uh
with the next question because if you
don't have a goal
you cannot build a plan to reach
something right
so risk and waste will be made lack of
focus non-delivery
um
success exactly it's accidental and no
alignment
so
yeah so some some some teams
think that they're just unpredictable
right their predictability is low
but it can often be that they don't have
a goal so success then becomes
accidental
why do we fail so many sprints
right oh because your goal is complete
these 12
right so
you might make it you might not and it
will be random chance on whether you do
or you don't right how do the how do the
dice roll this
uh
this sprint
yeah
so yeah without a without a spring goal
we cannot plan to get to that uh to that
goal
and without a daily um there is no
a specific moment uh to plan on the day
to reach that spring goal so everything
is is really linked
okay
yeah
christian's furiously writing down
things
he's a christian's a notetaker
he's not actually ignoring us
so i think we should jump to the the
conclusion anna because we have 11
minutes
oh yeah yeah yeah
see i'm doing better at the time thing
peter
yeah feedback is golden yes exactly
um
so i think if we've got we can do uh two
minutes each
on the what so what now what
um what i'd like you to do is um just
individually
right and we're gonna do three rounds
we're gonna have two minutes for each
round
um and in round one we're gonna we're
gonna answer
those questions there are to help
right
what happened
what did you notice
what facts or observations stood stood
out and you can go have a look around
the around the mural how people answered
to get some of those
um
ideas so what what what do you think was
what happened during this
um this this workshop so i'll put two
minutes on
um and i'll i'll do my usual hiding so
we're just adding
i'm not sure what you are
[Music]
to think about um what what we talked
about what
you learned and what happened
during during this sprint was there
something that that stood out for you
that's actually what's the group what's
the critical what's the critical lesson
that i've learned
yes
what happened and then okay
i hate to say
i'll write it more than the same
nothing is an okay answer peter
no no
one always learns something in life
i'll go
mute actually your audio has been okay
since since i feel like well i i had
another
microphone it was
fully charged yeah yeah
breakout sessions
i i i still
would like to talk about that a little
more a breakout session during the
during the planning uh during the daily
stand up
i um how that pans out anna
do you have do you have a little bit of
time to go over
yeah so i anna anna can hang out for a
little bit and talk about that i i
actually have a reasonably hard stop
at well 7 p.m for me but in in nine ish
minutes because i have to go meet up
with ralph jochem and help him with some
mural stuff
um for his class that he's doing next
week and this was the time that we had
so
i'm gonna gonna go off and do that but
anna anna will be able to host everybody
who's here
um but it will be off stream so maybe
that's a good thing
okay so i'm gonna open up round two
so don't be typing in round one now
that's uh
round one it's finished
why is that important
right
what patterns or conclusions
might be emerging
maybe what hype
i don't understand frank while why
keyboards still come with a caps lock
key that's what i don't understand oh
yeah yeah yeah
i know i do it too and you accidentally
hit it and then you end up with
lowercase first letters
i do it all the time
and
unfortunately i've got a keyboard where
you can't remove the keys very easily so
i'd like to remove the caps lock key and
the insert key yeah yeah those are two
completely useless keys yeah but you
can't do it with this one i've got we've
got the same keyboard
yeah yeah the light of the caps lock is
doesn't light up anymore
oh mine does light up but um that
doesn't help me because i don't look at
it
nice setup with mural uh martin
uh it's my comp i'd like to compliment
you
it has taken a lot of iterations to get
um
my murals but literally i've got a drag
and drop capability for most of the
things now
and i was always like this is the
exercise we should have and then i
replace it with this one that looks with
all of the
the the the
setups but yeah
thanks for every kind of exercise for
every liberating structure because
when you live in mural
because i'll quite often um
like i'll spend at least
what what are what are uh i'll spend at
least 16 hours a week if not 24 hours a
week in mural yeah yeah
so but you did quite a time investment
in developing all those templates yeah
yes
refining them
and then uh yeah but it really pays off
well i i don't me though but uh
you know yeah the only i as i i always
say if if i
had this i've opened out round three
and in round three it's
oh i've er left the same text but what
now
let me delete that text because it's
confusing what now what could you what
could you do now what could you change
in the way
you do things next
i like that improvement requires effort
i know that's a good one
sorry
there's a in in round two there's an
improvement requires effort yeah and i
think that's what a lot of people
take time to realize
yeah well and i have to say that um
um i've been trying uh in the dailies to
do this
experiments
and
it it doesn't work at first
you you have to try it several times so
that the team starts uh engaging with it
and
for example
sharing metrics and and and helping them
understanding the metrics i know that
the scrum masters are not in a daily to
facilitate
but we need to help that event to be
effective
and positive
and
there are a lot of techniques that can
be used on start metrics and i use flow
metrics the overall the aging work in
progress i believe that in the scrum.org
there's the kanban guide for scrum teams
and then there's the professional scrum
with kanban class
uh which i'm actually i'm running one
next week
yeah i saw it yeah i think in the other
next to assets there's the the emblem of
uh scrambled or psk oh yes that's so
um we we
we're going to spend a little bit of
time talking about the metrics but time
time caught up with us as it always does
and we thought we'd left enough room
um
but
that's it's always not true right it's
always not true
but
the way i think about it frank is all of
these things that i build in mural are
just invitations to a conversation
uh yeah
yeah and bright colors and nice looking
you know structures do help
simple as that and i i think it's even
more in the virtual world than in the
physical world
because in especially when you go into
to to meetings and events and uh you're
doing things online
you need a little bit more guidance a
little bit more focus so that we're all
on the same page um so i i do do a
number of workshops where i just start
with a blank mural
yeah yeah um and just use it to put
notes on and have ideation and
it it it really does help but all of my
scrum dog classes use these these types
of templates
um because there's just so many things
to cover and so many things to talk
about
yeah
in the physical world
when i run workshops i do like to have
as many different color it's a number of
different shaped post-its and a number
of different
colored sharpie pens and i bought
another maybe 40 different colors in it
and you just tip these out into the
middle of the table and people think oh
i want the bright pink one or i want the
bright blue one so at least it just
makes it
not heavy yellow post-its and a heap of
black sharpies and yeah
lighting some buns
i have i have a a graveyard of in-person
class
stuff piled up here and i have another
graveyard of in person class stuff in
that corner over there yeah yeah
the the the i
i'm i'm planning i'm getting a new
computer in the next couple of weeks
it's actually almost shipped christian
so that's that's good uh getting this
really powerful new computer um and i'm
gonna clean out this room and i'm
basically putting all of the in person
class stuff in the attic
um i i much prefer
the engagement that i get with people in
the live virtual space
um i've been i've got a blog post that
i'm working on where i'm analyzing the
data from all of my classes
um so specific specifically for
scrum.org classes i've done
67 classes since lockdown
began
all live virtual classes and i've got
data of how many people pass the
assessments i've got people that have
done trust pilot reviews
so i've got all of my trustpilot data
i've got all of my assessment outcome
data um and i'm putting a blog post
together to to to look at
um
why i think it's better
so you you compare in person you're in
person yep scores
yep okay interesting and i have i have i
have a average
for example i have all of the assessment
scores for everybody that's taken a
class with me that took an assessment
and i've got averages for each total
averages and averages for each class as
well
um
so but you need to say that you're going
to clear out that cupboard with all
these board games you're gonna put them
in so it will give me room for more
board games
okay because i i wouldn't do that i
would leave them there i'm going to
leave them there but i have i have all
of i have all this posters and all kinds
of things in that in that space that
needs to go and more stuff over here
that all needs to go yeah
um
yeah
so i but nothing beats a board game with
a group of people and they're sharing a
table eh no absolutely absolutely we've
been doing a lot of live virtual uh
board games which is not as good
um
but i definitely like that that
camaraderie that
feeling of just just playing them
together even if when you're playing a
euro game and there's not really that
much collaboration between like a lot of
a lot of the the the really heavy euro
games there's very little contact
between people you're just playing
against each other for score
um but it's still it's still a lot of
fun and definitely cognitive yeah
peter's got to go to the pub
he's going to get
going to get blue turd
bye-bye bye
well i'm i'm i'm hoping um that i'm i'm
going to leave you as well with with
anna um i've summoned everybody in the
mural to the to the to the feedback wall
so any feedback would be good maybe what
next sessions you would like i did
notice anna that almost everybody that
came this time was a practitioner
um so maybe we can we we're not doing a
introduction to next time maybe we need
to do a more advanced
uh
topic maybe we need to go go spelunk the
the pspo2 or the psm2 and see if we
can't find some interesting things to
talk about for the next time
well
you know i did get some nice ideas and
it's always good to share you know with
other people uh
i mean the topic was
it was quite basic of course but
nonetheless you know
and you don't control uh the
participants i know that problem no so
yeah some
some sessions we get lots of lots of
noobs and that's great as well and
sometimes we get lots of practitioners
and it's honestly it's different
questions
right it's different questions we go
different level of depth into things and
and that's cool too
so um
yeah and the most difficult of course is
when you have
those two groups in one session yes how
can you cater to both that's not what
well what's interesting is i i do it
actually well i do it the same way that
i do it in physical classes
right well physical you know what i mean
in in professional classes is i i i make
sure they
understand that part of their job is to
help coach people in the different
groups they're in
not give away the secrets
right yeah uh and and see
how
those conversations pan out with people
and see how you can shape them and so be
being a lean agile practitioner in the
in the sessions as well and that can be
a lot of fun
um because
christian is a is a is an advanced
practitioner and he was in my pspo uh
last week with some folks he knows um
and he was a lot of help in the in the
in the sessions striving some of the
conversation coming up with some of
those ideas explaining things in a
different way than i would uh which
helps people understand which is great
yeah
so i i am we are going to wrap up the
the the stream anna is definitely going
to hang out for a little bit because i
know frank has some additional questions
in minutes
later yeah
just uh
yeah we're wrapping up right now yeah so
i am just going to i am going to wrap up
the stream