worst trait in unskilled scrum Masters
is probably
their thinking that they're the boss of
everybody thinking that they should be
telling people what to do thinking that
they should be micromanaging thinking
that they should be setting up the jira
environment thinking that they should be
allocating the work and all of that is
just crap that's nothing to do with
being a scrum Master being a scrum
Master is about helping teams be more
effective and all of those things I
can't think of an easier way to make a
team ineffective
focus on what helps the team stand on
their own be better at what they do
being visibly present
and yeah