[Music]
most managers today are just expected to
be leaders as well they're given no
training no Direction they're just
magically supposed to come up with these
skills themselves and that's just not
always the case there are exceptional
people that don't need uh um any
additional uh input of knowledge that
they're able to go off and find out all
of this stuff themselves and put it into
effect
but most of us benefit from a little bit
of a helping hand um so we have the the
agile leadership class which focuses on
um a manager transitioning into that
servant leadership idea where they're
providing services to the team they're
enabling a team to be
effective um at the organization level
so that's somebody who is who is learn
learning how to delegate um learning how
to hire the right people um learning how
to um connect the people doing the work
with the outcomes that we're trying to
achieve and all of those things are part
of the professional adual leadership
class um but in addition to that as a
leader it's important to understand how
the the the changes that we're making in
the
organization B benefit the overall
organization increase the effectiveness
of the overall organization and for that
we have the evidence-based management
class as well where we're looking a
little bit more deeply into how we
measure people what the impact of those
measurements are and how can
we maximize the
effectiveness in and how do we measure
that right that's effectively what it is
how do we measure that and so it's very
important that we understand all of
those things as a a leader in an
organization um so that we can make the
right choices and know for sure that
we're making progress in in the right
direction because we've designed a bunch
of measures that are unique to our organ
our product or our organization uh to
help us see whether we're making
progress towards the overall outcomes
that we're trying to achieve um
and most managers and leaders don't
measure those things they don't have a
have a holistic understanding of where
the organization currently is where the
organization's currently going and how
we're going to measure uh that progress
towards it and that really those two
things are are part of the key focus of
both the professional agile leadership
class and uh the evidence-based
management class to help leaders gain
additional skills s on top of the
awesome ones they already have to help
them be to be as effective within the
context of agel as possible if you want
to have a discussion about your unique
needs or situation then please book a
call or visit us at naked agility tocom
uh we also have our immersive and
traditional public classes on our
website and we'd love to hear from you