one of the key agile virtues that's
often overlooked in organizations is
diligence and diligence is that
attention to detail it's doing the
things that need done having that level
of focus that enables those things to
happen it's having a definition of done
and following it not just it's on the
wiki right you actually follow it
everybody on your team has the diligence
to understand the definition of done
know the direction and the grit to
follow it right you're not just paying
lip service to this uh uh level of
quality your your your definition of
done is your compliance bar for what
needs to happen in order for your
product to be able to ship and that is
the diligence that your organization
expects the reason organizations and
businesses don't really talk about
definition of done from a leadership
perspective is because it's just
expected that we'll have a level of
quality that they're able to use that's
just just the
default but unfortunately it's not the
default in many
teams so have the diligence to create a
level of quality meet it follow it and
perhaps expand it and increase your
level of diligence increase your level
of quality in your product in the way
you approach the work in the way you
approach working with others and make
your organization successful if you are
having difficulty getting the most out
of the Seven Virtues of agility then my
team at NE agility can help you or find
a consultant coach or trainer who can
it's essential for you to find help as
soon as you can and not wait use the
links below to get in touch because you
don't just need agility you need naked
agility