one of the key agile virtues
is one of the key agile virtues is
charity and that that
manifests in in in our world as things
like be being willing to help each other
for no specific gain right I want to I
want to help my colleagues on the team
because it helps us all not because I
get something out of it I want to be
looking at um making sure that my team
is successful that my product is
successful that my company is successful
and I'm not necessarily doing it because
I get my bonus I'm I'm I'm doing it
because it helps the people around me
that we're all better because of it and
that we're able to create the best uh
possible products for our customers that
that leads back to Dan Pink's autonomy
Mastery and purpose right I want to feel
like the work that I do
matters and charity is part of that
right uh for example I'm a Microsoft MVP
I don't get that mvp for paid work I get
that mvp for spending time in the
community providing help and support to
other for free and I do that both in the
technical space and in the agile space
if you want to have a chat you can go to
my website and book a coffee and we can
talk about agile we can talk about the
things that are happening in your
organization and if in half an hour I
can fix your problem that's great we've
had a coffee we've had a chat and you
get something to try that might result
in success right I I don't I don't do do
that for direct renumeration I do that
because I like helping people I like
other people being successful I want
organizations to be successful in agile
because that helps all of us all the
employees of the company the entire
thing the entire ecosystem and that's
charity if you are having difficulty
getting the most out of the Seven
Virtues of agility then my team at naked
agility can help you or find a
consultant coach or trainer who can it's
essential for you to find help as soon
as you can and not wait use the links
below to get in touch because you don't
just need agility you need naked agility