[Music]
my name is Martin I work for a company
called naked agility in Scotland doing
digital transformations DevOps agile
with lots of customers I
want to talk a little bit about the vs
TS sync migration tools but the first
thing I want to mention is that there
are more than one there's more than one
option for migrating from TFS to VST s
if you are taking you want to take your
entire collection
so you want to migrate your entire
organization from TFS to the STS then
the primary option you should be
considering is the VST S migration
services from Microsoft
this tool is a full fool ish fidelity
service if you go to the URL at the
bottom of the screen there you will be
able to see the caveats for what they do
but they basically take your entire
database your collection and the import
into the STS this means that you will
have a little bit of downtime depending
on the size of your collection I've done
small collections from I don't know
50 50 gig 58 collection that took a
couple of hours to do the migration and
I've also done a two terabyte two and a
half terabyte collections which took 40
40 odd hours to do the migration
the bigger the data the more complicated
it is moving that amount of data around
because you have to get it up into
onto a juror and then Microsoft have to
pull from that location into their
service which then processes your data
into VSDs but it is as close to filt
fidelity as you will get and Microsoft
are working to make that full fidelity
migration as powerful as possible so if
you have an option take the VST s
migration services option that is your
primary go to if however you have a
different scenario maybe you don't want
to move
your entire collection just now you only
want to move a few team projects up to
the STS or M you have five projects in
TFS and you want to end up with one team
project in V STS or you have one project
in TFS and you want to end up with 5 and
V STS then the V STS migration service
from Microsoft is not going to be able
to fill that need that's one of the
reasons that I created the V STS sync
migration tools its coped by query so
basically if you can query it there are
certain things that are the bounds of
the team project we'll talk about those
as we go through but it's generally
scoped by query and it is not even close
to full fidelity I've written a bunch of
processors I've had help from many
contributors to the project to add
additional
processors that are importing data from
one TFS /v STS location to another so
because the tools don't really care
where your data is and where it's going
to you can do TFS two-tier fast TFS the
VST SV STS to tier 5 TF fast you can
split team projects you can merge team
projects you can pull a subset of the
data out of one push it into another you
can do bulk updates you can do all sorts
of things I did I have done bulk updates
where
the customer wanted to migrate from the
agile template in TFS to the scrum
template in TFS so one of the tools that
I used to do that was this one with the
bulk update I have a bulk update
processor in there and you can give a
bunch give it a bunch of field mappings
and it allows you to process the data
from one format into another format in
place on your TFS server so you can
basically migrate process template you
can do all sorts of things it's a pretty
versatile tool set unfortunately with a
versatile tool set comes a lot of
complexity hence there's been a lot of
asks from users of the system for maybe
a little bit of an intro walkthrough
figure out how to how to move this
through
so just our word on support for these
tools who supports them well ultimately
I do mostly but there are a bunch of
Microsoft MVPs that are part of the
community some other TFS V STS
consultants out there have been
contributing and then just people who
are interesting people who have that
problem to solve if you're in a company
and you've been told go figure out how
to move this data from one place to
another you might end up with my tool
and you're going to figure out how to
use it we are currently on we've had a
hundred and thirty three releases of our
product so we are on a continuous
delivery pipeline so basically that
might be five releases in a week or it
might be five releases in a month or it
might be no releases in a month it
depends what changes people are making
what pull requests they're submitting
the source code is all in VST s so we
build the product in VST s so source
code build release all of those things
are there however we mirror that code to
github in an automated process so we
accept pull requests from both locations
if you're a trustee to contributor will
maybe give you the keys to the VST s a
team project and that's that's a smaller
number of contributors in there but
we've had 54 pull requests inside of es
TS we also take general public non trust
eat contributions and if you make a
number of submissions on github and we
like your code maybe we'll make you a
contributor in VST s but at the moment
we have 12 people who have contributed
reasonably regularly to the project and
you can find all of that information on
github apart from the VST s specific
stuff but we publish all of our releases
to github and to chocolaty so I'll show
you how that works
so I'm going to do a quick run-through I
want to show you how to find the tools
how to install the tools just a quick
overview of how to how to run the tools
and
how to
get some kind of meaningful execution
okay so first how do we find the tools
well the first thing you're going to do
is you're going to search our four V STS
migration and your first result is
always going to be the Microsoft full
fidelity
migration that's the one you want to use
if you can but if I put tools on the end
you'll see that VST s migration tools
pulls up the VST s sync migration tool
on the visual studio marketplace so you
can go in there and you can get some
basic information about about the tool
there's links to some documentation some
external review information links into
the github repo and what version we're
currently on
so there's some pretty useful things
there and to get if you could getting
started at the top there it will
actually take you through to the the git
repo which actually has some of the same
information but if you want to get the
tools the recommended installation is
from chocolaty
ok so there's been over 3,000 downloads
on chocolaty this is by far the most
common way
to install it and
we push out the bits automatically here
and so you can dynamically update your
your install pretty pretty quickly when
women releases go out so let me first
okay so if you once you have a para
shell window up you want to go to the
home page of chocolaty org and you can
click the Install Now button and
you'll see there are a number of
different ways to install it we're going
to install it with perish out so we need
to run this little command here
so I'm just gonna copy it right
click and run that command now what
that's going to do is it going to go and
get the chocolaty bets and install
chocolaty on your machine chocolaty is
just a tool for installing packages so
it's kind of like a package management
system built around PowerShell so it
allows you to install any of the things
that are on chocolaty with a simple
command line this is just a simple tool
that allows us to do that
okay so I'm gonna close that window
I'm gonna go back to
our Sigma greater there we go we've got
our scene migrator so in order to
install never get chocolaty installed
I'm gonna open our parser window
and
this time I'm gonna run chaco install vs
TS sync migrator
since jockle DS installed scanner right
okay so now that its installed
on your C Drive you'll have a tools
folder and instead the tools folder
you'll have a VST s sync migration
folder that has all of the bits and bobs
mostly their TFS dll's for allowing us
to call into the TFS
system you can see there's a single
executable in there called VST s sync
migrator that's what we're going to be
calling to do all of our all of our bits
and bobs
ok now that we have the tools installed
I'm going to open a command prompt and
we're going to navigate
CD tools
to the VST s migration for dog folder
and when we run the tool you can see it
pumps out a little bit of info you've
got the the version of the products
essentials going to check and make sure
that you have the latest version with
our telemetry via telemetry is enabled
your session ID so this session ID is
super useful if you're submitting our
problem with
the tool if you give me the session ID
I'm able to look up some of the
telemetry and find the exceptions and
maybe figure out what the problem was
and there you can see the full version
number of the product as well branch it
came from the hash everything's all
there and since we ran this with no very
selected so no in it execute our help or
anything then it just output the default
output so what you can do is you can run
in it
and what that has done is it is created
the default JSON file that you'll see in
the documentation so if I go back to
that folder
there it is these bsts bulk editor jason
I'm gonna open the JSON file and you'll
find it's all in one line luckily I'm
using visuals field code so if you hold
down shift and alt and press F it will
format it into a nicely formatted loop
there we go so this is the config file
that you're going to feed the tool in
the execute command that will tell it
all of the things that it's supposed to
do now this is the default
jason you don't want to run the default
jason this has all of the options for
all of the features
that are in here and you want to pick
and choose which features make the most
sense so let's go through a couple of
the things some of the processors just
need a source and some of them need both
the source and the target so this is the
where's my stuff SUV collection and team
project name collection and team project
name so obviously they should be
different if you just need the source
then it doesn't matter but if you need
both then that makes sense you've got
both of them there you've also got this
reflected work item ID field name this
is something that we inherited from the
old migration tools that the Rangers
supported
one of the reasons we use it is it
allows us to if that field exists in
your target
team project in the process template so
this is a field that you add to each of
the work items in the process template
we will update that with the location so
the full URL project an ID of the work
item from the old server this allows us
to pars off when we're running through
other processors and figure out where
things came from and then we can do
additional work on that you can also
have an update the source work item with
where that work item went but that slows
down the system it makes sense if you've
got hundreds of thousands of work items
and you want to skip over ones you've
already done because even just the act
of skipping over because all we found it
it takes too long so that's that's the
purpose of that and then we have a
number of field maps so there's a number
of different field mapping tools there's
one instance of each of the field maps
in here but you can actually have
multiple instances with multiple
configurations so basically you've been
an object type so this is the
multi-value conditional map at config so
you have what work item types applies to
you can just put star and that place
them all and then the source at field
so field1 and field2 and in the target
fields each of them have different
capabilities they're all listed on the
documentation roughly it takes a little
bit to get used to
what options we've got each of them have
been built to solve a particular problem
so it might the one that you want a
problem you want to solve might not be
one that we've solved before these tilt
tools are built ad hoc to solve those
particular problems so field we'll make
a field empty so you put in
the the field ref name that you want to
blank and it will empty that field of
data as it goes through processing items
and we'll talk about how that happens
afterwards
we've get the field value map so you
basically have a source field and a
target field so for example if you're
moving from state in the old work item
to state in the new work item you might
have a mapping from this looks like a
mapping from scrum to agile so approved
converts to new new approves new
committed moves to active in progress
gets mapped to act if those kind of
things as you go through
there's a field to field
mapping so I just want to push the data
from backlog priority in to stack rank
super straightforward and you can do
that with as many fields as you like you
can run these as many times as you like
at field to tag map and so if you're not
going to have a field from the old work
item in the new work item type maybe you
want to convert it to a state and it
supports regular well kind of regular
expression a format expression
to map that detail so this is going to
take whatever the state is and if you
place this mapper before the state field
value map it will take the old value
make it our tag scrum state call on
state name and then you can easily find
things that were in the old state make
sure everything's mapped up maybe you
have some queries that you don't know
how to do in a new system and you can
map it to the old one
okay our field merit map so this takes
two fields field 1 and field 2 and maps
them together so for example in the
agile template you don't have acceptance
criteria but in the scrum template you
have description and acceptance criteria
so maybe we want to take
the target field being description and
we're going to map her in with
description and then acceptance criteria
so 0 and 1 we're going to map and enter
the same field
sounds pretty cool and then you've got
the Reg X field Maps or we're going to
look at the source field so there's
release this particular reason I created
this was the release was a bunch of
numbers so a version number of a product
but in the new template they had a major
minor as separate fields so this looks
for a pattern and then replaces the
value can run that as many times as you
want to pull out different values so yes
you're running the Reg X multiple times
but it's a way to do that
field value to tag map I think that's
field to tag map feel valued tag map so
you can see Stars field blocked if the
pattern is yes so if blocked is marked
as yes then
put blocked in the in the in the in the
in the resultant field the target field
tree to tag map so if you're in your old
team project if you have a really
horrible
idea path hierarchy because it's been a
free-for-all in there maybe you want to
maintain some of that information so
this will actually convert each of the
nodes in the tree to attack and it'll
say which one how many to skip so maybe
you skipped the first three because
you're gonna keep the first three in the
next system and then everything else
becomes
attack so there are the instances of the
types of field maps that we have in
there so you can you can configure them
any way you like you know as many as you
like the order does matter they're
executed in the order they're listed in
the file so so have have at that
we then have a little work item type
definition this allows you to decide
what work items map to other work items
so here we've just got bug to bug and
product backlog item to put a backlog
item but maybe you have put it back log
item to user story and the system knows
to create a new user story when you have
a product klog item in the source user
story in the target and that allows you
to do a live migration I prefer in place
migration so I actually quite rarely
really use that capability
so there's two types of processing you
can go into the data in place or as
you're moving from one system to another
and that brings us to the processors
there's quite a number of processors I'm
not going to go through them all I'm
just going to go through the rough types
we're going to talk about the individual
processors in a little bit but here
you've got this is the work item
migration at config it has a number of
options for example if I want to prefix
the project to the Nords so let's say
I'm merging two team projects a team
project one and team project - and I'm
putting them into team project 3 if I
prefix project to nodes the new
area paths will have the team project in
the name that kind of makes sense so it
will be a
project 3 slash project 1 slash whatever
the old layout was now there's a little
bit of our these things have an order
that they have to be run in which is
super important if you just run it as is
this is going to feel that's kind of a
good thing because if you don't know
what you're doing it's probably going to
make things worse but prefix project
update creating date and update created
by if your source has not been modified
since and you you like by yourself then
maybe you want to update the created
date and created by fill that into the
new fields and and then update the
source reflected ID do you want to back
update the source system with the new
reflected ID of the work items so you
can do that and then you can also filter
this query by default filters quite a
lot you can modify this query to support
whatever you want at the moment is
filtering
only work items that are open and only
work items that have not got to reflect
work item ID already filled out and then
they're in these work item types shared
steps shared parameters test cases
requirements tasks user stories bugs
it's super important that you do not
migrate test plans and test Suites do
not migrate them it's not worth it
they're completely worth lights
worthless items you cannot map them up
again later do a full fidelity migration
with the microsoft's service if you want
everything the same way this has
specific ramifications and this migrates
work items without history with history
so a revision replay it replays it to
the revisions it's not really the same
history it's just each work item with
each revision so the timing doesn't
always match up and then a work item
update
allows you to update work items in place
so it doesn't use the target it just
uses the source and lets update a bunch
of work items in place okay they're the
mean
processors they're the main things going
on I'm going to mention all the other
ones and how they work they each have
their own quirks not all of them were
built by the same people but you take
this config and
we go back to our command line and we
run
execute and
execute with dash
config and we put our C
tools
the STS sync migration
the STS bulk editor Jason we run that
and it will run the configuration that
we've got do not run the default
configuration first off it will fail
that's a good thing and you need to go
through it and figure out what it is
that you're doing cool
okay so we talked about how to find the
tools install the tools running the
tools and a kind of overview of the
execution and the execution flow in
there okay so there are processors for
work items the order is important here
you have to run the node structures
migration context first that will create
all of your areas and iteration paths
and that
appending the are pre pending the team
project name needs to be the same
between node structures and the work
item migration okay if they're not the
same it's going to fail because when you
do the work item migration the area and
iteration paths are not going to exist
and you can't save a work item to alien
iteration paths that don't exist it's
just the way VST s and TFS work as would
run the node structures first it will
create them then run at one of the
migration contacts so there's work item
migration and there's work item revision
there's also the work item update which
only takes the source but migration will
move it without history revision replay
will obviously replay the revisions as
it goes through this the reason those
two is somebody else added it and they
did it as a second context we need to do
some work to pull them together so
there's only one but it works pretty
well at both of them worked pretty well
we just have to remember if we get a bug
in one we have to fix it in both at the
moment that's the only bit sucks there
after that you can either run those to
have to be run before you run the link
migration context obviously your work
items have to exist to reapply the links
in there that would be super useful so
if you run a link migration context it
will go and add all of the links the
relationships to the work items in again
and then there's two ones for doing the
attachments the export and the import
you export all of the attachments to a
folder you then import them into the
work items and this works a
great take some time to run depending on
the number of attachments you've got but
has some good filters in it to try
improve performance and then the last
one which I think
Richard fennel created which is awesome
which is the work item query migration
context allows you to migrate your
queries across and it does some of the
work to make sure that they work in the
new location I've not actually run that
one myself was added after the last time
I ran at the migration but um yeah super
good
ok so then once you've done all of the
work items which will bring the test
cases across ok so you have to do the
work item migration to bring the test
cases across leave out the test plans
and sweets
then you can run the the
processors for the for the test cases so
first one you run is the test variable
migration which creates the variables
then the configurations which creates
the same configurations that you have on
both sites they have to be in place
first before you create the plans and
sweets now you're going to create new
plans and sweets because plans and
sweets are made up of two parts inside
of the STS and TFS they have the work
item and then they have a bunch of other
data that is is inside of TFS the other
data is the bit that test management
looks at the work items is just some
metadata you can't push them back
together afterwards which is why we
don't migrate plans and sweets the first
time around we create new plans and
sweets but my way we might wire it up to
the existing test cases so it will run
through and do that there are some
caveats like queries don't migrate well
and some other other things but it's its
best case and then we've got our very
beta I don't think it works just now
for test runs we're trying to figure out
how to get test runs across as well but
that will allow you to migrate your test
cases we then have some processors for
other things
some these are pretty cool we have
export profile picture from Active
Directory
so you can if your corporate active
directory has the pictures of all your
employees in there it will do an export
of all of the pictures to a
username a folder with a username with
the picture name picture name is a
username and then you can import them
all into TFS this does not work with VST
s VST s is authenticated differently
only the user can update their own
profile picture but it works well with
TFS done that before you may have messed
up your migration therefore you want
some way to delete all of the work items
the work item delete takes a query
warning this is super dangerous and will
permanently delete all of the work items
that end up in scope for it
make sure you use that in a very
clever manner
we've got the fix git commit links if
you're also migrating get as long as you
keep the same name of the repo from the
old git repo to the new git repo so in
the new team project location you can
run this processor and it will go and
remap all of the links so that the links
in the work items point to the new git
repo not the old git repo in the old
location and so that will go run through
and fix all of that you've got to create
a team folders that's far if you're
let's say you have many teams inside of
your your team project and you want to
create a folder for each team so that
you can put queries and twosies or query
folders it will go and build out that
list for you so you don't have to do it
manually if you've give 50 teams it can
be quite time-consuming to go build that
run the processor will go do that
export team list literally just exports
a list of all the teams for you these
are all at processors and tools you can
go get the source code on github you can
look at how they work you can build your
own you can submit pull requests if it
doesn't work the way you want we you all
of that and bring it in if we can oh
we might mention the the field map again
there's three processors that these work
with work item migration work item
revision migration and the work item
update so they or those three will use
these the first two migration and
revision both move from source to target
update only operates on source so it's
an in-place bulk update so again you get
the field field map filled marriage map
feel blank map field to tag field value
map
field value to tag reg X field map and
tree to tag map those are as a bunch in
there that are super useful and again
the
JSON file is more accurate than the
documentation because the JSON file is
the actual options but it pulled out of
each of the configuration of each of the
code so
while the documentation gets out of date
the JSON file that you get from the init
command is always up to date well there
we go we've gone through all of the
options in the VST async migration tools
hopefully that will give you some
ability to get started with them and
start migrating some of your work items
so if you have any problems head is up
on github submit your issues we have a
very vibrant community lots of people
asking questions and getting answers but
it is ad-hoc support it's just us giving
up our free time and had to support it
but you can ask you
[Music]