so the question is
it's said that you can reduce time to
Market by up to 50 simply by removing
committees true or false and why
um
I would say that the 50 is probably
false right somebody's just made up you
know it was it it lies damn lies in
statistics right or or was it um 99.32
of all statistics are made up on the
spot right kind of thing
um but but
committees and I'm seeing that in
engagements I'm currently in
that the Committees of people being
brought together whether formal or
informal committees right
um to to make decisions result in those
decisions taking long
it results in those decisions taking
longer you know we need to make a
decision
uh we need to decide that I don't know
um
decision right but we need to be a bad
decision and
um all right in order to make this
decision
you know we need we need Bob and we need
Allison and we need Jamie and we need
Roberta and you know we need Maria we
need all these people together in order
to make this decision and suddenly
you've got disagreement and they're
pulling in other people
sometimes you just need to make a
decision
right and if it's the wrong decision
we'll fix it later
but we need to move forward because
while they're collaborating on this
um you've got a bunch of people sitting
about not doing anything because the
team is sitting there waiting for the
decision to be made so that they can do
the work and they have their deadlines
as well
um what oh I just I've just thought of a
a kind of generic but specific example
um from an engagement I'm working at the
moment
is that there's there's quite a lot of
um procedures and policies that need to
be created more rules right the
procedures and policies need to be
amended created or or adopted for a new
way of working
and what
one group of people would like to do the
people doing the work right the people
doing the work on the bottom would like
to be able to do is they'd like to be
able to just use a document management
system like uh SharePoint or Google Docs
right put the dock in there
and then send a link to the people that
need to collaborate on this Dot and then
they can come in on that link and add
comments and collaborate and make sure
you know make the little changes that we
can then accept using the review
functionality of these documents you
know modern document management
techniques
but the people on the other side were
like no no no no no no we're not we're
we we don't work that way we're not
going to do it that way
you send us your final draft
for the document
and then we'll take it off we'll go
around all of the people that in our
organization right and you don't know
how many that is that could be hundreds
of people need to will be emailed this
document and have their input and then
we'll have a group of people who
maintain an Excel sheet with a list of
all the changes and issues
in the document and then we'll give you
that back and you can you can you can
make your change
first way modern document management
techniques was specifically designed and
developed to solve this problem
right
but they don't want to do that so that's
a policy and procedure or a way of
working that is getting in the getting
in the way that committee is getting the
way of delivering value and I would say
in that circumstance it's way more than
50 uh of the of the of the time to
Market is is is increased by having by
removing that capability right you could
have a quick collaboration on a document
and in a couple of days of a little bit
of back and forth on this this document
come out with something that that is 99
of the way there
um or we can spend six to twelve weeks
going around with this other other way
of working where it's more we do our bet
we hand off to you you then do your bit
you hand that back we make the changes
and then hand it back to you and then
you do your bit right that's that
difference between collaborative and
agile
and staging in traditional
right so I think um committees are part
of that story committees are part of
that staging traditional management
practices
um and they really really they need they
need to go as a concept
um committees and steering and all of
these kind of things
um so yeah I fully think that 50 is not
unreasonable
but I think it's definitely under
selling
um the effects or the impact of
um or committees on your ability to get
decisions made and take advantage of
business opportunities right think think
about all of those business
opportunities that are floating by that
if you just had a team that was able to
take advantage of that business
opportunity but you can't because the
documents tied up in committee
how much money how much additional
capability not just time to Market but
how much how
forget time to Market how many
opportunities does your business lose
out on
Because by the time the decision is made
it's no longer no longer an option
or your competitors got there
and especially if you're a big
traditional bricks and mortar
organization like I mentioned Royal Bank
of Scotland before right like the Royal
Bank of Scotland uh and you're having to
compete with the likes of monzo right
small Nimble Tech in Tech based
organization that's able to move a lot
faster they don't even have to move a
whole hell of a lot faster they just
have to move faster than you
right that's all they have to move
faster than than to build a market for
themselves and start stealing your
customers has just move back and you
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility