when you think a feature is going to be
valuable to your customers or to your
business how do you know that that work
has actually provided value so been
working with a a customer recently where
a lot of um
sales driven features end up in the
product um which is actually having the
impact of fragmenting the product and
making the product more difficult to use
because the driving force for adding
those features to the product is closing
a
deal it's get nothing to do with what
the users of the product want it's got
nothing to do um with what the business
that is creating the product want all it
has to do with is closing the deal with
the
customer so what why why is that bad we
obviously want to close deals with
customers but why it's bad is because we
don't
know whether those things that we're
creating actually produce value or not
okay so um they're all there's
definitely an assumed value right so we
think if we add this feature we're going
to get value from it close that deal but
what's the longterm impact of that
feature we might close that
$30,000 deal but if over the next 5
years that feature is going to cost us
100,000 in support and maintenance and
uh all those kind of things and we don't
close any more deals because of that
feature then it wasn't worth adding that
feature to close that $30,000 contract
but your sales guys don't care because
they've made their 5% bonus on the
$30,000 of the deal they closed there's
no incentive um um for
them to really focus on the right
features that will support many of their
customers they're just worried about
closing the deal because that's how they
get the bonus um that's usually the
metric that
that that for salespeople so one of the
ways to turn that around is to start
changing the way you measure changing
the way you you you you deliver bonuses
um because people behave how they're
measured right so
uh a great great example again Microsoft
has lots of these examples because
they've been through some of these these
traumas is they they switched the Azure
sales folks from getting their bonus
based on the number of azure hours they
sell to being instead on the number of
azure hours the customer
uses so then instead of selling a
million dollars to the
customer and then the customer being
unhappy at the end of the year year
because they bought a million dollars
worth of azure and they've used $40,000
and the rest is waste so they're unhappy
um that the salesperson is focused on
usage how can I help you as the customer
use this product not how can I be
Draconian and close the deal and get you
to sign on the do line right signing on
the do line is not the value that the
customer wants using the features and
capabilities to the maximum capability
that they have that's what the customer
wants and it's that shift and focus from
um
um Revenue
extraction right towards value creation
because quite often that shortterm view
on Revenue extraction has a long-term
cost that's not obvious um to to it it's
not obvious to the people that are
making the decision that the feature
goes in it might be obvious to the
people who are actually doing the work
right but they don't have any say or
control over that so this this valid
is really important because you pull
back around and once you've shipped a
feature
you monitor that feature's usage you
collect Telemetry from that feature now
in order to collect the right Telemetry
because we can always in hindsight say
well this feature did this right but was
that what was intended is that why you
added that feature in the first place is
that the change that you wanted to make
and this is why I have I'm a big
proponent um as part of product
management of hypothesis driven
engineering practices um or it doesn't
have to be engineering it can be
anything we're building if we're
building a product I guess I would just
call that engineering anyway if we're
building a product um every feature that
we want to add to the product that is
not just table state
right there are features um that are uh
we just we we we have to have so for
example if you're going to have a
webbased uh product and there's um
Dynamic content specific to the user
they're going to have to be able to log
in I I don't need to have a hypothesis
to say is adding login a good idea we
kind of have to have it it's table
Stakes but
um what level does that go to might
include some kind of hypothesis right um
if we make it easier to log in right so
base username password is is how most
login systems work um most systems are
moving to password lists um if we
Implement a password list system do we
get more or less users using our product
if we put a a a LinkedIn Auto login or a
or a Windows or a um apple or or Google
auto login Facebook Auto
login does that increase the number of
users that we get in the system so the
hypothesis would be um if we add the
capability for people to L in with
Facebook um we're going to get a higher
number of people logging into the system
because it's easier for them to log in
right that would be a hypothesis and
then you might ask the question well how
how much more is that worth um and
hopefully it's very minimal F that sort
of thing should be very minimal effort
to add to your system right should be
not saying it will be but it should be
um if you add that to your
system what data are you going to
collect to know whether you've
successfully achieved that hypothesis
well I I I want to I want to know how
many people click the Facebook Link
versus us the username and
password right and I also want to know
the total number of people new net new
users coming onto the system so what I
would expect to see is you know we've
got our line for new users in the system
U we add that feature and that line has
a something noticeable that says we're
increasing at a higher rate right and
then we can look at the data and say
well um 10% of people clicked the
Facebook button we've got a 10% increase
in the net new users therefore we've
opened up access to new users and New
Market that less people go to the page
and then bounce more people go to the
page and then sign in just because it's
easy they can just click the button um
so that's hypothesis driven practices we
have to look at the data and figure out
whether um the thing that we added has
the result that we expect but this is
the important part that means um whose
job is it to provide the
hypothesis it could be the person who
wants the feature who's asking for the
feature right this is this is something
that I encouraged I customer recently I
encouraged them to push back to sales
right so if sales say we want feature X
because we think it's going to close
this deal right and this deal is worth x
amount of money engineering should say
well
how much other customers are going to
use the feature how much do we think
it's going to increase usage of the
product um
and I'd like you guys to come up with a
hypothesis of why we're adding this
feature and what we expect to be
different other than just closing that
deal because we want to look at the
total cost total cost of ownership let's
say over five years of adding a feature
so support and maintenance and testing
and automated testing and all of those
things what's What's the total total
total cost of that the amount of time it
adds to the build right all those kind
of things and a lot of that gesses but
we come up with here's what we think it
will cost
that's are we actually going to make the
money that back that we're putting in is
it is it enough of a difference to make
it worth doing if we do it what else is
it going to support how many other
customers is it going to help um and
that's the Clincher do you understand um
how
many customers are using the features
that you have in your product I think
the there's some data from the sish
group in in Boston used to create the
chaos report I think they still do
create a report called the chaos report
every year might have a new name now um
and in that report they've they they
collect data they're an data analysts
group they collect data across I think
it's about 70 75,000 projects worldwide
um mostly us and Europe but some rest of
the world I think it's like 60% us 30%
Europe and then 10% of the rest of the
world I can't remember exactly but I
seem to remember remember those numbers
could be making them up
but the data that they analyzed showed
that only 35% of the features that we
build in our products are actually used
by our customers I think it's um uh
used it could be used a little bit but
not enough to make it worth adding to
the to the to the to the product so
they've analyzed that across all these
products so why is that number so low
because that sounds like for every
million dollars you invest in your
product you're only getting
$350,000 worth of
value right so
that's a lot of waste that's
$650,000
waste that's a lot of money where's it
going why why why are we building
features that our customers aren't using
even worse why are we continuing to
invest in
features that we could know that our
customers aren't
using that's that's the even more
interesting question how many features
do you track the usage of features in
your product and how many features in
your product are you actively adding new
functionality to that your customers
don't use that because if they're not
using it you probably want to think
twice about adding new features you may
want to double down right you've got
that old a adage that we can either H
double down right so we keep investing
in that feature because we think it's
going to be valuable in the future and
customers will use it we pivot we need
to change the way that feature Works in
order to maximize the user user
engagement with it right which is means
it's valuable if they're engaging with
it um or or we stop investing in it and
perhaps take it out the product
how often do you make those decisions
and how often do you make those
decisions based on data do you have the
data to be able to make those
decisions th this is something that that
product management wants the data the
only way they can get the data is if the
team adds that capability into the
product it needs to be integrated with
the product because you want to be
looking at the actual features how they
work and create Telemetry specific to
those features
understand based on what you intended
the feature to do that you're able to
track that data see the needles moving
and decide whether to continue investing
in it or stop that's something that
every product manager every product
owner should have for almost every
feature they add um to the product or
the intent to add to the product and
that can be great feedback and
information you can use when you're
talking to stakeholders who've asked for
those features and um you know you
before you've built the whole
feature build a little bit of it
validate that it's the right feature and
you see there's very few people using it
and go back to the stakeholder and say
we don't want to keep investing in this
feature because nobody's using it do you
know why nobody's using it right no you
can go ask the customers as well but
this is your push back on that Financial
investment that's maybe been imposed
upon you if you don't control everything
so validation is a super important part
of product development it's often
lacking um I feel that it's more often
lacking than almost anything else uh in
in product development uh so go out
there figure out what Telemetry you need
in your product get your engineers to
build it and start making evidencebased
uh decisions and validate that the
features that you create actually adding
the value that you intended for them