to Be an Effective agile coach you must
have knowledge of the type of work the
context within which the team that
you're working with works now most
people most uh agile coaches get that
knowledge by having spent many years
doing that work right you might have
been a software engineer for many years
you might have been a test uh a tester
you might have been a ux designer and
then as you understand the value of
agile you bring in some of those tools
and techniques and move up into that
space of agile coach but you need to
have an understanding of what the people
that are doing the work are doing why
they're doing it how they're doing what
is the context within which they work
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a CH about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked
agility