how did I become
the third scrum training provider for
Microsoft I think
um there's a couple of things in there
the first one is I I have a
long-standing relationships with with
Microsoft
um I've been a Microsoft MVP most
valuable professional in the devops
space for 14 years
um so that also leads on to the second
reason right because people at Microsoft
know me but also I know I know I know
Microsoft I know the organization I know
how
um they're in acronyms right they're
very keen like most organizations
they're very keen on their own acronyms
um if you've popular phrases like let's
take that offline
um and let's double click on that where
where all the times I first heard of
those were through Microsoft so just
engaging with their product teams their
people on a regular basis has has always
been something I've done
um and
I'm seen as an expert in both species
right it's actually quite unusual I feel
to have somebody who's both an expert in
devops
and an expert in in scrum and the agile
space and that that combination means
that an awful lot of my customers are
Microsoft's customers right because
they're using as your devops they're
using Microsoft tools and they hear
about me through that and then we start
talking about agile and we have those
conversations
so when Microsoft asks its customers who
do you who do you go speak to they might
say me and when their customers ask have
been asking Microsoft for years how do I
do this how do I do that well maybe you
need to go speak to Martin right
um so I get a lot of referrals from
Microsoft I get a lot of uh
um
engagement that way so it just I guess
it maybe seemed like a natural step to
have that conversation so when Microsoft
reached out to scrum.org and said we we
want to speak to some trainers
um I was at the the on that list to go
speak to them and in in that meeting
just being able to to have those
conversations right to talk about what
it is they're trying to do and know
where they're coming from and that
that's part of that relationship that I
already had with Microsoft already
understanding how they work and how they
do things
um and that's something that that I try
and build with every customer sometimes
it's difficult because you don't work
with everybody for very long right so
building relationships is sometimes
difficult when all they want is a single
training class but I have other
customers that I work with constantly
and they keep coming back
um I've been working with the Department
of work and pensions in the UK for whoo
seven eight years nine years maybe and
they keep coming back for more classes
and they keep having to it what's more
interesting in that engagement is they
have to really struggle to get me to do
the to do the engagements for them so
they really want me to do it right
um because of their procurement rules
and how do you get the person that you
actually want to do it to do it and
that's that's that's hard
um and I think that attests to the value
that they are getting from the classes
that I'm teaching and some of those
values might not be immediate or
immediately apparent it's not like
people learn a new skill and suddenly
they're magically able to do it but it's
in that that long-term systematic
engagement with a single customer and
keep coming back off I'm speaking at
their
um
they're having a conference this week
um an internal organizational conference
and I'm doing two talks for them at
their internal organizational conference
um I speak at Microsoft conferences I
was just last week at the MVP Summit in
Seattle talking to people on the product
team engaging with them giving them
feedback on the product
becoming more known right you you build
those relationships and that's really
what it's all about
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility