I always find it
interesting when in a in a in a in a
recession or potential recession or
Market instability right whatever
whatever your story is in in your
country um we T we we we we talk about
this this idea of of cost cutting and
organizations divest themselves of of of
of things they believe is waste um like
we've seen uh Capital One uh get rid of
a lot of uh agile coaches and scrum
Masters and even though they didn't
really because they're still hiring
agile coaches and scrum Masters lots of
other organizations have kind of done a
lot of those those cost cutting measures
and actually they're shooting themselves
in the foot they're absolutely shooting
themselves in the food they're they're
disadvantaging themselves in the face of
other organizations that don't do that
that do it differently um probably the
best analogy I I I
remember I have done a little bit of of
marketing in the in the distant past or
remember from from University at least
that
um the best
time to invest in marketing is when
sales are down and the econom is not so
great
because the benefits that you reach on
the other end are the payday right you
have to put in the investment put in the
time when everything's boom and
everything's going on you don't need a
lot of marketing to do the business that
you want to
do when everything
sucks you need to do more to get what's
there right because everything sucks and
there's not none enough to go around so
those that invest in sales and Market
during a recession are the ones that are
more likely to be successful coming at
the other end and the same is true for
agile for agile and uh uh let's call it
business agility rather than the big a
word whatever we want to call it um I
want businesses to be able
to effectively take advantage of Market
opportunities when they arise right um
all businesses exist in uh volatile
Market there's very few there used to be
nonvolatile markets today there's very
few nonvolatile markets maybe diamonds I
don't know that's maybe a non-volatile
market I don't know much about it but it
feels nonvolatile but all of the markets
that we're all going to exist exist in
if you're building software and products
I have a good example in oil um oil and
gas that if you're in that volatile
Market when things start to
suck that's the time you should be
investing in your efficiency your
productivity and your
Effectiveness right those are the times
when you should be investing in those
things
because part of it is you get a little
bit of breathing room right because if
there's not a lot going on in in in the
market like the market starting to
stagnate a little bit then you've not
got that clamoring for for for for new
features and it gives you time to get
your house in order to re reorganize
re-evaluate weee what's going on um but
we tend to focus purely on the numbers
right because a lots of organizations
have shareholders and shareholders want
their cash um so we can either not pay
the
shareholders um this quarter and
reinvest in our company and our people
in our organization or we can fire 500
people and give the shareholders this a
higher yield than they were expecting
right and lots of organizations opt for
that second one and that is shoting
yourself in the fut that is h a um
Revenue
extraction over value creation we want
to be focusing on value creation because
long-term value creation is what Builds
an effective business it's how your
business was built in the first place so
we want to be focusing during a
recession um on Effectiveness
productivity and uh uh all those lovely
goodies
so in the boom
times we um tried all the things right
anything that came along oh we've got
cash for it let's do that oh we've got
cash for this let's do that right
because we've got a lot of cash we're
we're
affluent when we start moving into um
the opposite of Boom bust I guess when
that bubble pops um or deflates right it
could just be deflating a little bit
then we need to focus on our own
Effectiveness if we can become more
effective we can do more with what we've
got and that means that we'll be the
ones in the market
innovating and adapting to the changing
Market more effectively does that make
sense like if if we start
um oh if we start if we start firing
lots of people we're going to have an
unhappy
Workforce because people are unhappy
when their friends get fired and or
other people in the company because they
get scared and then there's fear and
they don't want to do stuff and they're
like holy crap what's going on so
unhappy afraid people don't do good
work so by having those layoffs within
your
organization you've created a Culture of
Fear maybe unwittingly and maybe some of
it's necessary right but you've created
that Culture of Fear and the people that
are in there are not going to be serving
the customers needs as well because
they're
fearful
so then customers are more un happy with
what it is that you're doing and you get
that vicious cycle and lots of
organizations end up in a death spiral
at that point um and you just know
they're going to going to disappear it
can be quite difficult to recover from
from from some of those
things so what what we do when the
bubble starts deflating is we start
focusing on our Effectiveness how do we
ensure that we're able
to maximize the amount we're able to
deliver if you think of this this is my
market line right and above the line is
the market and then the people that are
doing the work are here and all the way
down here is the CEO who's not really
connecting with the market right the
market the people in your organization
are connected directly to the market
they're the ones that we want to have as
effective as possible and dynamically
shifting to whatever Market
opportunities come up because the more
opportunities we're able to take
advantage of within that market space
even in a recession the less impact it's
going to have in our overall business
especially if we're doing lots of small
experiments which can be risky but also
we get you know without risk without
risk you don't get the bonus right um
and we're able to adapt to those those
changing needs as much as possible as
quickly as possible then we as a
business are more likely to survive
we're just more likely to survive if
we're able to adapt to those changing
Market needs um and I I want to quote um
Sati and Adela here I have a little H
quote up here um there cannot be a more
important thing for an engineer for a
product team than to work on the systems
that drive our
productivity so I would any day of the
week trade off features for our own
productivity I want our best Engineers
to work on our Engineering Systems so
that later on we can come back and build
all of the new Concepts we
want that is the epitome of this idea
right although from an engineering
perspective because Sati has a
engineering background
right if we as a
business have Slicker more effective
processes minimized processes right you
you want to have you want to have
systems on your business that is based
on principles not rules if you have
rules everybody will follow them and
they don't need to to think if they
don't need to think when a market
opportunity comes along they follow the
rule not the market right because
they're not thinking they need to follow
the rule but if we have a system based
on
principles then the people within it
need to think and within the bounds of
those principles they take advantage of
Market opportunities as they arise or
other opportunities or different way
different ways of doing things in order
to be
successful so this idea
of of boom and bust of non- recession
and
recession um is when things are going
badly the thing you want to be investing
in is your your people and your
organization and your uh practices and
processes and making things more
effective more effective is really
important a lot of people in business
talk about productivity um and
productivity is important but I think
effectiveness is that nuanced version of
the word productivity that is because
because we could be highly productive I
we're delivering lots of stuff but are
we delivering the right stuff right I
know that this is basically me
nitpicking the word right but
Effectiveness is includes are we
building enough of the right stuff and
these are the types of things that um we
need to we need to invest in and that
that doesn't mean that that you've to go
and invest hundreds of thousands in
scrum training or cand training or uh
coaches or scrum Masters or any of those
things you want to figure out for your
business in your market right because
remember you were in that volatile
Market what help and
support do the people that are
interacting with the market need in
order to become more effective
now sometimes that is going to be
training right do they understand the
theory and principles behind this we
think this might help those teams let's
train them in this we're not going to
make them do that right we're not going
to for example let's take scrum as an
example we're not going to make them do
scrum we want the people that are doing
the work that are engaging with the
volatile markets to choose to be able to
choose the best approach based on the
principles that we base our organization
on so in order for them to choose the
best approach best within the context
right most effective within the
context they need to have the Knowledge
and Skills and understanding necessary
to be able to make those decisions so
this is where actually you you also
don't go and hire one of the big
Consulting companies to come in and do
it for you right so you could hire a a a
Boston Consulting Group or uh McKenzie
to come in and say this is how you're
going to do
everything but the people in the system
didn't learn
anything the way humans learn is by
doing we learn more by doing than by
just talking about it so in order to
learn what works and what doesn't and
how much it works and how much it
doesn't we need to actually do and try
the things so you need the people within
your system right that's the people that
work for you in your company this is
your people they need to be the ones
that do the work they need to be the
ones that learn that become the
practitioners that understand those H um
uh processes practices tools uh uh
principles theories right so the theory
of constraints you be talking about
scrum Theory you might be talking about
first principles for all of these things
they need to be the ones that understand
it so that they're able within any
context to make the best decision
possible Right to make the best choices
possible within the the the the system
of principles that we build around our
our our organizational structure and
that that means that you're probably
going to be doing a lot of uh training
you're probably going to be bringing in
experts on specific topics to help
engage with with people inside the
organization but generally you you
probably don't want to be doing that
wholesale right because what's right for
one part of the organization might not
be right for another part of the
organization so what I I think is an
effective way is let the people that are
doing the work decide who and what they
need so I work with a a company in
Spain um the the there kind of two
sister companies that it's kind of same
but different but y um and they give
every single one of their employees a
budget for for for training and
Consulting right so every employee I
can't remember how much it was let's say
it's
€5,000 every employee has €5,000 so if
you've got a team of five
people um that's €225,000
to spend on training and Consulting it's
their budget they can spend it how they
like they can get together and bring in
some kind of Coach they can get together
and and bring in maybe they they want a
scrum Master for a little while um or
somebody specific right like you want
somebody who who who focuses on a
particular thing like there folks out
there that focus on Sprint goals and
goals and value and that and there's
people out there focusing engineering
practices and devops right so you could
bring in an expert for for a period of
time to participate with the with the
team and it comes out of their budget
they're the ones making the decision and
that means that because they're making
the
decision they care about what that
person they've chosen to bring in have
to say this is this is the whole whole
thing of other people don't care about
your
goals right they care about their goals
so the way you enable more effective
organizations is the either you make
their goals your goals or they make your
goals their goals right so we all have
to be going in the same direction what
is it we're trying to do and princip
and goals strategic goals intermediate
strategic goals those are the things
that help us move together in the same
direction as a as a distinct company and
when we put all of that together um
we're then able to be more effective
we're able to deliver more value we're
able to adapt as needed to the changing
circumstances right so as a as a team or
group inside of your organization
decides they need some help with
something they can just bring that help
in it's not hard there's not a bunch of
procurement Hoops none of that crap
right that just gets in the way they're
able to just bring in those people get
them to help them with that story make
it a little bit better what's the next
problem we've got right we need this
other person to come in help with this
little bit make them a little bit bit
awesome right what's next we maybe don't
know what's next maybe we bring in a
generic expert who's able to oh maybe
you should try this this and this oh
that's a good idea let's try that
they're able to do do all of those
experiments build that story of
Effectiveness that works best for them
and
each area within your organization is
able to do that concentric circles all
interacting with the
market so
ultimately it doesn't matter whether
you're in boom or
bust this is how you want to focus on
maximizing your
chances of weathering that
storm all markets deal in Surprise
Doesn't Matter What markets you're in
there are going to be surprises a
recession is just another type of
surprise how effective is your
organization at dealing with those
surprises