so I I believe uh that immersive
learning is is the future of I I think
almost all um of this type of learning
uh whether it's scrum or Canan or
anything where people are involved
you've got a high degree of complexity
this is different from tools training
right different from tools training um
but anytime you you're you're talking
about um processes and practices that
people have to organize around I think
the immersive learning approach um is
much more the future of the way that
learning should be happening um it's
very difficult for people to spend uh uh
two days or four half days in a in a
class and then be able to go back into
their organization and actually actually
change something right it's it's very
difficult cuz they'll go to try and
change something in their organization
and they'll run into all of these
roadblocks all of these things that get
in the way and there's nobody there to
help and support them because you know
we did the training a couple of weeks
ago and now we're doing this and and we
run into those roadblocks so the the the
immersive format allows people to keep
coming back around and having those
questions having them answered
especially the the longer immersive uh
stories so the the they six to 6 to 10
weeks um and collaborating around with
that group of people bringing those
learnings back to the
organization this this is a total game
Cher for the learning experience that
people get when they come to these uh
these types of classes um so definitely
um the future of scrum training is
immersive if you want to have a
discussion about how mive classes can
revolutionize your training experience
then please book a call on our website
alternatively you can find all of our
public immersive classes listed there as
well and we would love to hear from you