one of the Seven Virtues of agility is
kindness kindness could be uh compassion
it could be benevolence it could be
empathy um and it could be directed in a
number of different places within our
organization uh the two key things that
I'm thinking about uh one is the
customer right we have this Relentless
customer focus that we're trying to
deliver something that adds value in the
market right and for that we need to
focus on the customer we need to be
compassionate about the customers issues
and their difficulties and what it is
they're trying to achieve that could be
you know when dealing with bug reports
or it could be just with engaging with
them and talking to them about the
problems that they're encountering and
trying to solve within our within our
product domain um and we want to be
benevolent we want to be seen as we're
providing ing them with something that
helps enable them to do something else
if they see our product as a burden or
they see our product as um I don't know
what the what's the cost version of
Burden for me burden's Broad and then
there's a cost like a cost center if
they see your product as a cost center
then um they're they're not going to
think of your product with kindness um
and you're probably not thinking of them
with kindness right um so that
Relentless customer focus building
empathy with your customers why do
people queue up outside of an Apple
store to buy the latest product it's not
absolutely not because they have the
best products it's because there's an
empathetic connection between the
customers and the company and the
products that they're trying to create
and the vision and the outcome that the
company has so building those stories is
really important
um and you don't do that
by doing something negative towards your
customers you don't do that by screwing
them over right you do that by building
again trust right building trust with
the customers with kindness the the
other side that I was thinking of um was
the developers are you the people doing
the work are we building compassion and
benevolence and empathy with them how do
our employees see our organization what
do they think about our organization um
I was I was um listening to Richard
Branson um and he did a a a talk and he
was talking about that your employee
happiness is a leading indicator of your
customers
happiness right if your employees are
unhappy but your customers are happy it
won't be long till your customers are
also
unhappy if your employees are happy but
your customers are unhappy it won't be
long till your customers are happy
because people that are happy and
engaged do the right thing they do the
thing that helps other people rather
than you know kind of be dismissive and
disgruntled and right you need people to
think with kindness and in order to do
that you need to demon demate that that
compassion that benevolence that empathy
within the context of your organization
to your employees and they will then
demonstrate that to the customers and
build um value in your brand value in
your organization and value in your
Market if you are having difficulty
getting the most out of the Seven
Virtues of agility then my team at naked
agility can help you or find a
consultant coach or trainer who can it's
essential for you to find help as soon
as you can and not wait use the links
below to get in touch because you don't
just need agility you need naked agility