having scrum
Masters that have a a a a lack of
competence within the context of the
team's work the product owners work and
the organizational
structure means that you're going you're
going to
be getting less return on your
investment I mean that's fundamentally
what it is uh the team is probably going
to be delivering less stuff it's
probably going to be making fewer bets
on new stuff so you're probably going to
spend less time on that new stuff and
they're probably going to have higher um
higher defect rates right because they
don't have the modern engineering
excellence and devops practices that are
needed to build awesome products in
today's world there absolutely teams out
there that are doing this without scrum
Masters right I I I I'm not disagreeing
with that um I'm saying that if you have
a scrum Master with the capability to
help a team maximize those
capabilities
then you're going to be able to to
vastly increase your Roi for your team
but you need scrum masters with those
competencies otherwise all you're going
to get is teams that are happier with
each other not teams that are able to
actually deliver more stuff both of
those things are important but
delivering more stuff is where your Roi
comes in um so we
you what I would want you to do is I
would want you to collect some metrics
and you use those metrics to measure the
fundamental benefit that the scrum
Masters are bringing you okay bang for
their Buck Right and so here's some
examples I'm going to use an example
over here because I have some data
around it um I would want to measure
Innovation rate which is the percentage
of time that your team spends working on
net new
functionality versus maintenance and
support and augmenting existing
functionality right so if you're Netflix
that's a new series versus a second
season of his existing series right or
remastering some older Series right so
that's this
measure um I want to measure my on
product index I want to be measuring the
percentage of time that my team members
have to work on my product versus having
to work on other things right so what
percentage of time are they actually
working on my on my
product I want to be monitoring my usage
index for my product so I'm looking at
at uh um the percent like uh data around
Um how my users interact with my product
right that's a great metric and then
perhaps uh if you have a let's say you
have a a an app that is installed I
maintain and support one um you have the
installed version index what percentage
of people running your tool are on the
latest version of the tool and what
percentage are on older versions of the
tool because that goes to to engineering
excellence and various things let's say
you had those
metrics I'm going to tell you the
industry standard for each of those
metrics um and we're going to base it on
a on a for every dollar and yeah I'm
using US dollar pound Euro whatever you
want um for each dollar you spend on
your product um what you
lose by by each of these metrics so The
Innovation rate is about
29% that's the average Innovation rate
that's from the Dora metrics so for
every
dollar that you spend on your product
you're getting about 29 cents of net new
value right for opening up new markets
for adding new capabilities to your
products 29 cents so you're 29 cents in
the dollar right um right off the
bat most teams spend about 80% of their
time working on the product and 20% of
their time doing other stuff for the
organization so that could be meetings
all hands
training stuff right it's about I think
that's about a day a week isn't it
something like that anyway um so now
you're down to 23 cents in the dollar
because you've lost 20%
right what about usage index what do you
think uh uh uh uh the the the metric
show the data that I've seen um some of
it's from real
customers um The Happy metrics are from
uh uh the chaos report uh from the
Standish group in Boston um and they
found that only about 35% of the
features that are built are actually
used by your customers only about
35% right that's because we're not
changing fast enough we're not adapting
fast enough 35% so now we're down to8
cents on the
dollar 8 cents on the dollar eight out
of 100
right 8 cents return on investment for a
$1
input what the
heck that is
terrible 8 cents on the
dollar and that metric is really
optimistic I did some work with a bank
in the US who said that uh 35% usage
index that's that's crap we know our
customers way better than that we
understand uh uh they're using all of
our our features or as much as you know
they're oh we're 80% right so we said
why why don't we add some Telemetry onto
your product and let's see they are
cloud-based products it was easy is so
we added Telemetry to the product we
gave it 3 months and we looked at the
data and it was about
8% of of the features in the product
were actually used by their customers
and that was over a year end luckily we
were just in the right time for that so
it was over a year end so that was a
really good picture 8% not 35% 8% of the
features so that wouldn't be8 cents in
the dollar that would be a lot less um
and then let's say installed version
index let's say it's 70% 70% of your
users are on the latest version of your
product now we're down to 6 cents on the
dollar do you you know do you even know
what your numbers look like just those
metrics Innovation rate on product index
usage index and still version
index it's only four
metrics go collect
them and then
measure your progress over time and if
you hire scrum Masters they should be
able to change those
numbers your scrum
Masters should be
accountable for the effectiveness of the
team and you can measure the
effectiveness of the team within the
context of a
product by some of these metrics these
are not the only metrics I just picked
four right because I have some data
around
them pick some metrics that are product
based metrics value based metrics for
you as a
business and expect those numbers to
improve
when you hire scrum Masters if they
don't you've got the wrong scrum Masters