so I first encountered Azure devops back
in
2006 so that's quite some time ago it
wasn't called aure devops back then it
was um Visual Studio team Services back
in the day it's gone through many name
changes since then uh but it's
effectively it's not the same service
but it's the same intent from the
service um so as your devops is
something that I've been using since
then and I I was a lowly software
engineer um plugging away building some
products and as your devops was really
my root into into devops into helping
teams become better at what they do um
use increase their capabilities
use um tools to help them uh better
their capabilities right um because team
Foundation server was was intending to
that be that tool I I think it it
largely struggled to do anything outside
of the Microsoft space until they moved
much further on to to Azure devops the
cloud version but
um that early product was actually as
how I got my Microsoft MVP as well which
was building plugins and uh playing
around with the apis for um for
TFS um so I I worked with a number of
teams uh Team some teams at maril Lynch
and then some teams at agreco and are in
both
circumstances while also
doing the work I helped those teams
understand um how to do automated builds
how to um use the work item tracking how
to link all the things together um I
built some visualization tools against
the against the apis so I've really been
plugging away at the Azure devops um
apis since
2006 um so I know where a lot of the
bodies are buried in the apis which is
why when um I think
what happened I I got my MVP I moved to
the US I worked as a devops consultant
almost exclusively in the Microsoft
stack but as a devops consultant in the
US for three years so I was doing a lot
of azure devops work um we did a lot of
API work there were some migrations
there used to be this old tool um that
was
totally crazy to work with um I'm trying
TR remember what it was called Microsoft
created it originally but really it was
just a big ass code base and it allowed
you to migrate data from uh um TFS to to
to other TFS but it had this kind of
adapter model so that you could get from
other systems into TFS that was the idea
um so I think I'm the only
one I I I would hedge I certainly the
only one that
published um creating their own adapter
for it so I did uh created a migrator
for Test Track Pro into TFS um back in
the day when Test Track Pro was even a
thing and maybe it is still a thing I've
just not heard about it in in 15 20
years but um that
that experience of creating that adapter
really led me when I invite the UK
started my own business what my first
gigs was with um a company called
Slumber and Slumber was consolidating
they need a lot of devops help um to to
help make the most out of the tools that
they had uh they were using the tools
really well it was just a little bit
convoluted um so they wanted to take um
they're the sort of organization where
everybody does everything right so
there's there's um every tool you can
think of every Engineering Process
they have everything and they wanted to
consolidate down into using at least a
single Source control tool with work
item tracking and the tool they picked
was TFS team Foundation server um so I
helped them
migrate something and they had a
standard process template so I helped
them migrate something like four to 500
teams from what they were doing before
into this new model and then move them
from server to server and originally I
built a bunch of Powershell scripts
right that's when you're prototyping um
scripting languages are the the best way
to um kind of kind
of run your thought processes you're
effectively writing down your thought
process and then running it and say yeah
well that kind of works and if I select
this bit that kind of works and if I do
this that kind of works so it's a really
good way to to do some fast it's
incredibly error Pro and buggy as heck
um but it's a good way to do to do to do
those things and I built a bunch of par
shell tools that I had I think at one
point four or five people um else in the
organization running those po shells to
start uh migrating data around change
process templates move data around in
fields um all of those things and then I
started looking at well really this
needs to be a little bit more solid this
needs to be a little bit more capable it
needs to be something that's a little
bit more pluggable um um and I built the
first version of the Azure devops
migration
tools so there's kind of there's kind of
two ways to to do migrations in as your
devops one is really limited but really
powerful the other one is mine um the
one that's really limited and really
powerful um is Microsoft's own migration
tools obviously they want as many people
as possible to move into the cloud they
don't really want to be supporting and
maintain te team Foundation server or or
as your up server the on Prem
version of the product so um they they
they want people to move up to the cloud
so they've built a tool that if you get
onto almost the latest version of azure
devops on Prem um you can effectively
package up your database give it to them
there's a whole process for that but
package up your database it's not as
easy as it sounds package up your
process your database give it to them
and they'll import it into as your
devops so if you're if you're trying to
get into asure devops the easiest most
high
fidelity uh most productionize way to do
that is to have Microsoft Do It um they
provide a bunch of tools uh I've done
this for a bunch of customers over the
years tons and tons of customers uh the
biggest one was the the Slumber um
engagement where I think it was 2 2.7
2.8 terabytes was the collection that we
moved up to to Azure devops it was
pretty pretty ginormous I think they
became the third
largest customer using Azure devops
outside of Microsoft in in the
service um and it that was a huge amount
of work but it lots of smaller ones are
much easier I did one for a for a
customer where we we we did it in about
an hour right their database was small
enough they're on the lat version they
had control of all the servers the
passwords all the things it was small
enough package we just sequenced it up
and then they looked at the result and
went yep that's good let's go with that
and we turned off the on Prem uh version
so I I have uh personally done a whole
bunch of migrations I have a team that
helps with that uh we did one recently
that was um it's more complicated than
it sounds right you're not just taking
the Azure develops database and putting
it in the cloud Microsoft have to to
process it in um
so you have
to you have you have to be on a version
that's supported by that process which
is the absolute latest version and one
back so one Service Pack back which
means that if you're sitting with a
local team Foundation server and you're
on TFS 2010 uh 201 I don't know 12
2015 uh what else was there 18 I think I
think there was a 19 maybe there was a
19 uh but if you're on a on prep server
you have to upgrade it first which means
that you might need to upgrade SQL
Server you might need to upgrade the
operating system you might have to do
all of those things so we did one
recently for a customer that was TFS
2010 I think they were on 2010 all the
way up to Azure devops and there there
were
three distinct migrations we had to do
cuz you youve got to upgrade from 2010
to 2015 then you've got to go from 2015
to I think you can get to the latest
version from 2015 up to the latest
version of TFS then you have to run and
validate all the things that you need to
do to go to the go to the cloud then you
can take your your your environment into
the cloud and that can go one of two
ways you can just take the database if
it's small enough it's under 150 Meg you
can just give them the database that
pack and it'll work uh but otherwise you
have to set up in a euro environment you
have to install the data the SQL Server
upload data and then get Microsoft to to
to do stuff with it so that that that is
that is the easiest simplest and most
productionize route uh but it's not what
a lot of people can or want to do um
lots of companies have lots of
circumstances that are out with the
bounds of that um they' they've got 100
teams and only five teams want to go to
the cloud they've got other teams that
can't want whatever reason um that then
adds complexity to that mix uh they've
got teams that want to go just now and
other teams that want to go
later um those are the most common ones
for for for for that pushup into we're
going to Ado um but also you've got
companies that sell products right so if
you've got five products in your company
and one of those products is being sold
it's probably inside of the same TFS or
as your Devo and you want to move that
piece over to somewhere else because
you're selling it to somebody and
they're going to take the history um and
all of the the the the stuff that goes
along with it um and Microsoft provide
no support for any of those scenarios um
so if you've got you've got I've got 50
projects and I want one I've got
projects across five collections and I
want one collection at one count or um
I've
got I don't know I created one big
massive project and I really should have
created two projects these are things
that are just not fundamentally
supported by the by the tool or by or or
or in any productionize way by
Microsoft so what my tool that I created
does is it allows you to migrate pieces
of your whole thing to another location
um so we do our query based so it's
predominantly focused on work items
although there's lots of other tools in
there in the it's like a Swiss army
knife um and the people are adding new
tools all the time but the main I don't
know the knife part the main tool that
you use or is it the scissors right
because that's the main tool you use on
a Swiss army knife but anyway whatever
the main tool is um is is work item
migration because that's the thing
that's just not out there um so you're
basically saying here's a query I want
these work items and I want them
recreated over here and the tool goes
and recreates them um so there are lots
of limitations lots of caveats lots of
things around that but that's
effectively the idea so I quite often
get asked to help customers in a variety
of different ways sometimes they want to
do the migration if they've got loads of
migrations to do um I I've got people
out there that have been using my tools
for
years um and it makes sense if you're
going to use the tools like big big uh
Enterprise customers find quite often
they need to move data from one place to
another they want to consolidate they
want to split so they spin up a a group
of people probably the administrators of
as your devops for their company that
that they want to spin up on the tool
and use the tool um so I provide them
with a bunch of support sometimes it's
just support calls sometimes it's
training they want to train some people
on on using the tool but more often than
not with lots of organizations it's a
one-off thing right we're going here we
want this to happen and we just want it
to happen we don't want to have to we
don't need that skill in house if it's
not your core business you're not doing
it all the time and you don't need it to
support your core business then that's
when you Outsource right um and I did a
big migration recently of about 80
880,000 work items for a customer that
wanted an audit Trail right so they've
they've bought another company they've
not got their hands on all of that
company's stuff yet there still all the
legal stuff that has to happen in
between but they want a copy of all the
work items and all the code so that
their then audit Department can then go
through all of that and and and validate
and check and match things up and yes
this is the right thing and all all this
is missing and that's missing all the I
don't know what they're doing right but
they wanted that copy so they don't want
to mess around having their own people
learn a tool and then do it so we just
did it for them um probably took eight
or 9 days to migrate actual 24 hours uh
running on it to migrate that number of
of work items because it's a lot um but
then after it's it's done they have that
copy in the new location and they can do
their own thing so sometimes we do the
migrations sometimes we help support the
migrations sometimes we help train
people um and sometimes we just consult
I I quite often um get calls from folks
that just need some advice on how to do
something in asure devops
um these big infrastructure
ideas that people have the business
decid they want to consolidate stuff
they want to split stuff they want to
move stuff around like what does that
mean for us what are our options what
are our capabilities so I quite often
have have uh um discussions with
customers on how how that all goes
together and sometimes they use my
services to help them and sometimes they
have enough information to go do it on
their own or it's easy enough that it's
just following the docs from
Microsoft um
so as both a user of aure devops which I
have been for many years although not so
much anymore right um I do a lot of my
work in GitHub now but as a user of aure
devops um I really appreciate the the
capabilities that it has but then there
are some gaps that you need um somebody
to fill and um sometimes you want to
spin it up yourself and sometimes you
need to kind of get somebody in to help
you out so that's kind of my experience
with the your devops