I think kanban is
hugely popular in all Industries not
just creative Industries because it does
model the behavior of the existing
system right it doesn't require you to
change uh how you're currently doing
things so effectively when you're
implementing a kanban approach you you
start from where you are you model your
existing system right and in modeling
your existing system you actually iron
out some variability because if you've
got 10 people in your organization that
are let's say uh let's say our output is
marketing videos right uh marketing
content for uh for businesses that we're
working with then and we've got 10
people working on that marketing content
How does each person choose what the
next thing it is they go work on if
every person picks differently right
makes choices differently then we've got
a high degree of variability in our
system that we can iron out right if if
all these 10 people just got together
and agreed whatever thing is in in our
list of things to do that's been sitting
there the longest let's do that
right that that way the oldest thing is
the quickest thing uh uh to get through
the system because you're trying to
reduce your overall cycle time right for
your customers then you can use
kanban to model your system right you
have that conversation what is our
working agreement what is our definition
of workflow for our system you model it
decide when it starts when it finishes
and then you've got the data to figure
out
when we make changes
is it improving the system or is it not
improving the system actually I I had
this conversation uh a couple of months
ago with my dentist
right so totally nothing to do with
software nothing to do with it nothing
to do with any of those Industries if
you're if you're a dentist right you
have to book people in for appointments
how quickly can you book people in for
appointments so if I say to my dentist I
need an appointment and it's three
months out
right that's that's that's that's a very
long time right so their their cycle
time their ability to get something into
the system I've asked for an appointment
and be able to actually deliver it is
really really long really long what
could they do to shorten that cycle time
well perhaps they need little gaps in
their CIS in their in their in their
calendar to be able to have things that
pop in perhaps they need to deal with
cancellations better perhaps they can
chase people to say do you still need
this appointment all those kind of
things right but how do they know that
that's effective how do they know that
it's valuable and it's changing uh the
way they do business
right because wouldn't it be great if
you went to the dentist and said I need
an appointment and they said yeah we've
got one next Thursday for you right that
would be great
um so having
a model for your system so you can
monitor the flow of work through your
system and look at your cycle times look
at your throughout look at how long
things are taking because
the shorter uh the throughput quite
often shorter the cycle time right
people getting into the system and
getting through it quicker and I'll tell
you something people are happier
customers if they get their stuff faster
and that's what we're looking at we're
looking at that Continuous Flow
continuous delivery of stuff whatever
stuff's in your system we want to
deliver it as quickly as possible
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility