so one of the harbingers of the agile
pocalypse is plague and what plague am I
referring to uh the plague of
incompetent agil coaches and scrum
Masters and yes I'm using that word very
specifically I'm talking about those
folks that have no clue or understanding
about the work being done and yet seem
to be elevated to a position where they
are responsible for the effectiveness of
the people doing that work and they
often especially in large organizations
that have a lot of hierarch
hierarchy um have more Powers than you
would ideally like an agile coach or
scrum Master to have and they wreak
havoc and Devastation in your organiz
organization by leveraging those Powers
um this uh looks uh very much like
what's a good example I worked with an
organization in um in Seattle I think
they might have been actually in
Portland it was just that part of the
world I was in and um this organization
they had just fired their scrum
Master why had they fired their scrum
Master well their scrum Master had
decided that if you're not standing up
you're not doing scrum even though
standing up has nothing to do with scrum
but if you're not standing up uh uh
you're not doing scrum and
um the team had decided that they would
sit during the daily
scrum because they had a team member who
was disabled and in a wheelchair and
they didn't want to Tower over that
person during the event which of those
two options is the very epitome of scrum
and agile in that mindset it's the team
that self organized to pay
respect to their teammate and had the
courage to to to talk about it and
decide on a way of doing something that
is the epitome of scrum and the scrum
values this scrum Master total charlatan
didn't have a clue what's really going
on on focused on mechanical scrum and
practices and I'm seeing right now this
is quite topical cuz I am seeing a ton
of posts about here's why agile's [ __ ]
right what was the what was the one
today agile is a cancer or scrum is a
cancer I think it was scrum is a Cancer
and he goes on to talk about why why is
Scrum a cancer although you know that
terminology has its own weight right but
it was because because it gives an
excuse for leaders to tell teams what to
do it gives uh uh uh you have to stand
up during the daily scrum you have to
too many meetings right too many
meetings um what were the other things
man there was a whole host of those
things uh today that the and there's
been a number of posts that seems to go
in waves right um so this this plague
that affects scrum and agile in general
is this mis Mis not even
misunderstandings they're just abject
failures of competence abject failures
of competence these are people that have
maybe never read the scrum guide never
kept up to date never actually read the
agel manifesto don't actually understand
what are the underlying principles that
we're talking about here and they just
make decisions and do stuff based off
nothing um and then then you have the
impact right what's the impact on the
organization what's the impact on the
teams you can see these posts from
people that abjectly hate scrum or hate
agile or just think that agile just
doesn't work right and mostly when you
ask them what are the things that you've
seen that is the reason why agile
doesn't work or scrum doesn't work or
many of these things they describe
scenarios
that are the very opposite of agility
right agile doesn't work because we all
have to do story points and guarantee
the number of stories delivered per
Sprint these are things that are part of
this plague this this it's just a oh you
can see that I'm quite annoyed by this
one it it it annoys me every day and I
meet scrub I meet such awesome and
amazing scrum Masters and agile coaches
every day who really understand what
they're doing they're lean agile
practitioners and they have a complete
complete deep technical understanding of
the processes practices and tools that
are needed for the teams that they
engage in coach with for them to be as
effective as possible at the job that
they're doing but unfortunately for
every one of those awesome uh coaches
there are 10 people who decided
yesterday to become a scrum Master after
their um I'm being bit sarcastic their
arts degree right um and they they they
have no clue they want to change their
career and become a scrum master and
they have no clue about the work that
the team does they have really no clue
and certainly no experience about how to
engage with those teams and because
there is a
shortage this is a big rant because
there's a short AG of
um of qualified people in the industry
most organizations they need scrum
Masters only two good ones apply but
they need five so they hire three crap
ones because that's who's
available we can do better organizations
need to stop
hiring for just their need they need to
hire for the quality of the people that
they get as well
this is a good example of technical debt
in organizations and it's a great
example of a plague affecting our entire
industry and
organizations thanks for watching the
video If you enjoyed it please like
follow And subscribe I always reply to
comments and if you want to have a chat
about this or anything else agile scrum
or devops then please book a coffee with
me through naked agility
okay