I'm going to configure uh the release
management system to send emails um but
my mail server is Office
365 so if I open up uh release
management click on
Administration and then click on the
settings uh uh option right at the very
end you'll see I've got a number of uh
configuration options here but I've got
my smt P server
configuration and now the way I'm
configuring it is I'm using outlook.
office365.com on Port
995 I've got my uh username in there
entered my password and the sender
address um now Martin nn.com is
authorized to send uh info so that
should work you may want to set up a
mailbox specifically for your account um
and that would obviously make things a
little bit more um
uh generic but you can do that now where
do you get these Account Details from
well you need to open up your browser
log to
your office.
microsoft.com if I sign
in if I think I sign
in Oh wrong
email
and this is my organizational
account that is okay now if I go to my
Outlook address Outlook
app and then if I click on the Cog and
go down to
options now that we are in options um if
you scroll down to the bottom and you'll
see settings for pop or IMAP access if
you click that you will get your uh pop
and IMAP connection details and you can
use that to configure
um release management as I did
here