we are going to take a look at how to do
a migration with the Azure devops
migration tools um I'm going to take a
very straightforward simple migration
and walk you through it um we're also
going to take care of any exceptions or
issues and all those little things uh
that come up at least the common ones
that come up so let me switch to my
desktop there we go uh so first thing
I'm going to do is um install
at the Azure devops tools we need to get
them first um if we go to
GitHub the tool repo uh you'll find just
down on the right hand side you'll find
a little list of all of the releases and
the latest release will be at the top um
so you can use this release here um
whatever the latest one is is the one
you should be using we only support uh
the latest one we have one going through
the pipeline at the moment uh but if you
open up that
release uh if you're in an environment
where you can't you don't really have
internet access you don't have uh any of
those things then you can use uh this
version of the file
here and you just download that and you
will be able to unzip it to any location
any folder and then run uh the migration
from that folder
um so you can you can do that I'm not
going to do that today uh because if you
check out the documentation which if you
scroll down a little bit you will
find a link here to documentation in the
documentation it talks about how you uh
install and configure the tools and
there a little getting started link up
here in the top left um and it talks
about the install now we deploy uh to Wi
get and
chocolatey so so if you are uh on a
Windows Server uh you need to use
chocolatey you can use chocolatey
anywhere in fact uh that you're running
Windows uh but we also have Wing get as
well uh for those of us that are on
Windows 10 or Windows 11 um so let's uh
put this in the other mode I'll switch
over here there we go so what I'm going
to do is I'm going to open uh command
prompt and one thing uh to note is that
you want to use a non-admin command
prompt there's actually a bug in uh
winget uh that if you use an admin
command prompt it doesn't add the app
folder to the path um you don't have to
worry about what that means but they
don't add it to path which means that
you get a missing file so I'm just going
to find the package so if you do Wing
get uh search then I'm going to do um
Azure devops um and pull up the list of
tools that are available for a your
devops and I'm just going to
copy that uh uh ID
there and I'm going to do uh wi get
install that tool and you'll find that
will uh shoot off and go do go do
that it'll take a minute or so it's
going in downloading the package
verifying it and then unpacking it and
setting up uh some stuff but again it is
just a portable uh uh portable setup
while that's running um you can go to uh
do I have the chocolatey Link in here no
I maybe don't have the chocolatey link
anymore cuz we want to use we want to
use the the the new stuff so there we go
starting the install of the package and
it's it's set it up uh so now if I uh
switch to uh see
temp and do di you'll see that I've got
a config file in there I'm actually just
going to overwrite it and create a new
one um by calling the tools so if I go
CLS right so if I want to use the
tools I just call devops migration uh
that will initially show you uh cuz
you've not selected like what do you
want it to do it will say what the
options are and there's in it and
there's execute execute is for executing
a a migration and in it is for creating
config files so if I do init and then
help H you'll see it's got some helpful
options there uh for for what things are
available
um but we're just going to call in it
and it will
create there we go it's updated and
created this config file in C temp so if
I just pop that open and go to Temp
there we go I have that configuration
file here I'm going to open it in visual
studio and there we go I'm all set up
with this is the default out ofth box uh
configuration file um we've got some
changes to the default configuration
file coming down the pipeline just now
they're not quite here yet so there's a
couple of fixies that I have to make so
if you have an older cont file or you've
generated one before uh there's some
fixes that you're going to want to make
uh the first fix is going to be to
remove all of the um field maps here
field maps are great uh for for when you
want to move from one process to another
process uh but they get in the way
especially the default ones do get in
the way uh so we've we've changed that
um so when you create uh although we're
on uh 2.2
three I think if you do
2.2.3 which has already been updated
while the package is being deployed um
then you will uh have these things will
already been removed so you need to
remove that and then down down here uh
there's a skip to final revised work
item type uh that should be false by
default it is currently set to True um
and the other one is these node paths
just get in the way
so you uh best way is just to delete
them and replace it with null and then
they are gone we don't have to worry
about them those are the two things that
you have to that that will be the
default what you see here um will be the
default in by tomorrow by tomorrow let's
see so what we're going to do is we're
going to set up um this for us so we
have a a source project and we have a
Target project okay now the
source project uh we're going to use
prompt to connect to it um and we're
going to connect to an Azure devops
instance in uh preview but uh not this
project that one doesn't exist so I'm
just going to
open that and go to migration Source
this is my uh default uh migration
source project here and something to
note here is that um you will need both
the URL of the
collection and the URL of the project so
this one here is the project and this
here is the collection so if I take I'm
just going to copy the project because I
already have the collection in there and
you'll see here's the collection and I'm
going to update the project now for the
source you don't actually have to worry
about reflected work item ID is not
required for you to update this it can
be anything uh you like it's not going
to use it on here and you can leave this
as prompt because we're only going to
read from the source we never write to
the source we only read from it um so
I'm just going to use prompt there
because it's just easier just now and
then we need a Target project so what
I'm going to do is I'm going to create a
brand new Target project um and I'm
going to call it uh
migration Target three cuz I have lots
of Ingenuity on what to call things um
so I'm going to use the same process so
the source is also this process and I'm
going to create that project here so
while this goes off and creates the the
project this is going to create an empty
project um it is worth noting there we
go uh so this has no work items work
items nothing here uh recently updated
Creed nothing uh recently created
nothing
okay but it does have uh the process
here and if you're looking for the
process I just clicked the project
settings on the bottom left and then uh
once you've got that open uh you will
see the process that's connected to your
project in here and if you click on it
that will go into the definition of the
process so you can take a look even if
you can't edit this you will be able to
read it but you will need to be able to
edit it on the target environment uh for
sure okay uh because every work item
type that's in scope needs a special
field on it so that we can track which
work items we've created and what
they're related to in the source
environment and so for that we actually
add a field uh called reflected work
Item ID so I'm just going to add a new
one just to show you what it would look
like for you so I'm going to create a
new field
ID uh I'm just going to call it
reflected work let's call it three
because I think I already created one
called two reflect work item id 3 it's a
single text line it can go anywhere no
default value and it can go anywhere so
I'm just going to stick it in details
because I don't care okay so there is
added it if you go to edit again and go
to options you'll see what the name of
that field is okay so this is the ref
name rather than the friendly name this
is the friendly name here and then the
under the covers name is the custom uh
do reflected work item ID3 if you've
added or had already got a reflected
work Item ID in your system like I do
going to remove that one which is this
one you can go check in options what the
ref name is and you can see this was
created quite some time ago and as your
devops has changed the way this works
yours will probably say custom if you're
adding it recently um if you've added a
long time ago it will say the name of
the process within which it was added so
that's um nkd scrum so I'm just going to
copy that go back in uh here and now I
can update uh the target element to mkd
scrum that reflected work item id okay
uh the other thing that's worth noting
is that in the Target if you're using uh
uh
azure as your target um you will need to
fill out a personal access token there
are certain capabilities in Ado um that
require us to do some weird patchy
things that require a pat token um so
all you do is on your environment H
click on the little uh person Cog go to
personal access tokens and create a
personal access token you see I created
one earlier so I'm just going to
regenerate that one
and there we go I've got my personal
access token H now you'll notice I have
it set up as full access you can try
other stuff but we tend to use full
access when uh creating these so now all
I need to do is put in my personal
access token in there and if you want to
only use the pat token and not use
prompt um you can
say access token in the authentication
mode and it will just use the token so
we can set that up here so we're going
to use prompt for the source and access
token for the Target um prompt just pops
uh aure active directory authentication
uh and that's that's easy
peasy you don't need to worry about
these language Maps if you have uh you
may need to worry about it in the source
if you're migrating from uh let's say a
German uh installation of uh TFS where
it the database is set up as a German
collation then then uh you'll need to
fill out whatever the German is for area
and whatever the German is for iteration
CU that's uh uh how the system uh stores
it and then that will make sure all the
mappings work uh so you just fill out
your language specific uh uh terminology
in here but 90% of the time you're not
going to need to uh you're not going to
need to do that at
all so then everything else is kind of
uh uh not needed for a simple migration
if you're changing the process or you
want to move data from one field to
another um I've done things like I had a
customer who had uh the version number
as Year Dot number I think it was year
do month in uh their Source system and
in the Target system they wanted two
Fields one with year and one with month
so I just added a field map to Reg X
those out into the individual Fields no
problem at all uh the documentation uh
has a list I jump to the docks
the docs have a list on the left hand
side under under V1 under ref V1 you'll
find a list of field maps here so
there's the regx field map um and all I
did was set up a source field being my
version Target Field my version year
only pattern match the year out and put
it in the new field right that's that's
pretty pretty straightforward so you
would just copy this um obviously change
it to what you need and put it into the
field map okay so it's just a a list of
field maps and the field maps are run in
the order that they're listed there
right so you can control the order a
little
bit if you have links from your work
items to get repos then um you will need
to have those links fixed so that in the
new system um they will match up it's
worth noting that we only fix the work
item connection to the git repo we don't
fix the git repo connection to the work
item so in your git uh commit text uh
you might have IDs for work items that
no longer exist they're not links it's
kind of invalid it's just text but uh um
the link from the work item to the git
commit will be fixed with the tool so if
you've changed the name of the git repo
um you just create a name list of name
value mappings in here similar to the
language map right uh and have the
original git repo and the target git
repo um under here um and only you only
need it if you've changed the name of
your git repo during the migration if
it's the same name on both sides doesn't
matter you don't have to do anything in
there
okay so then uh the main uh body in here
is the processor that's the bit that's
got all the gobbins for actually doing
the
migration and we're actually pretty
close close to being able to run a
migration at the moment so we've set up
the the connection and and then in here
uh we have the the the migration the
important bits are what type of
processor it is and then you've got your
work item query bit here that's one of
the most important uh sections here
we're going to run into a few problems
when we do our migration we're going to
fix them in here uh so I can show you
what that looks like so what I'm going
to do is just show you this uh this
query so in this query here you can see
it excludes certain work item types
these are work item types that we do not
migrate at this point using this tool um
there are things you can do with shared
steps and shared parameters uh but that
is definitely more advanced feedback
requests test plans and test Suites
should never be migrated with the work
item migration processor there's a
separate tool um for for for doing that
stuff so in here uh this is this bit at
the front um and Clos date equals
nothing means that it will only migrate
things that aren't closed uh but I can
just delete that and I will just not
migrate those types of work items
everything else will come across that's
basically everything uh this is great if
you have a really big migration if
you've got more than 10,000 Things uh
that come back from your query you're
going to get an error um and what you're
going to have to do is shape your query
so you bring back chunks of smaller than
10,000 work items um so you might do
that with date ranges uh uh you know
let's migrate everything that's that's
uh been changed in the last 90 days
migrate everything that's been changed
between 1990 120 days and then keep
making those chunks uh in order to
migrate it
across
um and yeah so that's that's it we've
set up our query we've set up our
connection uh we should be good to go so
I'm going to run the migration so I'm
going to switch back to my code there we
go and what we're going to do is we're
going to do devops
migration
execute uh minus C for the for the
config file and it's C EMP um and
it's
is it Jason I actually can't
remember what is that configuration.
Json there we go all so I'm going to run
that there we go so it's loaded the file
and it's done nothing so this is the
first thing that will happen when you
try and run it because you have
forgotten something uh in the config
file you'll notice that it has processor
enabled equals false we need to change
that to through for it to do anything uh
this is so that you can actually um you
can set this up so that um you can have
multiple configs in there and then
enable and disable them as needed I tend
to have multiple files um just to make
things less confusing uh but now going
to go back and run it so this
boom okay so now it's you can see it's
went quite quickly there and I got an
unhandled exception I maybe messed
something up so I will need to check
that so it connected
here
to the source granted then it tried to
connect to the
target with access token
and then I got access
granted and oh look what I did see there
we go what I did was I forgot to update
the project name always something that
Martin does that things up there we go
let's go back to so it's
migration Target three was our empty
empty project there it is Market
migration Target three uh so there we go
I forgot to update
that so C there we go let's run it again
and see what happens so connected to the
source connected to the
Target um and then it's doing a node
migration so it's creating the area and
iteration nodes in the Target all of
these little things here um and they
have to match that's we use a a thing um
called rules overrides
can't remember what it's called by rules
bypass we bypass the rules engine um
which means that uh all of the areas and
iterations that are on the work item
must exist so the first thing we do is
we go through if I make that smaller
there we go uh we go through and this is
uh checking and validating all of the
areas and iterations that are in the
source and checking that they're in and
valid in the Target okay um but
what we also do is after we've loaded
the work items and you see there's 10
work items we actually go through the
full history of all of the work items
and we pull out all the area and
iteration paths and we check that they
all
exist okay we check that they all exist
because in the history there's two
things that might have happened uh you
might have an area or iteration path
that's from a previous project if
somebody has moved a work item from one
project to another only happens in aure
devops but it's possible and the other
issue is that you might have an area or
iteration path that has subsequently
been deleted right so then it doesn't
exist anymore in the source so when we
create the main set it doesn't exist so
what we're what we're going to have to
do is we're going to have to create a
mapping for these the system will stop
and say the missing uh
um missing iteration uh there there's
one that is missing that we need to deal
with actually there's two right because
what it's what it's actually done here
is it's created these two um which it
didn't didn't exist before so it's
generated them on the fly but we're
still missing this one called Sky Point
Cloud because it doesn't recognize what
to do with it right it's from a older
older project uh so if I open up work
item
414 in here so if I just go 414 it
should let me just oh I might need to go
to the source
project
Source 414 there it
is so here's 414 and you can see well
looks like it's got perfectly valid
iterations but if I go in here and all
the way back to the past you'll see that
the team project that it was created in
was skypoint Cloud that is not this
project this is migration source so it's
been moved from one project to another
but that data is still in the history
okay so it's had history and then it's
been changed removed to this this
project so we need to go deal with that
in the config so the config has been
helpful and just said here's the missing
thing you need to add um so I'm going to
grab that cuz that's what we need to
create and go into the config so down in
the config under the processor uh you've
got area maps and iteration Maps I'm
going to give you you some secret
information as well that you need to
need to add so effectively we
have an iteration map that we need to
add for this text right we want to match
this text and map it to uh to something
else uh so I'm going to give you some
Secret Sauce first is that um in Jason
uh you need to escape slashes that's why
that's doing that weird underline so if
I put another slash in we've escaped it
uh but because this left hand side is a
regular expression uh we need to add we
need to escape this the Escape slashes
so we need another two slashes to escape
so when this goes through uh the Json it
will turn into two slashes uh to go into
the r x and the r x will turn it into
one slash for it matching um I know
Madness but there you go um and what we
want to do is we only you know we might
have an iteration path that has skyo
cloud in it like old project SL
something/ skypoint cloud/ Sprint one
and that would match that so just to
protect ourselves it's better to put a
hat at where you want the start of the
string IE this has to be at the
beginning Sky Point cloud and then you
can put a dollar at the end to say that
is the end of the string don't match
anything after that uh so it will only
match this exact text and then our uh
Target project is migration Target three
so what we where we want it to go is M
duration Target three we need to escape
that slash and then Sprint Sprint one
maybe I guess it could be uh uh Sprint
one let's check uh so
migration
Target Target
three
let's go
project iterations oh there's a Sprint
and there's an iteration that's all
messed up but you know that's what there
is uh so we'll put it in Sprint one and
then just to give you a super secret uh
thing there's a a bug at the moment
where it doesn't
list the root as a problem and you'll uh
if you remember from uh viewing the
history uh you'll note that the area
path was also skypoint Cloud so we
actually need to match just skypoint
Cloud on its own and map it uh to
migration Target three for the area maps
Okay so just need to remember uh at the
moment that if you're doing a project to
project map um sorry a project rename or
change then you need to move these in
okay uh so now if I go back and run this
migration you'll see it
will skip past um
that there's loading the work items it's
getting a
list just going to check it
twice there we go now it's migrating
work items so it's iterating through
each of the work items creating them we
iterate through each work item in turn
let that smaller so it makes looks nicer
uh we work iterate through each work
item in turn so when you're doing work
if work item a links to work Item B
we're going to process work item a first
and we're not going to be able to create
the links you'll see on the first work
item it will actually usually say uh you
know migrating link skip skip skip right
that's absolutely fine because the other
side the target side doesn't exist yet
the target work item has not been
migrated yet but as it goes through um
so you'll see skips and then as we go
further down we'll start to see creates
right it's going to create them so when
it creates the other side of the link
it's going to link it back together and
if I go down to the bottom it's probably
pretty close to finished it is finished
so we have just migrated all the work
items and uh links uh for those those
work items and we did it fairly quickly
took 48 seconds there we go so let's
take a look at what we what we created
so in our migration
Target I'm going to look load up work
items
um migration Target three I'm pretty
sure that's what I called it so let's
have a
[Music]
look there we go they are there it was
just a cashing issue so if I go back can
I
uh there we go so here are the work
items uh that we just created uh you can
see there's the one that was moved from
Sky Point cloud and in the history all
the way back in the source it now just
says migration uh three right because we
did that we did that core
mapping um so we got all the work items
if I go to the
backlog close that you able to see that
it's uh linking linking things in and if
I change this to look at parents as well
you'll see there's the feature the
backlog item and the tasks coming in as
well and we did have some other work
items on there right we had uh ppis we
have uh some tasks and stuff so we're
not we're not particularly worried and
there's all the the stuff
there so there you go we just
migrated uh our first set of work items
uh so this operated fairly fairly
quickly um it brought them all across if
you want to run it again uh you can run
it again um and what it will do is it
will go checks everything twice thinking
about how we might resolve that but it
checks everything
twice um so it's going to go through
each of the it's actually not going to
check all of those work items again it's
just going to say that all all work
items were found but what will happen is
at some point somebody will go to the
source okay and they'll go on the
board and they'll whoop drop that item
from resolved to active right because it
because it regressed so now when we run
this we actually want it to um migrate
that extra change but it will not
because at the moment we've got a a a
thing that will remove all found work
items so what you need to do is go in
here filter work items that already
exist in
Target false once you've turned that to
false uh let me do
clear rerun the
migration and what it will do is instead
just going to check it twice again
instead of just not trying to run all
those work items it will run through
each of the work items it will check the
number of revisions and it's found one
work item that has one revision that
needs to be updated and there you go it
is moved that revision across it's going
to check the links as well and make sure
they're all up to date and it skips it
because they're already existing um so
it's checking every revision of every
work item that it exists that it's
correct uh um that all the links work so
it will eventually find that work item
there we go run the whole thing
um and if I go back to so that was the
source if we go to the
Target go to the board it should have
moved across there you go it's now uh
moved across so we reran the migration
uh wow that's aoop oop oop there's a
there there's a bug shouldn't do two of
those but that's the different migration
run that uh we can turn that off in the
config uh but there's that additional
change that came across we changed state
um and then it's adding this text which
it shouldn't do but uh in here uh uh
migration comment B St won't do that
again it can be handy if you want to do
it for the first run because in the
actual work item um it creates a link
back to the old work item so you can
quite easily just click it and go oh
what was the old work item again oh it
was this one does it match yes it
matches right um so people can find that
so there you go that was um a pretty
straightforward uh migration between uh
two Azure devops projects moving the
work items don't forget to check out uh
the git repole for any updates and
changes