one of the seven deadly sins of agile is
envy and for me I think
Envy in agile looks like um just copying
other people's stuff right that's one of
the the the ways it
manifests that um we we we believe we
maybe believe that if somebody else is
getting success with something then of
course we will get success with
something and the difficulty is that
that's not necessarily true at all um
and it I'm going to rephrase that it
might be it might be it might be
possible on the small scale right so
you're you're you're working with a with
a team um one of your colleagues another
scrum master or another product owner is
using a practice that they're like oh
this is great we do this and this and we
have this value stream and we're able to
to to get good good stuff from that and
you're like okay I'd like to try that
right that's that's not really what I
consider Envy that's just trying
stuff Envy would be um looking at a
great example of NB Spotify
model Spotify model is a fantastic
example of Envy there is no such thing
as the spotif model there is no such
thing uh so there was a
presentation uh and a paper uh that a
couple of folks that were were leaders
in at Spotify did at a conference uh so
I think they did a couple of conferences
talking
about what Spotify was
doing what their Journey was and where
they currently were on their
Journey right that was their their
they're telling an example of how they
did things and everybody went ooh the
Spotify model let's let's do that and
they absorb that into their you know I I
want this uh uh um this capability and
they go try and bring it into the
organization but what folks don't
realize is 6 weeks later Spotify were
doing it differently they weren't doing
what was defined in the Spotify Model A
year later they got rid of the idea of
of tribes and uh guilds and whatever
else they were doing because it it
didn't it didn't work for them right
they tried something and it didn't work
for them and that that Envy of oh
they're doing this awesome thing so we
need to be doing that awesome thing I
think it results in a lot of it results
in a lot of fomo if you've heard that
expression fear of missing out I think
that's kind of part of of envy other
people are getting stuff and you want
the same
stuff and that's where at many levels
organizations fail so they fail at the
the the the process level right because
you you look at um a a a Spotify model
or you look at safe or you look at any
of those big uh uh uh models and say I I
want that I want to install that in my
organization and then you pay lots of
money to get it installed and then
wonder why you know you're not getting
the benefit uh there's the the
application Level um I talked about this
recently on a on a podcast um that the
installing an application that enshrines
somebody else's business processes into
your organization is not necessarily
going to be successful for you right so
the example I used before was um sap
right sap is a a massive application
tool very common in our industry but if
you if you adopt a sap tool right sap
comes with a bunch of different
capabilities so let's say it's let's say
it's invoice processing let's say it's
invoice processing right sap has a
workflow for invoice processing that
comes out of the box it has certain ways
that it does things and you're giving up
the way your organization does things in
order to adopt the way sap does things
does that kind of make sense that like
there are some things that you can adapt
in sap but only within the bounds of
what the developers that created it
allow which means that when you see some
of your
competitors um perhaps installing sap
and building their whole procurement
processes in sap you think oh we need to
do that if they're doing that we need to
do that or if our competitors are adding
these features to our product we need to
add those features to our product and
that that's that's that's following
that's Envy right that's following not
building your own path uh Simon syak
does a great video uh that is on this
topic and he talks about the the the the
why you know start with why and he talks
about going to two uh conferences one's
a Microsoft conference under Balmer uh
and one's a Apple conference and at the
Microsoft conference everybody wanted to
know what their competitors were doing
what are their competitors doing what
are their competitors saying uh uh what
are they what are they launching what
features do they have at the Apple
conference they didn't give a crap about
what the competitors were doing they're
like this is the way we're going we're
doing this CU it fits within our belief
model generos yes generosity Comfort
confidence contentedness friendliness
Goodwill kindness benevolence friendship
those are the the Opposites of of of
envy and I think that that if you can
put
aside what everybody else is doing and
focus on what do you need to do and what
do your customers need um you'll have a
lot better time both in the process
space in the in the tool space and in
your organizational structure space
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked
agility