this workshop is for practitioners that
are interested in starting a career as a
scrum master existing scrum masters
agile coaches and consultants
trying to improve their use of scramble
the professional scrum master is an
engaging enjoyable learning experience
where students gain a deep understanding
of scrum theory and principles scrum
master accountabilities and why each
element of the scrum framework is
important our training is delivered as
an interactive activity-based course
over half-day sessions using microsoft
teams in europe between sessions we
provide additional reading writing and
watching activities to maximize the
learning opportunities and complement
the classroom experience after the
conclusion of the class we provide
access to a community of peers
and continued access to the trainer
through office hours quarterly catch-ups
and constant engagement to maximize
validated learning all students are
provided with a password to take psm-1
assessment and if they take it within 14
days and are unsuccessful they will be
granted a second attempt
[Applause]
you