well the question is the tools you use
to train are awesome how do people
transfer their training experience
with these tools into their job
they need to try stuff that that's the
thing that I kind of try and encourage
people to do and it's one of the
particular reasons that I talk about
how I run different segments of the
class that met a conversation about how
I run different segments of the class
with them as well as actually running
the class I guess it depends on the
group as well right if you've got a
bunch of practitioners and scrum Masters
and facilitators who are interested in
that stuff I maybe spent more time on it
than than other classes
but those
um those tools like the different
flavors of liberating structures for the
virtual world are things that they can
take away and use in their own
organization to help them make their
environments a little bit better to help
people engage and and tell stories a
little bit better inside of their
organization because that's really how
humans connect information to the real
world is through stories
and how do you tell your stories in a
way that helps other people inside of
your organization understand them
um
so some examples of of tools uh one of
one of the key and it's one of the the
foundational Tools in
um in liberating structures is the the
it's called a one two four all it's a
great tool
um where you do one minute on your own
two minutes in pairs four minutes and
two pairs and then bringing everybody
back and the the core goal is always
I've got a group of people they're not a
tiny group of people there may be a
bigger group of people and I want them
to engage on a particular topic and come
up with ideas
but I don't want to just ask the room
let's say you've got 20 people in the
room I don't want to just ask the room
um what do you think about this topic
because you know already before you ask
the question the one either nobody's
gonna say anything and it's going to be
tumbleweeds going past right or you've
got that one person who you know is the
loudest person in the room they're going
to be the only one that speaks or the
hippo in the room right the highest paid
person uh is going to be the one that
that that that talks and everybody else
can be like I don't want to see anything
in case the you know get in trouble
so how do you create an environment
where everybody's voice is is equally
contributing to the story and enable all
of them even if it's just they feel like
they're involved in the conversation
that they're getting getting their
stories across so one minute on your own
right is everybody heads down write some
ideas on your own and then you go into
Pairs and this is this is this is my
interpretation of this based on based on
my personality right but I feel like I'm
an introvert maybe it doesn't seem that
way but I am
um I'm an introvert and having one
person to go speak to
and express my ideas to is great right
because I'm not talking to a big room of
people I don't feel like I'm going to be
ashamed by people and people in the room
who don't like my idea but I can share
it in this small group and then we
shared our ideas we've collaborated in
our ideas it's only two minutes right
but you get that feeling and then you go
into two pairs so that's two friends
right people who have made friends and
collaborated on their ideas coming
together to to expand those ideas and
make them bigger
and then when you bring it back to the
rest of the room you've maybe only got
three four or five groups of people
to hear from and you're healing hearing
collaboratively created ideas so it's
it's okay to have a spokesperson in that
group and everybody else doesn't feel
like they're not being heard right
because they've already had those
conversations and built up to that story
and that that's just one of the tools in
liberating structures and you can also
take what what do we do with the output
of that well maybe we feed it into
something else that we use to you know
we've created a whole list of ideas and
perhaps we want to figure out
how do we get through that growing zone
in the middle of of of collaboration and
coming to consensus towards having that
back consensus and single idea like what
is it we're going to do do next
so so helping people understand how
those tools work in their world they can
experience using some of those tools in
the class and then hopefully they can
see how they function so that they can
then take them and use them in their own
facilitation techniques as well and
because I I I feel like I specialize in
the virtual space I feel like most
people are in either hybrid or all
virtual environments today
and there's no point I feel there's less
value in you coming to an in-person
class and me teaching you how to run all
these liberating structures or or using
them you seeing those liberating
structures being used in the physical
space and then you go back to work and
there's three people online and two
people in the office and you're like
well I can't use that thing that Martin
used because it doesn't fit the space
that I'm in just now
whereas if you come to a virtual class
you're going to learn how to do that in
the virtual space and we've all seen if
you're in the hybrid world is really the
same as the virtual world except a few
people are in the office and they go sit
at their desk and everybody has their
own camera and their own so you can do
the breakout rooms you can do use those
tools and that's also partly you know
using using the the Technologies as well
that we use in the class we use mural in
my classes we use mural and Microsoft
teams
um enable people to then go back to the
office and use similar techniques again
additional meta learning from the class
where they're able to learn more than
the content that we're actually teaching
them because they're learning how to
actually
do those things through experience
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility