my name is Dave fresh I'm a developer
with health grades
I I was vehemently opposed to the course
initially because I didn't understand
the value and spending at least couple
of days away from development in order
to understand the process that we set
myself we were already using
what is focusing on the foundations of
scrum understanding how to use from the
professional manner and really focusing
on refinements is that something that we
have been missing previously so the cost
changed your mind very quickly
this is going to help health grapes
because we are going to be delivering
valuable deliverable software or
products every sprint as opposed to
throwing things against a wall which was
our sprint previously too often people
especially individuals from the business
will come over and say hey I need this
now without understanding that there's a
there's an order of systems in a process
that needs to happen in order for their
what they believe to be an emergency to
be implemented
absolutely I think it's important for
everybody to understand the process that
needs to be applied here whether or not
they they are a full-time member of the
squad they need to be aware of how to
operate