if you are working on an agile team and
you're focused on story points and
velocity then you're probably an agile
Bandit um story points and velocity has
a really negative impact on our ability
to deliver for many teams I know there
are going to be lots of people that and
you're welcome to comment um that story
points and velocity works great for you
uh I'm I'm sure that are teams out there
I have yet to meet a team that uses
story points or velocity uh that got a
positive benefit from it um and that's
from observing many many many teams um
it creates uh uh um lot lots of little
negative niggles like um getting Point
wanting to put things in the Sprint to
get the points right oh we're going to
have a we're going to put a bug in the
Sprint how many points is this worth so
that we can get our points at the end of
this Sprint and the point becomes the
points we don't want the point to be the
points we want the point to be the value
that we deliver for our customers the
points are irrelevant the points are
just a tool to help us as developers on
a team have a
conversation about what we know and what
we don't and our understanding and to
gain more understanding that's the point
of any estimation for complex cognitive
work where You' you're building a brand
new product that doesn't exist yet you
want to be focused on the flow of work
through your system and throughput and
cycle time those are the metrics you're
looking for story points and velocity
are terrible metrics for teams to look
at and I I do there are lots of teams uh
uh especially brand new teams who have
never done anything before that
definitely get encouraged to move down
the story Point route and I I just it's
a bad idea um ditch the story points
from the start focus on Flow metrics
cycle time throughput go there um I did
have a a customer recently um who
made the
biggest agile banditry mistake I have
ever seen and that was that story points
were in the contract with the
customer they were
mandated to do story Point estimation
UPF front to provide that story Point
estimation to the customer and the
customer would measure the team based on
the number of story points that they
delivered and if you were out with a 15%
standard deviation of the number of
story points you normally deliver then
you were in trouble and potentially in
breach of contract with penalties that
come along with it I can't think of a
better way for everybody to just make up
whatever they needed in order to
complete the contract right you're not
going to get transparency there you're
not going to be able to see what's going
on those story points are not going to
be the story points that you want them
to be um even if you could possibly get
there which I don't think you can ditch
story points don't have them in
contracts H don't ever talk about story
points outside of the team if you want
to do um planning poker uh and sit with
a with a team on a team and do planning
poker fantastic uh great tool to help us
as a team collaborate and figure out
what we don't know but at the end of
that event at the end of that meeting
delete all the data it is of no value
whatsoever beyond our understanding of
the need to bring break things down
that's what estimation is about it's not
about story points and it's not about
velocity and product owners should not
be using velocity to monit monitor teams
that way lies agile banditry so you
should avoid being agile Bandits and
instead of focusing on story points and
velocity subjective matrics focus more
on objective metrics like throughput and
cycle time
don't be agile Bandits if you're being
ambushed by agile bandits in your
organization then my team at naked
agility can help you or we can help you
find a consultant or expert who can you
can set up a no obligation consultation
using the links
below don't forget to like And subscribe
if you enjoyed this video