I think the most common um challenge
that organizations face when trying to
adopt uh devops practices is regression
I think that's probably the best way to
describe it is you make two steps
forward and five steps backwards and
part of that is um how do we maintain
our ability to control risk within this
new context because the risk profile is
different
because the risk profile is different we
need different tools and techniques to
manage that risk um in in the old the
old days I'm calling it the old days it
might be the current days for lots of
organizations but in the old days the
the we we would spend a bunch of time
designing our product right we would
design the architecture we would decide
what we're going to build we would list
out all of the features and then would
work towards some kind of release date
of our product and then once we get to
that close to that release date once
we've delivered a a body of of features
that make sense we're going to test
those features so we have a different
group of people who are who are testing
and validating um those features I mean
it is still quite common to have
separate test teams to engineering teams
rather than a combined uh combined arms
combined engineering Force and um then
once they've done those testing it's
probably handed off to some kind of
operations team who are going to deploy
it to an environment and then something
like uat is going to start where you
have some kind of additional validation
of uh um what's what's going on in the
product and then once all of those
things are are successful then it moves
on to um maybe deploy to production or
staging or you know you might have other
environments that the traditional most
common traditional model is deploy by
environment and that fundamentally
doesn't work within the context of of of
of devops it's going to slow you down um
it's not going to get you the the the
key thing that devops that's trying to
bring to your business is high quality
flexibility adaptability and your
ability to validate assumptions right we
we have an assumption that this feature
is going to be valuable but in order to
actually validate it no matter how much
stuff we do on paper or in Labs or in um
studies right no matter how much of that
stuff we do the only place to really
validate that feature is is in
production um a great example of that is
uh Windows 8 right Microsoft spent
hundreds of Millions on user experience
um on Labs on um flying people into labs
to video them using the product
performing certain tasks and then
getting feedback from them in interviews
or sitting with people that are using
the product all of those types of things
they did all of the things that you're
supposed to do and still they ended up
with a product that bounced off their
consumers from a usability perspective
and
and that is because of that production
problem um one of my favorite uh people
Brian Harry um who used to run the Azure
devops team um he made this comment that
I loved and it was there's no place like
production right the little red shoes
there's no place like production because
no matter how much testing no matter how
much validation you do especially if
you're in the service
world where you're building a service
that's that's got thousands and
thousands of customers using the same
service no matter what you do you cannot
simulate production you just can't it's
not possible to simulate production we
we can we can make it maybe we can do
some stuff but that's that that common
challenge is how do we address these
things as that world is changing right
we've no longer got 6 months or a year
or the windows team used to be on
six-year delivery that's how long it
would take them to get a new version of
Windows out the door from from starting
writing the code to it actually been
released to production was six years
they've got six years to do testing uh
oh I had a colleague from Boeing um and
he talked about um one of the things
that he saw as a problem and he said
Boeing don't build quality in they test
quality in right so you've got all of
this aggressive testing that's happening
as part of you're building something and
then you're testing it oh right it
failed right so what do we have to do
differently that that is a quite often
you have to do that with some
manufacturing stuff these days you've
got simulators so you can you can
digital simulators you can do a lot more
but in the software world we don't have
to suffer from from that problem right
we we don't have to spend lots of time
building a rocket to put it on a rocket
pad and launch it and then it explodes
and we look at the Telemetry and figured
out what went wrong we don't have to do
that we're building software we can get
that software out the door as quickly as
humanly possible with the level of
quality that we need to maintain our
business brand or our our H um uh
protect our business protect our
consumers and protect our producers
right um with that level of quality and
we can get things out the door as
quickly as possible test it in the real
world test it in the market find out how
accepted that thing is in the market
whether it's increasing our Market or
decreasing our market and then adapt
around that and that's part of that that
devop story is closing those feedback
loops not just identifying those
feedback loops and eliminating waste in
the process to get it to go through the
process as quickly as possible but
actually closing the feedback looks not
just collecting the dat
closing those feedback loops so the the
two big common challenges um that that I
see is one is that huge one is closing
the feedback loops and but the other one
is actually getting how do
we change the way we understand our risk
profile and how we mitigate and organize
around risk within that context and then
how do we
adapt to the the things that we see in a
timely manner those are the two most
common challenges and those are the
things that we can help teams products
and your organization deal with and
figure out how to do better