[Music]
oh you love it when that when a plan
doesn't come together
there we go
so
let's do that
so i'm six minutes late running six
minutes late already how's that for for
timing for folks so let me put another
uh i'm gonna put about five minutes on
the timer
for us to answer some of these questions
and i can see that the everything is
working now
i have a i have a visitor who wants to
say hello
um
because she gets upset when she gets
left out of things
yeah
well plus i had to go shut the curtains
because otherwise she barks at everybody
that walks past
do you have a dog garden
yeah we've got a couple of dogs yeah
we've got a couple of dogs yeah but our
family uh pizza snake she's a lot more
she's she's a lot more quiet
i said with her on my hand and then she
like pops her head up in front of the
camera and everyone just sees a snake
every night i will i will lock that
background
for
um
i'm gonna let the last few people in
we've got 20 people that's pretty good
oh
more admittance
i will post the mural link again for
those that just popped in
so those that just arrived the link
for
the mural is in the chat uh we're just
doing the ice breaker i'm going to lock
the meeting uh when we're done with the
icebreaker um
so that
we don't keep getting uh people bouncing
around
because that was a problem last time
oh somebody's been changing their mind
oh let's see this is this is very uh
much more
what's the the contentious these
questions it might be the way i phrased
them maybe i've just phrased them badly
it could be weird it could be that i've
just phrased them badly right that's
entirely possible so when i go through i
can clarify but maybe i've deliberately
phrased them in a contentious way
so that we have a conversation ah that
could be my secret weapon
yes i did forget about four
don't worry it's just a question mark it
was meant to be like that
okay
ah thank you for the green tick on the
four for the question mark thank you for
that whoever that was gordon i knew it
was gordon
it's always gordon
okay
so cool
i got a couple more people coming in is
that unlocked again
there's some secret way
that people are able to grab things that
are locked in mural at the moment i'll
report it as a bug but
we'll see it generally it's good wow
we have a lot of answers to these uh
questions 23 people in the mural now so
i just brought everybody to the same
place sorry if you're removing something
okay
see many people have answered
somebody else got a dachshund
they they have this thing where they
just like to lick
yeah they're liquors
my favorite uh meme with dachshunds is a
dachshund did a barbecue and it says
would you like yours licked or unlicked
only joking i licked them all
i'm gonna have to put her down because
how is that getting dragged around
that's that's that's like that
background's locked and somebody keeps
managing to let me just delete the true
and the false background there we go
since it was uh uh
getting moved around
there's about a minute i think most
people have answered um so i am going to
i'm going to lock
i'm going to lock the meeting
oh one person getting at the last second
just as i was going to click the lock
button
let me how do i do this
there lock
okay
no one else
right in theory we are not going to get
uh interrupted again
so let's have a a little look here well
this is a lot more contentious than i
was expecting it to be
um i'm i'm gonna blame wade for that i
think um
wade wade's
been a bad influence there oh
so um let's let's start from from one
and go from there and just um i'm gonna
see how much we i'm on a time limit
right so i don't want to go too long
so i'll maybe just give some answers
uh
based on
the scrum the scrum guide right so that
there's an answer based on the scrum
guide and then uh
there's maybe wiggle room right because
it's a guide not a rule book uh so if
it's a guide then there's obviously
wiggle room
so it says scrum teams must not uh be
bigger than 10
okay
uh quite a few people looks a little bit
like 50 50
on that one oh i can take the end
private mode there we go
i think if people created a sticky
uh then
oh maybe i shouldn't have clicked that
button because i've got a spinner
hold on just a sec uh but
where does it say
in the scrum guide
that scrum teams can't be bigger than
10.
it doesn't
doesn't say that at all right
might might teams bigger than 10 be more
difficult to manage might they more be
difficult to communicate yeah
right
um but a good example is the azure
devops team
teams at microsoft that's about 650
people or it was before the github
acquisition um and
they are teams of about 12
right and they seem to be able to
successfully
build build a product
um so it depends who you need on your
team how big it is
smaller might be better but it doesn't
mean it can't be big
uh so i'm just gonna what i'm gonna do
is i'm gonna just grab one of the
crosses and make it bigger uh for for
for my uh suggestion
uh scrum master is there to make sure
that the developers take enough work
and get it done i i like all of you that
had a cross
right that's obviously uh well not
obviously because one person said yes
right but it's definitely not the case
the scrum master is not there to make
sure anything gets done
they're there to facilitate it getting
done
uh number three the daily scrum uh the
develop daily at the daily scrum the
developers must each day say what they
did yesterday what they will do today
and what's blocking them
no
doesn't say that the scrum guide at all
no mention of the three questions uh
there you in the previous versions of
the guide it mentioned the questions as
here's how you might ask those things
right so it's definitely not mandated in
fact i would suggest if you're still
doing the three questions after 10
sprints your folks are probably bored
out of their mind
right so you want to you want to keep
changing it up get to the root of the
problem which we're going to we're going
to talk about
which is
understanding right understanding what's
going on uh each day so we'll come back
to that uh so from three we go to four
which
gordon you were right um he got a green
tick on there at five at the sprint
review the developers present their work
to the product owner
um no i can see uh
navlin shaking her head
um that is a big big no-no
the product owner is presenting what was
done to the stakeholders
right so i've been in d in sprint
reviews
where the team says this is how we did
something
a stakeholder says why did you do it
that way and the product owner turns to
them and goes yes why did you do it that
way
right that is not a team member
scrum team product owner is part of the
team they should be standing in front of
that team
and defending
whatever was done and seeking feedback
from the stakeholders and maybe we'll
take that feedback and maybe we won't
right because
maybe there's time constraints maybe
there's money constraints um it's not
it's not a free-for-all
right so that's that's really important
uh number six
uh you must be finished with all of the
things in your sprint backlog by the end
of the sprint uh the knees have it that
is a nice big x you don't have to be
finished with the doll
if we're on time
right if we if we have a fixed uh a
budget which is the number of people
fixed time which is the sprint
what happens when we fix scope as well
quality suffers right we don't want to
do that so the the scope is always
variable
in a sprint we may or not get to do
stuff
uh number seven the scrum master does
not even have to attend
the daily scrum
that is correct it is true they don't
even have to be there um i think the
wording in the scrum guide is they
help facilitate as needed or as
requested
right so they don't have to be there in
fact if they have to be there every
sprint that to me suggests a dependency
on the scrum master which is not
supposed to be there obviously if
they're a team member they're going to
be there because they're they're on the
team as well
at number eight ux work is separate and
should be done as a separate stream i
love all those crosses
that is awesome uh i am in 100 agreement
it's not a separate stream of work it's
part of the team's work it's part of
building the software just like
architectures you could put anything in
that ux
word there you could say architecture
you could say security you could say
what else could you say gordon pretty
much anything any type of work i was
just gonna be security because normally
that's the thing that people would say
like oh no that's some other folks they
need to worry about security
yeah and then what happens when those
folks get your software
they think it's terrible
right
number nine product backlogs should
always contain user stories
there are lots of ticks there
unfortunately if you put a green tick
that is not true there is no mention of
the word user story in the scrum guide
user stories are not a thing um they are
might be useful for you or they might
not right but scrum doesn't mandate them
and number 10 last one developers commit
to delivering the sprint backlog at the
sprint planning event
i am disappointed to see all those ticks
i'm going to put a nice big cross
on that one they do not commit to the
sprint backlog because that would be
committing to scope
again
right we already had that question you
get the other one right but not this one
right because it's a common thing they
used to use the word commitment
during uh
the the sprint planning
and the word commitment if you look it
up in the dictionary
right means try really hard to achieve
it doesn't mean guarantee
okay but lots of people
take it to mean guarantee especially
spouses right if you've if you if you if
you made wedding vows right you made a
commitment it's more or less a guarantee
um but then
they change it to forecast
so that you're forecasting the work it's
a prediction of how much we're going to
get done and what happens to predictions
sometimes they don't come true
right and that's okay that needs to be
okay otherwise we're committed to scope
and quality
drops awesome
so that definitely uh uh helps me set
the tone oh that's predominantly x's i
only got one with a with a with a tick
on it that actually surprises me because
i was trying to
be more flexible but there's so many uh
um what they called uh
myths
david corbin calls them myths
about scrum
um and they're really common that's why
we get into a lot of trouble
and so we're gonna do a couple of
exercises around uh uh this idea of
scrum how come that says there's two
presenters
sometimes i don't understand teams
garden
um
it doesn't help that this is a beta
version of teams
that we're using my tenant
is in the beta place victoria yes
victoria's got her hand up
hello martin hello everyone
so my question has to do with the first
one around the number of people that
make up the scrum team yes
in the new guide
it talks about
a scram team being small enough to
remain nimble yes and
10 or fewer people
so yeah and it does say
typically typically it's 10 or fewer
people and and that is that is correct
right typically it's 10 or fewer people
but for example that a good example is
there's your devops team or the windows
team yeah at microsoft right they're
they're doing everything inside of the
sprint all of the security is checked
the documentation's updated the the um
it's ready to ship at the end of the
sprint and in fact they do ship at least
at the end of the sprint if not
continuously throughout the sprint
if you're there
what do you need to be sure you can
deliver that software what do you need
done do you need security work done do
you need documentation um do you need ux
uh what else could be in that list could
you might need compliance or legal uh to
sign off depending on the type of
software you're building if you're
building some financial software and
maybe you need some financial uh
knowledge in there on the team so that
maybe adds a few extra people you've got
somebody on the team who
who trained as a lawyer right but is now
a software engineer so they can help
answer those more complex legal
questions you've got somebody who
was a security expert or as a security
expert but also a developer
right how many people do you need on
your team to build working software and
i think you're right the phrasing in the
scrum guide
is that
your team should be small enough to
remain nimble
right
but also large enough to get the work
done
and that that's that balance how many
people do you need
on the team
uh so somebody is uh posting a little uh
message there on the side saying sorry
they can't seem to get into the session
yes as i posted a couple of times i am
closing it after 10 minutes um because
if we start doing breakout rooms it's
really disruptive uh for the breakout
rooms when uh people come in and out uh
during during the breakout rooms it's it
breaks the breakout rooms i have spoken
to the team about this and they do know
about it the microsoft teams team
so let's spend a little bit of time on
on scrum because i think we need to need
to get some some some knowledge in there
so the first exercise i'd like to do
is i'd like to do a it's a liberating
structure um called one two four all
we're gonna see if it works better this
time it didn't work so well last uh
session but closing the meeting should
resolve that okay
and what i'd like you to do is like you
to pop open notepad or the equivalent on
your computer it can be any way of
taking notes on your computer
and write on each line a list of things
that you know
you know of that's part of scrum
so if you use user stories i want to see
user stories on that list even though we
already said it's not really part of
scrum right it's not needed for scrum
but it's part of that story isn't it how
many teams do you work with that that
don't use user stories right very few
so uh um
create a list of items so i'm gonna put
one minute on the timer
for you to silently and on your own
create that list
the reason that i asked you to put it in
notepad
is that if you copy out of notepad click
on the mural and paste it will create a
post-it for each entry
right that way you can very easily
get it onto the get it onto the mural
so one of the things that you know of as
part of scrum maybe you've heard of
ceremonies or events
or roles
or
um commitments
there might be some
what else might there be gordon
roles artifacts events
accountabilities
um practices
some good practices there are definitely
some
there are bad practices too ones that
most of the time have a negative impact
okay so i um we've got exactly 20 people
i love it when the numbers are even i
did not
close the rooms just when it was even i
didn't do that
um so i'm going to create 10 breakout
rooms all right we'll see how this uh it
goes because um last time oh that was
really fast
okay so i'm quite i'm definitely in a
happier place that was really fast
creating them so i'm going to open the
breakout rooms you'll get a 10 second
warning and then you'll head into uh the
rooms and you'll be in rooms of pairs so
only be two of you in the room what i'd
like you to do is get your items onto
the mural right you can just copy from
notepad and paste and it will create a
post-it for each line and then merge
your lists together you know so there'll
be some duplicates get rid of the
duplicates merge them together create a
single unified list maybe add some more
things as you bounce ideas off each
other
and then after two minutes you'll only
have two minutes to do that so it's not
a lot of time and i'm gonna merge
two of the rooms together so you should
then be in rooms of four
okay if you end up in a pair and the
other person's
gone to get a cup of tea i'm sorry uh um
if you if you ping me i should be able
to pull you out the room and you can
just talk to me um but
that is always a danger so i'm to open
the rooms i've clicked the open button
there is no going back once i've done
that
um
and you should have a little warning and
then you'll disappear in about
10 seconds after that so you'll have two
minutes
in pairs
to merge your lists uh just pick a spot
on the mural there i'll summon everybody
there we go
um
perfect okay
so
right
so you on the if you're on the stream or
you're watching the recording you're
still with me
everybody's gone into their breakout
rooms um so they should be starting to
to add uh things oh looks like that one
hasn't gone well that paste oh let me
get rid of the
height facility to cursors don't show me
cursors there we go
um that way we don't see a lot of
cursors running around on the on the
screen
uh there's one room that's causing a
problem
uh
john and
soyzo are you okay
let me call you again
okay i'm gonna bring john i think you're
gone zoyzo
okay so i'm gonna i'm gonna um
there's only 58 seconds left so i'm
going to leave john in there um
and then i'm going to
click assign participants and then this
is the mental thing that i'm going to do
so i'm going to forget about size
they've left that's the problem
so 10
merges into one
nine
merges into two
eight
seven
energies into
four
six emerges into
five
oh there's one person who's also left
okay
renata's left okay okay so
12 seconds and then i click the assign
button
and i've
broken teams
because if somebody leaves the meeting
then when you select them and try and
move them around it goes ah actually
gets confused so let me assign the
people i can move it's going to move
eight people because two people dropped
out
and half the people stay in their
meeting so let's see how that's doing
i'm gonna
add
four
we're gonna have to do some work to get
this mural into good shape
yeah let's
i am going to close that room
and close this room so one two three
four five okay so we've got enough rooms
we've got enough things
let's do that
i'm just helping out by
breaking things into
groups of things
there we go
so as soon as people click off
i can get it into
a set of post-its because we want a set
of post-its for one of the next
exercises we're going to do so it should
only be everybody's in the breakout room
just as on the stream on the recording
uh there's two minutes 50 seconds left
on the mural there you can see
uh so they're just creating creating
this list so uh some of them have gone
for for
accountabilities but we've got stories
user testing sprints artifacts and
comments these are good
uh sprint reviews this one's good as
well let me copy that um
all right i made that purple because he
was using purple there we go there's
your purple cards back again
uh
just sending a couple of messages uh so
we've got scrum commitments on the board
so i just messaged them and said um
try and
do it
try and change it so that it's a list of
commitments there are three commitments
what are they so what are the
commitments in scrum
uh with roles from accountabilities what
what are they
uh so we're starting to get groups of
things as three pillars
well there's lots of things coming in
based on empiricism
three three main artifacts
yep yep you're right there are three
main artifacts and they are the
uh
well they're not that so let me
just making some of these i know it's a
bit boring when you're just watching the
recording but i'm making these into
individual
cards because we're going to use them in
the next exercise
um
[Music]
in 24 seconds i'm gonna oh wow this is
i've got i've got to do some notepad
work now
let me split that up there we go
oh somebody's got jira
on there oh i made that dark green there
we go i'm gonna close the rooms
oh now i have to close them individually
because my all closed rooms is gone
because of the
people that were
so teams people if you're listening
if yeah so one person
it just negates the team actually uh
you could have various titles but
uh
yeah i was just gonna i was just gonna
go find and click the mute all button uh
just just um it is very easy sometimes
because teams kind of moves you
mid-sentence
uh and you wanna finish that thought
train um that's quite good i can see
there's a lot of things coming in it
looks like it was a little bit more
difficult than i thought it would be to
create multiple post-its when you paste
stuff in right it seems that some maybe
somebody's using uh um whereas i can see
somebody's making it into a straight
list
for that big one the whoever's the i
think that somebody's a raccoon the
green raccoon um is is is doing that um
once you've got them in a in a list you
should be able to just
select
edit it copy it
paste it onto the mural and it will
create individual cards
but that's a nice big list from whatever
group is that is
we have quite a lot of things on this
list we've got artifacts there was a few
things that were a little bit like
grouped like scrum commitments yes there
are scrum commitments but what are they
scrum accountabilities it rolls oh
somebody's get
user stories so we can just call that
card user stories there we go
uh scrum accountabilities
and tell you what i will copy that one
and
there you go with your
list i just sorted that out for you
uh
okay we have a lot of things
there's a lot of things here that are
scrambling all the things that aren't
scrum let's see i'm looking for
something particular
oh trello is on there i like jira jira's
on there
um
ah
one
has five values but didn't list them
let me list the scrum values
let me remember what they are there's a
little hint
here
focus
okay
so i've got i've got them here
for us
courage
respect
focus commitment and openness
the idea is that
purely with the mechanics
of scrum i know some of your engineers
i'm looking at you garden
right
um
when you're an engineer the mechanics
if you focus too much on the mechanics
you just end up with something
mechanical
but scrum is about people
and what's more important than processes
and tools and metunia
i did that badly sorry
chichi
i didn't hear what you say mutton what
what a see now i've forgotten because i
i garbled you
you asked what's more important than
process and tools yeah
interactions interactions
people and interactions
more important than processes and tools
so courage respect focus commitment and
openness is trying to encourage
those people and interactions a little
bit more right some of these are things
are quite difficult for engineers
um so we're gonna do a little uh scrum
circuit we're gonna use those cards that
we just created again
right in the next exercise we're gonna
do a little scrum circuit
and in a scrum circuit
um i'm going to create
five random rooms we did lose two people
okay that's how come i know at least one
of you ended up in a room on their own
um and that's because we now have how
many people do we now have
now i've got to look because microsoft
makes me do math 18 18.
that's including me and there's one at
the bottom at the bottom
yeah so uh what's 17 divided by
what's 17 divided by five
five i can create five rooms there we go
three points three points
thank you garden
see that's how you know gordon's an
engineer
right all the other managers they were
thinking three right gardens like three
point something
um
so i've created five rooms
it that when you go into your breakout
room at the top of the room you'll see
the room number
right so it'll say room one room two
room three room four one five
and you see i've got five stations wow
they match up perfectly right if if
it's as if i created that situation so
i'd like you to do is go to the station
that matches your room number so if
you're in uh
room five
um
you'll end up at openness
okay
and the idea is that you go to open this
and i want you to spend a little bit of
time
creating
some some post-its around here you
should be able to oh that's a massive
post-it create some small post-its
uh that represent
behaviors that you see in people with
the scrum values
right so what sort of behaviors would
you see around
openness
right try and be specific like a thing
that you've seen happen
um and how it serves or inhibits
transparency
right so sometimes being too open
right we've all got that customer
that if you're too open
right it has a negative impact on your
relationship
right gordon's got that customer i can
see that
right so you need to balance the level
of openness
with the level of trust
right how much do you trust that
customer to be able to provide openness
so none of these exist on their own but
i want you to think about in each box at
create a number doesn't have to be one
it could be two or three post it so
you'll have five minutes
in your station
that you start with and then at the end
of that i'll send you a message and
restart the timer for three minutes
and you go to the next station
numerically
right gordon yes when you're at five you
go to one okay just making sure you know
that i put a little message down here
just for gordon
go to station one
in the bottom right of that uh when you
get to five so it just loops round okay
so you'll see all of the stations
and if you go to a station where there's
already a bunch of ideas and post-its
review and you'll have three minutes to
review and reflect on
what the previous people came up with
but also change things that don't make
sense add things that you think of so
you're augmenting
each of the little
displays as you go through and we're
thinking about how the scrum values
affect the behavior of people on the
scrum team
okay people and interactions
so i will uh
click the open button so we'll get 10
seconds
hopefully this will all work this time
and i've added some post-its on there so
that there's there's some pre-made sizes
so maybe hopefully it won't create one's
too big
um so start at the station that's the
same as your room number
okay
five minutes send a message
uh five
room number there we go five minutes at
the station tomorrow so i've sent them a
message
uh we have
one person on hold
so
i'm not sure what will happen
in uh the
room if they're on hold they should just
go
right so microsoft teams team if you're
breakout rooms team if you're listening
if somebody's on hold
and i create a breakout room
put them in the breakout
because at the moment i get a little
exclamation mark saying that it couldn't
put them in the break-up room
participants currently not in the
meeting
cannot be reassigned to different rooms
right but that's not intuitive when they
come back they're now not in the room i
want them to be in the room
so even if they're on hold or they've
disconnected or
whatever's
i want them to go in that um room and
not
break stuff because it's just
unintuitive
that's my
thing
so hopefully hopefully hopefully you're
listening i'm not complaining i mean i'm
using using teams and it's super awesome
and this is this is feedback based on
the types of activities that i do which
i know are not the same as what
everybody else does
so let's get back to the scrum values
circuit
so we have
station one is off
on a rip roaring time so they're got
sprint review what didn't go well
uh
let's do
this is not
i'm thinking of how to augment room one
i think i'm gonna have to go to room one
and help them out a little bit
so i don't know what will happen when i
disappear in there so we'll see uh
opinion
so like if you think something is right
but it's not really the pop the popular
mindset or pattern
um
be able to say that it sort of talks to
that
so um i was
just popped in uh to say so some of
those are a little bit vague like
retrospectives
what what is the courageous behavior
that you would see
in a team during retrospect during a
retrospective what might a courageous
thing be
discussing what didn't go well
yeah
so for pushing or pushing back on any
commitments
so if someone wants to commit another
stories that you'll accent
and if they haven't looked at how it
affects your testing you know you're a
tester you might want to push back on
that
and that's not always a popular thing to
do
you know always want to commit stuff and
get as much done but that just screws up
your velocity then because you can't
think too much you haven't committed
yeah so discussing what didn't go well
based on
expectations right maybe you've got to
tell a customer they're not getting the
thing they really want
that's that that happens right what
other difficult discussions might you
have in some of the other events around
courage
i don't
okay i should be back
yes i am back oh that worked quite well
that that worked really well going into
the breaker room so you still heard me
in the breakout room that was i was in
room one uh with wade and gordon
um
so let's see how everybody else is doing
keeping attention on the sprint backlog
yep so focus is doing well
um respect
respecting each other's views and
opinions it's a little bit vague
keeping each other informed people feel
free to contribute
to contribute in meetings because they
know their views and opinions are
respected yep yep people contributing in
the event um so what about commitment
doing what you say you'll do
supporting other team members
asking all the silly questions cool
so what should should happen there's a
little bit of a meta uh discussion
around this scrum values circuit um what
i have 12 seconds left
so at the end of the 12 seconds
um i'm gonna set a timer for three
minutes and message them to tell them to
go to the next station
so there's the
bing bong
gotta keep the airplane noise
three minutes
there we go go to the next station so i
send a message to everybody saying go to
the next station
um and it's
room plus one
so i've copied that message
so that they can uh um i can send room
plus two room plus three so if you
remember what room you're in because it
says the top of your screen you know
which one to go to and it helps a little
bit and we'll see how how people get
confused
and
room five goes to room one
so hopefully
hopefully this is going pretty good so
that team went to
room two
so the idea uh behind this exercise got
a few minutes
the idea behind this exercise is that if
i just tell people about the scrum
values
they won't they won't they won't
remember
half they won't even remember 20 of what
i say
so instead
if they experience something to do with
the scrum values they'll remember them a
little bit better they'll remember the
impact or they'll remember you know
people remember things in different ways
and so they're gonna
it's this is a riff
on the liberating structure shift and
share that normally in a shift and share
somebody stays behind to present
the content that was created
um but that's actually really difficult
to facilitate in um the live virtual
world um i do do it in some exercises
but really only in private classes
because i can't i can guarantee that i
can pin people and move other people to
the next room so i actually have to move
them between the rooms
um and that works better when
everybody's authenticated in one account
and they're online and all that kind of
stuff
it's same as in zoom by the way
it's not more difficult in teams
um it's just the same
uh
but this means that people get to see
they get to create one right so they'll
remember a lot about the one they
created but then they're reviewing a
whole bunch of other content and
reviewing it with the same group that
they're discussing as they go between
the rooms so um they build a little uh
relationship they spend about 20 minutes
with that one group of people um and
they're talking about courage and then
they're talking about respect and then
they're talking about focus and they do
it one at a time and it it just builds a
little bit more knowledge
um
so if i was doing this exercise
like as a as just a bunch of groups talk
about the events it probably probably
would take 10 minutes right and
next room
message
room plus
two
um
it would take about 10 minutes this
takes twice as long but i think it's
more than twice as effective
so i'd rather
they understood this stuff because what
have we got left on our timer
um
we've used 45 minutes so we've got
another 45 minutes
left
ish
um
so let's see what we've got left to do
while everybody's out in their
breakout rooms so i'm gonna copy these
post-its down
and we're going to do an exercise
uh with
putting the post-its on do we require
are they complementary do they have a
negative impact uh that should be fun
and then i just get the
scrum story
right so i may hit this a little bit
less because we're time constrained and
i suck at keeping time that's just the
way it is
uh i don't think
actually we might spend
we might do do we need it and then the
scrum story and leave it there
right we might not have time for this
empiricism exercise
which is around the events oh it's only
20 minutes so maybe we will 20 and then
20. oh that could work
i thought that was longer but it's 5-33
[Music]
the second
circuit that you do with people always
goes better because now they know what
they're doing
let's see
no because we get 20 and then 20 so
there's 40 minutes left now
and we've still got
two more of these
then this
oh no
if we can get done by 20 past
we can do the
empiricism if not i'll spend more time
on the scrum story
right because there was a lot of good
the ice breaker had a lot of good
questions
i know i know i'm narrating but there's
nobody else here you're really watching
what everybody else is doing
um so let's go have a look again at the
things this is courage after um
so this is the third team that's looked
at courage
and they've got asking for help saying
no
saying what didn't go well
sharing your opinion having difficult
decisions
which items make it into the sprint
backlog
which tools to use as a developer yeah
that's good
station two oh we're coming up with
another
station change
bing bong
and then
three minutes
move to station
next station
and there's one more
uh so
station two
understanding yep respect
no judging
yeah not judging that's a good one
respect other people's time
finger pointing
being accommodating
well there's a balance to how you have
there i really like there's a book um
called never split the difference
um which is by uh uh the fbi hostage
negotiator bloke it's really good
um and sometimes
being accommodating is not the right way
to get to a good answer and and there's
a lot of good techniques in his his book
they're really individual well the way i
think about the really individual
techniques because it's a negotiator
negotiating with either one person or a
group
um
so it's useful uh but i'd like to see
how that works within a a a
the ideas work within a bigger system so
you have you know a team of people a
group of people who are all
collaborating with each other how do you
uh uh analyze that
i'm hoping that i'm doing going to do
some stuff around the
orsk
organization organizational systems
coaching um
and hopefully there's some stuff in
there around that that i want to to do a
bit of a bit of diving into
uh treat as people not otherwise yes i
saw recently a post online from a
company i'm working with and the hr
director uh was say it was it was an
email
i was saying
sending email out to everybody and
calling them resources it's like
you've just
called them all things
right make sure time sheets are all up
to date for resources and i'm like oh
try and treat people like people re-read
the things that you've written from the
perspective of empathy
and see if it still matches up
uh so station three was focus
so this is the fourth team through
there's one more one more group to come
through
blockers are quickly cleared out because
they're focusing do one thing at a time
somebody's done about whip limits
awesome um
protecting the team from interruptions
avoid multitasking
good sprint goal concentration
pomodaro yep my wife uses that
a clear acceptance criteria knowing the
value that the goal should deliver
these are good
right so 17 seconds left on this one
and then uh we can go to commitment and
have a look
um
i'm going to focus on the change for
just a sec
it's actually not hard to just can't do
two things at once
so the timer is going to go off
and i need to wait for a sec and now i
can do another three minutes
little message
for
last one wee
there we go
so i sent that announcement out to all
the rooms oh i've got a little message
in the chat maybe somebody's pinged me
and going
we
we need you oh no it's just somebody
posted the scrum guide what'd they post
yeah
it's like commitment thing
okay
not sure what they meant but we'll find
out
okay so everybody we're back in three
minutes i know you can only you
generally only see me and then the weird
teams thing uh below um i'm using
uh
ndi
uh so teams has the ability to stream uh
um
the different feeds in teams out on a
network broadcast right so tv studios
might use that sort of thing
um so i'm streaming i'm streaming that i
have a tool i have the the ndi 5 tools
installed on my desktop and i'm running
their tool called screen capture hx
which creates a network stream for each
of my screens on my desktop so they're
only active if somebody connects to it
right
um
okay i had a little commitment let's go
to open this
it's only active if somebody connects to
it but it means i have another laptop
over here that's doing the live stream
and it is uh showing
this screen
in the top portion
and then um
i've got the the me so this is teams
local it's showing which is me and then
the one at the bottom there is active
speaker so it's only going to show
if people have their camera on
and they're they're i'll show the last
person
that's speaking that's got their camera
on so the last person that's speaking
turns their camera off you get that um
if there's no cameras on because there's
none just now everybody's out in their
breakout room um you get uh
that as well
um it can be nice if it was just blank
but at least you know it's working i
don't know i it works for me
so i don't see a lot of let's zoom out
and see if there's a lot of change wow
there's a lot of post-its right that's a
lot of content that they've managed to
create
in that time
if i just sent
if i put them in groups of five and sent
them out and said go answer the question
of how the scrum values affect the
behaviors here's a list of the values
you would never get that much content
they're actually thinking about it
bouncing ideas off each other having
conversations so i do five groups
regardless of the number of people
so in
here in our breakup rooms we've got four
four three three three
right so it's a groups of four or three
times up close the rooms
um take about 10 seconds to close the
ribs
um but it
it worked really well even if you had
six people
right uh five groups of six works fine
as long as it's kind of scrum teams
yes hi john it's martin again we're all
back in the main room
it can be
i know it it can be a little bit
confusing when it kind of surprises you
a little bit you turn away and turn back
and ever there's everybody there instead
of just a few people
and people like to i don't i
i have my camera on all the time but i
know some people they're okay having
their camera on in small groups but they
prefer not to have it on in big groups
that's that's okay
this is this is the the fun of the live
virtual world
um
wow you guys created a lot of content
if you zoom out a little bit
if i summon everybody to look at the
whole picture
oh i'm sorry john if nobody was saying
anything in your room you were in with
uh simona and
fiona i think
um
[Music]
you will not get the same group again i
create all the groups randomly so if you
end up in a a negative group please ping
me
if you're having a problem because i can
always jump in and
see if i can figure out how to how to
get people chatting
um
i think you should be able to act
mention me in the chat um
so just do that okay
next time yeah because that's a long
exercise to to have that way
maybe they'd gone for coffee
uh
so hopefully
hopefully you learned a little bit about
the scrum values
while while you were in
your your your little uh discussions
uh i went round and we had i chatted
with the with with whoever is on the
stream i don't think there's anybody but
whoever's on the stream uh uh about
what you were writing and how you were
changing it um as you were going through
as well
and there was nothing that i i i didn't
like these are all good answers to these
stories
okay um
was there anything that surprised you
wait
sorry i'm just trying to find my ambient
button
um
yeah there was actually
i think i think one of the things about
carriage is there's there's a lot to add
but
how different things actually overlap on
each other as well because sometimes
some items from courage will come into
openness
so you can get over
as we move to the next station how many
people
write different things and you view it
in a different way so yeah it was
interesting yeah and that that's so the
the way i've done this exercise before
is i just say here's the five
values
go into your room and discuss the
behaviors right and you get nothing like
this amount of content
um because it's just too open there's
two there's too many choices and
people's brains shut down um i you for
those that were here last week you know
i have a lot of board games behind me i
have my green screen up just now but i
have a lot of board games and it's
if there's too many choices
you get something called ap
analysis paralysis
right your brain shuts down and you
can't figure out how to make a choice
and you take a long time um
this helps
bring down those choices while still
giving you all the options
which is nice so i'm glad that when that
that went well i like all of the things
uh that are on here
so i'm gonna do i'm gonna zoom out a
little bit
i have one last exercise i'd like to do
and we're gonna go and grab
the
cards that we made before
okay uh well maybe we'll grab them by
there we go it's letting me grab them
now so i'm gonna copy these and we're
gonna bring them down
to this uh this other exercise so let me
this will look a bit weird first
and then i'm going to
[Music]
resize to default
hopefully that will work
and then we want them let's make them a
little bit better shape there we go
and then pump them in a grid there we go
we got a massive
massive grid of stuff
there that we created earlier and it has
jumbled them up which is very deliberate
um also i didn't have a choice but it is
very deliberate as well um
that i have i have um three columns
here
uh we have required by scrum okay things
that are part of scrum and are required
to create and maintain the system that
it is it's an empirical process control
system so what do we have to have
right in order for that to function
right like an engine in your car if you
take out a part of the engine it doesn't
function in the same way
right so what are the parts that we need
to function
and then what are the complementary
practices right things that we can
choose to use
that can be beneficial it won't always
be beneficial that but it can i i was
trying to find
uh an example there which was user
stories
i i oh there is i found it see how
i've done this before it's going to put
user stories in complementary practices
they're not required by scrum but
they're
definitely lots of teams get use out of
it i have seen user stories end badly
okay in teams i've seen it end very
especially for api teams or
infrastructure teams or i don't know
anybody who's who doesn't have a user at
the end of their story don't use user
stories because it doesn't make sense
you trying to squish everything into the
terminology of a user story is not super
valuable
um so i'd like you to yep somebody's
already started start grabbing uh cards
and move them to the column that you
think they should be in
okay
based on the the statement
i'd also like you to there's a disputed
area at the bottom
if you
see a card that's in a place that you
don't like
feel free to move it
okay
if it you're moving it for the second
time put it in the disputed area
okay that way you're not arguing with
somebody over who owns the card we just
put it in the disputed area and then we
can we can chat about it
or maybe you just put i think product or
product manager might have ended up in
the disputed area without a dispute
because somebody wants a conversation
that's a sneaky way
in your infrastructure example
maybe they're not doing the the cattle
they instead doing pets so they're gonna
have user stories because their pets at
the end of it i think oh actually
exactly i mean you can
you can you can try really hard
alfred sorry i just muted you there um
uh
so let's let's see i'm
gonna i'm gonna zoom in to the required
by scrum and just see if there's
anything
uh
that i think
anybody see anything in
there that looks
like it shouldn't be there oh looks like
it should be there to me
it's quite a lot of cards though
we did create a lot of cards that's the
advantage to having lots of people in
the room
don't worry about it
if you do see duplicates do feel free to
to delete and keep one
okay
um
we could have done a de-doping exercise
earlier but it just takes a long time
what's an f15 or if is it f15 i don't
know whether you mean
like is ff-15s uh uh a fighter jet is it
not
sometimes when you create a card it just
flips over and just puts f15 and
even even though you've talked to
something else i found that happened
once or twice with me you you you are
you are you're absolutely right i have
seen that happen to other people too it
doesn't happen that often i don't know
what it is i think it's uh
like like i say in all my sessions um
mural is built in javascript
and any of you that are engineers know
exactly what the problem is
okay
wow we've got quite a few things in in
in
their
complementary practices
okay so
let's have a look
um
i'm just going to
grab everything in there and grid it
there we go
so it's just a little bit neater
uh so let's see
uh sprint reviews product backlog
uh scrum commitments planning inspection
daily meetings these are these are all
all things that are required by scrum
has three accountabilities i'm just
gonna delete that one it's too vague
right scrum accountability's too vague
they're the the product owner scrum
master and developers they're all in
here somewhere
um has five values we didn't list them
so i'll keep that one
um let's go to complementary practices
uh there's two user stories risks
sure risk management could be a
complimentary practice it in the in the
if you were at the previous session i
did on introduction to agile we talked
about how we manage risk in our
empirical world right and that's by
delivering working software at the end
of every sprint that's how we mitigate
risk because the variance is too big to
mitigate it with a plan um but it's
entirely possible
uh epics issues
load testing
features
ah i'm gonna put time boxes on the line
right uh there's five events i'm gonna
take that one refinement i'm gonna put
that down there
uh iterations
adaption
adaption and transparency are not
complementary practices they're core
practices take them over uh pbis
backlogs so product backlog items are
mentioned in the scrum guide
right so i'm going to take them over to
to required you need something in your
backlog
but user story and requirements
are types of things that you might have
as backlog items and that bit is your
choice does that make sense
right you're gonna have something on
your backlog here's an entry on my
backlog a unique distinct transparent
thing
okay
in scrum we call that a product backlog
item
um and we definitely have backlogs so we
can't have that on complementary
practices
and time boxes and refinement
so refinement is mentioned in the scrum
guide
right it just doesn't have an event for
it but you still have to do it
so
let's grid let's grid those again
there we go we'll grid those over there
and then in the middle we've got a bunch
of complementary practices i don't see
anything negative in there
and then what was f15
what was that 15 you remember waves
that's why it doesn't support scrum
i'm going to take it off because we
don't know what it is
um so we've negative impact we've got um
tfs devops
um i'm going to bring that down into
disputed and i'm going to group it with
jira trello and tfs and i'm going to put
them in
complementary prices right there is
i don't like jira
right
i see jira quite often have a negative
impact i sometimes see tfs have a
negative impact on teams right tfs
probably more than the people
all the people than the tool that's the
negative impact i yes it's the the
people
or the
process imposed upon the people by
somebody who's an admin in one of those
tools and nobody else is allowed to
change it right that's the problem like
gordon you'll know um the the the the
template that the windows team use or
used to use
for their work items
had 200 fields required fields to submit
a bug
right
exactly how many bugs do you think get
submitted when you have 200 required
fields
but they don't have much bugs right
wow so they've solved the problem solve
the problem of creating bugs
sometimes when we don't like something
right we put too many things in the way
one of the common ones that i see a lot
in organizations is we don't want to
accept changing requirements even late
in development
one of the principles of the agile
manifesto so what do we do we put
processes and procedures in the way of
the customer so that the it's expensive
or time-consuming for them to change
things that are on our backlog
right but we want to be accommodating
collaborative
uh with the customer
uh user user testing um
as it's described there i would put it
in
negative impact
right uat
user testing is something that we can't
automate
and we're going to want to do user
testing
but not before we're done not as part of
scrum that might be our output is
deployed to production and then there's
a bunch of things that happen to
validate whether we have been successful
at delivering the right thing so user
testing is valuable but not inside of
the scrum story that's why i'm going to
leave it in disputed actually because i
don't want to put it in
negative practices uh user stories i'm
quite did somebody want to have a
conversation about user stories
they moved it to disputed yes
chichi
that was me um
with the user stories i was thinking
the user
estimate the stories and then and then
they they
depending on what technique they use to
estimate their stories they might they
might give certain stories um the
importance that it doesn't deserve and
deserve and then that just brings the
confusion
uh between between them and wasting time
on things that don't add value at the
end of the day to the outcome or
the product that you have
and then
um
when they bring the the
user stories um the estimation when they
show them at the demo at the review
whatever you you decide to call it
that's the other disputed uh
thing whether you call the reviewer demo
or whatever you're trying to do
when they when they show them to the
stakeholders um it gives the
stakeholders um
the stakeholders will probably say oh
you said you're going to do this and
deliver this at a certain time based on
what you estimated
so that's the argument i was trying to
bring forth on the user's stories yeah
so it's just the estimation
yeah it's the estimation that's the
problem not the user's goals themselves
i noticed we didn't have estimation so
that's that's interesting and i'm
actually going to
based on that randomly
that was actually that was my first item
and then i didn't add it because i i
don't know i was tapping all the stuff
but i had i had only two items
estimations and ceremonies and i didn't
look at my list because we had so many
things so i'm pretty sure
[Music]
yeah so the word estimation
is not
in the scrum gate
no it's not it's not
so so what do we call it then
what is it
so there is there is an activity
after
the so i i'm okay with estimation right
so estimation is definitely a
complementary practice
we want to understand how much work is
involved and estimation is one of the
most common ways for people doing that
right so it's okay to do that i
doing estimation in hours is not wrong
right
there's no no there's no point in the
scrum guide that says you are you are
bad if you're doing estimates in hours
right i don't like estimates in hours
because i don't think it works and i
don't think it adds value but some
people find value from it
the the we do need to um
do some level of understanding of how
big things are things need to be ready
for the team to pull into sprint
planning
need to be ready
right what does ready mean
well it's not really defined
in the scrum guide it just says things
near the top of the backlog might be
deemed to be ready
right but if you walk into sprint
planning
and you as a team don't understand
what your sprint goal is likely to be
you don't understand
what you're likely to be bringing into
the sprint
it's not ready
what is the activity
that's mentioned in the scrum guide
where we would figure that stuff out
that'll be the defined one
it would indeed be the refinement
refinement
in scrum sometimes called grooming right
and the old guides that used to call it
grooming but refinement
is that story
around
the team looking forward into the future
what's coming up next not what are we
doing now
right that's in our sprint backlog
that's in our sprint plan that's what
we're doing now
but what's coming up next
right if you if you're if you're working
on uh uh
if you're working on a scrum team
and you get into sprint planning
and you realize that you need a new
server but you've got a six week leak
time for ordering servers because you
work at gordon's company
i'm just messing with you
but uh you've got a six week lead time
is that
in time or is that too late
it depends how long your sprints are
what you could have two months if you
get a six week sprint then you're not
doing scrum either right uh if you
didn't most people do two week sprints
these days
right
you should be able to to to to get that
thing within the time period or have it
ready
what happens if you get halfway through
the sprint and you realize that some
data that is supposed to be provided by
the customer isn't there and that
particular person that the customer is
not going to be available for three or
four days
right
you're not doing that thing
that's too late to find out you need
that data
wouldn't it have been nice to know that
you need that data six weeks in advance
and ask them for it six weeks in advance
so then you walk into the sprint
planning and you're like oh we've got
the data we understand what it is
somebody's done the the the ux design
it's ready to go we know what that is we
know what we're doing
so in that scenario is that is that
where you get
halfway through the sprints and then you
realize you need the data or is that
before the sprint started you knew you
were getting it halfway through because
you wouldn't want to take something
that's volatile into the sprint
yeah so i i
if i thought that the data was going to
be that might be made available halfway
through the sprint i probably wouldn't
take that item into the sprint yeah
because i'd be thinking maybe it won't
turn up right unless i actually have it
we don't know how long it's going to
take for that to turn up even if
somebody's promised it right because
what happens when people promise stuff
outside of the team
maybe it doesn't happen is there not a
fine line between
over-refining so coming up with every
single
conceivable action that you need to do
in order to deliver that piece of
functionality versus
find out as you go as you go
ab absolute absolutely john so um
the the the guidance used to be looking
looking about two sprints out
into the future
and doing you as the team's best efforts
based on the risk of not delivering
something
right so you need to find that balance
for your team there's no no hard or fast
rules if if you get halfway through the
sprint and you needed something and it
means you can't deliver that thing but
it's not that big a deal it's not that
big a deal right but if you get halfway
through the sprint and suddenly you're
not able to release your product uh and
it's a a good a firmware fix for a
medical device that really has to
we needed to know that first so it
depends on the the level of risk that
you're accepting and that the business
is accepting how likely are we to get to
the end of the sprint and have a a
working thing if something's missing
maybe we've got the engineering
practices john that we've got feature
flags and we're okay with testing in
production and we're okay with
continuous delivery but we can hide that
feature that we built half of and
couldn't finish this sprint
right but do we have the engineering
practices to do that and not just do we
have the engineering practices but do we
trust our engineering practices enough
to do that
right and again that depends on what's
the risk if you're building firmware for
pacemakers maybe that risk is too high
to do any sort of testing in production
if you're building uh um uh uh if you're
building a system upon which your
business decides or processes financial
transactions maybe the risk is too high
right
um but if you're building something that
has a lower impact
maybe it's okay
a really good good example is a a
starbucks um the company i used to work
with in seattle at northwest cadence
with steve borg and they did
work with starbucks and starbucks had a
um expected planning horizon
of 48 hours for their point of point of
sale system so they built it all in
house
right and the idea is that
not for big features
right but if some competitor comes out
with something that some offer something
that they're doing that we can't support
we want to be able to deliver that
inside of the point of sale to every
till worldwide in 48 hours
so what what yeah exactly garden so
there's risk in that
right and we've all been into starbucks
and the tales are down
right we've all had that experience but
the business has decided that the risk
of the till being down
is lower than the risk of losing
customers to not being able to
service that offer that thing
the the the customer the wall but i can
get that it it costs cost or i can get
that at the other tillies or whatever
whatever your other places
and they have robust manual processes
i've never not been able to get my
coffee in starbucks
right they can do a manual process and
i've walked in with my starbucks card
they can't take the money off it
right i don't have any other payment
options and they've given me a free
coffee
because starbucks would rather you were
a happy customer and you came back
then they lose the business
so with robust practices around it
you can support that faster delivery
schedule but that's the whole business
needs to support that from every angle
uh
so user test i'm going to leave that in
disputed
testing to be honest
in terms of estimation i just wanted to
add i think instead of estimation i
think somewhere just mentions about the
size size
so it doesn't talk about estimation but
it just mentions about size just add
that
yeah and i think you're right
um so
in product backlog it says that uh
so refinement's an ongoing activity um
and adds details such as a description
order and size
right to the things in your in your in
your product backlog
so
it's you want things to be sized
appropriately for the type of work that
you're doing right and i'm definitely
using vagaries here because there's no
rules for how big should your backlog
item be
um should it be big enough to fit in a
sprint i'd like that um is it okay if it
doesn't fit in your sprint and we can do
it anyway
yes because otherwise how do we do those
things
right um is it okay to start a piece of
work that's not going to be finished at
the end of the sprint
yes if your engineering practices are
awesome if your engineering practices
are not that great and you aren't able
to create a working increment at the end
of every sprint and hide features that
are unfinished
maybe you want to finish stuff by the
end of the sprint until you do have
those engineering practices in place
right so uh there's definitely a lot of
a lot of work on that but yeah sizing is
is is a useful tool how big is this
thing right because that's going to help
the product owner understand whether
they need to
break it down whether they're going to
do it at all right if it's a really
expensive item to build because it's
huge
but it's only going to get them a
limited set of value why would they
build it
right it's going to go to the bottom of
the backlog or be deleted
we're not going to do that thing
so there's only five minutes left in the
time box
for this event
i have no
and i have no next meeting so i'm
perfectly happy to hang out for for
questions and stuff but i wanted to
just at the end walk through
um a story
of scrum
so i've got this little uh what i call
this is my little backlog item here
uh
unlock there we go got can you see my
little backlog item do i have to i'm
gonna make it oh i'm not gonna do that i
was gonna change the color but it
disappeared we could see it and then
yeah yeah that's because i tried to
change the color and it disappeared
that's a javascript bug
and
i did not change it to white i changed
it to purple and it still disappeared
uh so what what what what i'm gonna do
i'm just gonna gonna
like a day a day in life a sprint in the
life of this uh uh this backlog item
here
right uh so at the the the start uh when
the product owner comes up with it it's
this massive thing
that goes
massive vague thing that goes and sits
in the product backlog
right um we're gonna the product owner
is gonna have this some discussions in
the business around it they may be if
it's really big they maybe have to do a
business case right how are we going to
fund this are we going to pay for it
and then maybe he thinks about breaking
it down into lots of smaller items so we
get a bunch of smaller items here's
here's one of the smaller items that
we're going to look at so as
it gets closer to the top of the backlog
at some point the product owner is going
to say i am okay
with the team spending time on this
right i want to pay for it
so then the team's going to bring it in
scope for their refinement
it's going to talk about it they're
going to discuss it they're going to add
some details they may have conversations
and questions for the product owner or
other people in the business and this is
going to slowly drift towards the top of
the product backlog and become ready so
that was its refinement it's refined to
ready
right but you don't refine stuff that
the product owner is not willing to pay
for
because that's cost you
money and then
we also have a product goal
for our product backlog that's our
commitment
to the product backlog but it informs
the product backlog it does not control
it
right it's okay to have things in the
product backlog that are not to do with
the product goal but the product goal
provides us focus and we want to
maximize focus so you can figure out how
to how to do that
then at some point the team heads into
sprint planning
and
this item this item's actually not to do
with the goal it's a little uh a little
side thing that they're going to do so
they're going to bring it into sprint
planning they've already sized and
estimated their things towards their
sprint goal they've created a sprint
goal and this is an extra thing they're
doing as you know some customers have
been asking for it it's a little small
thing it's not something that's going to
impact our sprint goal we can take it on
anyway so they bring it bring it into
the into the sprint
uh they planned out uh they create an
actionable plan for at least the first
24 hours and it ends up assigned to
their sprint back clock so it's not
towards the goal but it's within the
scope of the sprint
we're going to do it anyway there's this
item and there's a couple of bugs and
then there's five or six things that are
to do with the goal in our sprint and
we've got plan for the first 24 hours
we then every day
we're gonna work
right we're gonna work for we're not
gonna work for 24 hours but you know
that story we the next 24 hours later
we're gonna do our daily scrum
in our daily scrum we're going to review
our progress towards our sprint goal
and create an actionable plan for the
next 24 hours right what are we going to
do in the next 24 hours does our sprint
back clock still reflect transparency of
the present
right are we still on track to achieve
our sprint goal
those are the sort of questions we're
going to answer so you'll they go around
this loop every day
right keeping this sprint back clog
trans as transparent as possible it
reflects reality
and then somewhere near the end of the
sprint or maybe at any time during the
sprint they have an increment
right there's an expression that an
increment is born
when the product meets the definition of
done i kind of like that expression but
it needs a lot of unpacking to really
understand it
what it really means is at least once
per sprint
you have all of the work that you've
been doing plus everything that went
before meets the definition of done and
we say this is a working version of our
product
right that's our increment so it meets
the definition of done and this the
story's part of it
and then we're going to review it
right this is where uh uh and jumunya
was talking about the i got it right
that time uh was talking about or at
least close enough it was talking about
uh the demo you might do a demo as part
of your sprint review you also might not
right you don't have to do a demo i know
plenty of teams that don't do demos
but we want to reflect on the product
that we have
and update you can see that little line
coming out at the bottom of the sprint
review
we're reflecting on the product backlog
does the product backlog still reflect
transparency of the future
right does it still mean what we need to
do next
that's the purpose of the sprint review
based on the work we've just done over
the last two weeks
how do we need to change the product
back clouds so it still reflects
transparency so we know what's next
right everything else
is a complementary practice
doing a demo complimentary practice
answering the the questions
complementary practice right it's no
problem wade uh thank you for for being
here thanks very much very much
[Music]
right and then at the end of the sprint
review when you've reviewed the products
we go into
a sprint retro but we don't take the
backlog item with us i'll put it back
over here we go into our sprint retro
and we figure out is there something we
could have done better
is there something that we can do to
make our team more effective
right and that could be at the team
level it could be at the product level
it could be the organization level it
could be at the tools level it could be
at the relationships level you know
martin and gordon are arguing all the
time over um how they want to store
items and azure devops that's cool all
right
um
how's house
gordon and i are both devops mvps um so
we spent a lot of time with azure devops
that's why um that's a kind of in-joke
there
but
we reflect on how we do things how we
work together
and hopefully we have maybe some
improvements that might come into the
next print
and we do it again and we keep going
around that loop
so we have
in in
yellow there
i have the three
transparencies right the artifacts
product backlog sprint backlog and
increment and each one of them has a
commitment
to that item
the product backlog's commitment is the
product goal the sprint backlog's
commitment is the sprint goal
and the increments commitment is
definition of done
right that's our commitments to our
transparency
and then we have
four moments to inspect and adapt sprint
planning daily scrum sprint review and
retrospective
sprint planning inspect and adapt on the
product backlog to create the sprint
back clock daily scrum we're inspecting
the sprint backlog and adapting the
sprint back clock the review we're
inspecting the increment and adapting
the product backlog and in the
retrospective we're inspecting and
adapting ourselves
question or unpopular opinion
potentially with the
the sprint duration
out of a sprint retrospective
one of those items being that we need to
increase or decrease the length of our
sprint based on what we know the the
future looks like so near the beginning
potentially three-week sprints because
you're laying down a lot of foundation
but as you move into smaller stuff
where you generally be taking more into
a sprint to create more focus you bring
the duration of the sprint smaller
that's okay
so there's nothing i i think it's
dangerous right
and i've seen that work really badly for
teams but if you know what you're doing
you're you're you're looking at the work
you're doing and you're like we can make
our sprint shorter and get a tighter
feedback loop
awesome
right that is an okay change to make
um i would be worried if a team was
changing their sprint length every
sprint right
um that would that would worry me but
it's it's
just super fine to to to change uh uh
the length of your sprint you go from
four weeks to three weeks to two weeks
to one week yeah
the the i hear or at least i heard many
moons ago that the azure
team that managed the software that
controls azure and did daily sprints
so they deployed to production at the
end of every day um and decided what
they were going to work on that morning
and they had to stand up every hour
i stand up every year
that's the only bit i know i mean yeah
totally it totally totally could be but
i mean that's
when when i do when i do training
right we do um either 30 minute sprints
or 120 minutes sprints i think it's 75
minutes of work or 30 minutes of work um
and yeah that's that the teams that do
really well
will
you know every five minutes let's say in
a 30-minute sprint they have a quick
quick check right is everybody okay does
anybody need any help
right are we are we still getting the
stuff okay right let's let's go it takes
a few seconds to have that conversation
but somebody who was sitting there
noodling on something goes up no i can i
get some help
right let's help that person and then
we don't blow our 30-minute sprint
that's a short sprint by the way
yeah
and obviously you said that there was
you know there was the singular
increment
or you didn't say that was the singular
yes absolutely so um
there's a detachment that happens once
teams get enough uh get a
good enough engineering practices where
they're able to detach the planning
cadence which is your sprints
from the delivery cadence which is your
engineering practices
um so the the way that i usually see
that work is teams move towards
continuous delivery right every commit
that makes it into master that passes
all the checks ends up in production
right so they're continuously delivering
to production meeting all the checks
meeting their definition of done with
every single
ship to production but they still have
that two-week
planning cadence where they're
interacting with the business on that
planning cadence they're getting people
into their review on that planning
cadence um the azure devops team are a
good example of that although they they
talk about three-week sprints
right so three weeks
deployment first release although they
are releasing when they do a deployment
to the outside world they're releasing
every three weeks but that's just as a
ceremony where they say this is the
changes for the last three the changes
we've made in the last three weeks yeah
yeah most of them are already in
production they have a small number of
changes that they have to fit into that
rolling three week
because they're they've managed to micro
service a lot of stuff right and all the
micro services and satellite systems are
all working on that continuous delivery
cadence but then there's that bit that
used to be tfs in the middle the big
ball of fur they get hacked up by the
cat and it still needs a much more
controlled deployment much more
deliberate much more checks so they do
that over a a a rolling a longer rolling
deployment um so they might need to put
some stuff features on there and they
can only turn on the feature
once both
parts are shipped right once both parts
are in production you've got the the
rolling feature update where you've got
once every three weeks or it takes three
weeks to actually deploy it and then
you've got the other stuff
i and you see it as well in in microsoft
teams if you're a microsoft teams user
and you'll see that you can be sitting
next to somebody who has different
features from you
because they roll out features um in a
ring-based controlled exposure to
production system so not everybody
inside of a tenant gets the features at
the same time because there might be a
hundred thousand people inside of a
company right maybe three hundred
thousand people and what's tata tartar's
got like
600 000 people working for them right
they're all inside of one
tenant you can't just turn features on
for
more than half a million people and
expect everything to be happy you've got
to roll it out slowly so that you can
see the performance impact you can see
all of those things
yeah like that
that's slow rolled out this is like one
of the things that i think is from one
of the builds probably like six years
ago or something like that
where they
switched it on
like as they announced that they
switched it out yeah and then it wasn't
available for anyone because
the system just kicking in and then
people accessing it like it ended up
bringing the system down
it's not just the the the um there's
your devops team that had that problem
yeah all
uh uh the the the teams at microsoft
have had that problem in some shape or
another of they've they've turned
something on when it's been announced at
the conference
right and it's just taking out the
entire system because something's up or
too many people hit it at the same time
and so i i hear garden that there's now
a rule inside of microsoft that you're
not allowed to present any feature a
conference unless it's been in
production for at least 48 hours before
you announce it right and that's the
mitigate that's to mitigate that problem
yeah
you've got a chance to kick the tires on
it i mean generally like i mean if you
just browse around like the maximum
state like the week before a major
conference you'll start seeing stuff
that you don't know about because
it's about yeah
yeah it's about to be announced and that
you got to kick the tires right i i'm
i'm running on windows 11 and it doesn't
ship for how long does to windows 6 11
ships like it's october or something
yeah somewhere around there yeah running
windows 11
yeah
some interesting things the first
release we had
was the taskbar
this taskbar showed on the other screen
but you couldn't get any of your windows
with your icons so like if you drag
something you just lost it
so so i think i think it it's
it's important one one of the one of the
complementary practices that i really
recommend
there's a we're talking a little bit of
engineering stuff i know for example uh
uh uh eki's maybe a little bit less
interested in the engineering side maybe
uh and with engineering as well but um
the the the
that controlled exposure to production
is one of those advanced engineering
practices that allows teams
to continuously deliver to production
and
do something called testing in
production which sounds scary and it's
supposed to be scary because you need
good engineering practices to do it you
can't just uh you can't just do that
well i'm gonna i'm gonna uh
wrap it up for the
people that would like to go just now
i'm going to leave this diagram up i'm
going to pdf uh the the the mural um and
i'm going to
um send it out for everybody that that
signed up um obviously the video is
when i hit end it will already be on the
live stream i have already scheduled
next to gordon what time is it for you
uh
oh
dear you tired
you had a long day
it was a very long day you need water
you need some water yeah
so um the session in two weeks is going
to be a little bit later because i'm
teaching a psm class during the day that
finishes at five so it'll be 5 30 uh utc
plus one
whatever that makes it for you um if you
go to my website it will
convert it to lots of different time
zones for you which will make it easier
um and it's on linkedin as well and it's
an introduction to kanban
and flow
um so we're gonna gonna do do some
exercises around kanban and flow
so you're welcome to to sign up for that
it is already up um and it will be in
the same format in teams i am
contemplating using another tool for the
video side just for fun to try stuff
um but maybe not in in this session or
maybe need to practice a bit first
um so if if uh
you have any other questions uh feel
free to feel free to hang out i will
happily uh hang out for a little bit
gordon you need to go get a nap man
um gordon needs a nap
but i'm just happy to see so many
familiar faces coming along to to check
out these sessions
so if you do have any feedback
i have a little feedback section all the
way over on the right hand side so let
me summon bubble
i have a little bit feedback section and
if you use the qr code or double click
the qr code it will take you to a form
that will let you fill in like more
verbose feedback and i'll send that out
in the email as well um but if you do
have any
feedback i would love for you to add you
know one of the things that worked well
um what do i need to change
uh new ideas and unanswered questions i
think teams worked better this time did
anybody have a problem with teams this
time
it worked really well uh martin i just
have a quick question you know when i
was going through the strum guide myself
for
the strongest exam and you know just
understanding
and even on scrum.org you know i could
see many debates on the questions that
are there in the scrum guide
and um so even if you look up on
different websites you know you'll
observe different viewpoints
so that often confused me as to you know
what exactly to follow and then because
like you said in the very beginning that
people may have their own interpretation
because it's applied
okay
but then how do you choose what's
correct
so and there are there are there's
there's there's two useful techniques
for that right and and i i have had
feedback from students that i've given
this advice to and they're like yeah
that really helped okay
so what one one is always reading the
scrum guide again and trying to when
you're answering the questions
don't think about how you implement
scrum at your organization think about
what it says in the scrum guide
right that's that's one
but also
have the scrum values
written down on a bit of paper next to
your computer
when you're taking the
assessment anytime you're confused about
a question
look at the scrum values
which of these answers
enhance the scrum values and which
reduce them there will never be a
correct answer for a scrum.org
assessment question that reduces the
scrum values
but there are still debates around it
right because
there there are there are still some
debates around the ideas
um and what what we had it so
we do a lot of uh face-to-faces with the
trainers at scrum.org where we get
together and we have little events
uh my good friend steve porter
always runs a little event i can't
remember what he calls it it's like
contentious questions maybe um and they
bring up they have uh uh they know
who gets what questions wrong right so
they're looking at this particular
question lots of people get it wrong
let's put it in front of the traitor
like a multicultural group of trainers
and say
is this actually a good question is it
just hard to interpret
or is it actually true you know testing
something and lots of people get it
wrong because they don't understand it
so we have those debates for the for the
questions
internally and there's quite a few that
it's just yeah that's
just going to be a hard question right
because
it it it tests something fundamental
like like we talked about a little bit
with the the
um
uh what were the what were the things
that um
like how much refinement should you do
right i mean that's scrum's not gonna
answer that question for you
how much do you need to do
to mitigate the risk of being too late
to answer a question so how much is that
depends on your company depends on the
project within that company depends on
the people in your team and depends on
your product owner
so is it possible to say that some
things may be politically correct but
they may not be practically possible oh
that yeah that it that is uh uh uh
so
i
i don't think that there is anything
that it says in the scrum guide
that
every company couldn't do
right
but there might be things that they
choose not to do
for whatever
reasons they think are valid
okay
so
we
so you've got the the pragmatic side of
me
is saying
you've got organizational constraints
you might not be able to change those
organizational constraints do as much
agility as much scrum as you can within
the bounds of those organizational
constraints right
but then the the the
the thinker in me is saying well are all
of those constraints actually actually
valid do they actually have good reasons
or can we poke at them a little bit i i
like to think of it like do you have
kids
do you have kids no like once you get
kids you'll know kids kids do this all
the time you maybe remember doing this
with your parents right
but how do we know where our boundaries
are as kids
we poke at stuff
right we poke at it we get we get a um
a punishment
we don't do it again maybe when we get a
little older we poke at it again could
we poke at it now right can we watch
that movie you wouldn't let us watch
three years ago okay now i can now i can
do that
so in your organization
be the kid
right you're you've always got to be
pushing at the boundaries inside of your
organization which which are limiting
your ability to do stuff some of them
are there for good reasons and some of
them aren't
right
uh and some of them are there for a good
reason that's a good reason for this
other team over here that do a different
product but it doesn't make sense for
our product
right how do we encourage the
organization to understand the gestalt
of the organization to understand that
there are differences and that that idea
the agile mindset where what's right for
one team might not be right for another
team
right because there's that idea of best
practices which don't exist anymore
right it's fine when we're all factory
workers we could have best practices
here's the one right way to do this that
works great
but we don't have that anymore
so
i i kind of agreed with you and
disagreed with you at the same time i
hope you noticed that
yeah i believe that
thank you make sense you're very welcome
so any other questions
are some new ideas to try at google mate
or zoom
i would happily try google meet but i
wouldn't happily try zoom
i have a uh
a problem with zoom i'm quite happy to
talk about that offline with anybody
oh okay then uh so thank you very much
for for coming remember we're gonna set
another session in two weeks
it's a little bit later in the in in the
days about like one hour no
an hour and a half later an hour and a
half later in the
yes an hour and a half later in the day
um
so i hope to see you there you can sign
up uh
now so thank you very much for
your time
thank you
[Music]
you