[Music]
one two
three four
one two three four
[Music]
over here and press it there we go
okay
oh awesome now i can see you as well uh
cindy cindy alex ah see now we've got
people dropping in
and sharing it's it's it's it's when we
get that pop-up isn't it we get that
pop-up in windows to say
oh you've got a meeting okay well then
i'll go
but not before because that would be too
soon you're going to be fashionably
fashionably late
that's the idea i think
uh so i did post the mural in
the chat as well as in the
i think i posted it in the tool that i
used did i put the mural there oh i
maybe didn't so i will edit that
the workshop description and stick it in
there just now
right
i've put it in there and that way um
that way if people come late i don't
have to keep posting it in the chat
because you know what that's like with
this the temporary joining thing okay
marlena how are you doing
oh sorry not too bad thanks
that's my first time here so i was just
watching and
maybe something
well something you will come to realize
is there is no watching in uh
my sessions everybody uh workshops
everybody everybody participates uh but
it is it is fine there are no wrong
answers there's only things we can learn
and find out that's that's kind of the
point
um
so we're gonna um talk a little bit
about um agile leadership
i have
tried to create curate some content that
will help us into dive into some aspects
of agile leadership but we only have an
hour and a half you know we can't we
can't cover everything
um
and even in the i do a a two-day
agile leadership class for with
scrum.org even then you can't cover
everything that you might want to cover
um so let's uh i'm going to start off
with a little introductory exercise here
i have
a set of statements
in a box so i'm going to summon
everybody on the mural
there we go um so i have five
effectively five rooms here and each
room
has seven questions
okay
and what we are going to do is we are
going to either
answer with uh a yes
or a no
to any of those questions i'm just
putting some uh
ticks
and crosses
around our view for us so that we can
grab them
there we go we can always get more you
can always copy and paste
uh so that will get more but if you if
you zoom in to one of the items when i
put you in breakout rooms
i'd like you to go to
the the box that represents the number
of your room so at the top of the teams
window
and on the title bar it will tell you
the room number right so say room one
room two room three um and
we will uh
i want you to discuss and answer
the questions
that you see there so the statements
rather than questions
so um
let's see who have we got let's do
everybody's in alphabetical order so
i'll just do
that for room one
oh
one two
three
for room two
one two
oh there's two sharons i'll fix that one
two three
for room four
and then i think
well i'll put the other sharon in room
four as well
because then that will uh hopefully
so right i'm assigning everybody to the
rooms as new people drop in i'll send
them in to meet with you okay so it
depends how many people we get
and i'd like you to just drag on
a tick or a cross
to
each of those statements just agree in
your group uh there should be at least
three people in each group for you to
have that conversation with okay
so i'm going to open the room just now
you will just transcend into your
breakout rooms and then come back uh
when uh we're finished
um i don't think it will we'll probably
i'll probably put five or six minutes on
the timer and i'll see how you get on
okay
i'll i'll be monitoring from here
uh we have amanda
and
oh room one is still opening
so let me
there we go
room one is active amanda
nelly i am just going to
pop you guys into
room three
and there we go
you guys are heading into room three if
you go to the the number three on the
mural uh which you should find in the
chat
here
which i'll paste in the chat again if i
can no i can't
i'm sorry i'm
having a couple of issues um i'm trying
to get my team in here and we're having
issues joining
what sort of issues are you having
joining
she cannot hear any audio
was that uh cynthia
uh no her name is andrea andrea okay
so it might be
a setting in teams
um so in the teams window if you click
on the olymps and go to device
settings um you can pick a different
speaker and a different microphone and
sometimes that's the problem
ninety percent of the time it's the
device settings
uh so i see with a few
uh
folks join
uh let me see who's in what rooms
uh i am going to
uh pop christopher
welcome i just put the mural in the chat
and i'm gonna pop you in room three
okay let me open that room
oh dear now it's all gone to pot peter's
here
you okay peter
uh
there
and i'm having a
camera issue peter
you're having a mic issue when i have a
camera issue
yeah i still can't hear you you're on
teams thinks you're on mute
i'm good okay
i'm not i'm upset with my camera
so we've got a few people coming in so
what i'm going to do is i'm going to
assign you to
um
i am going to assign you to room five
everybody that just came in that doesn't
have a room assignment so that's
andrea
peter
i thought that was three of you but i
will sign anyway
ah somebody's on hold
victoria's on hold
uh
so peter i'm just going to and open the
room do you have the link to the mural
do you manage to get a hold of it
there's no audio peter
uh have you dropped into the chat i'm
just dropping it into the chat i did put
it on the community group as well
um
but it is in the chat now
oh let's see what this person
uh
i've got a few people that are having
difficulty
let me grab a link
uh
did you get a call to go out to uh
no you didn't peter
now you will
so you're in room five here
will probably not be too long but you
can answer a couple of the questions
as we get a few more people in
uh for anybody that's online
is trying to figure out how to get into
the meeting
um if you go to
the community channel you should see a
live button there on the left
uh click
the live button and then you will see
there's free workshop 5
go into the live event and then click at
the webinar link
just there
and just below that i've put the mural
link as well so you can get
prepared to join in so the web link in
the mural link are on that
event there
okay
we've got quite a few
answers
oh wow room two's uh
i think getting doing pretty well
okay
brianna you okay
ah cool i saw you type yes um i can't
hear you you're on mute uh that's okay
don't worry i'm gonna bring everybody
back in just uh just a moment
um
[Music]
as we
get started there's quite a few answers
already in the
in the board
so oh that's interesting
five is not answered anything
uh
looks like this side of the room is
pretty
pretty done so i can clean up
some of those
there we go
and i'm gonna bring everybody back and
then reveal the the answers i have over
on the right so i'm going to close that
unlock that and bring in the answers
okay
all right peter's just going to answer
them all correctly now
peter i saw you looking at the answers
before you answered them
no i didn't actually
okay
with those interesting questions
oh my video is frozen again
they spark some debate
pretty interesting discussions
yeah
so on the right hand side
um if you're in the mural and you're
following me i'll summon everybody there
we go we get 18 people in the mural i'm
not sure we've got 18 people in here yet
um i put the team's link oh no we do i
put the teams link on the on the mural
there
just in case some folks were having a
hard time uh finding it
um
but there's the the
well the answers i'm giving i guess oh
i'm frozen again dagnammit
i i have i have two cameras and one of
them's playing up so i'll be using this
one it means i'm not looking at you i
apologize
um
but we'll figure i'll figure that out
for for later
um
so
we had a number of questions
uh if teams are failing then i'm failing
as a leader
right seems to be the oh well there's
some confusion in group one
they want to they want they want both
true and false
in both of those answers and and the and
the the red x is much bigger than the
green tick so somebody didn't like the
green tech he made made it smaller
right
so i i i would say if if you've got
failing teams
for me that's a leadership issue
right
we as leaders
are
responsible
for the effectiveness of our teams
we're going to help them get better at
working together get better at doing
things and
sometimes that's hard
if if your teams are succeeding
then you are succeeding as a leader
right the job of a leader is not to
manage up
right although sometimes we end up
managing up a lot
job of a leader is to help create an
environment within which the people
doing the work
can get it done
removing obstacles from their path
changing at things in the organization
getting them the things they need
leadership can be tough
uh
i like this one a leader must never show
emotion or people will perceive them as
weak
have you heard that expression
because i've heard that expression from
leaders yeah
alex is nodding there
luckily everybody marked that one as a
as a cross so that's good
a leader's job is to create goals and
enable people
almost everybody put a tick in that one
yeah
if we're telling people what to do
and how to do it
we're not leaders we're managers
but we agreed that he should be um
he is a part of the team and whole team
should uh create their goals so in this
way it could be true
so
i i agree
but if we look at
leadership at the macro rather than the
micro
level i might not be a leader on a team
i might be a leader in an organization
i have
20 or 30 teams
um
that that work within my department
um and i'm leading 20 or 30 teams it
doesn't have to be
one team one leader
right
the leader
that's on the team
is is usually the scrum master
right the scrum guide talks about the
scrum master as being a true leader
who provides services to the team the
product owner and the organization
right they're the embedded
leader
but we still have leaders at other
levels in our organizations
and even if we're
on the team
we want to enable the team to create
goals
and help enable people
if we're higher up in the organization
maybe we're setting goals in strategic
direction
i will have to find out what's
interfering with my camera
um i like that one a leader must make
every decision everybody was unanimous
that was good i'm happy that everybody
was unanimous there and that
leaders don't necessarily make all the
decisions
and everybody almost everybody was
unanimous that people need to be
inspired
by the leaders
if if you're
if you're uninspired by the work
do you do good work
if you're looking at the thing you've
been asked to do and going i don't care
are you going to do that work well
you're going to be effective
no we're kind of gonna well
we don't care
but if we're inspired
to that work if we're excited about that
work if we're invested in that work
we're gonna put more into it and that
will be obvious in the outcomes of the
work
leaders job is to inspire
[Music]
sometimes understanding the impact of
our work can make a difference right in
the way we do it
yeah understanding understanding the
impact is is really
important
um for for how we conceive of of goals
and direction
right what is it we're trying to achieve
what impact
in the world are we trying to achieve
with the work that we do
right and that might be
depending on the maturity of your
organization that you might not be
looking at impacts yet
right you might still be focused on
output
oh we need 20 more widgets per day
okay okay but what value does that
provide to people who really cares about
these widgets does producing 20 widgets
get you 20 times more value or should
you be looking at something else
what's more about us
well so but that's isn't that the
difference between a boss and a leader
right a boss says i need 20 more mid
widgets
a leader says we need to move this
needle
right we need to we need happier
customers what what can i do to help you
create happier customers
yeah
and i love the one in the in the middle
leader doesn't need to trust people
so what why do most
management practices predispose
untrustworthy employees
because they do
right during the industrial revolution
we had large amounts of uneducated
workforce
and we were asking them to do boring
monotonous work
when they're doing boring monotonous
work their brain disconnected from the
work as yours does when you do boring
monotonous work
and then you figure out what can i do
not to have to do this work because it's
boring monotonous and i don't care i
just want my paycheck
those
characteristics of that type of work
created this idea of untrustworthy
employees
that has
gone through the years and is still
prevalent today in management styles and
management practices
and it's how do we how do we combat that
and trust people more
so we can delegate more
because you wouldn't delegate to the
uneducated factory worker would you
but you would delegate to the the smart
knowledgeable educated people that we
have today
[Music]
i would have to be a very unusual
and uh a capable and uneducated factory
worker that we would we would delegate
to right i'm not saying it wouldn't
happen it's just going to be rare
did you have any insights anna going
through those questions
nope looking for the mute button
it's always fun
uh i
does not agree with the second one
because you mean leader by position
there might be their own position but
there might be a true leader in the team
so the leader by position can be not so
good
but if you have a true leader in the
team there will be succeed
and if that's not
i agree with you
if i change the wording
to be as an effective leader
i think that might
caveat
your issue there like i i'm definitely
not saying that
you can have successful teams because
the leader is on the team in spite of
somebody more senior who is inept
absol absolutely
but then i would say that leadership
lies with that person who is the leader
not the inept person who has the
authority
authority and leadership are not the
same thing
the person who's the boss is not always
the leader
in an organization the management thinks
that the team leader in position is
doing all the good stuff which is not
true this is this is unfortunately
there's a
there's a there's an old adage that says
that we are promoted to the levels of
incompetence
right
and it's because
people are good at what they do right i
might be a really good software engineer
so somebody thinks i'll make a good
manager
of software engineers so they make me a
manager of software engineers and i suck
at managing software engineers
so they can't demote me but they're not
going to let me go any higher so now all
these software engineers are stuck with
a bad leader a bad manager right
um
i think as we as we change the way we
approach leadership
leadership of
time leadership so management in times
past
right like the stuff that came out of
the industrial revolution the scientific
management method
were really designed around low empathy
managers you wanted low empathy managers
because they might have to turn around
and fire 500 workers
and they're just cogs in a machine so
nobody cares
right i mean the workers care for sure
right but leadership doesn't care
management doesn't scare their resources
that's why lots of organizations call
people resources because then it does it
feels bad when you fire people
right but we're just going to get rid of
some resources we're going to refresh
some resources
right that's it's where that mentality
came from
but as we move into knowledge working
space we need empathetic leaders
leaders
oh i've got a little bit of an echo um
sg i'm just gonna mute you there there
was some background echo
um as we move into
knowledge working
we we we need empathetic leaders that
are able to
be leaders help remove impediments help
deal with our our team and our people's
maturity level and emotional safety and
all of those things that your
traditional manager couldn't care less
about and why don't you just be more of
a professional alex
i don't mind you gonna have unhappy
unhappy
time with this team i don't care you
should be a
professional right that's that's not
good leadership that's maybe good
management
well maybe good's probably
probably pushing it a little bit
i've heard even worse
what you were mentioning about the
resources before
uh i came across a manager who was
saying you know the products life's
lifetime is shortening it's all
so the same with the resources
meaning about the people that they need
to turn and leave after two years or
something you need to fresh
resources
yeah i i have i have worked in jobs
where
the management style was
work people hard burn them out because
there's always new people coming in
right that we can take advantage of
is the undertone there that is not not
well set
right
i did i did i i worked for a new media
design agency
um second job out of university it was
new media at the time grey hair it was
new media it means an internet agency
right web-based agency
and uh i i was getting 16 000 pounds a
year
i worked 70 to 80 hours a week
and at the end of that year i got my
bonus handy to me and it was 250 pounds
yeah it's like whoa i can buy that you
know couple of xbox games i wanted or
whatever was that
yeah
i kind of got handed the bonus and i
handed over my notice was kind of not
quite how it worked um i became unhappy
in that job can you imagine can you
imagine
yeah
i did i feel valued as an employee
no
did i feel like i wanted to go the extra
mile to help the business
cope with their inability to plan
right because you know how planning goes
in a lot of organizations no i didn't
feel motivated to do that
i didn't care to help them because they
didn't
seem to care about me
how do we prevent that well there are a
number of things um that we can we can
look at
um one of the things that's really
important is goals
okay we need uh
goals because
we
has anybody read a book by dan pink
or maybe watched the youtube video
alex has i know you have alex um i
heartily recommend it
and he wrote a book called drive the
surprising truth about what motivates
people
right and in it he talked about the
difference between our extrinsic
motivators
which are when you as an individual are
worried about putting food on the table
and a roof over your head all you care
about is money
right that's worries coming in from the
outside
once you don't have those worries and i
hope
that none of you in a knowledge working
position
right are worried about putting food
over on the table or a roof over your
head you're probably not even that
worried about i'd like to buy the dan
pink book right you'll just go buy it if
you want it
you have a few pounds to spare
right
but what really
motivates people is they're inside
motivators they're intrinsic motivators
so when you take money off the table
like you're getting enough
to get the things you want
the intrinsic motivators are autonomy
mastery and purpose
autonomy you want to feel like you're in
charge of your own destiny mastery you
want to feel like you're good at the job
you do
right
and purpose is you want to feel like
what you're doing matters
right i'm not doing something for no
reason
so how do we create a sense of purpose
inside of an organization
we set goals not tasks
right tasks don't have a sense of
purpose they're just a time limited
thing that gets completed
goals give us a sense of purpose what
are we trying to achieve
next
who does it matter to and then the level
of your goal
is going to change the way you look at
that picture depending on the maturity
of your organization
um so i've got three different types of
goals listed here
and i have strategic goals
which might be things like a product
vision or a corporate vision right that
might be your strategic goal
what are you trying to achieve as a
company
but that might be
very
i guess the british expression is pie in
the sky
what's like something you can't actually
reach out and touch
because it's too far away
so you as an employee
maybe don't
i don't understand how the work i do
today connects to that thing because
it's too far away
so we have something called an
intermediate strategic goal
and an intermediate strategic goal is
far enough out that we've got vision and
forethought and we're looking forward
into the future
but it's close enough that we can still
connect to it we can still see how the
work we do every day connects to that
strategic goal
that's that intermediate
goal
there
and then we also have tactical goals
tactical goals are what are you doing
now what are you doing today
why are you getting up this morning
right in the in the in the scrum world
right this doesn't just apply to the
scrum world but in the scrum world and
we have we have sprint goals
sprint goals are our tactical goal what
are we doing now
to make our next step forward what's our
next step
and then we have
product goals
which are our next waypoint
on the way to our intended destination
and the strategic goal is you know where
are we trying to get to
so that's the purpose of this
the
onion i guess we call it the onion
diagram here because get many layers
but there's the tactical goal and
scrum really only talks about
this bit at the bottom
doesn't talk about all this other stuff
that's that's leadership and
uh
organizational strategy and product
management
scrum doesn't talk about those things
but
you know
we're gonna have a business plan we're
gonna have a product vision we're gonna
have a road map these are things i would
expect companies to have
for each product
do you have a vision and a road map and
what are you trying to achieve
how do the people working on your
products
connect
to the story
so that they see how their work
contributes
right there's a little definitely a
little bit of an art and a skill
in being able to make those connections
because if people are connected to the
work they do better work
because we
feel like our work matters that we know
how we contribute
[Music]
but we also need to be able to to
to figure out how we get there
right are we making progress towards
these goals are our goals
the right thing
so let's do a little exercise let's see
how many people have we got now we have
19 people
damn it's an uneven number i was gonna
do pairs let's do threes
oh you're much smarter than me what's 19
divided by three
six point three three three three three
three see i just popped my calculator
that's how i do that so i don't have to
think about it
i'm i'm in a different mode for my my
coding mode
all right so i'm gonna create
six breakout rooms
let's create six recreate
four five six six great rooms and what
i'll do is i'll write you're all gonna
be randomly assigned to the breakout
rooms so i'm sorry if you're in there
with somebody you don't
like but what i would like the next one
will be random again so you'll get
somebody else
i'd like to use the first six
rooms there
uh so go to the the hex that matches
your room number at the top um and
create
a list of things that you're measuring
today
in your organization
what are you measuring
okay
so i just started the breakout rooms
take about 10 seconds to spin up
and then um
have a go at answering that question and
i'll put five minutes on the timer so
you know how long you've got
okay
that last room is still spinning up
victoria that's your room it should be
there it should be started in just a
moment
it's
hmm
for's taking a long time to start i
wonder what's going on
oh you're frozen that means you've gone
awesome
i think everybody's gone
james is unsure
what the heck is wrong with my camera
can i get under the desk and fix it in
five minutes or is that going to be
is that going to be a bad idea
what do you think
internet
i think it's going to be a bad idea so
i'm going to leave this one on i can
swap to the other camera
my new camera is supposed to be working
better but um
today
it's been working great for the last
five days
but today it's freezing up so something
must be different today on my computer
i don't know what it is what i'll
probably find is i'll just unplug it and
plug it back in oh i can unplug it and
plug it back in because i can unplug it
from here
right unplug it there we go unplugged it
i plugged it back in let's see if that
works
i will probably need to reset it
oh i double clicked in the wrong thing
deactivate reactivate
let's see if that works because i much
prefer this camera
um
okay so they're
oh we've got some story points
we've got some uh
whip
uh what else have we got
i'll just release everybody that's
following me
so
whip velocity
yep story points satisfaction
confidence
i'm gonna grab a link to
my good friend christian's
tool
uh
they have a tool
where is it
uh teammetrics.liberators.com
let's try that oh that's a participation
link
uh let's not do a participation link
let's do a root link there we go
i'm gonna start here
oh christian
you need to fix this
look you've got no default image set for
your team metrics page
that's not good
um
[Music]
but i put it on there
isn't there another
at one of these surveys at the
liberators i think there is
origin story built with stakeholders one
let's see workshops
[Music]
oh they have the zombie scrum guide
um i don't see
i don't see
ah
matter liberators are awesome
so we have a lot of things we have about
a minute left
on the timer i know you're all hanging
out here with me
um if you're watching online maybe
nobody's watching i don't know i can't
see so that's just the way it is
um but velocity capacity
resource for budget reports yeah
but cumulative flow burn down as well
sprint report
some good things what's over here
number of points delivered number of
hours in the office oh that's that's uh
where's my skull and crossbones
i'll just type skull and i bet i'll get
her
yeah that's a death
thing there we go
oh maybe use that one
there's my oh there's a skull and
crossbones awesome i'm gonna get one of
those over
oh number of hours in the office number
feature delivers in a sprint
estimated velocity visa actual oh yuck
um
sprint goal velocity budgets up time
backlog size whip story points velocity
oh wow right so let's close the rooms
and bring everybody back
so have a look around
the wall do a little bit of a a gallery
walk and see what everybody else has has
put
um i brought brought in a couple of um
lovely little little skulls
um
to put next to a couple of them
i i
number of hours in the office
that's an awesome metric
you work in a call center
i i do uh know of somebody who did work
at a call center and they got measured
in the number of minutes they spent on
potty breaks
oh yeah
yeah alex
when you when you put your your phone
you have a button to go well you have to
go off offline so you don't take more
calls and it asks you why are you going
offline so i'm going on a toilet break a
cigarette break or whatever and then
your manager gets a sheet that says
here's how much time you spent on all
these other things alex you've spent too
much time in the toilet today
right that is that is not a conducive
uh office experience for sure
this is the thing when when
when the only thing that mattered was
our productivity
right because we were screwing the top
on toothpaste tubes or
whatever the the the packing boxes right
then
those are how you measure people right
because that's money out of your pocket
as a business
but in the complex cognitive world
alex does his best thinking when he's
sitting down
doing something else right
so
it's not
time away from work it's actually time
in work
it's just
counted differently
oh there we go number of minutes number
of minutes in this yeah like this is
where the inspiration happens that's
where the inspiration happens yeah
you just hope you can reach a pen
um so the other one that i would like to
call on again is in room one
um is estimated velocity v's actual
velocity
i just want to to call on that one
i
that's that's a heart that's a hard one
because
what could have impacted
a change in velocity
for a team
a nouns
unknowns
what sort what sort of unknowns
no it's maybe it's that i don't know
someone is
um is sick and yep it's what the
capacity
i think yeah actual actual velocity is
i'm i think it's the capacity so
yeah velocity but you can't uh
uh you you take into account um
the number of workers actual number of
workers i don't know for
holidays or something
possibly it is yeah
absolutely it could be it could be
people off sick it could be you know
that time of year when everybody gets
flu because their kids go back to
kindergarten it could be um
the the
something else has has uh is happening
maybe it's uh what in in different
countries they have different holidays
right there could be holiday days that
week that shorten the sprint it could be
christmas
right lots of people have christmas off
um
it could be
that we just took on something that we
thought we took on a piece of work that
we thought we understood and we find out
halfway through the sprint that we
didn't understand it
but i want
i want to ask what do you mean saying
estimated velocity because in my uh
i understand the velocity like something
uh based on the
historical data
it's not estimation but you know
i agree melina
but quite a lot of
managers will say to the team
but but the last few sprints i've
calculated your average velocity so this
sprint i want to see no less than 20
story points
so this is the the
expectation yeah it's that expectation
gap because we're we're then
constraining on scope again
right i'm trying to avoid uh
constraining on scope
there's lots of rules
yes sorry um
celio
yeah
leadership called an all hands meeting
on wednesday and took everybody in the
team out for for a half day
announced that we're going to be laying
off 10 of the workforce and now nobody
works for the rest of the day because
they're scared about losing their job
and thinking about other things
they're all they're all surfing uh
job sites
these things happen
right
velocity fluctuating
is normal it's gonna happen there's
nothing you can do about it there's
nothing predictable about it
velocity as molina was saying is a
measure of the past not of the future
it's just a measure of what happened
[Music]
but there's lots of other things that
are really good in here like a a cycle
time
um number of clients affected
uh there's story points burn down charts
team velocity definitely very there's
some that are very team focused
right but there's also satisfaction
down here in room five
that could be customer satisfaction or
it could be employee satisfaction
couldn't it could be either
what about confidence
confidence is good how confident are
your customers that you're going to
deliver
there's a measure
that's this is also for the team and for
the customers so also that for how how
confident the team feels for the next
spring for example yeah and sometimes
you see that
this confidence goes down and that's the
indicator for something in the team did
they do the backlog refinement well
was the information for somebody do we
need some smes some experts so these
these are some small indicators
yeah um
and just because we've got a high
confidence doesn't mean we're right
lots of bad things happen to people who
have are very confident that they can do
something
like when you're drunk and you know you
think you can make it just maybe not
going to happen
yeah
but there's there's also some things up
a room six at kpis and okrs
right so key performance indicators
i i think there's more negative
connotation around kpis than okrs
um but lots of okrs are also
introduced incorrectly as something you
should achieve
whereas okrs if you meet 70 of your okr
that's good
in in in the definition of okrs
right so even good measures can be used
badly for sure
this is a this is a good list
whip limits that's good at all levels
um
[Music]
resource for resources for budget
reports is that people for budget
reports
i'm just wondering because sometimes
yeah
sometimes when we say resources we mean
things and sometimes we mean people
right
things
should perform how we expect them to
right i want my pencil sharpener to
sharpen my pencils what happens when my
pencil sharpener stops sharpening my
pencils
i throw it out and i get a new one
right that's a perfectly reasonable
attitude or i have to get a new blade or
whatever i do
but if a person's underperforming is it
okay to just throw them out and get a
new one
i'm oh
yeah it's nodding there
alex is appalled no it's not okay
right there's lots of things they could
be they could be your
they could have potential to be your
best employee
your best
creator your best innovator
but some things not right something
maybe somebody else on their team
there's friction between team members
maybe maybe there's something going on
right maybe maybe they work well not
under pressure
right
and so you have to figure out as a
leader how do i create a circumstance
where i can get the best out of all the
all the people right other than
what was that alex
i was just gonna say i like the fact
that the industry went from
hr management to people management to
talent management
these new terms you know are staying
away from resources
well
funny funnily enough i did i did an
agile training the other day and uh
email went out to all of the prospective
students
right so it was a private class inside a
company and and the email said mandatory
training at the top and it said and
instead in the body all resources must
attend
right how do you think that makes them
oh
all the meat must turn up in the
yeah yeah it's it's it's
if you read that as an employee you're
gonna be like
bastards you know you're just not going
to be happy with that doesn't create a
good outlook
right sometimes
no one couldn't know what they because
no one needs a resource over there so no
one is going to trade
and even when they go to training they
want to just sleep in the back and not
participate because
they were told to be there man mandatory
training is is is mental
um so in order to to
connect people to goals
we have to have goals that focus at the
right level
right so you get a bunch of metrics
there some of those metrics are focusing
on output right but for example
uh a
satisfaction of your customers is
probably more of an outcome
than monitoring output
so the three categories of goals
that i have here are activities
that's things that people do
right so how many tasks did you deliver
today benjamin
right that's i delivered four tasks
today and five tasks yesterday okay your
performance is going down benjamin it's
going down
right that's that's uh activity but if
you were screwing the top on toothpaste
tubes
i did 30 000 yesterday i did 32 000
today
okay well that's that's that's how we
might measure that
and then output is things that the
organization produces
so that's that
i did 30 000 tubes today
and the outcomes
things that the customer or users want
in their product experience the
different experience that they have with
the product
there's one level that i don't have on
here
and that's
impact
impact is above i should have had these
the other way up actually let's let's be
fair i should put these other way up um
after outcome comes impact
what impact
are you trying to make in the world
with your product
right
so if you think about companies that
maybe focus on
outcomes
um what might be companies that focus on
outcomes uh
i think
i'm trying to think of a
like something like tesco's
supermarket quite often
focuses on the outcome they want their
customers to have a better experience
when they come to the store but
sometimes they market it as
i want more stuff for my money
right have you seen those marketing for
supermarkets come to our supermarket and
you get more stuff for your money
is that an activity an output an outcome
or an
it's impact output
more stuff more things
the organization produces more things
for the same amount of input
good goals
have certain characteristics
uh
they should be
ambitious
right if it's just a mediocre goal
everybody's like yeah
right
how many of your your friends
uh
when they were were trying to quit
smoking
said i'm gonna i'm gonna reduce the
number of cigarettes i smoke from 20 a
day to
19 a day that's going to be my goal
and you're kind of like that's a bit of
a rubbish goal
right that's not very ambitious
[Music]
and it never works i agree
well i know i was a a smoker many years
ago and that one never works
zero or one
i i
a friend of mine's dad uh once told me
that
he'd not had a cigarette in 30 years
and he said you never really quit
smoking you just don't have one in a
really long time
that's that was his uh uh thing so this
should be ambitious they should be
specific
what do you want you want to get
something out of it right something
concrete
they should be transparent
right we need to understand it
the stakeholders need to understand it
the team need to understand that the
organization needs to understand it
and they should be discussed
all the time
continually revisited is this still the
right goal to have are we still going in
the right direction do we need to change
what we're working on
even your your your
product
your product goal
that you're going to have in scram you
should be revisiting it every single
review are we still going in the right
direction
your business goals
right your business plan are we still on
track to get to our business plan should
we change our business plan because this
it will be better if we go a different
direction
they're always negotiable
not negotiable that's the wrong word
disgust is the right word
once you have a goal stick to it
i didn't get halfway to my goal and
that's good enough
so get a little card uh sorting exercise
here oh i didn't even
that shows me not prepared doesn't it
let me
uh
nope i need to unlock those other cards
have a look so this little card sorting
exercise i'm just gonna oh
well that's gonna be fun
let me
how many grips do we need have we got
more people again let's look
i think we got whoa we lost a couple
that's what happens when we get uh
we cross that one minute over the
over the hour or the half hour because
people have other meetings booked or get
interrupted
uh so let's do
i think these are quite hard
conversations
so
i think we only gonna have four teams
okay for four groups
that's why i have it like this so i can
pick how many groups i'm gonna have
uh depending on who's here and
how you feel and how you're getting on
and also it makes it different every
time
uh someone create four rooms
automatically create it
okay
so in
yes that's four people per room that's
pretty awesome
and so in your room there are a number
of
oh
that one's get stuck
can we see that look my goals got stuck
that's not good uh so the easy way to
unstick it because it's going to be
every room
is you right cut it and paste it and now
it's unstuck
okay that's just a mural tip for you so
if one of them stuck i think that's the
only oh no see this one on the other
side stuck as well cut it paste it and
there you go problem solved
okay so that'll be a little extra puzzle
for you to solve when you get into your
room um what i'd like you to think about
is
each of these cards
would it go is it an activity
right something that is done by people
is it an output
something your organization produces or
is it an outcome
something that changes the behavior
of our of our of our users of our
customers i think i'll bring down these
uh
oh
unlock
unlock and i'm gonna bring that down
stick it over here and make it a bit
smaller
oh well i made half of it smaller i'll
fix the rest
um
just so that we've got those
words there
okay i'll fix that while you're in your
breakout rooms so you can um have a look
as well
does everybody understand what we're to
do it's just a card sort
okay cool i'm going to click open
it'll take about 10 seconds
um
for the rooms to open
and i've even fixed
well mostly fixed
it's always good fixing things on the
fly
so
let's make that shorter there we go
up there we go and then oh
sg did you get kicked out or did you
just pop back in
i looked you down you got kicked out
which room were you in
so your room two at the top of your
team's window there should be a button
that says go to room
or join room or something
can you see that
i do have your device setting into full
screen show background effect
uh so it's not on the ellipse menu
it should be just on the the top bar
next to the leave button
are you using the web-based teams of the
desktop app
oh
oh now now you're out with the bounds of
my knowledge experience then
ah
let's see so it's
still not realized
that you're not in the room
uh so why don't why don't we have a chat
here
um
let's go let's go down to there we go i
bet you it's stuck i know it's not stuck
there okay
hey you know i'm one of your buddy one
of your phd guys
you thought sorry
i'm one of your scrambled buddy
awesome welcome to be here
i i
just opened because it was coming in
meetups i thought hey let's meet the
great person today i would not say that
i'm a great person but uh
i guess that the
what i what i've found
uh is that loads of people don't
understand that training can be fun
um so
that's why i'm doing these as live
events
because then people can
watch the recording later and see oh
that looked like a fun interactive
experience maybe i should go to a class
um that's the idea
i know you always do amazing job
so
it's always a great learning
i am just making it up as i go along
so so
because
i
really struggled
i really struggled to create
um
to create this this this session
[Music]
just trying to
get something around agile leadership
is quite hard and then you don't know
who's going to turn up
so if i got a bunch of
ctos turn up
right this would be a whole different
experience
then it seems like i've got a whole
bunch of people that work on teams that
are perhaps very close to teams
so so it definitely it's how do you
balance that so i wanted to come up with
something that might work with both that
was the idea anyway
so i got so i i got lots of help jim jim
sammons helped out
and um uh uh simon randell helped out
uh so that's uh
that's good
are you enjoying it so far
of course that's why i'm here right to
learn from everyone to see what what you
create martin is doing
well
you i posted on the the slack group but
if you want to come to any of my classes
it's free
i don't i don't charge for psts
what's the great things about pst
community specifically the step you have
taken which is very bold right certainly
we see we are charging 500 dollars for
xyg
but i really love your approach yeah i'm
not i'm not paying anything so i'm not
charging from you cost me anything so
why should i charge you something that
doesn't make any sense
that doesn't seem
yeah i don't know
so yeah i've been i've been trying out a
lot of different things recently so i've
been um i do this thing where
if you're uh uh
if you're unemployed
or underemployed
um you just paid 300
uh deposit to come to the class and then
you pay the rest when you've got a job
so that's quite good
um i'm doing um
[Music]
uh uh what's it called like refer a
friend
so if you if you refer a friend not only
do they get a 20 discount but you get a
20 store credit for every friend you
refer so if you refer five people you
get a class for free that's kind of
trying that out see if that works
i don't think anybody's used that one
yet but
i need to connect with you to get all
these tips
well i have them all uh published on my
website and i have a terms of business
page with all of my uh stuff on there as
well
um and i try and post as much in the
scrum.community on on what i'm trying as
well
uh to see if it see if it worked yeah
because
anything that makes the whole community
better
helps us all so
one second
i was uh
me me esposa one thing to know when
when dinner was
and i hope you're not recording this
part of part of these questions
well it's uh it's going out live
okay looked amazing
well so i always find that i am
i am i'm a software engineer therefore i
am pretty lazy
i like to make my life as easy as
possible
if i live stream it
i don't have to upload it
and i don't have to edit it
yes
exactly
that saves me a whole bunch of time uh
later on because then it's it's just a
little bit more real as well for for
people that are watching they can always
skip ahead i have gone on and you know
how um
youtube can do the the like the chapters
i have gone on and done chapters for
each of the exercises for some of them
so that people can skip and i'll go
especially on on
i think we had 20 minutes at the start
of pending
um before we started so i'll go chop
that out of the youtube video but you
can't chop that out of other platforms
so
but i'm experimenting with more
tools yes it's always good doing new
things and for placing it to the world
so that people know people learn from
that
this is this is a hard exercise
i think
10 minutes is definitely not enough well
room one's all gung-ho
yes actually i tried in one of my
webinar uh something like that no
technically this one
and i added two more things i added
input and impecca also yeah basically
and that was two months that was two
months yeah i'm trying to
so
a couple of these exercises
i built for the
ebm
course
so this is me first time trying them out
as well that's the other reason i do
these is i can experiment with some of
the different exercises and layouts um i
did the training from the back of the
room
uh i finished up that course last week
uh so i i
feel like i i learned a lot from that
um
and i've been
trying to apply it i don't know if you
saw but my headings were
connections concepts concrete practices
and conclusions at the top so i'm just
trying it out seeing how i get on
um but also
i'm starting the orsk
training in a couple months doing the
organized
organizational systems thinking thing
with scrum the dark
yeah yeah
um see where that goes as well i don't
know it's always fun to learn new things
because there are a lot of learning
really
practices over there so i'm sure that
it's going to be amazing
yeah
i just noticed i got a new button in
teams
since this morning when i ran a
different workshop they've updated teams
so
that's always fun
and then what's now
you are you are a team guy basically
right
i use teams for all of my workshops and
all of my training i
i don't think i've ever i've
participated in training with zoom i've
never run a training with zoom
um but i have tried to run a training
with webex
that we switched to zoom within the
first couple of hours i sorry switched
to teams within the first couple of
hours because um it didn't work out very
well
does it let you
know in my organization
and sorry it was
i i'm using webex load in my
organization and it worked quite fine
but
before fuel is i will say it was better
than now
that's what i will say now it has become
very heavy resource serving
and teams fluctuates as well but i think
they all do because they try and add new
features and then it adds more load so
then they have to go
fix the features and and this account is
in the technology advisory group for
microsoft
so
i'm using i'm well yeah windows 11
as well as uh at teams insider preview
as well
so um
clean bro you are maybe now sorry
how many years you are continuously
envy being 13 years
wow
13 years yeah
i know it's
and there's actually there's no there's
no i got my mvp in 2008
but
in 2008 they gave you the mvp for the
next year and then in 2009 they started
giving you the mvp for the year you're
in so i have two 2009 mvps that's my
claim to fame there
so i clicked the link to bring everybody
back there we go
wow that that that look that was hard
anna's group stormed through it
and got everything done in like the
first six minutes
um
yeah i
yeah thanks harry i just i i did mute
you and then you muted yourself which
unmuted you because i'd already muted
you but yeah yeah let's go
the the the joys of meetings
it's it's okay these things happen
um
does anybody want an awesome tip for the
coolest device i have bought
it's this thing here
it's called a mute me
okay
and it is glowing green
wow that's cool yeah i i have reduced
the number of times that people have had
to say to me you're on mute
from many
to none pretty much
very rarely because i i can see it
glowing right here and it flashes red
when it's on mute it's awesome
look what i have the big enter
you can
you can stick it to your computer you
just just mash it yep
[Music]
that's a
i so that
the the the me only comes from portland
it's like thirty dollars but delivery to
the uk because you know we did stupid
stuff the last couple of years um
was like forty dollars it cost more for
the delivery
it was totally worth it yeah yeah it's
one of the best pieces of kit i've
bought
um
so useful so useful
so you're not running it over your
stream
so
i've got the stream deck here but it
doesn't
it doesn't draw your attention like this
it's like a big hockey puck that glows
green when you're not a mutant glows
flashes red when you're on mute so it's
very easy for me to when i'm looking at
you i can see the green glow
so i know that i'm not on mute it really
helps really does help
you can all see your green glow in your
glasses well that's that's because
that's the screen reflecting in my blue
light
uh lenses yeah i need to figure out how
to fix that i maybe just need more
expensive glasses that could be the
thing
so we need to have the word
in there as well
johnny memonic
no that was a that reference went over
everybody's head never mind
except for ove he found it funny there
we go
so always oh and alex got it cool
need to watch more movies
so
uh
how did you get on
in that exercise
mostly confused but we had some
leaderships
not everything was like we are totally
sure about
where to assign it
i
i believe that some of these things
depending on how you look at it
how you think about measuring it could
be in one of two categories for sure
there's definitely things that i would
say are on the line
um
what were the things that you found most
contentious
uh
obtain government ev certification
yeah we weren't sure if it's an activity
or
what's the
what would be the difference if we use
not obtain but obtained
word
okay
yeah i would i definitely would wouldn't
i wouldn't want to get that that
semantic every single group put it in
activity
so i definitely think it it i i think
it's a an activity something we're doing
but yeah you're right it could say
obtaining
yeah
and even for at least for me as a
non-english
obtained i it for me it's two you can
use them in both
scenarios you have obtained it and
you're obtaining it
yes
right right
it could be a goal or it can be a result
yeah
yeah yeah so if you've obtained it and
you have the certificate then maybe it
feels a little bit more like an output
yeah yeah
yeah that's in
in my head it's uh
the duality of that word
at least in how i interpret it in
english is i can i can you i can use
that in both sentences based on if i'm
doing it or if i got it
so that is an interesting point of
does the language of your goal matter
all right
the language that is used in your goal
the words that you use the choice
it's going to matter
if if maybe obtain government ev
certification
is fine if you've got a team in the u.s
or in the uk but if you have a
multinational team with people with
different languages maybe
that's not a good word because it's
ambiguous
or maybe it just needs explained right
what do we mean in this case okay now we
get it
right but anytime it's ambiguous a new
person is going to be confused aren't
they
yeah so maybe it could have been worded
better
i really like the achieve 90 fun rating
on driver experience
driving should be fun
increase roi by 12 percent
is that an outcome or an output
isn't that an outcome
um but
yeah it's confusing because because
we've got them the number here so
maybe it's it's like something like
product because it's it's just
a certain number
so
like i don't know
so the achieved 90 fund rating and
driver experience
is about
the customer
it's something that the customer
gets
right
increasing roi by 12 is not something
that happens to your customers
that's definitely
something that the organization the
organization produces more money
based on the
investment does that make sense
so probably probably slip that one over
the line
um
[Music]
reduce company carbon footprint that
sounds like a that's a that sounds like
a outcome
something we achieve something that
impacts our customers or makes them want
to buy us because we do it
but things can go in more than one
category shaping your goals
is actually quite difficult
right these are goals that somebody else
shaped and we're struggling
which which category do they go into
the words matter
them being
specific
and understandable
[Music]
is really important
where are we for for uh
well
we are
we have what seven minutes left i know i
always go over peter i know i always go
over i'm i'm one of those folks that
can't keep to a time box i should really
learn something like scrum or something
that would probably help um but uh
i i don't know i have when i'm having
fun i don't like time boxes
right and i'm always having fun so i did
have a an exercise for you here i don't
think we're not gonna do it because it's
gonna it's gonna take too long um but
what we can talk about is the outcome
right the bit that i have on the right
which is uh what to what to look at
um so in
in
who's heard of something called
evidenced based management
it is not a software term although it's
kind of been co-opted into software
evidence-based management was something
that started to be talked about about
100 years ago
and it was when
doctors
medical professionals
decided it was a good idea
to base their decisions about your
health
on data
rather than guessing
and gut feel
do we do we feel that was a good idea
this this is the reason
every time you go to your doctors
what do they do every time you go to
your doctors
they take your pulse
they take your pressure
they measure something they measure
something and they put it in the data
because
just your your your your rate being a
particular level doesn't tell them
anything they have to see it trending
over time and if you go to the same
doctor over many years
they'll see
that trend of
oh that it's substantially lower today
than it was the last time
i measured you therefore there might be
some reason for it
data is important in making decisions
so what data should we gather
if we just look at one metric
we might make the wrong decisions
because we're just looking at one thing
there's no balance
so here i've got something called the
the evidence-based management from
scrum.org
right ebm
and ebm talks about these four
value areas and i'm definitely going to
caveat this for depends on how you build
products okay
so the the top half there
is market value
that's your product owner's world
so if you're thinking about your product
or your organization
you want to measure
these two areas
what value do we currently have
in our
organization or in our product
right
so the goal there
is to maximize the value that the
organization delivers
right just now what are we delivering
just now
and then you might ask some questions
how happy are the customers how happy
the employees
how happy are your investors
all right it's about your current
product
and we can them yes
no when you are talking about these
things
i think that the the first column in
outcome should go go to goes to the
output i know i can explain it
good but it's not something that
makes the company
more attractive to the customers let's
say something like that that's my
explanation
but you're
the the items of value
in your product might be the result of
of driving towards goals
right
so the goal might be
um
uh what was one of the other goals we
had
i can't remember now because my my my
brain has moved on from there um but uh
that understanding
what the current state
of our current value
is going to help us when we create goals
goals change behaviors
the data
measures things that we can measure
and hopefully we can see how those goals
affect those measures
right but if we don't have any measures
how do we know our goals are successful
how do we know where we're we're making
changes in the way we do things that
have a positive impact on our product in
our organization unless we measure
and this is not necessarily just at a
team level it's at a product level
which i guess might be the same as team
but also might be a lot bigger
right so we need to understand our
current value and our unrealized value
right our unrealized value is what's
sitting there in our product backlog
stuff we haven't built yet that we could
get value from
right how would you measure that
what metrics could you come up with
within the context of your organization
to understand
the unrealized value
right
so those two measures are are about the
market they're about business they're
about product management
the bottom
two measures
it says organizational capability but
since i'm an engineer
right that's the bit that's 100
within the control of your team
all right the market value is we have
ideas we do experiments we need to see
if they work
the bid at the bottom all right that's a
little bit more
fundamental
do we have an ability to innovate
right are we able to create new things
are we stuck struggling with existing
things
that's our ability to innovate
what might we
we ask
in our ability intimate innovate what
prevents the organization from
delivering new value
what prevents customers or users
from benefiting from that innovation
because just because we make new stuff
doesn't mean customers are using it does
it
maybe they don't know it's there maybe
they can't find it maybe it doesn't work
for them
so there are some concrete measures
that i might use an ability to innovate
i might look at
my cycle time or my lead time
right how quickly can i get stuff in
front of
customers and find out we're building
new things well part of that is time to
market so that's my brain again
uh what percentage of our time do we
spend on capital expenditure versus
operational expenditure that's the one i
was thinking of
what other
measures could you use inside of your
organization
monitor innovation
are you innovating are you not
innovating
what can you do about it
find the things that are inhibiting your
ability to innovate and then there's
time to market
which is how quickly can you get the
ideas in front of customers
cycle time
is generally referred to as how quickly
from when the the the people doing the
work start working on it to it's
delivered
lead time tends to be from when you have
the idea
to when it's delivered
right but also what about the amount of
time from when the developers the people
doing the work are finished
till you get it in the hands of your
customers
right
if we're building software maybe that's
our devops pipeline right how quickly
can we push our product out to our
customers
what cost what what
what makes organizations successful in
that space automation
right how much automation do we have the
level of quality because we can't have
high time to market if our quality sucks
can we
we need to have lots of manual checks in
between us building something and it
getting to the customer if we have a
high defect rate
somebody checking those things
so it's really important
to have data to look at to make
decisions
about data but motivate
people and connect them to your
objectives through goals
so watch out the thing to watch out for
is bad metrics i'm going to use an
example of a bad metric this is all
sorts of bad metrics here's a bad metric
and it comes from a little company
called microsoft
and they used to have a metric
where every manager
in the organization had to stack rank
every one of their direct reports and
the bottom twenty percent was out the
team
if you're in the bottom twenty percent
three times in a row you're out the
company
how would that make you feel hannah
very bad
i'm not sure
i want to proceed there
what you you
motivation
so
the motivation the mo the motivation
that did in fact happen which is why
they no longer have this policy
was that
many so it's definitely a sales minded
motivation
right
um but what actually happened was when
you have a lot of engineers working
together
and they feel like
even if it's not true but if they feel
like they're going to be in the bottom
they don't feel like they can get above
that
maybe i can sabotage one of my
colleagues
in order to get ahead
and that is what was happening inside of
microsoft
people were stabbing their teammates in
the back in order to not be in the
bottom 20
the other side of that is somebody like
scott guthrie
in microsoft who's was the head of azure
he had an absolute rock star
team that he'd put together every member
of his team
outperformed everybody else in the
organization easily right absolute rock
stars
and at the end of every year
he has to lose 20 percent of his team
if you're a manager trying to build an
effective team
how would that arbitrary metric
help you
martin there's just one point of view
here
what did other bear out if an employee
poured in low 20 percent for
continuously
three year
what manager was doing to improve him
i believe he should find the manager in
that case right
because managers are there to ensure
people that yep was he
was he creating environment for them no
if i'm the microsoft director
so the problem was that the manager was
looking at the five other managers that
also reported to the same manager he had
to report to and was more worried about
not being in the bottom 20 themselves
right so um
one of one of that was one of the big
changes that was made as part of the
transition towards satya when satya came
on board at microsoft again yeah yeah um
if if you want lots of juicy
information on that you should read
satya's book
hit refresh it has some awesome insight
in there on the changes in culture and
things that had to be made because of
things that have happened over the years
um i i
i think the person who's in charge of a
company should understand what it is
that company is doing and microsoft is
ultimately an engineering company
they're building uh
products using software development um
so it's is i'm glad i for one am glad
that satya is in charge um
and not the other guy
well i think we're we're at seven
minutes over that's that's that's pretty
pretty easy over i think isn't it peter
we're usually like 30 minutes over so
that's quite good for this time
um
continuous improvement
yes i'm getting better at time boxing
right i'm definitely getting better at
time boxing i've been doing it in my
classes i have timers i've been setting
them and yeah i'm getting better at that
what i would love is uh for those of you
that came along provide some some
feedback
um what worked well
right the things that you want me to
keep doing and keep what needs to change
uh peter you were there for the disaster
that was the lean
uh
session where the time box was
completely blown i think we did a two
hour session that time it was ridiculous
um
and the the
the thing that needed to change then was
the time keeping so i hope i've done a
better job
and new ideas to try
if there's something that you think uh
you want even if it's different sessions
right because i've usually
i've usually by this point come up with
an idea what i want to do next but i
don't have an idea what i want to do
next in two weeks
uh so i'm gonna have to think about that
so any ideas you have here will
influence
that out that outcome
um and then
unanswered questions
on the topic
that you thought you were going to get
answered but you didn't get answered
because maybe that's a session in its
own in itself
oh intro to design thinking i think i
need one of those first
i wouldn't say i'm a design thinking
expert
lean startup
i have read book
yes i like the the way the exercises run
as well and i've added um they've
definitely changed a lot even over the
last three months
um in the way i i do that
oh oh you copied it
so
the link
the link to the meeting
is
in the
community site
if you open up the events
tab
it'll say live
on the left if the meeting started right
and it'll have a little countdown if
it's not
you can click on it open up the meeting
and then it has a link in the meeting to
join the webinar it says either meeting
link or webinar link is that where you
found it melina
yeah cool
um
yeah i i
i agree it could be more
event to my obvious private calendar so
i've got the link directly from the
calendar yeah and
the link in yeah perfect perfect
this is the that this is the best tool
i've tried so far for doing this peter
might agree he's he's been through my my
learning experience of sending out
invitations for these types of things
um and i think this was working the best
so far
although there's still quite a few
people there like i can't find the link
that's okay we'll figure it out it's a
learning opportunity
yeah
you're you're right as well i didn't put
the mural link in the in the in the
comment early enough
that's because i only finished building
it this morning that's that's why the
mural linked if i finished building it
yesterday i might have added it
um
yes
i added it after we started
so so i cheated and changed it yeah
i cheated and changed it
um but there's one thing for
i i was again maybe
in the invite or press maybe in the
community and the link is not visible
for maybe so you have to press going
oh it might not be obvious
you need to you need to stop clicking
maybe of because you had that problem
last time as well
yeah you know she just just never knew
how to fix it by press going
if only i could remove the maybe part
and it's either you're not going or
you're going
that's what i would prefer
but yes it is it is
i i uh do not build the tool i buy the
tool
so sometimes i have to deal with the
idiosyncrasies
like i have to go manually create all
the teams links for it which
um is sometimes a bit of a struggle
oh well i'm glad that the the microsoft
rooms are the team rooms breakout rooms
are working better we definitely
struggled the first few times
i sent a bunch of feedback to the team
that owns it and they've definitely
improved it definitely lots of lots of
improvement is good much more stable
um
more about ebm
yeah
so i
i was i was i was i i don't like to make
it uh uh a marketing thing um but i have
an ebm class later in the year
um where i'm doing the the pal ebm the
new pal evm class that'll be my first
time teaching that class i think it'll
be fun
but scrum.org has an ebm guide
on their website it's free i have a copy
in
html form on my website
um
and there's there's some good
information out there scrum the rock has
a bunch of videos
on it as well on their website um so you
should be able to find it
sallow
yes i might be saying that am i saying
your name badly
no it says it does correct okay so
yeah perfect
i'm very glad to be here today i learned
a lot of things
and i'm work i'm leaving now
one
drive now to go to work i don't want to
leave but my time is over now
well i am sorry you have to commute
yeah
i'm enjoying my not commuting that's
what i'm enjoying
thank you very much for coming
how can i get this uh
how can i back to recorded this home
again uh so the the recordings are all
already on my youtube channel because we
streamed live
so
it's already there or it will be when
youtube process it however that works
for you that's fine
perfect
thank you everybody thank you
yeah thank you everybody for your uh
time uh
sg do you have a question
nope that's my mistake sorry about that
it's okay you playing with the features
first time in teams
i have a question actually
maybe stupid or maybe i shouldn't use
words maybe
but
you you read that you read the questions
from
some kind of chat but where it is
because here i'm looking on the chat of
the of the meeting and i do not have
anything like the questions like you uh
was
reading did you read the did you read
the questions from the audience here uh
no i didn't
okay i actually
it looked like that for me
i just i was just looking over to see if
we got any questions online and i think
i think we did but somebody just just
said hello
yeah i i i i
[Music]
everything is fine with me yes
i was sure that you
read the rest of the place
questions you read from the mural we
call it all the questions there is that
yeah
okay so i need to find the place because
i
just didn't see the questions we wrote
i'll find it
good that's all for me sorry thank you
well i i hope this was useful looks like
i've got lots of feedback
to deal with yep ux and scrum that is a
dangerous one because i know some folks
that will jump on me for that okay ours
and scrum uh there's a good video on the
scrum the dog website about okrs um they
did a session recently on okrs uh
how do we know scrum is working or
failing yeah that'd be a good one
uh outside of it
i taught police officers in ghana
that was a lot of fun
um
one of one of my most fun uh
gigs i ever had
uh scrum at scale
opinions about safe don't get me started
about safe we can talk about that all
day and maybe some nexus
stuff yeah yeah these are all all good
ideas