hello my name's Martin Intuit and today
I'm going to be talking a little bit
around the professional scrum
foundations class and the PSM 1
assessment naked agility is available
for DevOps and agile training and
consulting contact us for a free
consultation
ok so I have some things I want to cover
the two main things that I wanted to
talk about unless we get some additional
questions are the PSF class how it works
what it's all about
and why you would want why we want to do
one and the PSM one assessment which is
the result of the PSF class that is the
assessment that you get at the end of
that class so first off the professional
scrum foundations class I think is one
of my favorite classes to teach and we
work together in teams so I just
finished a PSF with my good friend
Russell and we taught at 20 people at
one customer so it was a private private
class and we broke those 20 people down
into three teams so with three teams
working on the same backlog so they all
get given the same topic the same
backlog but they pick a team mascot and
that makes each of the things that
they're doing a little bit different but
they're effectively all working from the
same backlog and they actually build
software in the class that's
and I guess the crazy thing about the
PSF is the actually build software in
the class and I love that they do that
and I've taught this class in Ghana for
the gun a police service sorry look on
the police force and I had police
officers lighting police officers
building software in the class that had
never built software before we do
something super simple and we don't take
technology and we help people out if
they're struggling but the idea is
you're being creative you're building
something new and interesting I think if
I was teaching the police officers again
I would probably use something like the
scrum tail board game something of that
like where the activity the creative
activity that people are doing and is to
create a murder mystery novel and they
do it in an iterative fashion so I think
that would be really interesting but for
this class I tend to always default to
building software my background is
software engineering and it's I I guess
I maybe I'm a bit of a masochist my
favorite part of the course is when
folks find out they've got to build
software in the class and they have 30
minutes for their sprint length to build
build the software the sprints actually
the the the working part is 30 minutes
they have a 10 minute planning 15 minute
review which is split between the teams
because there's one review for all the
teams and then 10 minute retrospective
you're supposed to do four sprints and
when I teach this in person I have
managed to get through four Sprint's but
I think the most that I've ever done in
the virtual setting is two sprints and
I'm planning to do something iteratively
getting making the class better in the
next sprint
I'm gonna work with Russell next sprint
next class which is Monday Tuesday in
Pacific time zone which is gonna be fun
because I'm gonna be up late at least
Russell won't be up early and I'm going
to deliberately focus on just doing two
sprints and see how I can change the
dynamic in the class with that we do a
lot of really awesome exercises in the
class apart from actually building
software and we work a lot I actually
have one of the PCs one of the exercises
that we do here um let me can I make
myself a little or just disappear make
myself disappear there we go this is the
result of one of the longer exercises
that we do and where we build out the
students work together as a big group as
and in teams to come up with all of this
information that's on on the board here
so we talked about the the the three
roles in scrum and their core
accountabilities what we're trying to
get to in this class is let's make sure
everybody has the basic solid everybody
knows what our product owner is supposed
to be what the intent of the product
owner role is so then when they go back
to their organization they can look at
what somebody is doing in that role and
say well that's that's not enough that's
not going to give us the benefit that
we're trying to achieve from this idea
so we go through the three roles and our
accountabilities and we also go through
and the three artifacts which is the
pink things here and their transparency
so something that I've been using a lot
is a transparent past present and future
for the the artifacts so that you have
complete transparency across the life of
your project and that seems to our
product that seems to work pretty well
and has a good explanation for folks and
then we go into the
the empirical nature of each of the
events and the thing that I think folks
find super surprising about this class
is the number of things that they find
out that they were doing or that they
were told as part of scrum but is not
actually part of scrum and it's
something that people do and that's okay
I'm absolutely fine with complementary
practices that make things better for
groups but don't feel that you're forced
to do those things scrum doesn't talk
about user stories it doesn't talk about
burden downs it doesn't talk about
velocity and it doesn't talk about any
of those things doesn't talk about
standing up during the daily scrum these
are all complimentary practices the
organizations and teams may choose to
use as part of their endeavor and it may
work for them or they may want to choose
something different in those practices
so for example what's a good one in um
you know when I asked myself these
questions I really should have an answer
prepared but this is office hours rather
than the presentation so I just wanted
to show you some of these things that
were working on but having complementary
practices like standing up there's a
good one that some teams use I have
heard of teams in Norway that their
daily plank
instead of daily stand up and it might
work for them it doesn't work for
everybody you don't have to stand up the
purpose of the daily scrum is an inspect
and adapt on the work you've done in the
last 24 hours
to plan or create an implementation plan
for the next 24 hours that's that's what
it is how you figure out how to do that
inside of that 15 minute event that's up
to you we can make suggestions as
coaches and trainers we often make
suggestions on how to fulfill that you
might in your daily scrum use the three
questions what did you do yesterday
what are you doing today and what are
you was blocking you if you were focused
on the individual you might focus on the
Sprint goal what did you do yesterday
they helped the team progress towards
the Sprint goal you might ask that or
you might use a practice where you're
looking at and a board a visualization
of the work that's going on and you look
at the piece of work and have a
conversation about how that work is
progressing and who's been working on it
and what's been happening and telling
telling that story that way so you can
focus on the people you can focus on the
work you can focus on the data if you're
using the professional scrum with Kanban
guide and adding those Kanban metrics
you're probably going to be looking at
work item aging during the daily scrum
you want to be looking at is is
something getting close to our service
level expectation you know we have an
expectation that anything we take on any
piece of work we take on will flow
through our process within a particular
time period if it's starting to reach
one of those boundaries then then we
want to have a deeper conversation about
it we want to talk about those things
other things maybe we don't have to talk
about they're just progressing fine so
that this this was a very useful
exercise that we do it takes quite a
considerable amount of time but it
allows us to focus on what the events
are walk that floor and answer the
questions that people have what I
usually do is I give what we had three
teams so I gave each team a team got the
accountabilities a team got the
transparencies and a team got the
empiricism and somebody from the team
had to say what the thing was what's
supposed to happen in it and then we may
be modified that a little bit or we
added more to it and and then as we
added more to it people started asking
questions
and cuz they're asking questions there
then you know doesn't doesn't this isn't
the scrum master the interface between
the development team and the product
owner we can have a discussion about
that and figure out that no way they're
not at the interface between the
development team and the scrum master so
that was a very useful exercise and it's
part of a wider set of exercises that we
use in the PSF and we had a lot of fun
working through everything and figuring
out what was going on so let me switch
back I would like you to feel free to
ask any questions you would like this is
office hours ask me anything
so I'm going to talk for a little while
I'm gonna hang out here if there were
questions asked between the last office
hours which was last Wednesday at 6:00
and this one this Wednesday at 6:00 and
then feel free are they're not sorry
then I will be asking answering chat
anything attempting to answer those
questions and feel free to ask me any
questions just now I can see the chat or
maybe I can see the chat for each of the
platforms that I'm streaming to and
obviously if you want to have if you
want to ask me a question but not have
anybody know that you've asked me that
question there's always this link here
if you go to Nicola doula T net forward
slash ask and that is an anonymous
question ask you will just get a text
box whatever you put in the text box is
in danger of me reading out so put in
there what you want me to read out and
then I will attempt to answer that
question as much as I can as I said in
my tweets about an hour ago I'm happy to
answer questions on any of the things
that I deal with I'm a professional
scrum
trainer with scrum dark but I'm also a
Microsoft MVP in DevOps so I have both
technical background I was a software
developer for ten years I was a DevOps
consultant for ten years and I've been a
scrum trainer for ten years as well so
that experience of working with
customers both in the US I spent three
years living in Seattle consulting there
and in Europe where I've spent the last
whoa seven years since 2013
who moved back from Seattle working
across here as well so back to the PSF I
will I just had a question that I had
issues attempting to install the latest
II do migrator - do you mean the azure
DevOps migration tool that unfortunately
I built not unfortunately it's a pretty
good tool yes I can probably help you
with that I would not be able to get
into the technical details in here but
if you tweet me at at mr. hench
I'll happily help you out and I haven't
heard of anybody else having any
problems that doesn't mean there isn't
problems and I would need to check that
out somebody's having a problem
installing another installing the azure
DevOps migration tools which which I did
built so I can certainly help you out
with that again here tweet me and I will
directly help you out on my website
there's also a chat button and that will
get directly to me and you can use your
email okay Jerry no problem where was i
yes PSF so I really enjoy that whole
aspect to the PSF of level setting every
the class that I just finished teaching
Monday Tuesday was the third set of
twenty people in the same company and we
have three more classes scheduled now so
we're going to have a total of a hundred
and twenty people going through this
exercise build up that level of
knowledge inside of the organization and
try and get to a little bit of a tipping
point if enough people understand the
way things could be and I'm saying could
be rather than supposed to be but could
be that they could get some benefit by
jumping in there then we can get to
enough people we can make that change in
maybe maybe try and get it to stick
inside the organization so training and
training everybody is really important
the organizations where I've seen
they've had the best and biggest impact
from this type of thing have trained our
very large majority of the people in the
organization I did training in Utah for
a company and we trained everybody in
the organization from the CEO all the
way down to the software engineers and
the guy driving the forklift in the
warehouse and that really helped set
that idea of how people should expect to
interact with software how they should
expect to interact in that software
development world and even the the guy
who drives a forklift in the warehouse
and he's a stakeholder to the software
they are they were building software
that um handled all of their you know
where everything is in the warehouse
their stock management their inventory
control their web presence so then when
somebody makes an order they handled the
whole system all the way through and
that was part of their value add and and
the guy who drives a forklift in the
warehouse
had a iPad attached to his forklift and
and he had to interface with the
software so one of the things he learned
going through the class and was how to
engage with the software team how to
understand why they might not be doing
everything you want them to do because
they have other priorities why you don't
want to be interrupting them all the
time and changing what they what they
work on but also that they he now felt
empowered to give feedback the it's
expected that you give feedback and we
as a software engineering team want your
feedback and that was a very powerful
story for for them so the PSF again is a
very powerful class it's really the the
101 and I want to start up doing scrum
as one reason to use it and another one
that I i've done quite often with
organizations is the we already know
scrum we've been doing it for a little
while we've picked up some bad habits
and maybe we need to level set again so
I've actually taught the PSF more than
once for the same group of people but
with a large time span in between maybe
a couple of years and that level set
really helped solidify some of those
ideas for that for that team cool so I
have completed that class I have a catch
up with that team in two weeks and one
of the reasons that I schedule a catch
up with that group of people and after
two weeks I call it a reify event it's
just an error and but it gives them a
chance to ask me any questions that they
come up with and have an actual moment
when they can do that when they can get
on our live call with me and do that I'm
quite happy always and if you were in
one of my classes I'm quite happy always
to engage I with those times I'm always
happy to answer questions that's why I
do this session as well
but the PSM one assessment is what comes
out of taking the the PSF that's the the
basic scrum knowledge assessment from
scrum dad org and it's included in the
PSM what PSF class as well as the PSM
class and one of the things that scrum
dan org has found is that if you if
people that go through the class take
the assessment and they're more like
statistically more likely to pass if
they take it within 14 days so they want
to encourage people to take it within 14
days so even though you know the the the
token you get to take the assessment has
an unlimited timeframe if you take the
assessment within 14 days and
unfortunately fail if you don't meet the
grade then you will get automatically
sent a second token to take the
assessment but only if you take it
within 14 days so that encourages people
to just just take it you know even if
you don't think you're ready take it
within that 14-day time period because
then you get a second attempt anyway and
you learn something by taking that
assessment the first thing you learn is
about your knowledge level the
assessment has a number of different
sections and each of them are scored
independently and you will see in your
response at which areas you did well in
which areas you didn't do so well in and
it will provide links and not only to
content but the learning path that there
is for for scrum masters as well for the
PSM one so that's a pretty handy tool
for you as students is just take just
take the assessment it's really that
simple just take it and take it within
14 days so you get a second attempt in
case you you could just oh I missed one
question or I misread it
that could have been your feeling
percentage that's not really fear
whereas if you get a second attempt
maybe that will help you out and solve
that little little problem which is
pretty good and so if you're prepping
for the PSM one assessment and I send
out some data to students at the end of
the class it's something that I try and
send out the same day of the class so if
you've been through a class for me you
should have it already but I send out a
link to the scrum master Learning Path
which is a web a website provided let me
a website provided by scrum dot org and
and it has a number of different areas
that you can dive into so for example
one of my favorites
done understanding and applying done you
can see that there's a number of
different blog posts available so these
ones are our blog posts you can get
additional content obviously reading the
scrum guide go look at the scrum
framework I'm pretty sure that will pop
open the poster or at least let you
download it massive you can get in print
that out massive and additional things
that that can get you going and if
you're logged in to the website which I
am
you can go tick things off and it will
remember things that you've done things
that you've read so that you can get a
better understanding of those things and
that's that's a pretty pretty handy tool
and I like that one and it works well
enough I'm not saying it's amazing yet
but scrum the dog are iterating on that
Learning Path adding more content as it
becomes available and potentially asking
trainers to write additional content so
that's that's working pretty well and
then there's some some links I send
around for days I Joel the agile
manifesto a list of the agile principles
while your privacy's that kind of thing
but fundamentally reading the scrum
guide is probably the most important
thing to go read and having a good
understanding of empiricism scrum is
really just an empirical process control
system so if you understand what is
trying to be achieved with an empirical
process control system you can better
understand scrum and then better
understand implementing it and better
understand how to engage with people
inside of your organization to help them
understand as well there's also a scrum
open assessment it's I'm pretty sure let
me ah there are open assessments for a
number of the different classes there's
a scrum open product owner open
development open Kanban nexus leadership
and measurement open that actually might
be a cool thing to do in a live session
would be answer some of those questions
that would be certainly a little bit
interesting but those things looking at
the mindsets and practices of scrum the
learning path reading the scrum guide
going through the material I PDF the
slides that we used as well as all of
the mural content that tool that you saw
with the diagram that we built was built
in mural with the students I PDF all of
that and provide it to the students at
the end of the class so that they can
review that as well yeah that's that's
really that that PSF and PSM one in a
nutshell so the next class I'm doing is
the PSF on Monday which again is another
private class but I also have scheduled
a couple of public classes as well
they're in the GMT at GMT there in the
UTC plus one British summer time at time
zone you'll find them on my
on my website you can either click class
schedule and but you can see they're
rotating around here anyway
and I've actually done something that I
would be good to know from you if it is
useful but I've put the UTC plus one in
the title so that when it goes round
these rotations or it appears in Google
you should be able to see which time
zone the classes are and now we've all
moved to virtual it's a little bit more
difficult to see how that works
so I've put up to let me pop over here
at two classes and I put up my they're
both professional agile leadership
classes I'm running them in the
Edinburgh timezone if that helps as well
and the one on the fourth of June is
going to be a standard today class and
however the one on the 29th of June I'm
going to experiment with a four day
class it will be four half days that
might be better for some folks in the
leadership role and we're actually gonna
start early so it's gonna be eight till
11:30 I think so you're done before
lunch you can even you know start
checking your emails before lunch and
you've got the whole afternoon to get
everything else organized I would also
be interested in feedback on on that as
well so hopefully that will be useful
this session and I usually do depending
on the amount of content in questions
that I've got I might do an i or might
do half an hour we're coming up on the
half hour and I have answered the only
question that I've had there and we've
talked about the PSF so I'm wondering if
there's not going to be any other
questions
I can hear myself somewhere hold on I've
got technical difficulties
oh I'm I'm a bit of a silly I I opened
up YouTube and I started playing this
video live watching it it was just a
little bit behind
nevermind there is that and I also have
on my youtube channel you should be able
to see I have I'm I was going to be
talking at an event I was going to be
talking at the tech arama
event in Belgium that's in was in two
weeks
which I guess is the tenth I think it's
the tenth or maybe it's the sixth No Oh
third third next Wednesday ahaha so next
Wednesday what I'm going to do is I'm
going to do the session live that I was
going to do anyway at the conference
being that the conference has been
cancelled they're not doing the sessions
online they're just doing a bunch of
workshops so I would encourage you to go
look at the tech arama website and see
what workshops they're running there
could be something super interesting in
there do they have a number of workshops
but I'm going to be talking about live
site culture and site reliability
engineering from the azure DevOps team
at Microsoft and I'm going to talk about
that next Wednesday during the day about
2:00 p.m.
British summer time so if that is
everything I am super glad that you
managed to view some of this and I got a
question answered so I hope that this
was useful and if you have any
additional questions please make sure
you ask anonymously here and or put it
in the comments for any of the streaming
platforms and I will be notified I'll
get
question and I will answer it next
Wednesday at 6 p.m. UTC plus one okay so
thank you very much
Nik and agility is available for DevOps
and agile training and consulting
contact us for a free consultation