that is a very good question
uh so let's start from the very
beginning uh pal e so professional agile
leadership essential
Essentials course is an entry level for
managers leaders that want to transition
from traditional management towards
agile leadership the leadership that
agile teams scrum teams are looking
forward for the leadership that will
help them bloom that will help them
become
the best teams creating the best
possible products
so our current format typical format is
a simple I would say classical to Today
class today workshops
and in this format works pretty well if
you can focus for around 16 hours
and you have ability and support in your
organization to apply learnings from the
class
however what happens and it happened to
some of my students it might be
difficult to digest everything it might
be extremely difficult to come back
after those two days to your
professional environment and start
implementing changes I even remember my
course participant amazing women amazing
woman and she said oh my God Jana what
what I'm gonna do right now so many
Inspirations and now I feel overwhelmed
so I'm excited about immersive immersive
class this immersive initiative because
it it brings solutions to some of those
problems so instead of spending two days
together we have regular shorter modules
for instance every every week and we
focus on one area we learn we discuss
and then there is a break this break
will be used by our delegate to apply
learning in their professional
environment
so I believe it's it's no longer a
workshop it's rather a journey that
delegates choose to start with us and uh
I'm I'm super excited because I feel it
can help create a better relationship
between me and and of course participant
and I have a very strong feeling that I
can support my uh my course participants
better so I'm looking forward to to that
experience