all right so the questions can
organizations run a professional uh
scrum applying professional scrum
workshop and how will it help them
um I think of that they can
um we teach probably more private
applying professional scrum EPS classes
uh than public ones
um
it can be of huge value to have
everybody
within the bounds of the class be from
the same company right because you can
maybe have conversations that you
wouldn't want to have in front of let's
say you're in a class in one of your
competitors is also in a public class
right you I want to air some of the
dirty laundry that you might want to
hear during that private class and but
one of one of the big advantages of the
aps class is that it's an experiential
class it's a it's a practical how how do
we how do we engage in problem solving
um so the first part of the experience
that that people have as a groups right
so if you bring your whole team to the
class is that they they they get an
understanding of how they currently
approach problem solving
right so that this this works for both
teams that are doing scrum perhaps and
I've been doing it for a long time and
kind of want a tune-up
um as well as teams that are not doing
we're not doing anything particular and
we want to change to doing a new process
and maybe there's some some capability
in in scrum that we want to Leverage
um and so the first exercise that we
have them do is a practical exercise
Building Product
um and it's generally a bit of a car
crash right so they learn how their
current approach and the outcome they
get from their current approach
we kind of throw people in the deep end
and we just ask them to build some stuff
right but that's their default process
when you and your company go ask them to
build some stuff this is how they
initially approach solving the problem
and then we go through the process of
it's usually quite dramatic by the way
that that experience especially me
providing feedback on the product
they've created especially if they uh
deliver a PowerPoint presentation
instead of an actual product right which
has happened on occasion
um but I can be quite quite
um negative about the work that they've
done right which is very traumatic for
the people that are hearing it so they
get this kind of shock of
oh maybe maybe we've got a problem maybe
we're not understanding how we're
supposed to get to working usable
product at the end of every iteration
maybe maybe we need to think about this
differently right they've just failed so
their minds are more open to change
right what could we do differently in
order to have a more happier outcome and
then we teach them scrum we're on a
bunch of exercises we have a bunch of
conversations
and then we do another Sprint where the
use scrum practices they have a scrum
Master they have a product owner and
that
difference in how they feel right
connected to the way they work currently
changes their perception on what it is
they're trying to do how are we trying
to solve this problem how can these
tools that that we're talking about
scrum how can this tool help us get
better at delivering usable working
products and there's more to it than
that right there's a there's a much more
to it than that but that's one of the
key key learning outcomes of of the
class is that practical engagement with
the people that are actually there and
it really helps when you've got a
cross-functional group of people
so I actually don't recommend just
bringing your your software Engineers
right or just bringing your testers to a
class although I've had people try and
do that
and but you want to bring a whole who
who are the people that are building
this product right so maybe you've got a
team of of of of five to ten people who
are working on your product
who are the other people that engage
with them
right so that might be stakeholders that
might be other people from other teams
it might be people in leadership
positions that engage with this team
bring everybody
to the class so they all get a clear
understanding of what value scrum is
bringing right because you want the
people in a leadership position
to help enable this thing
you want the stakeholders to help enable
this thing and get engaged in the
process and provide help and support to
doing things differently
if everybody that surrounds your team
your your your group of people that you
want to do things differently aren't
inherently understanding and engaged in
that process
they may not understand why you're doing
things a particular way and then they
feel like it's not going to provide them
with value so why would they support it
and in fact maybe they sabotage it not
consciously right but you're not
providing what I just want this thing
and that might not be the engagement
that that's required so
that how can it help right quite part of
that question
is is is
it gives everybody that may be involved
in this process a clear understanding of
what value it's intended to bring
and it gives them a clear understanding
because during the class you know you've
kind of got a safe environment to
um do things differently from the way
your organization is it gives them a
chance to put their baggage
organizational baggage down and do
things a different way
and they also get a clear understanding
of well maybe we like this different way
right we everybody within the bounds of
the class sees that they like this
different way but they realize that
there are organizational things
that are going to make it difficult to
do that differently
and if you have the support of your
stakeholders leadership
and all the people that are building the
product it's very easy to make changes
to the way your organization does things
right because everybody's supporting it
uh uh uh from that perspective so
um I think that that
shared vision
of what it looks like going forward into
the organization is for me the the
clearest value proposition of the EPS
Workshop
right is that that everybody's then on
the same page everybody understands what
we're trying to do everybody's
potentially supportive right that's part
of my job as the trainer is to to to to
to to not only teach people scrum but
help deal with those I don't know what
do you call them when um
there might be negative perceptions of
of scrum or agile or or whatevers that
come from how people have seen it work
at other organizations or how it's been
used trying to dispel a lot of those
myths poke at some of those things and
and help everybody understand what they
could get from it if they did it in a
way that that provided the organization
with value right
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility