[Music]
the the
um the icebreaker i think this is gonna
be a harder one today absolutely
so welcome to uh
an introduction
to kanban uh workshop let me just find
who's making all the noise i think
they've muted themselves
uh so i think
everybody
gordon will let me know everybody should
have permission to mute everybody else
please use that power responsibly
like if i'm saying something you don't
like it's not okay to go mute me
right um but
it does
i'm pretty sure i have that
enabled so if you do see somebody with
this get some background noise or
whatever then um it's okay to go music
so i only see the
martin when i click on somebody yeah
martin when i do click on somebody
uh yeah okay i'm i'm ah right okay so
let me
go find gordon
there's gordon
i'm gonna promote you to a presenter
there we go
that way that way you have the power
well and you can you can help me out
with that that muting stuff there we go
that solves that problem
uh so then we managed to get into the
mural i can see there are 12 people
on the mural but there are
27 people
in
the call so make sure that you check the
chat
and head into the mural if you find it
in the chat i've set up a new um
um crazy thing uh
a kind of community portal and the links
to the mural um are on there as well
um so if you you should be able to get
access to that i saw a few of you pop in
uh earlier
george was poking around trying to
see what what the heck is this crazy
thing that martin's doing now
um sometimes you have to run an
experiment and sometimes experiments
don't go well
uh so the the using teams
um was okay
from a functionality well i wasn't
really okay from a functionality
perspective it was okay from uh from a
things working perspective but some
people lost emails
uh
some people didn't get the invites and
ended up in trash folders that kind of
sucks there's no kind of web-based way
to get the invites and
um
the other way of registering on my
website just really
wasn't a good idea
um
it's okay for selling tickets for
classes uh but it's not okay for for
everybody else trying to just i just
want to join a workshop that's free
um so i have
um
set up something else and i'll use that
next time and i'm going to use it for
some of my classes going forward as well
so we'll see how that how that works out
all right so i'm going to
um
just unlock
uh let me summon everybody summon i've
summoned the 15 people
that have managed to get into the mural
so far
and i am unlocking
all of the little let's see i need to
get a little space that doesn't have a
little
padlock on it there we go uh so here
i've got a little uh
icebreaker
and everybody that's been before knows
the deal you grab a little ticker across
and whether you agree with the statement
but this this week it is a little bit
more complicated
gordon said this was all too easy so i
decided to make it a little bit more
complicated so you can blame gordon um
and there are two types of tiles here
there's 10 questions
five of them are purely kanban focused
and five of them are scrum
with kanban
focused
so i have hopefully
clearly marked them i understand
that
that doesn't always work out the way i
think i've marked them and the way
people see it
um but it's basically the the odd
numbered ones
are
um
kanban and the even numbered ones are
strong with kanban so read the statement
grab a tick or a cross
and whether you believe it to be a true
or false statement
um
and drop it
onto onto the
onto the thing some of them are i have
managed to make sure that some of them
are true and some of them are false so
there should definitely be some things
going on
don't
there's no blank one this time
yeah there's no black one this time i
actually managed to
to
to get i was checking it earlier do you
know what i was checking it an hour ago
and i had five blank ones because i'd
only done half of it
so i had to go and figure out how to how
to get all of all of those things on
there or just what i wanted to put on
there
so as as usual at the end of the
um ice breaker or as usual i've done it
once before um i am going to
close
the meeting so people can't join it
um this is we've had a not a lot of
disruption when we're trying to do
breakout rooms i just posted the mural
again
um
when we try to do breakout rooms um
teams can get very confused when people
are dropping in and dropping out and
um i think it's same with zoom just gets
confused so i'm gonna lock it and then
um so unfortunately that does mean if
you
do get disconnected
um you probably won't be able to just
rejoin
uh because the meeting will then be
closed i am really sorry if that's the
case
uh but you can watch the live stream um
it's just too disruptive to have people
dropping in and out all the time
especially when we're doing pairing and
various breakout room formats
cool it's interesting
that was definitely some contentious
ones
so i i always think back when i'm trying
to come up with some of these questions
i always think back not just to
what what what
people ask
me or ask
at
some of the events but also um what i
thought right because
i get things wrong as well and i
uh understand things differently and i
have been quite often berated by daniel
vicanti for uh getting some of the the
kanban parts
incorrect and
we we have a good argument about which
way it is and usually he wins because
you know it's daniel
usually wins
um
so i'm going to give it uh uh another
couple of minutes just to
get everybody
on here let's see we have 26
people in
uh
the
mural
and how many people do we have in the in
the meeting itself
29 that's pretty close that's pretty
close
so most people are able to to to
participate
um if you're if you're just want to sit
at the back and not say anything you can
always join the live stream it's uh this
is streaming on
youtube and linkedin
maybe facebook i can't remember whether
that'll work or not and but everybody's
getting to look at gordon at the moment
um
just the way it works sometimes it kind
of flicks between whoever's uh
it's complicated when you're using teams
to do some of this stuff and i think
it's actually quite good because then
everybody's not
visible because not everybody wants to
be on the live stream
okay
well this looks good some interesting um
interesting outcomes okay
so i think i'm going to start going
through
um
some of the the the
the items these are are definitely very
common um contentious things in fact all
of them are pretty common uh contentious
things that either people get wrong or
scrum people get wrong about kanban or
camp and people get wrong about scrum or
both
right
um so
we've got our number one
um is a kanban
statement work is done
uh within prescribed time boxes there is
only one
tick on there i'm gonna put a nice big
cross
in the corner um there's no time boxes
in kanban it's just a continuous flow of
delivery and a piece of work can take
any amount of time it could take six
years
right i would suggest that's not a good
idea okay it's something to worry about
but
uh um there's nothing in kanban that
says
what that what that limit is
uh number two this one's pretty
contentious don't you think gordon
every item in the sprint backlog
must help the developers achieve the
sprint goal
i don't know if that's quite i think
it's about 50 50 isn't it
looks about 50 50. what what did what
did you say for that garden
i said no
you said no
you are
yeah i mean my thinking is sometimes
there's just stuff that needs to be done
you are you are correct it would be
totally uh uh ridiculous to say
um you can only put stuff in the in the
sprint that's to do with the sprint goal
and then
what about that bug that we just found
in the product that's nothing to do with
what we're working on now does that mean
we have to ignore that
does that mean we should have a bug
fixing sprint at some point in the
future
right maybe a hardening sprint
right all of those things as results of
incorrect behavior okay um it's okay to
have a
limited
focus
on the on the sprint goal it's okay
right i would be worried if it was
really low but it's okay it's okay you
can have that you can bring in other
stuff
i think this will come out in number six
as well
uh number three kanban question every
column
must have a whip limit on the board
there is no requirement for every column
to have a whiplap
okay
um it's a common uh misconception it's
one that i got wrong
uh when i was uh doing my uh profession
professional kanban
certification
[Music]
is now joining somebody joined on the
phone
that is gonna be awkward because if
you're on the phone you are not going to
be able to see the mural but hopefully
uh um you've got a computer and you can
see it there
um
yeah so every column doesn't have to
have a whip limit there just has to be a
whip between the start and finish time
that's where we calculate our whip you
could have many columns in the middle
that don't have whip limits but the
entire whip limit applies
um so maybe that's a little bit semantic
i guess
but it's definitely a big x number four
a scrum and cam man one the scrum values
are mandatory and scrum i love that that
is not ambiguous uh everybody put a
lovely green tick in there they are
mandatory you don't have to be awesome
at them that part's not mandatory uh but
you need to to um have a little bit of
focus on them
uh number five kanban
work must flow from left to right on
your kanban board
well
this was another one that i got wrong
and i argued with daniel for canty we
are all wrong
in that one it doesn't have to
so there's nothing in kanban that says
that your work has to flow from left to
right i would suggest it's a good idea
and i would suggest that if it's flowing
the other way you would want to look at
why it's flowing the other way
but there's nothing in the camera and
guide that says that it can't
okay
um
i i i agree with them
everybody
that is a good idea that it flows from
left to right that that i do agree with
but it's not mandatory
uh five six number six oh scrum and
camera one developers can reserve 80 of
their capacity for unplanned work what
did you put their garden
i said that was true i said that it was
true but again like for me it feels like
one of those things like depending on
what's happening that sprint
if you've potentially just gone live
with something you could be expecting a
lot of times you'd be expecting a lot of
unplanned stuff in the next
oh well hopefully you you have better
quality than that garden yeah
yeah hopefully but i mean it's okay to
reserve uh um 80
and only spend five percent of your time
on
uh uh
the the sprint goal that goes to that
same number two uh question it's the
other side of that we can reserve time
for other things right you already when
you walk into sprint planning you're
thinking about uh any business as usual
work that you have you're thinking about
any refactoring you might have to do
you're thinking about any production you
know your normal production issues uh
that you you know you reserve 10 year
time for production issues right so
we're already doing it
we just
need to formalize it and say it's okay
to reserve 80 of your capacity now as a
scrum master right i'm going to be
looking at that and going really we're
only able to spend 20 on adding value
for the product owner
maybe we should look at why that's so
low okay but there might be perfectly
reasonable reasons for it i didn't say
good ones i just said reasonable ones
ah that's number six number seven
uh kanban question a definition of done
is a policy on your definition of
workflow yes it is a policy it's just a
policy in kanban so um everything
is defined as a as you as a team
deciding a policy we're gonna we'll get
to that in a little bit um but that
should uh focus there uh number eight
uh scrum and kanban you can start a
five-day piece of work one day before
the end of the sprint
this is true i'm just going to grab
somebody's tech and make it bigger it's
easier for me
uh there we go it's true it's okay right
in the kanban world um we can have work
flow across the sprint boundary right um
and if we have awesome engineering
practices gordon knows all about this
he's a microsoft mvp as well if your
engineering practices are good enough
and that you can do continuous delivery
to production
okay and you can hide work
that is not finished and not show it to
the sprint review not to have it in your
already deployed product because it's
hidden behind a flag
then
there is no reason why
you can't start a five-day piece of work
one day before the end of the sprint and
you just don't show the sprint review it
doesn't appear in production but we've
we've written some code we've done some
work against it
okay that's perfectly okay in the in the
scrum world as long as our engineering
practices are good enough
that we can get a usable
increment of work at the end of the
sprint
right that's the key
i would say that many teams can't do
that so they're not ready yet to to
to focus on that
uh number nine people participating in a
kanban strategy are referred to oh a
spell mistake as the kanban system
members yup i don't know how many people
just knew that not many people answered
it so maybe it was a little bit
confusing wording and we call people
developers
in scrum or team members
right that's that's generally the
terminology we use the scrum guide says
developers and the scrum team
but
in kanban it's just kanban system
members people participating in the
kanban system
and that doesn't have to be scrum either
it can be waterfall teams
and then the last one number 10 you
don't need a sprint goal for every
sprint and everybody put a big x on it
that's awesome
i am quite happy
with uh that one you don't need to argue
that
and anything surprising for you there
gordon
yeah the the lifts are off
um like i felt like if any way that's
going to be mandatory it would be in
camera
i know i just me too i thought that as
well and
um i went i went round and round with
with daniel vicanti on it and and he
said as well it it is definitely
a thing you would expect
with positive behavior
i'm trying i'm trying to not be too
explicit here right yeah um you would
def i i would definitely like to see the
work moving from left to right
right it's going to break your data it's
going to break your ability to monitor
your flow if stuff starts flowing in
multiple directions and things moving
back that's what's going to happen
um
but
there's nothing that says it can't
camera it's not just about the data i
mean it is but it's not
so
um
would any anybody else have a
comment they would like to make on
maybe something they thought was
contentious
athena
i heard a cockerel in the background on
your audio there that's pretty awesome
martin i have a question on
um
the definition of this isn't it
i yes i guess like i recognize the voice
and jumunya
right um i was the only one that put an
x on the
on the definition of done on the
workflow
and the reason why
i put an x was
if a team is not using a scrub
then the definition of them doesn't
apply so maybe you can comment on that
well that that's that's that's
definitely uh uh
i understand
what you're saying
and there would be no requirement for a
kanban team to have a definition of done
okay
but
how do they
know when their work is finished
how do they know
to move that work
from
being in progress
to being completed
what what rule do they apply what
decisions do they make as a team
in order
for that to happen
and where do they define that
and wouldn't that
definition
in the scrum world we would just call it
a definition of done in the kanban world
it's
a
policy for
being finished
being
complete yeah they probably probably
i was going to say they probably
wouldn't use the terminology definition
of done but i think the terminology
definition have done is kind of
ubiquitous at this point
um most people would just use that
terminology our definition of done to
move into that final column or if it's
called completed they might call it
definition of complete eat um but it has
the same meaning
okay you're right
you're right
um
yeah that's a little bit maybe maybe
that should have been on a scrum with
kanban uh a card instead of just a
kanban one um
must be a way to phrase that that
doesn't um
imply
scrum
i'll think about that i'll think about
that for next time but yeah thank you
for that
so i want to do a little um
exercise i'm going to
at this point we're going to have to
close the
meeting so let me lock the meeting there
we go
so
oh i clicked it
oh there we go
it didn't disappear right away there we
go logs no one else can join okay
uh so i have space for eight groups of
five how many people do we have 31
uh but one person's on the call
so maybe they need to stay with me um
if the person that's on the call are you
able to see the mural
i don't even know how calling in works
for going off mute
tomorrow
okay so if if you can't
see the mural um it's going to be very
difficult to participate with everybody
else but
um
[Music]
let's
see
yeah nobody joined after i put the last
uh copy of the mural in there and so if
you can't see the mural um let me know
in the chat or however you can and i
will not put you in a breakout room uh
because that will put everybody else at
a bit of a disadvantage
thank that
yeah so raise your hand if you cannot
um
access the the the the mural because we
do really need that for this exercise
uh so i'm going to
30 people into five
gordon you're the smart one
it's six people six in the room man
right right
if you're doing
well
let's
do i'm thinking
um
if you wanted your eight to do four
people in there you really want eight
rooms i really want five people
in a room
um
so
yeah but i'm just worried about so six
rooms let's do five rooms
and then the spare people
just in case
there's somebody who can't access the
mural in a room that'll help us caveat
that problem
so i'm creating
five rooms they'll be numbered one two
five
i have eight boxes here but we'll just
use the first five um so let me summon
everybody
oh
i clicked on the wrong thing because
there we go so it's 26 people yeah we
should have
we should have enough okay
so
this is going to be fun gordon does this
look complicated to you
a little yeah oh yeah okay
a lot more boxes than last time so let
me zoom in to one
activity and i'm gonna summon everybody
again so this would be
the the room one
activity
and there are five boxes vertically can
you see that one two three four five and
round one round two and round three
does that make sense for you gordon yeah
yeah
cool
um so in each round
we are going to do an activity in our
breakout rooms and i'm not going to be
there to help you because there's five
rooms
so
hopefully there's at least one person in
each room that totally understands
everything
um but i have
little uh
oh well it would help if they went on
top of the thing bring to front
i have 20 little circles here so i'm
going to copy that paste it in
on top there we go
so i get 20 little circles in the red
box
okay
and so in your rooms you're going to
decide
who
diana are you okay
yeah android phones don't have right
access to mural if you have an iphone
you do but mural have not been good at
supporting android very well um but yeah
uh uh so
hopefully
your room uh that you can work with um
the the other people that are there or
you could be the timer
right and so what we're going to do is
we're going to time
how long it takes to do some work
okay that's what we're going to do and
we're going to alter the batch size for
each round
okay so the instructions are in the
mural but i'm going to go through them
because yeah i understand it's it's
complicated so in round one
this is for gordon because he's
difficult with the complicated stuff so
garden in round one
we're doing batch sizes of 20
right so you you can only move 20 things
at a time
so you have to
whoever's in the red process box
has got to process 20 things move 20
things uh to the green process box
so what i'm going to do for example is
i'm going to change
each of these
and i'm
clicking the right trying to click the
right button i'm going to change each of
them to to green
right and then i have to move them over
to the green box
oh sorry
i am
not smart am i gordon
let me put that back
i'm going to change them to red because
they're in the red box gordon you should
have caught me on that
i'm still remember i'm this low and i'm
busy catching up still
yeah so when it's in the red box i've
got to change it to red
and i'm not allowed to move anything
over to the green box until they're all
red because the batch size is 20
right so once they're all red and i'm
going to lay down some rules
you're not allowed to multi-select
gordon
that's what i was thinking
you're not allowed to to
why can't i click i'm having a mural
difficulty here
euro's not letting me deselect the items
um so let me
refresh my browser because turning it
off and turning it back on again
generally solves every neural problem
there is
i'm just refresher
okay i can see some people are
having a place seeing how you do that
you basically click on an item it pops
up a little uh box you've got a color
button you click it and you change it to
another the red okay
once you've got them all changed to red
right it will look like this wanted
garden well apart from that pink one
that somebody just changed before i
grabbed it
okay and then one at a time you're not
allowed to multi-select you move them
all to green
and then the person who is in the green
process box has to change them to green
but they're not allowed to start
changing them to green until there's 20
items there
so some people will do all 20 items then
move them across one at a time some
people will change it to
red and move one item across red and
move red and move ready to move but the
green process cannot start
until they are all green
does that make sense
yep
and then they move on to
the yellow process
and whoever in your room is designated
owner is going to make them all yellow
and then pink
and then purple and purple is the
customer
right so once
they're moved into the purple box
we're going to
write down how long it took to get
everything done so somebody in your
group's going to time how long it takes
to get the batch delivered does that
make sense
yeah okay
so the two things
have i made it complicated enough for
you gordon
i think so okay
let's uh what we're gonna do
is i'd like you in your group when you
get into your group is to estimate how
long you think it's going to take right
like how long do i think this is going
to take
and then
you're going to time how long it
actually takes so do go start a timer
somebody do it on your watch on your
phone whatever it is start a timer and
when the first batch is delivered
split the timer that way you know
it took four minutes to do the whole
batch
when we break up into smaller batches
right because when you move on to round
two
you're gonna do batches of five
so you change five color five to the
color
move it across change five move it
across change five move it across so we
should have three people four people
working at the same time
make sense yeah
and then on the last
round three it's batches of one
right so you can change the color and
move one change the color and move one
so if you're processing in that color
you can process one at a time or five at
a time or twenty at a time that sound
good
so when so just to make clear so we do
round one we move everything to get it
all the way through down to block five
we capture how long that took do we
immediately move on to round two and
then do it in in batches of five then we
don't
wait for like an external timer or ping
from you
correct we're gonna we're gonna do all
of them and oh
tell you what martin
something weird happened there
i see what happened there
and i see what the problem is this has
become unl why has that
become unlocked
right
yes gordon so you do uh i'm gonna put
i'm gonna fill up all of the the little
boxes
okay so you've got your starter
items
can you see that now
yeah i'll i'll do the other teams as
well okay yeah and but the idea is you
click an item change the color so when
you get into your rooms
decide who's going to work at each
station
there's five stations the customer is
the last one
then time how long it takes
to get one batch done
and then the final batch done
so we don't care about all the ones in
between first batch final batch so
obviously in round one there's only one
batch anyway so it's the same number
round two there are four batches
of five and round three there are 20
batches of one
does that make sense
just the
just double check so the on round two we
move five across the two right
so once on round two and you change five
the color of five of them
move five across to green and then the
green person can start working with that
batch of five
but can the red person start working on
the next batch so long yes
okay cool that's the idea that's the
idea is yeah yeah as soon as we start
reducing the batch size we're going to
have multiple people working at the same
time
yeah right and we're the important thing
is to collect
collect the numbers okay so i put um
some little stickies on there so you can
put the numbers in those box and i'll
just add
uh
some stickies to the
other two
there we
go right so it's just taking me a minute
to to set this up and then i'm gonna
copy that whole thing so don't move
anything around yet and we've got
there's
why is
mural is definitely being a bit weird
today
and your first batch is the
the first time that all of that batch
stars make it into the customer and your
your second sticky is once basically all
20 have made it through to the customer
the timer
correct
so let me have just filled up two of
three of the things let me get the
ah
i almost got that to sit on top of the
thing that i wanted to sit on top of
there we go
so everybody remember
now
these things can move around so i've set
up all five
batches
what i'm gonna do is i'm gonna monitor
what's going um and i might jump into a
breakout room if folks are having
trouble
right but cheating
cheating
is uh multi-selecting
right that's cheating in this case so
when you're dragging and moving you can
only move one at a time
you can't start your batch until your
process until the full batch that you're
expecting is there
does that make sense as well gordon
yeah
i don't seem to be in any breakup uh you
are definitely not yet
eki i have not opened the breakout rooms
um
mainly because
uh
gordon was having such a difficult time
understanding so i wanted to make sure
everybody everybody he's my litmus test
he's my litmus test
uh so i'm going to open the rooms i will
come and help but proceed from
round one
to round two to round three
right
um
do them one at a time make sure you you
know which process you are what color
are you changing things to and agree
before you start
how you're going to do the work okay
does that make sense
and i will keep an eye out for cheating
that's what i will do
okay so i'm going to open the breakout
rooms um if you need me ping me the
seven
six six six six in the different rooms
and so maybe somebody's just watching
but um
if you're just watching either do the
timing or um
watch out for cheating that's that's
lots of vigilant people that's what we
want
uh so let me do that
so breaker rooms have started opening uh
you should all
um
end up in a breakout room and the number
of the breakout room matches the
box at the top of the different areas so
there are five areas and five breakout
rooms
okay so
oh
i did that badly
right so don't show cursors hiding on
facilitator cursors
okay
that should speed things up
so
james
are you okay
i can see you're still here
james did not end up in a room
i am having a bit of a
it sounds like
um you're having a little bit of
internet connection issues which room
did you
get uh
let's see we lost
um
see we lost a couple of people there's
there's your room let me ask you to join
your room
do you get a pop-up now james
one two three four five
so room threes get five
one two three four five room four is
good five one two three four five room
fives get five so we're good there
and one two three four five awesome um
so we lost dennis
james is being difficult
yeah
so um have you seen this exercise before
james
is it a variation on the coin game it is
a variation
yeah yeah
so instead when you're doing it in
person um you can't really
um
you can't really do
do that so we need to to do it a little
bit differently um i think we're going
to struggle for for for time actually
because it took a long time to explain
that
um
is sometimes difficult with so many
people as well
yeah it's awesome the way you've set it
up it looks really good i'm sorry i'm
just really struggling with
these things happen internet sometimes
uh it doesn't work out so well um it
looks like i'm i'm not sure who it is
that's on the on the call um because it
doesn't say your name it just says your
phone number um but plus 23 um must be
having a bit of trouble as well and
decided just to call in um and sometimes
that works too
right i mean
um
luckily once murals mural can take a
long time to load on a poor connection
but once it's loaded it usually works
pretty well
um
but actually i've no oh there's one team
group three has started to move items or
they're thinking about it there's there
may be still
i'm actually going to pop if if you can
forgive me james for leaving you here
for a minute please do
i know please do i'm sorry i can't get
into the room i i'm trying to
did the calling you again see if that
works
um
but i'm just going to pop into each room
and
make sure that folks are okay
it's heading into room
okay you can't see
i can't see
yeah i think somebody else has the same
problem as you couldn't see the mirror
hey folks how are things going
to
coordinate which one will be which color
no no that's totally good so um
what might be might be easy is just
putting a post-it with your name
on the boards
do you know how to put a post-it on
there if you drag one
uh over from the from the left
yep we got so make the post it's really
small
that's probably a good idea um
and then that make it easier to pick
who's who's which color
yeah
you're very welcome
so um
no the the the there is only one batch
in round one
of 20 items that goes through the whole
process
so you only need to record one number
for
uh um for round one okay
that's that's just
me duplicating
things at the bottom
five minutes you guys think you can do
it in five minutes
hey guys can we start
so who's doing the timer
one after the other yeah yes
perfect
ah yes
so uh
i think uh uh gregory is gonna start the
timer once you change the first color
anna
yeah
cool okay
sounds like you you're all sorted i'll
go check on another group okay
okay thank you
ah that's better
let's see
group two oh
there we go
and there we go
group two's off to the races as well
looks like james managed to get in there
i think he's done the the coin game
uh before uh for those on the on the
stream who are wondering what the heck's
going on uh you can see the
to the site yep opposites
uh you can see
uh each group has a a little set tokens
and they're just changing the color of
the tokens which simulates flipping a
coin when you run this
in person with a group of people um i
usually turn up with a bag of coins like
20 coins and um first person gets the
bag of coins they have to sort them out
so that they're all either heads up or
tails up
um and then each person
that it goes to in the process flips the
coins over and they have to flip all of
the coins over and you you make rules
like you know one hand behind your back
or uh you know not flipping two at once
um
all those kind of things and then it has
to go around all the people before um
it's it's done in in the batch size uh
so the first exercise is batches of ten
so you can already see that it's going
it's going pretty slowly uh for the for
the for the for the groups i might have
to pop in and help out group four if
their stuff doesn't start moving in a
minute um but you can see uh group ones
getting uh going from one to two and
then they're gonna start changing to
green we have to get them all across
first um and it's it's the time it takes
to do all of those things builds up and
builds up and builds up
um and when you've only got one person
working at once
on a particular
activity it really slows down
right
so if you're in the in the in the in the
software world
and what that equates to
is a big backlog item
right some big chunky thing uh flowing
through the process that's a big batch
size that's a batch right um i have
another exercise that we probably won't
have time for we'll probably wrap up
this one and that's all we'll have time
for uh just because of uh the length of
time that this uh took to set up um i
probably need more practice at doing
that
um
but that that this time is going to be
huge for
uh round one and then it's going to
reduce obviously as we get towards round
three
but the thing that's surprising is the
amount that it reduces okay
um
so it tends to be a
a huge amount of time
i think 20 items is too much i need to
reduce that to 15. um
thank you claudia
gladia um
i had it at 50 50
15 15 and i changed it to 20. 15 is the
right number
um oh i see a big multi-select going on
in room four i'm going to let them away
with it because they're quite far behind
so they are uh
cheating a little bit
that's okay
um
so let's see what we've got
uh
yep room one is on
two to three
room two is on two to three room three
is on three to four
room four is on two to three well
they're on two the processing two
um room five is almost finished
processing too
that's that's that's okay the numbers
are going to be really horrible and
that's what you want from this exercise
you want to demonstrate that the numbers
are horrible when you have big batches i
use this exercise quite a lot with teams
uh when they uh are are
don't see the value of breaking things
down into smaller items this can be a
good exercise to kind of just trigger
them thinking about well
what does having a big thing mean how
important is it to break things down
because there's extra management effort
in at working with uh smaller things
right um if you think about you've got
your your tickets in jira or as your
devops or whatever it is you're using um
i have one ticket to manage versus i
have 20 tickets to manage which one's
easier to manage from a from a tooling
perspective well the one ticket's easier
to manage
but from a work being done perspective
it's better to have those smaller units
so
the
balance of work
between the amount of time you spend
doing the work versus managing the work
is where that contention comes in and i
do find
that a lot of teams
begrudge the extra i don't know
30 minutes the extra hour even it takes
to manage those 20 items versus the the
the one big item um but the benefit of
breaking them down into smaller things
is huge
it can really help teams improve their
flow of delivery improve their
predictability um and just get better at
delivering stuff um so we've got
yeah this this uh
is definitely taking uh quite a while we
are gonna hit the time limit i'm gonna
carry on because um
that's what i
do but i think we took a little bit too
long in the icebreaker and then it just
took too long to explain it
i'm trying to think of ways to do this
um exercise that make it easier for
people to understand so we can get into
it quicker
because it should take about 30 minutes
all told um probably about eight minutes
for the first uh round and then reducing
there i think i put ten minutes for the
first round five minutes for the second
round three minutes for the third round
because people do get better at doing
the task right uh there's a little bit
of learned uh
repetitive movement you're learning
better ways to do it so that improves
but only a little bit
right the biggest improvement comes from
batch size uh so we get three to four
three to four
okay
awesome
so we've got one group
that is finished and took
eight minutes 32
but their expectation was about four
minutes
so that's that's pretty pretty uh
pretty awesome time so they're on their
second round and it's batches of five so
hopefully um
they
will get that organized
i am going to
let me
i'm gonna
delete
that i think
um
sometimes mural doesn't like having too
many things
on the board so if i delete these even
though i've made them one thing by
grouping them i wonder if grouping
really helps from a
a performance perspective
it should do it should do
um
which group is gardening
james is in group two
gordon is in group three how's group
three doing okay so group three started
on there
second round
ah so they're thinking six minutes for
the second round okay
so that could be interesting
so that's their first group of five
and then the next person so they've
they've got a little bit of a bottleneck
there you can see that how they've
organized the stuff they would need to
learn
the first batch is here the second
incoming batch is here that way they
don't get them mixed up
[Music]
but they'll learn that as they go
through because they're they've got to
do it four times so they get four
chances to optimize
their process as they go through
it's definitely uh interesting i love
doing the exercises uh this one
is just a little bit uh time-consuming
but i'm gonna pop in and
because i think
group five there is struggling a little
bit
oh and so is group two
group two and group five are struggling
oh okay group four is um
let me go help group four
give me some assistance here or martin
khan
okay
martin i'm trying to select about these
so that i move them
yes so
i was using
yeah so so you're only supposed to
select one at a time
but
right can you drag them and move them
just now
there you go yes so how how how we are
doing it is once you change all of them
you take all of them at once then you
start changing them then you start
recording time then okay
so does that work it does it does you
you do it do it that way that makes
sense um
remember that we want just the the time
for the first
batch all the way through the system so
it goes one two three four five how long
does it take to get everything through
the system
okay no problem yeah that's that's the
time that we're looking for
okay okay it's your turn change them to
which colors is orange or yellow
yes one of those colors duplicates i'm
moving to that next box the way that
that is for you if you can move them to
the next box
now i've already moved them it's for you
to change to yellow yes right so i'm
changing yellow
this is my screen
i think i think you lost somebody um
would you like me to take yellow and
then you take pink ecky yes this boy
so
yellow so let's do yellow
yellow
it's very hard isn't it
it's tiring
it is repetitive strain injuries coming
on here
develop developing a repetitive strain
injury
oh oh oh click the wrong nope stop
spinning it right i'll go over here
sometimes when they're too close
together
you end up
with a tool dysfunction and it's trying
to spin the items rather than
uh
what color am i picking i forgot the
color now there we go yellow yeah well i
think i picked kind of orangey but
oh man i could love blind you excused
yeah what what's the what's the timer up
to
three minutes 49 seconds 50 seconds 51.
so in our in this group we're selecting
them all at once yeah
yes right
so whoever's doing the pink process your
goal
hecky
you don't need to share your screen just
change the change the items we can all
see them
in the the pink process
i'm changing this to pig
yes
i think okay
all right you can start the time like
this
okay then started oh i need to go help
group one so hold on
write it down just write the sticky note
so
one minute like 50 one minute 50 seconds
something like that was
one minute 50 seconds hey folks
you you guys should be working on more
than one batch at once
so so whoever's whoever's uh red should
be changing the next batch and moving it
on to two
the next batch of five keep that keep
those batches going this factory doesn't
isn't going to change color itself
that's okay
right so only five not all the twenty
so um
do five move them on do five move them
on do five move them on
you
you can you can start the next five as
soon as you've handed
the previous five off to the next person
okay
cool
so room three is good
to finish the fifth bit or rota are you
gonna do it
okay
how are you guys doing the pink stuff
needs to move into the customer don't
they doesn't it
yes how do you select all of them at
once again uh so if you just hold down
control
and then select
they'll go
what's the time on the timer now the
total time
six minutes
eight seconds it's never six minutes six
seconds
i'm gonna put that down though six
minutes
six seconds
but that's for
that's not for the first batch
so what do you mean by the first batch i
don't
all of them
how long did it take you to get
them from one all the way down to five
so we haven't finished five years so as
it is
the the first batch we did it at one
minute 28 seconds okay so
the customer one which is now i guess
we're supposed to change them to purple
what let's what i want let's call let's
call the customer one done
okay then so it's six minutes six
seconds
in total one two three four okay yeah
six minutes it seems like you were
stopping the timer but um we'll we'll
let it go okay so
for round two i'd like you to start
round two
um
change five of them move five to the
next process and then start changing the
next five does that make sense
so there should be
so
five turn to red
give them to green
next five turn to red give them to green
green works on the first five they get
from red moves them to yellow
they should have the next five from red
waiting move them to yellow
make sense
okay then
so if if that's the case that means they
shouldn't stop the timer so start the
timer again from scratch
okay
so if you if you hit the reset okay
so um
let i'll be i'll be red
okay
and who's who's green
who's who's the green color
is that you dennis dennis are you green
okay
so i'm gonna i'm gonna change
so start the timer
oh
start your timer
started
started it cool uh so i'm gonna change
five of these one
two
oh
three
four
five to red
and then i'm gonna put them one
two
three
four
five whoever's green can start changing
those ones to green while i work on the
next five
okay
one
two
three
four
five
okay so whoever's in the yellow process
once you've got five you can start
working on the five
so there'll be three of us working at
the same time
one
two
three
four
five
you can tell i've done this before can't
you
kevin whoever who's pink
icky
do the pink beats
right i'm gonna check out on the other
rooms because i can see some of them are
are done so i might bring you back early
okay
i don't know what's happening in room
five
uh i knew it would be gordon and
michelle in room three
gordon michelle you got it you get you
guys are finished the fastest
fastest
out of everyone room one's almost
finished i'm actually not sure
what the delay is
um they've got some kind of malfunction
um
probably bring
i don't know what's happening
what i'm gonna do is i'm gonna close
oh
victoria i'm just putting you on mute
there's just a lot of background noise
i am going to close all the rooms bring
everybody back and we can look at the
data from uh
from room awesome sorry room uh
room three
you do you want to figure out the top of
this is 15 15.
but the time we had left over we
helped out
thank you for that michelle my everybody
knows my spelling is atrocious
it's a well-known fact but there's a
number this is the number 15 or 20.
so i have i let me
i'm just going to mute everybody because
of some background noise from a couple
of people um but feel free to unmute
again if you don't have a background
noise um so that was uh
very interesting there was a lot of
things going on there and i see that
some teams managed to have different
degrees of how quickly they got through
it and i'm just looking to see who who
was the longest
in room one uh 10 minutes 30 seconds
for
five
uh
[Music]
nine nine minutes 55 so about 10 seconds
again for two
seven
eight minutes for for room one
i'm just gonna look at room three
because they managed to to to finish
all of their items so i'm just going to
summon everybody over um
to see what we what we got here so i'm
just going to use this as as indicative
of
um roughly how it would have turned out
for everybody okay because everybody's
kind of doing the same tasks although
some teams were cheating and
multi-selecting but let's not go there
martin are you gonna share your screen
by any chance
uh i can share my screen i think a
couple of you are struggling with
internet so let me share my screen and
then you can um
see that
and let me do that so i can give me a
second so i can see you guys again
there we go now
and see you guys so i'm sharing sharing
uh my screen here
uh that's working over there so
um in in round one where we did batches
of 20
so only one person was working at once
weren't they
so with one person working at once uh it
took about nine minutes if we average it
between all of the teams it probably
took about nine minutes to get 20 things
done
what was your guess your guesstimate
michelle at the start of round one
four minutes yeah
so part of the problem there was there
was a bit of a panic um the estimation
because we sort of forgot to
do it and then we got started with the
first four and there was like a panic ah
four minutes
and then we we like got like halfway and
then it was already like just over four
when teams are working for real all the
best decisions are made in a panic
currently
i mean yeah and
you can see that we got better with
estimations as each uh sprint completed
there yep as each round as you finished
each round you definitely got got better
you got closer in so um round one four
minute guess eight and a half minute
finish eight and a half
actually pretty fast
for this exercise with 20 items
round two six minute guess
four minute finish
but how quickly did you get the first
batch of five
two minutes
as half
half the the time
that you took to get all of them
and that time to get all of them in
batches of five
was twice as fast as the time it took
you to do a batch of 20. why was that
because there
was people working
it was more efficient
the the more efficient because you get
more people working at once
yeah
and then what happens when we go to back
but also there must be a little part
there must be a small part of they've
already done it once so they got better
at the job as well yes
so so there is a there is a uh uh
if you run the whole exercise again
right that's you've got the skills now a
little bit extra skills to do the job
you find that the timing doesn't change
that much but it does change it does get
a little bit better
right a little bit better
but the vast majority of this time
savings that we got
was in the team being more effective as
a whole
right and working more people working at
once and then you can see how long it
takes you to get one piece of the first
piece of value in round three
28 seconds yeah
that's that's a quarter of the time it
took you from round two
so the value's not the value's not huge
number three right but if that's now
if that was your first experiment
you would find out in 30 seconds that
the rest of it's not worth it if you
only if you had to stop after the first
piece of work
which piece of work should you have done
first
did anybody notice that the pieces of
work had different numbers on them
yeah yeah
we got some of ours in the wrong order
on the second one second thing it was
that it was that's so it was kind of for
that but kinda to ask the question
wouldn't it be best to do the tens first
if 10
represented the amount of value
right you would do the tens first so i
mean
well in my mind
the size or at least when i saw the
numbers i was thinking of the sort of
amount of effort required in getting
that piece of work done
which is why you would want to start
with but they are all the same
yeah fair enough yeah
so the the if if it's value
if you did the tens and then the fives
and then had to stop
and there's only the ones left
you've got
90 of the value through the system
already yeah
yeah the other small side effect that i
noticed was was
the the
i suppose you could say the quality of
it so if you look at the first block
first block um when we're doing twenty
like
i was in in block four there the rushing
of dropping it on they sort of all just
landed in twenty twenty um
the second block you can see some of
them overlapping but not that many
and in the fifth block i think there's
one block that's touching each other so
the overall quality of the job with a
more streamlined workflow um
was better as well as well i i agree
gordon and there's also that that piece
where if you're looking at a pile of 20
things you're going holy molly i've got
20 things i've got to do when there's
only one thing i'm just doing one thing
one thing you know you you do it you do
that one thing right that one thing
right but if i've got to do 20 things
i'm starting to rush i'm starting to
make mistakes i change it to the wrong
color i set a a border rather than a
color but you know accidentally um or i
i moved to trying to drag and drop too
many things that were too close together
and you end up spinning one in a circle
um
you know so that's two issues
right but that represents the real world
yeah and when i do this with physical
coins the coins fall off the table
right somebody has ham fists the coins
so they fall off the table the timer
doesn't stop because the customer still
wants the value
yeah and we've got to go pick it up that
simulates a bug that simulates something
getting in the way of our process and
our problem
yeah it's something that we spoke about
i was like
with my ocd
like i would if i chose the wrong shade
of pink even though it's pink i'd have
to go back and do it again michelle is
like well i'm the customer i'm not going
to accept different shades of pink
yeah so so there's also a quality check
at each stage
that you could do as well
right make sure it moved to the right
right
the right process happened i mean we're
just changing colors which is a little
bit
straightforward
right but when we're building software
or we're building products things moving
between the stages it's a little more
complicated
yeah so we can see
visualize using this exercise this is a
good exercise to run with your teams as
well
we can visualize why smaller batches go
through the system faster
right it helps us make that connection
in our head quite often i work with
teams
and they don't want to spend the extra
effort to break things down into smaller
chunks
right because then we have to manage it
in jira or we have to manage it in azure
devops
yeah yeah that's more overhead
but that overhead is tiny in comparison
to the amount of time you save because
you've got smaller batches
can can you think of what might
make this more difficult to have smaller
batches
so i was
saying um if we had to set a whip limit
um so you can't move
stuff into one block if there's already
like say the limits three three because
then that would cause a build up in the
box going backwards
yep you could introduce a whip limit
that's definitely a good experiment to
try and see you know if we if if you
our our batch size when our batch size
is one
right in this scenario we got the most
effective
delivery
right
what would happen
if we were using physical coins
flipping them over and each station was
in a different
room with a batch size of one still be
optimal perhaps not because you waste a
bunch of time running between the rooms
so maybe batches of five might be better
or maybe batches of ten would be better
if we have to run between the rooms yeah
i suppose the distance between rooms
would would would have to be a
factor there in fact i mean if the if
the rooms are like 100
parts
batches of 20 because 20 because or even
batches of 10.
um whereas if it's like
yeah exactly
exactly so the batch size there's no
right batch size yeah right yeah you've
got to figure out for your context with
your type of work with your type of
delivery
what is
the the most optimal batch size for our
moment in time based on what we're doing
and that may change over time as well
but in general
in general smaller is better
in general
what are what are other batches garden
that we use at work
five seems quite common
um
i don't know why i don't know why i was
thinking of types of work that are
batches
ah
so uh
it's okay it's it's late for you is it
not no it's not is it not like nearly 7
p.m uh
10 to 8.
oh 10 to 8 okay only one our difference
michelle what what what other types of
batches
also one hour difference
also we're not different
so
tickets
tickets tickets or batches yeah tickets
are batches
sorry
cases
yeah tickets casey's backlog items
stories
these are these are batches any other
batches that what batches might use in
scrum
we have a sprint don't we
yeah sprinter batch
as well yeah here's the body of work
that we're gonna do a release
might be a batch if that's multiple
bigger body of work
right
so so
we have all these different sorts of
batches that we just have to understand
how they go through the system how are
we delivering those things and
knowing that bigger
takes longer but there might be reasons
to have things bigger
hey
uh so i am conscious uh that we are a
little bit over so i covered um a couple
of these um already
um and i just wanted to highlight that
there are some good
pieces of information uh that we can use
to do a little bit of research obviously
uh
i'm trying to wet people's appetite with
the mindset
right so you go read some of the the
content it's difficult to to teach a lot
in an hour and a half
there's the kanban guide for scrum teams
so if you are a scrum team
um working to deliver software
you can help optimize your scrum get
more effective
at your scrum by using
combat and the kanban guy for scrum
teams is how did we do kanban within the
context of scrum without breaking scrum
right
there's also the kanban guide which was
released like i was going to say last
year yes december 2020
by daniel vicanti and
the pro kanban
community and that's focusing just on
the core strategies
of kanban
right um so it's not looking there's
also the kanban method
which is taught by uh david anderson and
lin kanban university and that is more
than just the core strategy for kanban
it's got a bunch of practices around it
like scrum has a bunch of practices
around it around an empirical process
control system but the kanban guide is
trying to distill that down
to a very
small group and there are two books that
i really recommend um one is a practical
kanban right that's the that's the easy
one to read out of those two um
practical kanban is a a a pretty good
team-focused uh value-driven approach um
and then flow
if you really want to understand
cues
and how uh
the math works
for how that work flows through the
system and then flow uh principles of
product development is a really good
book but if you don't have a math head
thank you gregory if you don't have a
math head then you're probably not going
to have a good time with that book it's
it's it's it's very mathy um so there's
another book by daniel vicanti
which is a lot easier to read while
covering a lot of the same topics um and
that's
actionable agile metrics for
predictability um and he actually has a
new one which i've not read yet so i
can't
i don't know much about it yet but when
will it be done but it sounds like a
good book title doesn't it um that's
something that
everybody asks us when will it be done
um and that's uh really important
so i wanted
to cover a a little bit more i wanted to
do a little exercise with you uh around
the three
core practices in kanban um i don't
think we have
time to do it just now that's that's
that's my fault we took a long time with
that
at coin game exercise i'm going to blame
gordon that's for for asking too many
questions at the start
but maybe it was my explanation sucked
us i would have definitely cheated if uh
if i didn't ask as many questions
yeah that's that's okay
this it's always it's always the
facilitator if timing is off it's always
the facilitator and maybe i bit off more
than i could chew there
but the three core practices around at
kanban the first one is defining and
visualizing your workflow
right whatever system you're using it
doesn't matter whether you're doing
waterfall make it up as i go along or
scrum right whatever process you're
doing
define and visualize your workflow what
are the stages that the work flows
through why do things move between
different columns why do you choose
particular items so definition of done
is your in the scrum world definition
i've done is your leaving gate
definition of ready might be your
arriving
gate right you're not going to pull
things into your system until they're
ready and so they're part of your
definition of workflow and then you've
got your columns and work flows
generally from left to right garden
generally from left to right
through through different stages of work
do you do some design do you do some
analysis do you do some coding and do
some testing and then do some validation
and then it's done right and you've got
to meet your definition of done
so so while we're looking at the columns
just saying back to the
the first exercise we did where you said
like each column doesn't need a work in
progress as long as it sort of works
with the overall workflow
is that is that saying then that's the
overall workflow you would have like
regardless of what the limits are you
still have a certain amounts of things
in play at once at once yes
so you you have to have a whip limit
minimum requirement of of kanban is
having a whip limit between the arriving
work and the leaving work right you're
starting work and you're finishing work
and that's part of the second core
practice which is actively managing your
work
right so not just looking at it and go
oh look we've got too much stuff right
um actively doing something about it
yeah so in order to do something about
it we need to count it
yeah
i was just thinking like every time
every time i mean i've used this with
the team we've always always used uh
limits that are on each column as i
suppose inherently the way to limit
what's in the flow for the whole
workflow but we've never looked at
actually applying that i mean because
we've never really looked at the book
either to to do it academically how are
we supposed to do it's sort of that
yeah we don't have a process we just
drag [__] across the board off the board
well so i but it's the same as uh
we we do scrum we store our work in jira
and we stand up every day yeah
same idea um so
having understanding how much work you
currently have in progress will help you
understand um the limitations that
you've got in your in your system
generally not just reducing batch size
but reducing the number of items that
you have in progress
tends to improve the flow of work
through the system so the speed of an
item um as it goes through the system um
it just flows better and so they're
they're the two biggest improvements
that even a scrum team can make in their
process is understanding their flow of
work right so we need to
visualize it so we can see what's going
on because you know what it's like
gordon when you when you don't look at
that board with the 50 things on it it
doesn't look like when you're looking
down here that you've got 50 things
you're working on because i'm working on
two things but there were these ten
things that were blocked yesterday yeah
right so i took on these two new things
which means i've got 12 things in
progress that that
that big the big number
is the bit why have we got so much stuff
in progress why are we not getting
things done
right and then in actively managing work
you can look at
how things are arriving into your system
and how things are leaving
from your system right
that's what the cfd cumulative flow
diagram is showing you
right your average arrival vape versus
your average leaving rate and then
you ideally want two parallel lines
really close together on your cumulative
flow but you're never actually going to
get that in the real world but the
closer you get to two close parallel
lines the more effective your system is
being the quicker things are flowing
through your system
and usually you get big chunky bits you
can always tell looking at cumulative
flow for for uh for a team that's doing
scrum because they have that big chunky
you know we deliver at the end of the
sprint we've got more work taken on
deliver at the end of the sprint you've
got a chunky uh cumulative flow going
through so that's visualizing the work
uh uh um and defining
the workflow
is the first
core practice of kanban right so that's
that's defining why things move what
type of works do we have uh what type of
works do we have what type of work do we
have represented on the board stories
bugs what are the support tickets what
are they and then how they flow through
the system what happens at each stage
why they move
and then actively managing that work by
monitoring how many things we've got in
progress and and taking steps
to reduce those things that's part of
improving uh the workflow so the last
part is that improving the workflow make
changes to your system
see how those changes that you make
affect the flow of work through that
system and can continuously improve over
time so if you look at the exercise we
did
the main thing we changed
with each round was reducing the batch
size and we got better numbers
right but at some point you're not going
to get better numbers you've reduced the
batch size and you make it smaller and
suddenly the numbers are worse okay well
we found what might be our optimum batch
size just now
okay maybe maybe that's four right four
is a good batch size for whatever it is
we're doing
now you've got four
things flowing through the system you
can then look at what else can we change
right oh things spend a lot of time in
waiting in testing before the testers
can take it on have we got some kind of
constraint there that prevents that work
flowing more effectively where how do
you visualize that well you can see it
on the board
right um so that you've got that cycle
of
visualizing the workflow actively
managing the work and improving the
workflow and there are four
metrics
um that we we want to look at as part of
that system
and you've got your work in process
gordon that's the from when work started
to when you agree it's finished
okay
um but you've also got the age of work
in the system how long has something
been sitting there
and you can use that that's the data i
would look at during my daily scrum for
example right things that have been
sitting there longer are less likely to
get done
and you're looking at your cycle time
which is the time it takes for an item
from when it started to when it finished
then you could look at your average
cycle time and then your throughput
right that's number of items delivered
per unit of time so in scrum you know
times normally a sprint right but it
could be five days 10 days 50 days
whatever your unit of time is
um and your throughput is is your
average throughput is that measure of
how quickly you're going to burn through
your your your backlog right so if you
want to increase your throughput you can
reduce your batch size
right that's one way to increase your
throughput um or reduce your cycle time
depending on what happens
right you're not going to be able to
control those two things through put in
cycle time but you can control your work
in process
that's the one thing that you as a team
have 100 control over
is your work in process and if you
reduce your working process either your
throughput increases or your cycle time
decreases or both right
um
because math
right i should really have uh the the
let me just grab it
um
i'm let me grab the one from
[Music]
i've got a little uh diagram
a little formula
that i should have put in here
but i forgot
um so let me just load it up for you uh
but it's little's law
or it's our uh
a rendition
of little's law in the software world so
and this is from daniel vicanti and it's
just a little formula let me grab it
here somewhere there it is let me grab
that copy image and then i should be
able to paste it in here and i'll make
it a lot bigger there we go
so this is this is little's law
and this is this is true
uh regardless of whether
you're waiting in a queue in the
supermarket
right
or uh you've got work backing up in your
backlog
or your sprint queue right so your
average cycle time
equals the average work in process
divided by the average throughput
so there's two of these numbers that are
very difficult for us to control
right average cycle time how fast things
get done
we
we have no control over that in the
software world none whatsoever
how many items we deliver we probably
have no control over that or very little
control over that it's very difficult to
affect those two numbers
but we can control average work in
progress
so gordon you're a mathematician aren't
you
what happens
what happens if our average work in
progress gets smaller
but these other
the the average throughput stays the
same
what happens to cycle time
so you get less
less work in progress
and if you have less work in progress
and throughput stays the same cycle time
will get smaller
will deliver the same number of items in
a shorter period of time
yeah yeah if average working process
gets smaller and cycle time stays the
same throughput will get smaller
okay so the one thing we can control
is the amount of work we currently have
on our plate
and that's the thing that we need to
reduce
if you want to know all the math behind
it go go read daniel's book
right that's probably the the the best
book if i was to pick anything to go
read
um is probably actionable ideal metrics
for predictability
right it's called an introduction and
it's got all the graphs that you see
kanban teams use right and it explains
exactly how they work what a good one
looks like what a bad one looks like
what to look for in the data aberrations
in there so that you can visualize and
see what's going on
and that's that's really important
having those information radiators being
able to visualize that work
so i think that's all we've got time for
i'm kind of seven minutes over i saw a
few people had it dropped off already um
i would definitely like some feedback
um and i think i know quite a lot of the
feedback is going to be around um
timing
this one is a lot harder to bring
together
a flow discussion is a lot harder to
bring together in a short period of time
um and
i will need to
pivot and experiment
differently
uh to try and
um get these things across a little bit
more easily what do you think gordon
yeah yeah
i was just trying
this oh it's the was the mural slow for
people
or i know there was a few people that um
struggled to get on the mural if you've
got a slow machine
mural mural kind of sucks
for sure if you have poor internet
access it takes a long time to load i do
know that this is quite a small mural
compared to the ones that i i normally
use for training um
but as it turns out i had i had too much
content anyway
how do you swim lanes come into the
picture
does that work with the priority thing
or is it more just a categorization like
how does that affect your work in
progress
so you're talking about the horizontal
swim lanes yeah yeah
uh so there's a really good video from
daniel vicanti about swim lanes on on
how
usually it's um
the swim lanes are
categories of service
i think is the phrase that they use
um so you might have an expedite
lane yeah and then a normal lane so most
work goes in the normal lane and you can
have and then you maybe limit the
expedite lane to one item
right so that one item flows faster
across the board uh but daniel vicanti
does a good talk on why that sucks and
makes everything worse
yeah i was
just
um
so
you you can either not break your whip
limits
or
there's nothing in in
in kanban
right in the kanban guide that says you
can't break your whip limits yeah sure
but i mean the the
the idea of it being there is because
it's a good idea not to break them yes
right it's definitely a good idea so
what what i normally see teams do is
they have their normal body of work and
then they have an expedite lane and the
ex by expedite lane has a whip limit of
one
okay so they're only adding one more
thing to their process
but
there's a massive negative impact like a
knock-on effect of that one thing
getting priority time instead of maybe
you normally pick the oldest thing
on your back clock
right um so so it's definitely a little
bit worrying
uh
to have have an expedite lane i've seen
it be successful with teams and i've
seen it be a complete car crash um so i
you
project managers like them because
it means they can prioritize stuff like
here's the p1 stuff and the rest
um but it tends to have a negative
impact on our ability to deliver
uh i'll need to look out i'll post the
the video from daniel and i'll try and
find it and post it on the on the on the
community page um
because i think that's going to be the
easiest way to get it out to folks
because the chat in this disappears when
we all disconnect so that so
i suppose maybe then a a good way in my
mind with what we said now a potential
good way to
have swim lanes is to
have them have them for the the value to
customer so it's just a visual
categorization
like yeah
i suppose if you're prioritizing stuff
from the top anyway you have value
generally at the top of that list right
and just because it's high value doesn't
mean you're going to do it
yeah yeah
right if you if you look at holistically
it's it's
this is gonna cost a million dollars to
deliver but the value is 500 000
yeah yeah it's not worth doing even
though 500 000 is a lot of value
yeah so so you need to balance the value
with the effort
or the risk as well the complexity of
delivering there's uh i i don't i'm not
going to open it just now um
there's a topic that i do want to cover
on value
um
[Music]
you know for for product ownership
determining value and determining what
or how we order our backlog and you need
to take into account value effort and
risk
right because the risk is going to come
into that too
yeah yeah
so um
it would be awesome if
folks if you've got ideas not just new
ideas to try but topics you want to
cover um i hadn't decided yet on what
the next session is going to be in two
weeks obviously i need to work on timing
right that's going to have less less
content
more discussion um
but
what are the topics michelle if you were
if you were coming back in two weeks
what topic would you like to
cover i
i want to understand better about kanban
and flow because i don't have any
background knowledge about these things
so
i've got the practice from the exercise
but i haven't really got the theory yet
yeah yeah i i totally if you if you read
the kanban guy for scrum teams and the
kanban guide
are your teams doing scrum
are you are your teams doing strong yeah
yeah kanban guys for scrum teams then um
is is what i would recommend
and that's a good place to start so it's
a it's a short
i think it's like a as a 12-page guide
just like slightly scrum guide but
here's a an addendum for the scrum guide
that says how you introduce the combat
ideas um
it's very difficult to cover
the kanban theory
in in the period of time that we have
here um i do i do an exercise with teams
as part of the kanban training um with
the the
we play the get kanban
game
um i don't know if you've seen that
board game but there's an actual there's
a physical board game i have copies of
it here and but there's also a digital
version but it takes about two hours to
just to play the game and then probably
takes two hours to do the debrief
afterwards
um so i have i have done that for
just that part for teams before for for
companies
um
and that that can be super valuable in
just understanding that flow of work um
but i can certainly we can have a chat
about the
the theory
um but it's definitely a lot i
definitely recommend the the material
that i put in the
notes there
but i totally get it michelle at this
the lean flows this is the real the real
struggle that we have
as an industry
is that velocity and story points is
easy but useless
right the kanban metrics are awesome but
super hard to understand super hard to
to implement and super hard to get value
from because they take a lot of effort
and brain power to interpret and
understand and collect and change the
way you do things
that that's that's i think going to be
the bit the next big struggle
uh for for teams and organizations is
that the canva metrics are awesome but
they're super hard for people to
understand
and they're counter-intuitive to
people's traditional understanding of
how work works
right
michelle i've got this other these five
projects i need you to show progress on
all five of these projects at once
right and that's that's so dumping all
this
whip on top of you uh
is not gonna help you deliver stuff
faster it's gonna help you deliver stuff
slower um but
if we were doing boring repetitive stuff
it might you know we might be able to
make progress on it but it just it's
slow there's a really i'll post it in
the the the the community there's a
video that demonstrates that uh the the
the the downtime for switching process
perfectly i'll post that one as well
that's a really good one
so i'll post that because i saw michelle
you joined the community thing i think i
saw
um so i do encourage i'm i'm switching
over to a different system i was running
everything in microsoft teams
uh but microsoft team sucks for people
engaging with it it's just uh not great
for that so um i'm moving over to a
different tool i can't even remember
what it's called uh but it look it's
community.nkd
i have a link on my website and you
should be able to just go join
um
and i'm going to start adding a bunch of
content in there and hopefully we can
get some conversations going in there
michelle
right if so if you have questions post
them in there and i can if you've got
specific questions like you've read the
kanban guide and you're like what the
hell is this martin right i can we can
either
maybe something in the chat or we can
have a separate call and maybe just
invite a few people and have a
conversation
does that sound good thank you yeah
great thank you yeah
totally any time same with you gordon
and ev everybody else on the call if
uh if you want to talk about something
you can ping me on the
uh um the community dot nkd agility.com
and we can either set up a call have a
chat uh
do it in the text i can post some videos
whatever helps us get to the better
learning
okay
so i have not decided what i'm going to
do in two weeks i saw some people asking
for
um
oh somebody's asking really important
question for me when's the next psk
class
um
i actually can't remember i have
everything on
my website i have i just did my schedule
for the next six months
and i know there's a psk on there
somewhere um i've clicked the button to
load it
because my machine is doing a lot when's
my next psk it will be purple
29th of november at four half days
uh 8 30 a.m till 12
um gmt so
that's utc plus wha no gm
gmt that's back into utc
because the times change michelle
you know when you're coding up that
stuff is really hard
yeah
um last week of uh
yeah october isn't it yeah
so um
and i had to write the php that
calculates that on my website
not my proudest moment php's not fun
um
but
29th of november uh is the the psk class
then i have another one on the 7th of
march
next year so that's a little bit away
yes hello martin this is totally new to
me and
i am actually a change lead for an
organization that's just trying to
essentially get into agile right so
the first agile project they basically
use dsdm for all things yeah and now
they're they're realizing that
potentially the route that they might
have to go is
uh for like operational little changes
that might just be using kanban yep and
then for some other big very digital
web-based kind of projects they might
then be using scrum
so you know i really would need some
kind of i don't know what i say help or
some kind of way that i can get the team
to basically maybe attend a session or
whatever it is i can use to get this
this team working the way they shoot
because it's obviously a very
traditional and headstrong environment
in terms of
they're not understanding the power of
agile in particular you know you know
scrum or canvas i don't know whether
there's any
ways of helping or what else can i do to
basically get these people going
so the the the thing with kanban right
is it's a strategy to optimize the flow
of work through any system okay
so you can use it regardless of what
you're doing
whatever it is you're doing
you can use kanban to help you get
better at it it's just a strategy
so you just start you don't even need to
mention kanban to them you just have to
start with
what i usually do is i do something
called a board design exercise with
teams and i basically i just use mural
right because it's ultimately editable
and
let's build up build a board decide when
work starts when it finishes what are
the columns we're going to have why do
things move through the columns and just
get them to write that down it's like
it's like a working agreement
right you find that most teams
lose a huge amount of time because
they're all doing something different
every team member doesn't have the same
understanding of how we're going to do
stuff
and that creates conflict and friction
within the team that results in loss of
time and loss of effectiveness so at
least
getting that visualization
of your your your workflow and defining
your workflow or your explicit policies
for how you're going to do stuff but you
don't tell them what their policies
should be you get the team to come up
with them
because the team has to own them
build those things do do that type of
workshop with them
that's the first stage then the next
stage is actively managing the work look
at that visualization you've created you
can build boards in jira you can build
boards in azure devops and there are
many other tools out there uh
canva eyes
that you can just build a board in and
then we use we use it as your devops
that's what we use okay
that makes gordon and i happy yeah our
planner as well um pl
planner is not the most awesome tool but
it does do the job same as trello you
can use trello as well um but having
that visualization of work and as your
devops will let you set up the columns
and have have
set up the whip limits set up the the
definite they call it the definition of
done for each column right why what are
the explicit policies for each column
and why things move between the columns
if i have that information explicit and
then start tweaking it a little bit at a
time yeah github projects v2 um is that
even like can we use that yet garden
you're on mute my friend you need one of
these little green lights that i've got
i think i was not on mute and then i
clicked mute to talk
so i think it's available for um
public
public orgs at the moment
either that also in
beta
what's it called i know that github
yeah get up projects v2 i think it is
because it came with issues v2
if i go look at my org it will tell me
maybe give me some more info info there
well i guess lots of people don't don't
care i'm interested in that because i
have a project on i have many projects
on github and
i want to know how to enable
those
features
are they just enabled or do i have to go
do something
um so it's in beta at the moment i'm
assuming it's private uh beta so
yeah probably
probably have to email somebody
i don't know who you can
he can get hold of that yeah yeah uh
i'll email myself
yeah i mean i'll i'll take a look if i
can see anything that sort of
i mean
if you look at the i suppose let's go
straight to issues feedback um so maybe
projects is part of issues or at least
lumped with it yeah so dennis is just
saying that he really likes the delivery
plans feature that they've added in
azure devops and i do too it does
dependency management as well um it's
pretty awesome
uh
i've been using that a lot with some of
my customers and they're really enjoying
using it um so i i work with a number of
organizations around the world
uk
ghana nigeria
where else gordon
well pretty much pretty much everywhere
i think i've worked in 36 countries in
the last 10 years
um usually about 16 countries a year
and that was before
i wasn't allowed to fly anywhere
now it's probably more because people
just message me
yeah i mean you said
at summit you say what you're you're
home two weeks three weeks of the year
so you didn't buy a car because it was
pointing yeah i didn't i before lockdown
i have a car now
but i didn't i didn't own a car before
lockdown because i it
i wasn't here long enough i was only
here at the weekend like what it was so
sometimes it worked out as one day
garden from the perspective of a rental
car
so so i i just did i just did the rental
car thing um
so i rented a car when i was at home
that's how that's how much i was
traveling
but uh yeah now not so much and quite
enjoying it and i get to spend more time
with customers and i get to do things
like this
with uh with folks that i wasn't able to
do before
well thank you everybody for uh the
feedback i am perfectly happy to hang
out we are like 26 minutes over i'm
perfectly happy to hang out if there's
more questions
if you want to go please go if you
provided feedback
awesome um i will set up the session for
uh the the the next one in two weeks
um i want to go back to the original
time but i need to look at my my magic
book
garden i've got an actual diary
physical diary yeah i have to look out i
moved
i moved to one of those
a couple of months back yeah
when you're tracking when technology
can't track all the uh to do's that you
have to do because it's
the best knowledge is too fragmented
across all the different companies i
work with so i have everything written
in my book that's my single source of
truth
um but i'm gonna um
i'll post in
well i'll do the usual post on linkedin
but i'll also add it to
uh um
this new community portal i've created
uh once i get it uh
set well once i've decided what it is
we're going to do
victoria did you have a question
do
it's around the kanban principles
combined practices
yeah i think as a principal some
practices yeah so sometimes you read
online and then it says the
principles are six
and then some say four yeah and then the
practices some also say four
and some say six and
i am actually very confused right now
totally so i i would in
um
there's the kanban guide for scrum teams
which lists four things
okay
because it's got to work with scrum
and then there's the
the
kanban guide
which lists three things
three three x four practices
what you find is
there's there's kanban
and then there's the kanban method
which is a named framework
from uh
david anderson and that ha i can't
remember how many practices that has
does that have 16 no i don't think it's
that six
i don't i don't remember i'm not a
follower of uh uh david's work um
but uh there's there's they have a
bunch maybe that's where the six comes
from right that's the sixth four and the
three and then we've got it but um what
what they're trying to do with the
kanban guide is get down to the core
must-have practices
lots of people use other practices just
like when we're doing scrum
right we also we also use
burn down charts
but burn down charts are not part of
scrum they're just an extra thing that
people do
um
and just like gordon and i had the
discussion about things moving across
the board from left to right right
that's how it's right yeah that's a
normal thing that kanban teams do but
it's not part of the core we don't have
to have that
to be doing kanban
um
so so i i think
go to the kanban guide and the kanban
guide for scrum teams depending on
whether you're doing scrum or not
look there for the core practices and
then there are other practices you can
bring in from any other place you like
right right right right okay but that
that's definitely
victoria i might do
i'm going to take a note
um
uh
kanban v's
psk versus pk yeah
um i i will do a post on the
um community group with
a a discussion around that just to to
help help you out with that just to
focus on it okay
so chef thank you so much just i guess
why why is that an extra one in the
psk versus pk
professional camera and versus
professional camera scrum why is there
an extra practice core practice
and then if you say if you if you post
on that and add the where you found the
six
maybe we can start a discussion
yeah okay we can just start discussion
around well why is there six over here
and okay where do they come from
yeah
everybody does something different
there's no right or wrong way to do
almost anything
um everybody does their own thing and
we've got to figure out what works well
for us and what doesn't
that's what it is
empirical process control
um
so i guess that's a good segue to to
wrap up 31 minutes over that's better
this time gordon i think we were 45
minutes over last time
but now we're in the networking side
networking is when everyone goes home
right yeah exactly
when the pub kicks you out
yeah we can't we can't go to the pub
anymore well we can probably go to the
pub again but i i don't know none of my
none of my friends
go to my local pub
because all of all of my friends are in
uh uh south south africa like uh gordon
or ghana like victoria
um
anna where where are you in the world
estonia estonia see this is no macedonia
balkan macedonia ah
so
we we can't just all go to the bob
garden
well as i said every time we go to mvp
summit it's like it's a very tiring week
but it's the one week a year where i see
all my friends like
i know so we'll we'll maybe need to have
a have a have a online
i like rum rather than beer but some
kind of
uh yeah
some kind of beer thing going on
online cocktail yes dennis some kind of
online
cocktail session
that would be good
although i'd we we
won't be able to live stream it because
we might say thanks
we'll talk about our companies
okay well i think i think we should wrap
it up um
i definitely see the feedback on time
management uh i need to i need to work
on that this was the first time i'd
really run this session
in this format definitely needs a lot of
work i agree
um
and we'll suppose we'll we'll see what
happens next week okay
thank you very much everybody for coming
along
[Music]
you