agile training is great for
um
hard testing you know getting that
knowledge into the business getting that
knowledge into a large group of people
um especially if I've done gigs where
you train everybody in the company in in
the agile Practice season and nobody can
say they didn't understand what that
thing was right
um but agile Consulting is also
generally hard hitting right because
you're you've got a very time limited
nature of that
um but it's about targeting specific
things that the consultant identifies is
not going well or opportunities for
improvement within your business so
that's the main difference between
between training and Consulting