what does your dream and your Consulting
week look like
it looks pretty busy I think right so
the the there's there's two
when when I'm Consulting with a customer
there's there's multiple work streams
going on right
there's work streams where you're you're
liaising with leadership
and
trying to encourage the larger changes
that maybe need to happen but there's
also the the day-to-day work of
um um sitting in with with teams in
helping them get suggestions right
because that's the difference between
coaching and Consulting is coaching
believes that the customer already knows
the answer
um and Consulting doesn't assume that
they already know the answer we're gonna
as a consultant I'm going to I'm going
to make a suggestion right well maybe
maybe we should we should monitor the
flow of work have you been collecting
these metrics right uh maybe we can
figure that out here's some tools that
you might use with the tools you've got
in order to to understand and visualize
more let's try that right so you're
making more proactive and directing
suggestions based on long experience and
for me the most awesome week is a week
where I'm able to help as many people in
the organization as possible while still
continuing to make progress on the
overall strategic initiatives right
because ultimately strategic initiatives
are long term and don't help people
day-to-day
um so I really enjoy
working with teams
um perhaps sitting in on some of their
their events right it could just be a
daily you know fly on the wall I'm not
gonna interrupt them I'm not going to
make suggestions during those events
but I'm going to have a have a chat with
them afterwards perhaps just with the
scrum Master right because it's it's
kind of there I don't want to step on
their toes either
um but help give them advice Point them
in directions and help them see the gaps
maybe in what the team's understanding
and their knowledge and how they can
perhaps fulfill them and how they can
fill their own gaps so for for me
constantly engaging with teams while
also dealing with
um the long-term leadership and
strategic stuff is probably probably my
dream week as a as a agile consultant
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility