there are three core principles of caman
to keep it really simple there's
defining and visualizing your workflow
that's like creating your rule book as a
team how are you going to function what
does your system look like right so
defining and visualizing a workflow the
second core principle is to actively
manage the items in the workflow so now
that you can see them you can see what's
going on you have a visualization you're
going to actively take action so you're
not just going to passively look at it
actively take action and then the third
principle is improving your workflow you
want to make changes to the workflow in
order to make things a little bit better
to make things flow better through your
system