why isn't the scrum Master given any
real power or authority in the scrum
guide was thinking behind that
so but they are they are given they're
given accountability over the
effectiveness of the team
in in scrum the product owner isn't
really given any power or authority
apart from the accountability for
maximizing the value of the work done
right the the developers aren't giving
in giving any Authority apart from
um
um maximizing the the the the quality of
the product that they're working with so
the scrum master has the same type of uh
accountability assigned to them that the
the they need to figure out without That
explicit Authority
how to
create
an environment within which the scrum
team can be as effective as possible
um and that generally is the way that
most things happen within organizations
right most things in organizations don't
happen through authority authority is
used for escalation right something
screwed escalated up somebody says make
this Choice doesn't matter it's the
right one or not but go this way right
that's that escalation point but a scrum
Master is a leader right and leaders
while in some context yes leaders get
Authority and they may have authority as
well but people need to choose to follow
them
people you need people to want
to do the things that the scrum Master
is suggesting because they're helping
because people see value in the things
that they're doing
and that takes real skill
right it's not you as a scrum Master you
need to and you need to understand the
processes practices and tools right what
is it that the teams that you're working
with are actually doing right what's
their their context of their technical
environment what's the context of the
business environment because you're
going to be helping the product owner
and what's the context of the
organization as a whole and figure out
how do I Inc what can I do to increase
the effectiveness of the teams going
forward
so while they don't necessarily have any
real power or authority
they can gain That Power Authority
through people looking to them uh um for
not for answers that's the wrong way to
think about it
for for for guidance for they're
providing value to people if you provide
value to me I'm going to listen to the
things that you have to say because I've
listened to you in the past you provided
me with value I got a success out of it
therefore if if I'm unsure or I need
more information I'm going to perhaps
come to you because I respect you I
respect your opinion I respect the
information that you have
um I respect the value you provide me
and that's how a scrum Master makes
changes in an organization
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility