so the question is why is uh Joanna a
great teacher for the professional agile
leadership class and I think
there's there's two aspects that I think
uh really make it perfect for her uh one
is her her absolute enthusiasm for the
for the class
um I've heard her say a number of times
that this is her favorite class to teach
right and that sort of thing really
comes across when you're when you're
engaging with people because the
questions are just so interesting I love
this class as well the questions are
just so interesting the answers are
really interesting the type of people
that come to the agile leadership class
if especially for for Joanna and I as
also Consultants right it's the type of
people that we're trying to talk to all
the time inside of organizations
um and because that leads to the second
reason she's so awesome
um because she's got a a a swathe of
experience and engaging with
organizations
um at various levels trying to help them
understand agile practices add your lean
all the all the flavors right
um she's she's very experienced in
having those conversations with
leadership with managers with people who
are who are playing at that level
um and and those conversations are just
so much fun because convincing somebody
in a leadership position
um to move towards agility or the they
get more value by pushing responsibility
down
convincing one of those people helps
lots of people and that's I think where
where she gets a lot of her passion from
in that class
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility