so the first major benefit is that depth
of learning that you'll get because
you've got more application
what do I mean by this
there's a weird thing that happened
during the covered lockdowns when kids
were homeschooling
suddenly
instead of being at school learning
maths with a teacher who knew the maths
the kids were at home learning maths
with their parents doing maths that they
hadn't done for 30 years
so the first thing the kids have to do
is teach their parents how to do that
kind of maths
guess what the kids learned their maths
better because they weren't just trying
to learn it they were learning it in it
to enable them to teach people about it
and then this concept of learning
together which really helps so you end
up with a much deeper level of learning
when you're applying the skills as you
learn the skills when you can see that
Journey coming together so there's that
real depth of learning that you really
get and you can get no other way than in
application of things
the second thing is
practical
experimental learning that complement
what they're doing in their real life so
while it's great to go through exercises
in class and it's great to use metaphors
to create your stories it's great to use
pre-prepared exercises that allow you to
come out of your context to learn things
this allows you to do that and then take
them back directly into your real
context
So you you're actually seeing it work
where you are rather than just work in a
classroom setting
so this this makes it real it makes it
something tangible it makes it something
that helps them do their job better
while they're doing their job
the third one what is the cohort setting
by doing this as a group of people
either in the same company or it
actually ideally in this in different
organizations in a public class setting
you're bringing different Knowledge from
different experience from different
Industries and and different thoughts of
different organizations you're getting
to help each other and understand more
about
what's going on in the world you get
this idea of I am not alone it's not
just me with these struggles it's not
just me trying to fight against these
parts of the organization
because I think everyone forgets this
the when you go and do scrum
it's different to what traditionally
organizations have done and
organizations have spent years and
decades evolving to be fit for purpose
for how they already do things so when
you start doing scrum you'll find
yourself rubbing up against things like
um legal teams like um the way Human
Resources teams interact with people
you'll find all of these support
structures that are the you know pmo
offices is another classic one where
they're all set up to deal with how we
currently do things but now we're doing
things differently that's hard so when
it's not just you when you can see other
people and pitfalls that they're having
in their organization and you can talk
to them about ways of overcoming it and
the way they've overcome it in their
organization and bring that back that's
really really valuable and it's giving
you a really wide community of practice
with a really wide set of experiences
but it's really hard to set up a
community of practice because any good
team has to go through some stuff to get
to be a good team you know you can be
all right when things are nice but if
you look at even any sports team they
only get to be great if you've gone
through some stuff together to allow you
to merge so this is giving you the group
of people and it's giving you the stuff
you've got to go through together
and talk and make yourself vulnerable
but at the same time get that safe space
where you can get good help
why should that stop with a class
I'd be very disappointed if it did I'll
be honest so I think the cohort element
would be the third great benefit