[Music]
i'm jb brown the nordstrom innovation
lab manager and this is the lab
we work on one week experiments somebody
will have an idea and we'll find a way
to figure out how to prove if the idea
is going to work and this week the
innovation lab is going to be building
an ipad app with customer feedback as we
go through the week we wanted to work in
the store to make sure that we were
getting customer feedback as we worked
so that we were never working on
anything that wasn't valued by the
customer and only doing things that are
delivering value so we'll be building a
feature and testing it until we get to
the point where we have something that's
good enough that we can just leave and
leave the ipad app behind and have this
new thing that customers can use
this is the world's first flash build
it's a flash mob where a software team
shows up it builds an application in a
surprise location this is the nordstrom
innovation lab and we're at the flagship
store in downtown seattle right now the
team is just setting up their equipment
to get started we're going to build an
ipad app that helps customers pick the
best pair of sunglasses for them we
really don't know what the features are
yet we're going to use customer feedback
as we go along throughout the day and
the rest of the week in order to build
the best thing so the next thing we're
going to do is a user story map so we're
going to sit here and together outline
all the steps the customer would take
and actually even beforehand how they
buy sunglasses like what are the
different things that they might do and
how that process might change if we have
this application and we'll actually dig
into what we have to build in order to
support that process so now that we've
done a card mapping we're going to do a
paper prototype and this is something
that we commonly do in the innovation
lab it's a great way to
show what we'd like to do in a rough
prototype that we can easily throw out
change alter based on feedback from the
customers i'll continue building
individual paper slides and our user
experience specialist patel will bring
the prototype to a customer and say okay
i have this app and this is a paper
version i'd like you to kind of use it
like you would normally use an app and
you can press things interact with them
and then she'll change out the pages
based on how the customer uses it so
it's a similar experience to the ipad
only
an analog version
so it's day two and we have our first
working prototype of this app and how it
works is i take my first pair of
sunglasses put it on
take a picture all right and then i want
to compare it to this other pair i've
got right here
get these on
take another picture i can just hold
these up like this and see which one i
like better well telling kim having
talking to people and doing paper
prototypes we've been coding building an
ipad we take a stab at something we look
at the paper prototypes they can't put
together
we might take one at a time usually we
come to the board and
we grab the most important feature and
we started implementing it the really
cool thing with this flash build is that
we have actual real customers just today
we delivered four or five different
separate features and i deliver it swap
the ipad with tell she'd go and talk to
a customer and 10 minutes later i had
feedback from real customers about this
thing that i delivered and it changed
how we did the next thing and it's been
really really great watching day to day
what they've been doing the team to get
all the feedback from the sales people
the feedback the sales people gather
from the customers and it's a really
interesting process to kind of come in
on tuesday we had no idea what this
would look like there's an idea that
somebody had to say people take a lot of
pictures themselves with the sunglasses
it'd be cool if we could show them side
by side to help them make the process
better and that was the idea that was it
they came in they had nothing built and
they've been building this literally on
the spot throughout each day and by now
we actually have an app a functioning
app that they can go through it's very
intuitive to help look at themselves and
make the
sunglass selection process easier which
is pretty cool to watch so yesterday the
sunglass buyer for nordstrom came down
to check out our progress and she
happened to put on polarized glasses and
then held up the ipad in portrait view
and was surprised that she couldn't see
anything because it was black we figured
out the polarization of the ipad running
up and down and the polarization of the
glasses running vertical cancel each
other out you don't see anything but if
you turn the ipad to landscape you see
perfectly fine because the polarization
of the two items line up and it's okay
so it was pretty good find to be in the
store and she just happened to put on
polarized glasses and so today first
thing we're going to do is switch it to
a landscape design and then lock in the
aspect ratio of the ipad so customers
and sales people just naturally pick it
up and use it in landscape and not try
and go to portrait okay so i'm going to
show you what we've been working on the
last five days we've added quite a few
features over the week you take a
picture multiple pictures of the
customer and then you can pull them up
and tap the first one you can see it
larger and then tap the second and do a
side-by-side comparison of each glass
next to each other we also added a
feature where you can rename the picture
because we heard from sales people if a
customer is trying on quite a lot of
glasses it's helpful to be able to know
what order they were taken in and also
rename if you want with the brand or
some distinguishing feature about the
glass another feature we added was the
ability to zoom you can zoom in and
really get a good detailed look at the
frames side by side also to see one of
the pictures larger if you want to just
better view of one frame
you can flip the camera view as well
face it forward so the sales person
could take a picture of it like this or
you can flip the camera
like so
take a picture
uh yourself facing forward and then at
the end of it all we have a button
called new customer which just erases
all of the images and allows the
salesperson to start with a new customer
we're just trying to put the final
touches on the app tell talk to a lot of
users and they said that when we went
into the compare view it was unclear
where the pictures were coming from and
which picture was which so the animation
here is trying to solve that problem
make it a little more clear what's going
on one of the challenges with software
is when are you done right and i think
the answer is really it depends on how
much time you have
at least the most important things got
done so this was time box to a week and
we did a week's worth of work and it
seems like what we have now is something
that makes customers happy and addresses
the main problems and something that we
can track we have metrics on so
i think we're going to call that a day
the application has developed so far
everything's finished everything that
we've asked for and even the little
roadblocks and glitches that we kind of
stumbled across as we use the app during
the week has been solved i think that
it's going to be really easy to be able
to implement into our sale and i think
that we're going to find a lot of
success with application whether it's
via a selling tool for us or if it goes
public into a downloadable format
whatever happens i think this was
generally quite a success