if you're struggling with scope creep
it's probably because you're
using uh practices and philosophies that
were developed within the context of low
variance right very little changes all
the time so you can create a plan you
can create your your your Gant chart you
can run the plan and that's how you're
managing risk but when your your your
variance the difference between what you
think's going to happen and what
actually happens is bigger than what you
thought in the first place more than 50%
variance those tools no longer work and
we start having problems with scope
creep right it it we start to not be in
control of what's going on and that
shift
towards product delivery a product
operating model is that move
away from those old ideas of scope and
deadlines right there's there's other
tools that we use to have the same
outcome right because the outcome you're
looking for is usable working product in
the hands of your customers so that
you're delivering value right maximizing
the value of that
item
but those are those old tools are no
longer working for us if if you're
having a conversation about scope creep
then we're probably having The Wrong
conversation because it needs to be okay
for the scope to change because the
market doesn't stay still if you're
delivering a product into your
organization or into a market right
whether it's B2B or b2c or internal then
the ecosystem within which you're
delivering that product is changing over
time it's not only changing over time
continuously but that means that what
what you need is changing continuously
which means that what you have to do is
changing continuously and it might even
change in response to something you show
the stakeholders right you show the
customers you show the users you show
them a capability and they're like oh
yeah that's awesome don't spend any more
time on that this is the next most
important thing and suddenly we're
shifting Direction and maybe there's a
hundred things in your in your list of
things to do
that you know don't need right so that
scope creep the good way where we have
less scope to deal with but also that
you might show them something and
they're like oh that's not not what I
want I need something completely
different and suddenly you've got a
whole bunch of additional
work that e and flow of what needs to
be is the reason that agile was created
right so the lean movement came out of
that story of EB and flow of delivering
products right lean Toyota system and
agile was the adaptation of that story
Into the context of software delivery
which is which is slightly different
right it's much easier to change
software it's much easier to iterate on
software you can ship a new it's
difficult to ship a new car to the same
Customer because you you want to change
something than it is to do it for for
software so that this idea if we want to
be on time and on
budget then we need to consider scope to
be not the thing we're looking for we're
looking for Value the thing we're
focusing on is delivering value to our
customers and if we're delivering value
we're doing the right thing and we
manage budget and time differently
within the context of agile so if we
have a clear product vision a clear
Direction on where we're going and a
welldefined PCT backlog that we know is
going to change constantly then we can
much more effectively plan what we're
doing and change direction as needed
without worrying about scope