so the first in our series of harbingers
of the agile
apocalypse um is is really about the
Antichrist what what is the
Antichrist of um agile and I think um if
you've been following me at all you'll
know exactly what my answer is going to
be um and that's that um Alpha
organizational structure the traditional
management structure in
organizations um that create an
environments within which you have uh uh
that that steering from the top right so
you've got the the market at the bottom
where we're interacting directly between
the people in the company and the
customers and then you've got this
hierarchy up the organization to
somebody who's the decision maker um or
makes decisions or needs approval for
something or whatever that is that's one
of the facets of the the alpha
organization where
um that type
of model organizational model um
inhibits the ability of the organization
to move towards agility um you you can
absolutely get little wins right you can
make things a little bit better you can
improve your time to Market you can
improve um the ability of the teams to
deliver right so a team could be doing
continuous
delivery um you can you can do all of
those
things to make the team as effective as
possible but
ultimately within that traditional
organizational structure you're not
going to be able to have a product owner
who decides what it is we're working on
that looks at Market looks at budget
engages with customers
um decides what and when to release um
decides what we're going to build where
are we going to invest money in this
product where are we not going to invest
money what's our pricing strategy for
our product those are all things that
are often decided far higher up the
organization so as organizations flow
from uh um the alpha model of of top-
down commanding control I mean it's not
it's commanding controls oversimplifying
it right but that top down uh uh uh uh
steering based style
towards a more uh uh beta
democratized uh
self-organizing um format more of a sale
based structure that is able to interact
directly with the market as they move
towards that you'll start to see more
and more benefits in the organization
but what happens in most organizations
is the the the the Antichrist blocks it
this Alpha topown organization where uh
somebody says uh no I'm not going to
approve that or um you need to get my
approval for all of those things or um I
don't know any of these things that just
get in the way and mean that the
organization never crosses that line and
starts its Journey towards uh a
decentralization right they never start
making that Journey towards
decentralization because we work this
way this is our hierarchy this is how we
do things um and that is the killer to
Agile in your
organization thanks for watching the
video If you enjoyed it please like
follow And subscribe I always reply to
comments and if you want to have a chat
about this or anything else agile scrum
or devops then please book a coffee with
me through naked agility