the applying scaling portfolio cbank
class is really about how do we look at
our system no longer at the team level
and but how do we look at our system at
the at the organization level at the
program level um and what how how do we
then
understand analyze the work and create
create effective strategies for enabling
that flow of of uh uh uh portfolio items
through our system to increase the
amount of value that we deliver for our
products to to to increase
predictability so that we can um have a
better understanding of which things are
likely success to be successful which
things we need to cut our losses on um
which things need to be changed
drastically in order to to to result in
that value acrel and so it really
focuses at at at for heads of
departments so agile coaches uh project
managers development leads uh high level
product owners scrum Masters and product
managers that are trying to deliver lots
of things um that may be competing
things into production um and they need
to to increase the flow through the
system right we want to deliver um more
stuff more quickly we want to get faster
and more predictable um at delivery and
those are all things that we're going to
talk about in the applying scaled
portfolio cbang class so th this course
will help
[Music]
um leaders in
organizations understand the current
flow through their system and ask more
interesting questions about what they
can do differently to improve the flow
and predictability through the system um
so whatever your your your system is at
that level how do you understand what is
going on in portfolio and increase that
flow of delivery of work for the
business and increased predictability if
you want to have a discussion about your
unique needs or situation then please
book a call or visit us at naked agility
tocom uh we also have our immersive and
traditional public classes on our
website and would' love to hear from you