if you're hiring an agile coach not only
do they need to be able to engage and
gain credibility with the technical
folks they also need to be able to
engage and gain credibility with
management and leadership in your
organization this means that they need
deep technical understanding of business
uh particularly within your context so
if you're a financial organization
you're going to want an agile coach who
understands uh the financial
ramifications in business of your
organization if you're a tech company
then they need to understand the
business of tech so that they can more
effectively help leadership and
management be more agile