okay so the question is why why did I
Embrace agile over traditional project
management practices when I was a
developer
um
I don't think well I don't think I did
while I was a developer
I think the reason I picked
agile and agile practices was because as
a developer I was always subjected to
the traditional project management
practices
um I'd worked through that I worked at
Merrill Lynch
I worked for a number of design agencies
I worked for a generator uh
manufacturer and and rental company and
in all of those cases they approached
the projects in quite a similar fashion
probably the most Progressive was the
was the generator company which is weird
but it's because the boss was awesome
um and that
damaged me I think I I I definitely felt
like
these people didn't know what they were
talking about didn't understand what
we're actually doing it didn't feel like
they even gave a crap
um and then as I started to do more
devops so I started to migrate from
development into the devops space so not
even the agile space it's the other side
of uh agility from the technical side
um I started to get more engaged in the
idea that yeah devops is devops is great
but a lot of devops is about tools I
know people might dispute that but a lot
of devops is about tools and a lot of
devops in the world and they're in the
real world is about tools
and I started to realize more and more
that it's not the tools that solve the
problem it's the people that solve the
problem and it's not the tools that are
the problem it's often the people that
are the problem right because time and
time again I was using I did a lot of
migrations to Azure devops for customers
so moving them from whatever they were
doing before to Azure devops and they
wanted to do the same stupid stuff that
they did with their old tool with Azure
devops and I had to try and explain to
them that that so the reason this tool
is actually a problem is not because the
tool is a problem it's because of the
way you're using the tool and a lot of
them did it deliberately right they're
like yeah we've totally messed up this
tool and we really want a clean slate to
go into this new thing
um and then we don't have all the
baggage and I'm like yeah but you're
bringing this baggage in that baggage in
this other baggage and that's where you
start talking to people you start
convincing people to start thinking
about working in different ways to
simplifying their process to reducing
levels of Bureau
custom fields and rules oh my goodness
me
um if anybody's uh used jira as your
devops of old
um custom fields and rules of the bane
of your life
um and trying to go back back to
defaults right do you actually need that
thing does it actually add value does it
bring you Joy right the the the the you
know only have uh those those fields
those rules that you absolutely have to
have to do business and you don't really
want anything else
so
um my my move was through that technical
going into the high level Technical and
then kind of sideways into agility and
actually
um
um went to Australia to do the the the
um the PSD the beta for the old PSD
class from Richard Hunt housing
um and that that was where I got
introduced to scrum
um because in order to be a PSD trainer
I had to take a scrub class
um and I I just totally totally made
sense right it just made sense it it fit
the ideas solved the problems that I was
or enabled the problems to be solved
that I'd been looking at my entire
software engineering career and I wanted
to help other people do those things
better because I saw in all the
customers that I'd had that this would
start to solve their problems too
um but I still came in for the next
probably five years with a devops Focus
but as soon as you come in remember you
come in with one Focus because the
customer says we need some devops help
and then you like okay you say you need
some devops help but actually actually
you you need to fix this problem over
here which is about people in
organization and bureaucracy and how you
organize your business in order to
maximize the value they create and the
engineers can take care of this devopsy
stuff over here you get smart people
right they're just constrained and
aren't able to actually do things and I
think that freeing nature of of agility
is what what kind of Drew me to it
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility