oh so if a scrum master was battling
with their team
would you recommend an APS Workshop or
an agile consultant
I may recommend a new scrum Master right
because if the scrum Master is battling
with the team that doesn't even make
sense they're there to help the team be
effective they're part of the team
um if a whole team is battling with them
that then that makes them the [ __ ]
right I think I think it does
um I guess it would be circumstantial
but that's how I feel
um
with an APS Workshop or an agile
consultant be better
what I tend to do as an agile consultant
is is more of a coach the coach right so
I'm I'm happy to be there observe the
team
maybe give the whole team advice if
that's what's asked for
um but I would tend to focus on
um observing and then coaching the scrum
master and if the scrum Master is
battling the team maybe that's not going
to be effective right
um
so probably it depends what the scrum
Master is battling the team over so if
the scum Master is battling the team
um
like the team I I we we
the team are objecting to doing things
that could potentially benefit them it's
kind of let the team decide it's it's
meant to be a democracy democratized
process not a dictatorship so the scrum
Master can't dictate anything but
perhaps there's some value in helping
the team understand
more about what
scrum for example has to offer
so that they have more ammunition to
make a determination and perhaps they'll
make a different determination right
because if the team decides not to do
scrum
they probably shouldn't be doing scrum
right because if you enforce it they're
not going to like it they're going to
push back against it and you're not
going to have a good time it needs to be
a a a a
um a chosen thing so so what what I
might suggest is yes an APS workshop and
treat it as a workshop treat it as
having having fun right from their
perspective
um but also from from from my
perspective they're all going to bring
the things the reasons why scrum can't
work for them
so it's almost like a hybrid that would
for me would be a hybrid situation where
I'm going to run an APS where I may run
an APS Workshop
but I'm going to treat it very much as a
Consulting gig that they do want some
answers right they don't necessarily
just want to understand APS they want to
understand EPS within the context of
their company and their problems and
their issues because there's no point in
just teaching them scrum if they're
vehemently opposed to the idea of
anything anything like that or anything
being imposed upon them so
um probably approach it from that
perspective that that we're going to use
we're going to use the aps curriculum as
a way to shape the conversation and hit
all of the things that we need to hit
but even at the end at the end of the
aps I've mentioned this a couple of
times because I I just love this this
feature of the aps is after we've had
those conversations right whether it's a
standard APS where I've got a bunch of
public students and we teach the class
they learn a bunch of stuff about scrum
but we don't necessarily dive too much
into their individual context or if it's
a a private gig like the one that we're
describing here where we're able to
spend as much time as we need on their
stuff as well and understanding that
link because it matters to everybody in
the room at the end of the class we have
this we have this this session where
um we dive into what should you do right
there's there's a number of little
workshops
um that I can run with the group that's
in the room that depends on what the
group is and one of those is a kind of
getting started with scrum Workshop
um one of those is a a tune-up right
we're already doing scrum and we need to
tune up our process what should we look
at
um but we also first have a a kind of
set of questions to set them up and one
of those is should we use scrum
right and one of the questions is
what are the reasons we shouldn't use
scrum what are the reasons we should
what will happen if we don't change what
we're doing
because those are important questions
not for me to answer but for them to
answer for themselves
do they feel their current way of
working is actually working is actually
providing value to the customer if if if
not
what are they going to do to change
we've just talked for for four half days
about a bunch of tools that they could
use to help them change
are they going to try some of those
tools or do you want to try something
else if you think those tools won't work
what needs to change in your
organization in order for that to be
effective and I think uh that's probably
probably the way I would approach it a
kinda hybrids
APS with some agile Consulting in order
to help the team make better decisions
and you know when to I need to have a
long chat with the scrum Master if
they're battling the team right
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility