good now to you hello good now this is
riffing with Ryan I am Ryan Ericson
surprise surprise um if you didn't want
to see me this morning o too bad for you
um but if you did thank you and welcome
to be here today for an episode that we
have titled should companies take money
off the table why why why you ask is
this the topic because of the two
gentlemen I'm going to invite out of the
Penalty Box on stage had a little bit of
a reparte about this a couple weeks ago
we've been trying to arrange the session
for a little bit one of those gentlemen
I'm going to bring on stage now Martin
hinwood hello Martin hello how you doing
oh I'm just fantastic you know that
because I'm always fantastic um and the
second gentleman to bring on to the
stage for this conversation today is Mr
Michael cers hello Michael hello a
frequent partner and friend on this
particular show that we do here I do God
I keep calling it a we who is a we
anyway um so so
money I yeah I I know and and I have a
big huge deal with saying we we we like
we are not a Wei until I agree that I am
part of this Wii you get it um and
that's hey that's just me but um I would
I'll propose a couple things here one is
that Martin um actually I'm going to do
this one way Michael let's go first and
say just 10 words or so about who you
are what it is you do and where and
we'll go to Martin and then uh we'll
come back to Michael again and you can
give your your Riff to start us off so
without further Ado uh Michael give me
10 10 words about your
life uh oh 10 words okay that was
to okay so I'm a currently coo for one
of the pretty important Edge networking
things I've have my background in
everything it computers love to be full
stch developers been in edel
organizational development and I like to
get into a lot of
conversations write a lot of stuff and
yeah that's my life
there there you go all right 10 words
from
Martin well I am a um professional scrum
trainer uh professional campan trainer
and I've been a Microsoft MVP in devops
for the past 15 years I run my own
business H called naked agility um where
I do Agile devops Consulting coaching uh
uh helping helping people get better at
building software and
products perfect nice that's the 10
words okay Martin gets round one for
using less words than you did Michael so
sorry about that
um so to set the stage for for the
conversation again we talking about
money the post that you did a couple
weeks ago Michael um had some themes
around financial literacy
and general
again I'll I'll leave it there financial
literacy is that enough to to guide you
into your point of view on that
particular
topic Michael that that's
you oh that was my C good I didn't so so
I can bring the post up if you want but
it was it was um should should companies
take money off the table that was
that Alfie con Dan ping says you take
money off the table is beautiful and
then you you came in with a a not that
so exactly so uh there's uh one very
interesting proverb I picked up in my uh
student time and that's everything wor
doing is wor
overdoing so that is basically where we
get from uh so of course uh I know that
the original intent of Dan pink is uh to
say that uh I don't want people to be uh
worried about their
livelihood because it distracts them
from achieving the things that they're
setting out to achieve and that is not
something that uh we would like to have
in a company uh but of course uh I'm
taking this one a bit further and it's
also based a lot on uh investigation a
lot of experience in organizational
transformation organizational change
observing also from the good old times
of being a project maner manager or
system architect that uh the financial
conversation is usually very very
hard and friend of mine recently also
gave this example so you have this team
of developers they working in their
traditional way of working and
everybody's somehow happy the salaries
are paid everybody has a stable job
nobody needs to worry anything and uh so
they have this issue that they're doing
three release per year which is not even
once a quarter but every like three or
four months more like it and uh of
course they're always doing work but uh
then when the release comes first you
come the release packaging then comes uh
release testing the debugging preparing
the release release coordination all of
those kind of things and uh so does this
team have a problem yes or no and a team
somehow starts to argue yeah you know
what nowadays modern and uh cicd and we
should make the transition and what do
you think the manager understands oh the
Nerds want a new toy what does the
manager say no we've got serious work to
do so what they're failing is the commun
conversation about how much does this
process cost us so we're spending like
uh 60 days for a whole team just on the
release uh Management on the release
process every quarter or every four
months that is uh 60 days cost how much
let's just say $1,000 per developer per
day so 60,000 per developer you have a
team of 10 people we're talking 600,000
three times a year we're
talking over $2
million for what what do we get for that
what is the value we produce and that is
a kind of a different conversation and
yeah we would like to introduce
continuous delivery because it's a
better process because it's more modern
and it's kind of a conversation many
people are not able to lead and because
they have never
considered how much are we spending on
what and what is the returns that we are
getting because they do not have the
literacy to even think in those terms
and what I just told you is really
really really simple Mass one developer
one day 1,000 dollar 10 developers is
10,000 60 days is 600,000 there's no
magic to this it's not like you need to
have studied accounting or an MBA in
order to do this kind of thing but
people struggle to have this
conversation
because like I said the money for teis
has been taken off the table they are
happy we get a fixed salary can we can
live from this salary we can pay our
rent and where the money comes from or
where the money goes that's my manager's
problem but like that they are bringing
themselves into a situation where they
are unable to make the impact that they
need to make in order to do the best
possible
job all right we let that sit for a
moment thank you Michael Martin you had
a response to that in public I'll hang
you out there to when you go yeah
so so I I mean there's there's
absolutely nothing wrong um with what
what Michael said I think I think he is
correct that there is a a an
epidemic of organization people in
organizations that don't understand what
their time and their group time costs to
the business um costs to the customers
so they're making decisions and making
as as as you know Ryan Michael but every
developer every person in your
organization all the way up the chain
makes lots of micro decisions every day
within the context of what you know
their knowledge and expertise that they
don't go ask anybody but they make those
decisions and those decisions cost the
business money and are they making the
right decisions or are they making the
wrong ones and I fully agree that they
should be making those
decisions within the context of
understanding what it costs to do
business um I used to work on a a scrum
team with an Australian company and we
knew that our scrum team was charged to
the customer so this was it's a
consulting company so that includes
margin as well um for $60,000 a Sprint
so this was Australian dollars right so
$60,000 for for for for two weeks so we
we were looking at every
Sprint thinking about well if the
customer is giving us $60,000 and we're
doing this work what are we providing
for them what are we doing next what's
the most valuable thing we can do to
spend their
$60,000 um and that that's absolute
absolutely
key but I think that is completely
unrelated to the Dan pink story it might
be anecdotally related as in um a a a
manager that sucks or an organization
that sucks and I'm using sucks in a
totally bad manner there but um that
isn't very good that doesn't understand
these Concepts um might equate the two
and thus we end up with a with a the
difficult comp conflation that M
Michael's talking about but the idea of
me as an
employee and my personal outlook on my
finances and having enough as an
individual with my family nothing to do
with the business the the the the the
the the the business that's
running that's a totally different story
that's a personal story to the business
operating cost story although my
personal story of how much I earn and
how much is provided to me is a number
on the accounting for that right but for
me this is a personal story of if I'm
sitting here this is the Dan pink idea
if I'm sitting here worried about being
able to pay my
rent I'm not going to be focused on
solving the business problems I'm going
to be focused on worrying to pay my rent
me having enough so I'm not worried
about the intrinsic Mo extrinsic
motivations and can focus on the
intrinsic motivations of autonomy
Mastery and purpose does not
precludes me understanding how much I
and my team and the work that we're
doing costs to the business or the
customers they should definitely
understand that stuff but I think I my
belief is they're they're they're two un
I'm I'm going to say they're two
unrelated and separate stories however
the outcome of the personal story is a
line item on the accounting on the other
story if that makes sense that's that's
the way I think about
it actually in this one and uh this may
be my person I'll take
here I have a company
too how do you separate me as a person
from the company I
run it's probably pretty difficult
because I I identify as this company and
this company exists because of me if
this company is in financial trouble so
am I and the other way around so for me
as a business owner it is absolutely n
natural that every financial decision
every product decision every development
decision I have to take from two angles
even the question do I go into the cloud
do I rent the VM do I host this stuff by
myself is made from a perspective of
this one ultimately it hits my pocket so
I have a different way of making
decisions uh then I would have as an
employee who doesn't care where the Bill
Gets Sent and how big it is and even you
have this I mean I'm joking in this one
because what we're talking about is five
or 10 dollars but still the point stays
that if you have financial
responsibility for your own business
because it affects you personally you
make different decisions than if it's
completely
detached sure but that's not an employee
issue that's a business owner issue and
there is only one or two or three of you
in a particular business maybe a little
bit more depending on the scale of the
business and then there's hundreds of
other people who are the people doing
the work that actually don't care about
that story explicitly because the the
success of that story for you as a
business owner lines your pocket it does
nothing for the employees but if the
business makes a 100 million more profit
this year I don't get any more as an
employee in my pay check Mo for in most
companies unless this profit share right
um but as a as a as a business owner um
and as a business owner myself I I do
separate those things right my my my
success as a business owner means I earn
more money right because it's my it's my
business so but I need to be
conscious as a business owner that
that's not how my employees think and
that's not how they're supposed to think
and even all of that doesn't
preclude those employees taking care of
the pennies and pounds a a great example
of this is um what they've done in
Jaguar Land Rover recently so one of the
things that they found um they they were
they were doing a bunch of analysis
on why why did this disaster happen they
disaster that cost them something like2
$300
million and it was it the fundamental
rot cause of this problem was an aging
machine that was creating slightly
faulty Parts like they were good enough
but not good enough long term so they
had to be replaced later and that was
much more
expensive and this machine was run by a
person and they asked that person why
didn't you request a new machine and
they're like I've requested a new
machine every year for the past five
years but what happened in that story is
that that that um request went up in the
organization to somebody who it wasn't
in their budget for this year because
perhaps they were you know looking at
looking after the shareholders right and
we want to have a certain amount so we
can't afford $5 million for a new
machine and they would deny that
request so the change that they made in
the
organization was they now allow every
single person in the organization to
approve any amount of spend and that
sounds ridiculous that sounds like
people within the organization will just
start spending money willy-nilly and you
know you're you're you're then
hemorrhaging cash but they created this
this understanding of kind of spend it
like it's your own money right would you
spend this money on this thing
and that's kind of that's orthagonal but
related to what what it is we're talking
about right that that we want the people
doing the work regardless of whether
they are owners in the business or not
if you're doing doing work if you're
making decisions you want them making
decisions with the understanding of the
context the operating context of the
business the costs that we're running
and things that are happening and and I
absolutely one thing I totally agree
with you Michael I I see time and
again especially in Professional
Services
organizations where they seem they seem
to deliberately
Shield the the they seem to deliberately
Shield the people doing the work from
the costs of the work um I was just
working in a in a in an organization
where I think we had the group group
that I was in that was about 150 people
working with the customer right and this
was this is Mega ridiculous cost you you
probably would talk about an operating
cost per day of about 2,000 two to2 and
a half thousand maybe $33,000 to the
customer right so $3,000 a day per
person 150 people that's that's more
than a that's holy crap that's like more
than 400,000 my math in my head sucks
Michael sorry it's more than 400,000 per
day it's a lot a lot of
money and what what were they getting
for it people were sitting doing make
work because they couldn't think of what
to do but they didn't fundamentally
understand the cost of the business they
didn't understand what they were being
charged to the business to the customer
they didn't understand how much money
they were burning just sitting there not
doing anything for a day so they weren't
making
decisions with context and it's that
context that's important and and I very
much agree that lots of businesses think
that they have to Shield their staff
from the cost of actually doing business
and I think that's
wrong exactly and that is the point
where where I said this is the
point where I said that look really and
I was teasing with this post quoting
then ping take the money off the table
of course because uh this is the point
where it go goes wrong when you run your
business and say I do not want for any
reason whatever not picking out anything
my employees to know the financial
impact of what they are doing at that
point you're hurting your own business
you cannot run a successful business if
you're surrounded by people who don't
know the consequences of their actions
from a financial
perspective I I guess then I really
don't understand why you put down on the
table because they're completely
unrelated things right so I I know
you're saying you're you're you're
you're teasing right but even even even
when you're when you're teasing it it if
you're making an analogy between two
things they have to be the same thing
and I think they're fundamentally not
the same thing and that's what that's
what triggered me to reply right is that
because because I I guess I I got
suckered I'm easy to be triggered right
um I have I definitely I I have I have
an Asbergers coach and helps me very
much on on not poking at things but for
for some when when they're ABS the issue
I I I have is not that when when you're
reating these two things that are
radically different even even in kind of
in G right it's it's not for the likes
of us who are practitioners within this
space who could potentially fully
understand that oh yeah Michael's just
taking a rip at Dan pink to try and H
you
know get engagement and talk about the
topic and
Views yeah but pull pull it apart a
little bit um but but what what about
all of the people out there who stumble
upon your
post and what they read and if they if
they read your post and they're not in
that context of understanding these
Concepts they're going to read
um Dan Pink's ideas are crap they're not
what we want to be looking at and we
should disregard everything he's talking
about that that's what I feel that they
would hear which is why I quite I quite
often Ryan will know this because he we
follow each other as well I quite often
reply to posts based on that context
right I'm not actually replying to the
person who made the post I'm replying to
all the other people who would read that
post and maybe the at least I can save
some percentage of them for getting the
from getting the wrong end of the stick
that's a that's a British idiom what's
wrong end of the stick would be getting
the wrong idea right misinterpreting
misinterpreting the joke as as as a as a
reality and I think it's very easy to
make those make those
conflations that result what's the
what's the the um dual track agile
that's a really famous one right where
are you familiar with Joel track agile
yeah so track
AG it's this
idea
sorry
go means the ability to do the right
thing at the right time so duel track is
uh let's have the ability to sometimes
do the right thing isn't that better
than doing it all the time yeah so so
this is this is yeah this is Joel track
agil was essentially this a paper
talking about this idea that there are
there are two types of work right you've
got Discovery work and you've got
delivery work and you need to do both
and the same people need to e and flow
between that work depending on how you
know if you don't know about something
you're going to spend more time on that
Discovery track if you know a lot about
it and you're just executing on it
you'll maybe spend a little bit more
time on that delivery track
but lots of people read that and then
post about dual track agile being you
need a delivery team and a discovery
team and they end up being two
completely separate teams and then we
all have to spend a whole bunch of time
and effort explaining to people that no
that when people say that that's not
what it was talking about you end up
having to to explain away those those
those issues and I just felt that there
was a danger in the comment that you
made of that that similar idea happening
that disconnect between your your your
intent and what what we want to help
people understand and what Dan pink was
trying to help people understand which
is that intrinsic extrinsic motivation
thing which is separate from that
business operating cost as part of the
context that every employee should
understand
interestingly I would say yeah I am not
so sure that uh how to say and like you
say maybe business owners are a little
bit different than the regular employees
and the question of uh should money be a
motivating factor but then I even come
back to the concept how can you promote
entrepreneurship not entrepreneurship
but
entrepreneurship if your employees don't
have this
mindset Whi which mindset are we talking
about because there's the mindset of
they they they're they're happy and
successful and feel like they can spend
more time focusing on the work because
we've taken money off the table at home
versus the business focus of we need to
understand the financial motivations
within the context of business for
business and I don't think that piece is
any different between an employee and a
business owner right it shouldn't be if
we can agree that it shouldn't be I'm
with you the problem is in practice it
too often is very very
different why why is
it why does that
happen I've got an idea on
that it's a very good question
ultimately I mean uh just look you
brought this up that the employee they
do not think like the business owner so
uh yes I agree with you so what's the I
do agree I mean I was thinking about
this one from my own perspective I used
to be an employee for a long number of
years and when I transitioned into
freelancing into being a business owner
this shift it took me like I would say
like three or four years to start
thinking
differently I mean in part it is like
you said because as an employee there
are other people making this decision
for me I I used to work for a company
where I was out of the loop I did not
know the company's finances except for
yeah we don't have enough money for a
Race So So this go ahead go ahead I
think you're gonna come back in there
yeah I think I I I I think there's a fun
there's a fundamental why here that's
really important which is which is why
um historically that thing that we're
talking about has happened that we've
disconnect that businesses have
systematically and deliberately
disconnected their employees um from the
financial Runnings of the business and
it's fundamentally so that they don't
discover what their colleagues are being
paid because they pay them differently I
had and purly I I had this exact
circumstance I used to work for a little
company called Merl Lynch uh you might
have yeah it was not fun Ryan was not
fun I sub Prime Mortgage as well so it
was even worse pre 2008 um the the so I
I was having a conversation with one of
my
colleagues and I
offhandedly not even thinking of of of
the ramifications offhandedly said oh
we've just cuz we we'd all just got our
and pay Rises and stuff and I
offhandedly said oh now I'm in the 40%
tax bracket this that's going to kind of
suck
right and my colleague who did exactly
the same job as me was incredibly pissed
because they were nowhere near that 40%
tax bracket yeah so they go they go to
their boss and I get in I get I get into
trouble rather than them getting into
trouble for not paying them properly I
get into trouble for letting slip
funnily enough that was in 2007 and in
2008 in the UK that became protected
speech right because in many places
it's I know it's to it it everybody
should be talking to this is part of how
we break this cycle Michael is that
every employee should be talking to each
other about the financial stories how
much do we earn should be open
information within an
organization it absolutely it absolutely
should and in I think in Most states in
the US is now isn't it protected speech
as well or is it federally protected I
think it might be federally
protected you're as an employer you're
not allowed to say to your employees you
can't tell each other about if you don't
want to you don't it's not you're not
forced to talk about it right yeah i'
I'd have to I'd have to check into the
legality of it um but that seems that it
seems like it would be a more companyto
company kind of compliance issue I'm not
sure
regulations protect it and that's that's
again this is completely BS as far as
I'm concerned I think as far as you're
concerned what I was gonna say is going
to Michael's point and then coming back
what when you become a a contract when
you have your own business what are you
you're
independent well what do what does that
mean you are dependent on yourself for
your financial awareness and your
business acument and that kind kind of
those things but when you are employed
by a company who has the financial
information and controls the
compensation about who they decide where
you are ranked what are you you're
dependent it creates a dependency
relationship and then I think that was
that was evidenced Martin by that
situation is that oh well we're
dependent on this other person to give
well hey boss uh you know Martin's
telling me this and then then seeking
some other authority as opposed to
having a conversation where the
structure set up for you to have that
conversation and and and I I agree with
you I mean we we Ryan and I both went on
the same master class so we know uh um
that I I the reality is in many
organizations though that you do have
that situation even with the the the the
the best intentions of leadership when
it comes down to salaries and stuff you
normally I'm not saying it's the right
I'm not saying it's good but you
normally end up in that hierarchy issue
with line line management and
discussions of salary perhaps with HR
right and I think that the the that does
fundamentally have to change I think I
don't fully understand what that would
look like in an Ideal World and maybe
there is no ideal and it's company to
company and that kind of thing but I I
I I did see who was the the web guy from
new New York that used to be very active
I think he's retired now um he had a
company and he published his all of his
salaries for all of his employees were
published internally in the organization
and they had
levels because it wasn't R alio was
it I can't remember but guy but this was
an engineering they were software
development company um and it was just
it was very interesting and and he would
he would open source that story right
and say Here's the story here's what I'm
thinking and actually publish it
publicly and then say what what do you
think is this going to work what are the
things that might not work and I think
that kind of open
discussion I actually I don't understand
where the closed salary discussion comes
from me
personally and this is this is a Martin
thing I'm quite happy to tell anybody
what I earn
right but but I definitely feel like
most
people feel like it's secret
information yeah I'm not sure where that
comes
from there's also a lot how to say
there's also a
cultural element to this I know that in
Germany there's this uh PR you don't
talk about money you have
it but literally that is part of the
problem that the people the business
owners who have access to the money they
don't talk about it so that other people
don't know and like you already
mentioned it creates a dependency it
creates a power slope and uh even
bringing this one back to the point of
taking the money off the
table as a regular employee will I ever
know whether I am being paid enough to
be silent or whether I am being paid as
much as I am
worse how do I find out for that one I
need to understand what my contribution
to the company is because if I
understand this I can argue look because
of me you're making 50 million how about
my share is just two of that it's an
entirely different story of I would like
a race yeah but financial situation is
difficult well per perhaps employee
employe the employee employer
relationship ship has had its time right
Perhaps Perhaps it should be business
owner to business owner relationship and
everybody we hire in our organization is
I I always found it weird this Ryan
won't get maybe won't get this and I'm
not sure what happens in Germany I found
it weird Ryan that I had to do my tax
returns when I went to the
US in the UK you don't do a tax return a
normal employee does not do a tax return
it's done for you by the by your company
and the tax man
why
yeah because that's how it's that's how
it's done here same reason we don't have
sales tax and it's all included in the
price you pay the price on the ticket is
the price you pay right um the the the
the salary I get is the salary I get and
I don't have to worry about how much tax
I've paid I don't have to that's all
taken care of by your
employer
right how does that different so this is
very interesting I had no idey how is
that different in Germany Michael yeah
actually it's very interesting the Texas
is
probably it's been a running gag for a
long time that uh sometimes politicians
like to advertise uh that
uh one it was like 10 years ago they
said that maybe there we should should
simplify the tax system so that your tax
form fits on a beer stamp uh but this
never happened if I would show you the
tax forms and literally every single
German has to do their tax form every
year and it's a science literally uh it
takes you about a day just because of
how complicated it is and uh how to say
in Germany you tell your employer your
envision ient gross
salary but that doesn't mean that that
is your net salary so what is
transferred to you on your bank account
is about half of that and depending on
which tax bracket you are and whether
you're single married have children or
more it could be a bit more than half a
bit less than half the problem is that
this one already creates the first level
where people feel treated very very
unfairly because in Germany you have two
levels of tax one is the tax that you
pay as an employee and the other is the
level of tax that the employer pays and
I like to say I run a business I charge
my customer 100 from those  100 I as a
private person can spend about 30 the
rest goes to the government in one form
or another so as an employer I always
see the  100 EUR that I need to make in
order to pay
myself as an employee there 0 as an
employee and there was even one comedian
in Germany who made this joke that he
said that it's a bit schizophrenic
running a oneperson company as an
employer you say my employees they're
asking too much money and as an employee
you say my employer is ripping me
off but but I think I think um Michael
by default if you're just an employ
employee in Germany and you have no
special
circumstances the company does your tax
return no correct no no they file of
course they legally have to do but you
still have to take care of your tax
returns by yourself the company's not
involved in this
process okay that's that's not the
information I have over here it just
says that um you may may want to file
tax returns but you don't have to um so
in in the UK I can file as an employee I
can file a tax return if I want to but
by default unless if I'm only working
for one company
Ryan if I only have one
employer then they know everything about
my incoming finances so unless I have
any other things that I need to declare
I can just let the company file my my
tax returns on my behalf and that's a
legal obligation of theirs uh Within in
the UK so they play pay the employees
tax what's actually really interesting
is companies shield from employees that
other piece that Michael's talking about
because you have the cost of the
employee right from the perspective of
the employee like I know I get paid x
amount and my tax is this amount but
what you don't see is the employer's
liability
tax workers compensation and federal
programs and all that stuff that we have
here and even even like we we pay
something called national insurance
which is like Social Security in the US
which used to be for a specific thing
and now it's just tax right um and and
there's employer employees contributions
and employers contributions and the
employer contributions is higher so
staff don't normally see or even under
staff employees not business owners just
pure employees don't normally have any
visibility on what they actually cost
the business exactly and and yeah that's
weird well I think this comes down to a
basic so we're talking about individual
incentivization right and I think this
and Michael you brought Alfie con into
the into the conversation with that too
and and Alfie as as you know and Martin
I think you know this too from from
where we've been talking about in beta
codex and all that stuff is that um
incentives are individual incentives are
demotivating the punished by rewards
kind of thingum and that and and
iemp pardon employee of of the month is
one of my favorite ones yeah well and
this I think we're coming down to this
okay so my individual tax burden is this
what do I what am I contributing to that
that all that
conversation becomes null and void when
a small group of employees in this area
are managing a business in and of
themselves with their own profit and
loss statement they're managing that
again different it's a different
relationship in kind in terms of oh it
doesn't necessarily matter you know what
what all of us no no one person creates
value on their own and I think that that
is a big concept because I need both of
you to create value in whatever I'm
doing
and on the variable compensation is top
of that but if if you raise and then
I'll I'll leave there but the
Baseline base compensation if you pay
people fairly and pay them well yeah
then then that quote I think this is a
Deming quote I think that that is
actually I was trying to find it my
Deming I'm not 100% sure but I'm yeah I
think so it I think I think it's it's
really interesting though Ryan that
that the and suddenly we're we're
starting to have a conversation just
about capitalism right um the
the the big the elephant in the room
right in in the the the the the system
within which we
operate that we're all
operating is fundamentally about a small
group of people Gathering large amounts
of wealth right because the the the the
wealth flows from the people who don't
get paid very much but we make a lot of
profit on the people that are not and
rather than paying them
better the wealth flows up to that one
one person at the top right the CEO with
the multi-million dollar salary for
whatever reason but they're taking a lot
of risk but are they really taking
hundred million dollar worth of risk
right personal risk not really right and
and I think that's that idea that we
were kind of the employer employee
relationship if every person in in the
story would their own boss right You'
basically got a they're a bunch of
Boutique uh uh individuals who are
selling themselves for how much they
think they're worth and doing their own
taxes and doing their own thing and
understanding at that part of the
business like you're saying Ryan doing
profit and loss for that part of the
business yeah I think the reason we
don't have that
systemically is because those people
would be absolutely a
gas at the levels of profit that they
generate that's money that's going
somewhere else that they don't get right
exactly behen to the business to hide
that it's not really hide it's a virtual
hide make it make it um what's
the
through ASA as they can
so that employees don't get upset that
why am I doing this work and making you
100 million when you're only paying me
50 Grand right and and and again it's
not like like each individual oh I need
to have you know 98% of that you know
our team makes X and I need that I think
and this is part capitalism is not evil
capitalism what we have creating value
is not evil you know I I think there's
there's there's this bifurcation wow
okay right so there's this bifurcation
of oh it has to be way or the other
either we're this socialist dippy commun
folks but but some some folks bring it
but yeah I agree I agree with that there
there's a way to
say
individual the nordics are are are
fairly fairly good at creating that um
bif bifurcation where you you you've got
and the America you America used what
was the
1970s under a uh Republican government
what was the tax Max tax bracket I think
it was 70% yeah there was 75% tax
bracket I think there was a 90% D
bracket back in the in the FDR days the
the the we had we had a thing in the UK
that was it was really interesting had a
really interesting effect at one point I
think it was in the 80s or early 90s I
can't 100% remember so somebody would
need to look it up and and validate it
but we had a whole bunch bunch of
companies that were making unbelievably
ridiculous amounts of profit and they
were doing Revenue extraction not value
creation they were extracting massive
amounts of revenue from from effectively
from the economy and it was damaging the
entire economy the amount of money they
were taking out and taking overseas and
doing all of those kind of things so
they created something I can't remember
which government it was probably a labor
government because it sounds not like
something the conservatives here would
do
um but they created something called the
winfall tax and the windfall tax said if
your business makes over 500 million in
profit everything over that is 100% tax
that was the wind tax and it forced all
of these companies to start going we
don't want to pay the tax so what should
we do with this money instead perhaps we
should invest it in our infrastructure
perhaps we should invest it in our
people perhaps we should invest it in
the things that we're doing to generate
value within our context and encouraged
people to do that and I I thought it was
a it was a I'm not saying that would
work now but it was a very interesting
Dynamic that happened as part of that
that that story and very very
interesting in terms of regulatory
impact of that well now we have that
regulation then then the folks who who
have been
get in the ill gotten gain from before
that regulation might hire uh capable
and intelligent tax accountants to say
how might we Shield that profit and put
it somewhere else else I mean and that's
and we've we've
we right endend up with with with with a
lot of whack-a-mole because you don't
have this problem in in in the US Ryan
but we we've got we've got a thousand
plus year old tax system in Europe for
most of the most of the the the the
countries so there's all kinds of weird
stuff in European law and and European
just in in the countries right in the
tax law and the things that that are
very hard to close because they've just
been there for so long and nobody's the
things have superseded them but then
they find this way of loop hauling
something I I know you have that in the
states as well but when you've got a
thousand years of tax law it's worse 250
is different than than a thousand or
more Michael I think you you're going to
hop in there um in a moment or I don't
know if that's no it's okay but
if I mean the entire conversation about
tax is very interesting because it
somehow closes the loop between uh the
economy as the global system the company
as how to say our system of work and me
as an individual with even how to say my
family my close Circle as my
personal system of control I would say
uh but how to say I would say one of the
key issues when we talking about those
is
even the system that we are operating in
we can always uh reframe it and we just
reframed it by saying let's talk about
text let's talk about capitalism as a
whole uh and even this uh when we bring
this one back to the point where we are
coming from is what kind of decisions do
we want whom to make because uh what we
were talking about Martin with this one
the 500 million the windfall tax is uh
literally the big decisions made by some
of the big corporate players which is
yeah yeah yeah that's really high 1% of
the
population and uh I to say the what we
need to talk about and that is why I was
bringing up the entire point is uh and I
think that is fully within the spirit of
anything that any one of us is promoting
I would like uh all those kind of
decisions to be more decentralized to
have everybody involved in the decision
everybody being able to talk at face
level rather than I am on the top that's
why I'm telling you and then you tell
your people and then they tell their
people face level conversations are the
way that we can change this system so
what we need to create is a system not
only where the phase level conversation
is possible but where people do have a
self-interested in saying I want to join
this
conversation yep and Ryan has a lovely
diagram behind him behind his head right
there uh uh getting to some of some of
those some of those ideas it doesn't
have all the answers but it definitely
is a is a definitely a a a structure
that can be
I I I think you're you're absolutely
right but I think it only comes with the
that that's that idea of the sale based
structure of the profit and loss at each
level that that we just don't
fundamentally have now I I worked with a
company in
Norway and uh it's a French company but
I worked with the the Norwegian
department and they had a product that
cost a lot of money to make 650 people
working on it every day and the product
owner for that product had no visibility
of how much that product cost to
build none none at all so the way I know
exactly the way the way it was organized
was that that there was I think it was H
nine 13 Technology Centers in nine
different countries and each Technology
Center invested their own money in
features for the
product so profit and loss was all
country based in these nine different
countries and the product owner and
management for the product had zero
visibility on because they they're not
allowed to see the profit and loss for
the division in this other country
that's not allowed within the context of
this big hierarchical oil and gas
business right and and but that
fundamental lack of visitability is part
of the problem yes and it's not but it's
not it's not I think we're losing sight
of the big picture though because it's
not just money that's the problem I mean
we're talking about money in the context
here is money but I worked with a car
company and they couldn't get in order
to get Telemetry data from all of the
cars in existence right to get access to
some of the tele data it took six to
eight months of request forms and
getting the data and the person I was
speaking to had colleagues in Tesla who
could just go
the data right and then we can make
decisions based on what's actually
happening out in the world now did now
in that example did they have a have
visibility understanding of why Tesla
was functioning that way and what was it
about that organization
different I I kind of know what it is
but I what was
the I
mean I think Tesla is a funny Beast that
doesn't fit into any particular category
because and I think all of elon's
companies are the same right that the
the there and probably Apple was the
same under under jobs right there's a
little bit of cult of personality
driving the decision making rather than
policy based decision- making which is
how most organizations and I say most
Ryan for sure most organization what
what could you tell me what you think
well what I I think I don't know whether
this came from from a a talk I saw with
Joe Justice because I know he had been
involved there in
some some background knowledge but what
I understand is that they kind of have
apis between their different teams that
there are agreements of how this team
deals with that team and that team deals
with the other teams and those are not
mandated and that if if I have a a Rules
of Engagement for myself as it were and
you have it for yourself and we serve
these different needs that that
information can flow much more freely
because we have that kind of
relationship I think that that also may
be true of the actual Hardware of the
vehicles um and that how that is
assembled that we we can assemble
different parts in different ways but if
our if our protocol if our interaction
Protocols are if we have a good
understanding of the interaction
protocols then we will have have the
ability to get information back and
forth effectively without having to
translate and make legible why we are
doing what we're doing in order to
satisfy some need for status level
control and as opposed to to going based
on value
creation but I think um Nils talked
about this a little bit in when we did
the the the master class he talked about
um maybe it wasn't Nils maybe it was
because I was speaking to somebody else
about um not
uh not ah I'm trying to get my brain in
gear um they were talking about you you
need to have a sponsor for whatever
changes you're making in the
organization if you want to make those
types of changes you need a sponsor
that's senior enough yeah it it was I
don't think it was Nils it was open
space beta it was um open space agile it
was the open space agile D isic open
space that's that's I speaking to um and
he he he was talking
about the hard part is getting people
somebody senior enough and I I like I
like Neil's comment that if you're
talking to somebody and they're like oh
I've got to go ask somebody you're not
talking to somebody senior enough right
but the difficulty in doing doing that
with smaller organizations is
easy doing that with large organizations
was hard I I when I worked at Marl Lynch
my boss was a project
manager his boss was a regional director
a business Regional
director and there were living people
above
him yeah so how like at some point in an
organization like that management is
effectively Bean counting right there's
not there's not actually any
understanding of the work being done we
don't care about the work being done
it's numbers and spreadsheets and profit
and that's all we care about yeah and
management by remote
control there was I had a great I'm so
I'm thr in a lot of things but I had a
great conversation with somebody at a
conference years
ago who he asked me what I did and I
said I help organizations that are
screwed get unscrewed right that's
effectively well that's that's what
that's what we do right right yeah um
and he said
why and I said I don't know he said you
should just let them die go go find a
company that's not like that and make it
successful and ignore the companies that
are that are have that because they're
not they're not fundamentally going to
change it does feel a lot Ryan like
we're what's it h peeing up wind I think
is the expression peeing into the wind
right yeah a chotic or someone say quick
sotic Quest you know you're tilting at
windmills kind of yeah it's it's just so
hard to actually help people to actually
make change in
organization is it wor worth actually
making the change and then with with the
effort and then I think about
organizations like Microsoft right that
while certainly not awesome on on these
things has made massive changes in the
fundamental way they do business over
the last 10 years that has enabled them
to take advantage of many of the things
that that that we talk about not all of
the things that they still they're still
a big hierarchal organization right how
many 50,000 150,000 I'm trying to think
how many people in how many people you
need uh two in front of that and an
extra zero yeah there two
200,000 200,000 people in in in in
Microsoft but if you think about it as a
group of businesses which is why Google
changed right that's what one one this
is my I'm not saying it's why Google
changed it's why I think Google changed
right that they changed to a venture
capit
company alphabet because they realize
that you just can't change its scale and
what's better is you kill the old
companies and start new
companies um start new efforts kill old
efforts right um and yeah it's a
decentralizing
pattern but it's it's kind of like big
kind of moving solar systems out of the
Galaxy instead of you know moving
planets to different parts of the solar
system kind of thing um so and maybe
this is about the Arc of History you
know if we if we each as individuals we
are where we are when we are there um
working and living within a Microsoft
mirror Lynch a IBM or name your Behemoth
and are are you choosing to be a force
for Force for good or Force for evil but
a force for um changing the system and
intervening in the system and standing
up for something that that there is a
there is a way that we could be we and
and do more and be more and not only
just only for the employees and like ha
human relations you know big deal make
the employees feel happy and then still
extract the universe but to actually
have people in relationship one another
and relationship with the customer in
service of a greater good for the
company and for the society because I
mean I think we we got in from
individual versus team and then we also
when we started talking about taxes
you're talking about wow what is our
responsibility as individuals also to to
the the legal and government struction
around us isn't what we're talking about
here very similar to a
Cooperative
similar it's kind of a new new kind of
Beast I think I think we have to think
of some new kind of animal because
because the the language around around
what we're talking about becomes oh are
you talking about this are you talking
about that I know I know there's a new
type of company that they've just I I
created a new type of company in the US
like an official you can put it on the
form company it's a a low profit a low
profit company yeah I think those be B
Corps
yeah I I don't know the exact
terminology um and and I I I think I
think it's really it's really
interesting
and I think it's the future but how
quickly do we get there I think it's
going to be really really difficult
because we still we still have I mean
existentially we still have to get over
the um Universal income hump as well
which is we've not got it yet uh it's
it's going to be a really
interesting
decade I think yeah well and I think and
this is this is all we're not talking
about I mean there's there's there's
ways to think about this that are not
either or that are better you know it's
not Universal basic income which is like
everybody everybody gets this and no one
get and more and there's no no variable
compensation but I think the idea of
variable and and hey we're talking about
money so we can talk about compensation
I think compensation and motivation was
one of the things we were again with
talk about Dan pink you're bringing that
in there but so if we are if I trust you
if I respect you and we're do we're in
we're in this love together and if we're
there with it um then we can talk about
compensation what is what what are our
relative
compensation what is our contribution to
this group each other and you can't have
that in a 50 person
organization among 50 people but you can
have it among five to seven or eight
yeah and and so so that I think that
it's it's a different model of
compensation and and financial
management that that you have to be
willing to suspend your disbelief and
have someone and have dialogue with
someone who has sponsorship authority to
make the kind of change that we're
talking difficult to get enough snowball
to make
the these sorts of things viable because
the the the where all the all the money
is is in these big biomic organizations
and these big bomic
organizations um don't want to deal with
the seven or eight person company
because then oh crap I'm going to have
to um if if if we have a thousand seven
or eight company companies we've got to
deal with I've got to do a thousand
invoices a month but if I go to
Accenture I only have one invoice a
month I'm done right and the the there's
a there's a uh how would you describe it
there's a a a local
optimization um where they want to
minimize their invoicing
costs that is really that's a tactical
problem though
that's Sol it's a problem but they a
strategic initiative right it is
extremely relevant
and even though it might be disclosing a
bit too much of some confidential stuff
that's going on on my end but this is
exactly some of the stuff that we are
doing we are operating with some of the
world's best players in their field and
let's just say I don't want to name uh
any big Consulting but those people do
not work for big Consulting they have
their own business so if you want them
all together you do not have a choice
you have to go saying that where do we
find the right
people I think there's two there's two
different sorts of
Consulting right and and and I'm I'm
definitely polarizing here putting
things in buckets which I fully fully
fully admit I'm happy to do right
polarizing always fun right there's two
types of people in the world those that
understand binary right
SC so there's but I I feel like there's
two main types of Consulting
there the big
Consulting um like the the the the the
accent and infosis and uh I don't know
pick pick your McKenzie
deoe you know a lot of people don't
realize how long McKenzie's been around
right I think they're they're coming up
on their on their
centinary um and and and the Damage
they've done I really recommend um uh oh
what's the book called the big con big
con yeah that one that one awesome
Marana matado yes yeah um those those
types of
Consultants tend to be about fulfilling
consultancy like consultancy is the
point we want to take over parts of your
business and we will run it for you
because it's more efficient for more
cost effective for us to run it because
we've got a 100 people in a room that
can do your invoicing for you right um
but the reality is that Outsourcing
those things results in a company's
inability to adapt to change because
they're relying to pick on upon this
other system I my favorite example is
anything to do with sap right as soon as
you bring in sap or
I let's let's let's double down in
Microsoft moft uh Microsoft's got a sap
compete whatever the heck it's called
Great
Planes no it's not called that anymore
but yeah it was called grip planes um as
soon as you you bring in somebody else's
business model that you have to follow
you're limiting your ability to change
it it doesn't matter what it is right
sometimes we accept small limitations
like we might use as your devops to hold
our work items or we might use jira or
we might use that's a small um dis
what's the opposite of optimization un
optimization dis
optimization whatever that compromise
it's just a compromise yeah we we we we
compr you're right we compromise our
ability to change a little bit in order
to streamline something and when you do
it at the small scale like we're going
to store our work items in aure
devops awesome pretty pretty high
benefit for pretty low uh uh limitation
right until it's not and then you change
but when it's something as systemic as
our entire procurement
platform that goes to every part of the
business it then makes it really
difficult to change because any change
is hundreds and hundreds and hundreds of
millions of dollars to get it to change
we we we
we it's an optimization that creates
this inability to change
right yeah a friend of mine said one
time that uh he hates uh let's not name
the company this one with a passion
because he said that once you bring them
on board it's easier to kill your
business and start a new company than to
get rid of them
again yeah I think that's but I I count
the big consultancies and big software
in that
and I guess there's software that maybe
doesn't count in that category like
bringing do doing Office 365 or Google
probably doesn't because it doesn't
impose process on you yeah right it just
provides capability you can decide how
you use it but I it's where you cross
that line
into imposing upon your your your
business
practices actually in this one I think
that one of the key challenges that com
companies face is they buy these things
as a commodity and don't realize that
what they are onboarding is not a
commodity but a business model yeah B
they're bring and when you when you
install somebody else's business model
what makes you different from that
somebody else and that's exactly you L
differentiating factor and uh I remember
working many years ago with a Telco
operator who said at literally I mean
you as a customer you take your phone in
the end does it matter for you you go to
AT&T you go to T-Mobile you go to Dell
whatever it doesn't matter to you so
what's the discriminating factor for you
as a customer the price teag what
defines the price de process efficiency
but if all three of them have the same
process how's that supposed to
work so to bring this all the way back
to our original question right that that
sh the should companies take money off
the table and understanding the cost
it's not just the employes not
understanding the cost of um what their
cost to doing the work it's everybody
who's a decision maker in the
organization understanding the cost of
doing not doing a thing and also the
longterm cost like if you in if you take
sap and replace your procurement
processes with with a sap
equivalent what's the cost to change
later if you decide you want to
change and How likely is that cost of
change to happen and I I think people
don't make
decisions with that level of
foresight and why why don't they and and
U so my opinion about why I agree I
agree that those decisions are not made
with that level of information I know
why too why well yeah well yeah we all
know why but yeah we might not agree but
again if if you take U
obscurity off the table what do you have
you have transparency and and if your
open book all the information is there
if the information is distributed in an
effective and free fashion then then the
then you can make the decisions and then
you can agree and there there's there's
certain frames about making group and
group decision making is a whole other
issue but I think add there's an
additional piece on that Ryan and that's
I I've been um there's a marketing guy
who I've been watching a B I think he's
actually a psychologist but he talks a
lot at marketing forums but he's a
psychologist and what he talks about
is
mathematics taking decision making off
the table
and they want people look at the cold
hard numbers and make a decision based
on the numbers because then they didn't
have to make a decision the numbers made
the decision for them oh God that's evil
um and they don't have to take
accountability for that decision because
the numbers made that decision for them
yeah and and that that goes into another
whole and interesting it'd be
interesting to hear who that person is
and what the rational I thought and I
thought as soon as you said Cold Hard
Cash Michael's ears would perk up and he
would she would show up on screen like
oh my God I want to talk about the
numbers
um yes yeah that's you I'm talking to
you it's inform decision making not do
the decision making for you I I talk
about I talk a lot about numbers and
Telemetry and evidence-based management
and all of those things but ultimately
we're playing poker not chess right and
we don't have all of the information we
have some of the information and some of
it's hidden and we're trying to use our
intuition based on the data that we have
to make the best decision possible
within the context and then we see
whether we're right maybe we need to
make a different decision and yeah I'm
I'm trying to get that um that guy for
you because
it's there he is there's something very
similar I'm f
uh and that is how to say I am part one
of the startups I'm involved in is
literally to make the
information of an entire organization
available and use a management framework
to support decision making like you say
I'm not taking the decisions away from
people because I do not believe that
mathematics can have the full
understanding of what is going on but
saying let's take all the data that you
have how fast can you as a manager of
10,000 people organization process
everything that's going on you can't
there's more happening in real time than
you can catch up with but with AI you
can catch up you can use algorithms you
can use machine learning to figure out
what's going on and say those are things
that you have to pay attention to and
that is noise and based on what we know
what's going on those are decisions
that are
likely to bring you in the direction of
the goals that you want to pursue and
those things are the things that you
have to address otherwise you're not
going to reach your goal and I'm
building this kind of thing with a team
with AI and it's really fancy stuff but
this is the organization that I want
that everybody in the company has access
to the information and decisions they
need so that they can make them without
meeting Madness
well absolutely a and and I think the
important thing is that this is a tool
that's fit for purpose and that when
when also this is I think this is
another thing that Deming has said that
if there are if there is fear involved
in what the numbers are stating if
there's people have fear of loss or this
incentive to gain based on what numbers
they are in individually responsible for
reporting then those numbers are going
to be lies they're just going to be lies
and instead but I like the idea of okay
the machines understand the numbers
right if and if if the and again the
algorithms and the calculations are also
freely open and that that if you want to
see how those decisions are made how
those tabulations are done and what what
what you're measuring if it can be
measured and measured objectively and
put out there for the actual carbon
hydrogen oxygen and spirit beings to
make sense of as opposed to the silicon
and electricity beings um then then I
think we can we can hold hands and talk
about again like Martin like you're also
saying is that making informed decisions
and um making decisions quickly with
with as good of information as we have
actually I would say that one of the key
challenges so have you have your turn
soon one of the key challenges we face
with decision making is that there's all
always uncertainty so what we can only
talk about is uh bets every business
decision is a bet not a fact because we
don't know until we tried it and
probabilities but there are things that
we know that most likely will not give
you what you're looking for and things
that are pretty likely to give you what
you're looking for and there are
patterns we've observed for many years
uh and we can see if we can spot
patterns and if we say that you're on
this pattern then we can say okay this
is the kind of advice I would provide
for you because literally as a
consultant that's what I do I am uh
trying to figure out what the patterns
are that are going on in your
organization I'm saying that okay based
on what I've seen before this could work
this is probably not going to work if
it's you want to try it you can still
try it it's your choice but let me make
a prediction of the outcome and if
you're good as a consultant then um I
would say that at least two thirds of
the time uh you're pretty on spot maybe
not fully accurate but pretty on spot
and this is the same that in many
organizations is going wrong that uh
most decisions are made without an
understanding of where does this lead us
it's just okay that we have this
meetings we need to talk about this
topic let's make the decision but what's
going to happen nobody knows
and again realizing that we're at time
Martin I know I know you have to be out
of here um a great conversation both
both of you gentlemen Michael also want
to bring you here to say some words
Martin is there anything you wanted to
say here bring forth that you had not
yet had a chance to
do no I think
um that the the context is really
important and don't Shield people from
from that context in your organization
for what is in effect selfish reasons
right um I want to hide the information
of how much the team costs because I
don't want members of the team to find
out they don't get paid very much that's
a selfish reason um that's not a good
reason to hide those costs and limit
people's ability to make decisions and
reduce the effectiveness of those
decisions because I it's it's just not
good enough
but on the other side don't
confuse Dan Pink's story of taking money
off the table with that story of the
corporate context the business
context um the personal story of people
who are
individuals and want to be able to um
make make the best they can of things
that that that intrinsic focus on those
intrinsic things of autonomy Mastery and
purpose um and we want to enable that
from the context of our business but
don't
compromise the context and knowledge and
understanding and transparency of your
business in order uh to support that
right have both have both is what yeah
show Nuance show Grace show respect
sounds like human things um Michael
would you like to drop in with your your
final thoughts before we head
out actually I can only say I fully
agree with Martin and uh despite the
seeming conflict this is exactly the
point that I wanted to bring just uh
have the conversation provide people an
environment where they feel comfortable
to have the right decisions to work in a
way that is conducive both to them
personally and to their business to
their environment to society and if we
can shape this in a way that everybody
benefits then this is good for everybody
but like you say don't for what is
ultimately a selfish reason keep people
away from things that maybe they should
know because it's G to backfire you're
not going to make the best decisions if
people don't know what the consequences
are
well I will I will leave the uh leave
the conversation at that thanks to both
of you for hanging in there um and uh
we'll hang off for a moment or two in
the back Mar before you have to leave um
and I'll put myself here in the center
thank you so much thank you for the
precious gift of your time and attention
and thank you to Martin and to Michael
for showing up and having a respectful
and intelligent conversation and
hopefully it was valuable to you we see
you next time on riffing with