one of the common uh myths in scrum is
that is really a a forum for
micromanagement and the there's a
there's a core test for this in your
team it is it is a myth right but it's a
reality for many teams so is it a myth
or is it not a myth that is a matter of
perspective however I would point out
that it's not scrum so it's a myth in
the context of scrum but it's not a myth
in the context of how lots of
organizations and teams approach scrum
because most organizations approach
something like scrum from their
traditional topown steering based
perspective and they want to tell teams
what they're going to deliver in a
Sprint so you walk into Sprint
planning and the product owner or the
tech lead or the project manager
or whoever the scrum Master the worst
one but the scrum Master says here's a
list of things we need you as a team to
do this
Sprint as soon as that
happens not
scrum we've gone out of the bounds of
the scrum guide who decides what we work
on this Sprint the developers who
decides how we work on it the Developers
okay it's not anybody else because the
developers that's this this core reason
why they dislike that approach it's the
developers that understand the nuance
and intricacies of the technical
challenges of actually delivering on the
work inside of the
Sprint nobody else can understand that
Nuance because they're living it right
they've got skills that I don't have as
a manager or as a product owner they've
got understanding of the product and the
technologies that we're using to deliver
that product the tools and techniques
that we're using their best place to
make that decision now can the product
owner say oh my goodness me we're in a
difficult place because we're not
working through the work that we need to
deliver as fast as we would like yeah
absolutely they can have that
conversation and they can have a
conversation with the developers about
how the developers might choose to cut
corn ERS into in order to accelerate
work but it must be done with their
Ascent if the developers say no then we
can't work any faster cuz we might be
taking on too much technical debt and
most businesses and for all businesses
all technical debt is a risk to the
business and most businesses don't
understand the context of technical debt
enough to make an informed decision on
whether they should acrew it
and how they should pay it back that's
why we have hired these technical
experts in order to deliver our product
and we should trust their understanding
and view of the product in order to do
that so I would say that it is a myth
that anybody should be telling the
developers what to work on and when to
work on it but I do understand that lots
of organizations don't understand and
how to let go of that control and are
not yet ready for agile thanks for
watching the video If you enjoyed it
please like follow And subscribe I
always reply to comments and if you want
to have a chat about this or anything
else agile scrum or devops then please
book a coffee with me through naked
agility