hey Joshua I am just looking at how to
do that thing we just talked about so
you go to admin teams on microsoft.com
let's see and I drag this meeting
policies thing on to the other window
let's have a look
so I'm pretty sure it's gonna have to be
not in messaging policies but in meeting
policies I don't think it's meeting
settings let's check meeting settings
first anonymous users can join oh that's
nice
URLs quality of service so I think this
was off by default but I turned quality
of service on that may have had an
impact so let's have a look let's do the
global policy global policy okay
so somewhere in here where is the ah
there we go so media bitrate determines
the meaning of bitrate for audio video
or video without sharing a meeting
feeling organization the setting gives
your music really cool or my blah blah
blah the minimum value is 30 kilobytes
that would suck for meetings that need
the highest quality video experience
such as CEO board meetings and live
events we recommend you use 10 megabits
so this is in kilobits so convert a
little bit let's see what it comes with
okay so that's already set to 50
megabits again I may have changed that
you wanna go check and see 10 mega rez
yep so I might set 50 megabits that's
the policy that you want to go check on
and make sure that things are enabled
I also enable most of the features that
allow guests and people coming into the
meeting to do a bunch of things and so
this one is deliberately off because I
don't want anonymous people being able
to start the meeting or get in so if I
were just a meeting invite and honor
those people if I have our team's event
then I set it up so that only
authenticated people can join and I can
show you how to do that I have some
explanation of that and you can also
control like our lobby waiting room if
you want but since every team's URL is
unique it's a little bit different from
zoo where you have one URL and that
covers everybody okay