so the question is what is a Sprint
backlog
uh so according to the scrum guide a
Sprint backlog is is kind of three
things together the first is the Sprint
goal uh the second is the selected
backlog items and the third is a plan to
complete them some kind of some kind of
plan for that those three together is
the the Sprint backlog
uh my my perspective is that the the
Sprint backlog is our transparency of
the present
right it's how do we know what are we
working on just now how do we know where
we are in our progress towards our our
current Sprint goal and ultimately our
overall product goal
um so the the Sprint backlog is
made up of all of the things that we're
working on this Sprint but it's very
important that the Sprint backlog isn't
100 to do with the Sprint goal if we
always have our Sprint backlog must be
100 to do with our Sprint goal then what
do we do with all those other things
that we need to do over time perhaps
we've got some refactoring perhaps we've
got some architectural work we have to
do perhaps we've just got some bugs to
fix do we have to have a bug fixing
Sprint right that's where that
dysfunction comes from so what you do
instead is your your your Sprint goal
encompasses some of your Sprint backlog
this is the thing that you commit to the
thing that you're definitely definitely
going to try really hard to achieve
right because that commitment try really
hard to achieve that's the thing you're
definitely the thing you'll talk to your
customers about talk to your
stakeholders about engage with them on
that that topic and then there's a bunch
of other things that you're going to
bring into the Sprint that are perhaps
nothing to do with the Sprint goal you
might have
um some some refactoring work you might
have some technical debt you want to go
want to go fix
um you might have here's some stuff that
we haven't automated in a while and we
want to want to go back and and fix that
up uh perhaps you've got oh the build
the build's taking too long
um and we really need to go re-engineer
that thing so that it's it's faster and
our Engineers know quicker that
something's wrong that's all work that
needs to be done that doesn't fit within
a Sprint goal because a Sprint goal is
always talking about what the customers
need what the stakeholders need what are
we trying to trying to deliver for for
for them
the rest is business as usual right
stuff we have to do all the time so
that's included in that story
so try and avoid having a Sprint goal
that is so big
that you can achieve it
right any team that is working towards a
Sprint goal and then they can't achieve
it is not going to be happy right
hopefully they're not going to be happy
I'm not happy that I wasn't able to
achieve the thing that I committed to
try and Achieve to achieve to the
customers that wouldn't make me happy
what if the the the the are in the
position of doing that Sprint after
Sprint after Sprint after Sprint they're
not delivering because the Sprint goes
always too big it's complete these 10
things and you only get six of them done
so we failed or it's do this big thing
and we got 90 of the wear so we failed
right if we're constantly failing you're
gonna have a unhappy depressed team and
unhappy depressed people don't make good
products they don't make good decisions
uh they tend to not give a crap about
what it is you're building anymore at
some point and we don't want to go there
so create set them up for success by
having a Sprint goal that has a narrower
Focus right not the whole Sprint just
part of the Sprint so we know we can
achieve it and then add other things
that are much more flexible right
whether we do half the refactoring or
all the refactoring is kind of
irrelevant as long as we do some of it
and make progress
we've got that Sprint goal and don't be
afraid to change what you're working on
during the Sprint right you can accept
new work into the Sprint that's the
other reason you have that flexibility
right you have that Sprint goal that's
smaller is you can bring other work into
the Sprint you can change what you're
working on and we can respond to the
needs of the business the needs of the
customer that needs of the market much
more quickly that's what a Sprint goal
is
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility