building a culture of quality within
your organization is absolutely not
something that you can do on your own
it's not something that any individual
can
do each individual within the context of
your organization needs to be able
to demonstrate their own technical
excellence
their technical leadership their their
engineering capability if they
demonstrate their own other people
around them will see a way of
Behaving that hopefully they want to
copy the more people in your
organization behave that way the quicker
other people in your organization will
see that as the way to behave I I I was
trying to think of an example there of
of of
it that being true and I I really keep
coming back to the opposite being true
um and that's that's the boing story if
you've been following the Boeing story
really for many years the Boeing story's
been been going on when
Boeing before Boeing bought McDonald
Douglas Boeing's Focus was on
engineering Excellence technical
leadership ship and they built that
Mantra of if it's not boing I'm not
going I theirs were the best planes they
were the best build qualities they were
the least likely to fall out the sky
they were they were the standard for
quality in the entire aviation
industry and then and they had that
culture engineering excellence and and
Technical leadership and and then they
moved they bought McDonald Douglas and
through some weird happenings which I
don't fully understand M McDonald
Douglas came out on top of being in
charge right McDonald Douglas's
leadership and their focus was on
Revenue extraction that was their focus
we're we're not here to build value
we're here to extract money for our
shareholders and for ourselves that's
what we're here for and over the next 20
years I think it's been 20 years I might
be a little bit out there 15 20
years they've decimated that culture
that culture of quality inside of boing
completely and utterly destroyed it so
much so that that you might have seen
seen videos of Boeing
Employees saying you know yes I'd fly in
this plane but yeah I've got a death
wish right that's not if if you're going
to be flying in a in a in a plane that's
not what you want the the culture you
want with within the context of the
engineers that are building it so why
would you want it within the context of
the software that you're purchasing the
software that you're using and how much
of the software that we use is actually
life critical or actually has a substant
substantive substantive impact on our
quality of life on our on the world
around us and we we want those products
to be built within the context of a
culture of quality of delivering the
right thing of doing the right thing and
providing us with value not let's cut
all the corners we possibly can to
deliver more Revenue to our
shareholders right so if you want to
build amazing products rather than
mediocre or even dangerous
products we need to focus on the things
that really matter and you know agile a
agile people talk about agile Frameworks
all the time and how agile Frameworks
were the solution and agile Frameworks
are now the problem none of those things
are
true agile Frameworks are just tools
that we use it's the culture within our
organization that leverages those tools
in a positive or negative way a hammer
is just a tool but you can use it to hit
a nail or you can use it to smack
somebody around the head and which one
is going to add value and which one's
going to land you in jail right so
building those those those cultures of
quality can you what world of culture of
quality did a Volkswagen engineer write
code that determined whether a car was
in a test condition and faked the
results right changed the way the end
didn't fake the results they changed the
way the engine operated in order to get
the results they wanted and the engine
operated differently on the road right
what world of
quality does anybody in your
organization make that sort of decision
no world of quality if you have a
culture of quality you're not going to
have people make that decision and
that's what we need to focus on we need
to focus on building a culture of
engineering Excellence the technical
leadership to set that direction and go
in that direction and we need to build
within our
organization the the knowledge and
understanding of the theories behind the
reasons the things work the way they
work and how we can then apply our
empirical learnings within our context
so every organization's
different with the knowledge of those
theories to then extrapolate what's the
next best decision
that we can make and this is something
that naked agility can help you and your
organization do we cannot do it for you
but we can be there to help you
understand the theories and practices
how they apply within your context and
what are good engineering decisions and
what are bad engineering decisions so
build engineering excellence and
Technical leadership within your
organization