so the
concept that we talk about a
lot from the perspective of modern
software engineering that enables you to
push
quality build quality build security
build these things in from the beginning
build it in rather than testing it in
later is the the concept of shift left
of
moving quality assurance earlier in the
develop M cycle now shifting left is
often controversial cuz when do you stop
how far left should you ship and as far
as I'm concerned it's all the way to the
left the people writing the code should
be the ones that are writing the tests
that should be the ones that are running
the tests that are taking the Fallout
from the tests that are all the way
through to I need to support this if I
wrote the code I need to support this in
production now usually in bigger
products that's team based right so the
team that's working on this feature or
this capability or this part of the
product this area of the product are the
ones that also support it in production
but I don't just mean support it in
production they're they're they're
dealing with the bugs they're dealing
with almost with the support requests
it's probably being in a big
organization it's probably being
filtered through some kind of levels in
a in a center but they need to handle
those support requests and they need to
look at the Telemetry for the
experiments that they're doing and
figure out whether their experiments
successful whether things are right do
we have the right alerts to know when
something's gone wrong with this feature
or capability that is all shifted left
to the engineering team that is building
the product they are building it running
it supporting it maintaining it
validating it going forward into the
future which means you need all of those
skills that in the past you maybe had
dispersed around the organization you
need all of those skills on the
engineering team so usually usually you
have a lot of people who can who can
code right but you also have people who
are who are have security expertise who
have testing and validation expertise
who have user experience expertise all
of those things move further towards the
source of all of our all of our problems
and all of our successes which is which
is building the Cod and in
I in the modern engineering space in
agile practices there are a bunch of
tools and techniques that have kind of
grown in that space to be really popular
um but also um very contentious because
people don't
they don't want to put in one they don't
want to put in the work because they're
more effort to do right so it seems like
we're going to deliver less stuff
because we're spending more time on the
engineering space but because we don't
have that Arc or I don't have is
probably too strong we have less of that
Arc of uh people finding problems in
production we have less of that Arc of
uh reduction in in in brand everybody's
losing their mind because we're we're
we're we're not being presented well in
front of our customers we have less of
that we're on we have an opportunity
here to do stuff but we need to fix this
stuff first because we never fixed it
before we just pushed it out and we
didn't bother with it all of those
things are more effective
therefore when we start shifting left
and we're doing more things from the
perspective of the engineering team it
takes longer to do each thing the first
time but each thing is done more right
and
because the lack of doing things I'm
trying to avoid the term technical debt
because I'm including more things in
this story than just technical debt are
poor engineering practices and poor
quality output right for whatever reason
including technical debt is
is an
exponential problem not a linear problem
problem right because think about if you
build if you built the first story of a
building with substandard materials and
then you built the second story of a
building with substandard materials how
far are you going to get before the
building collapses right now we have an
advantage in the software industry that
we can't build the first level we can
build the first level of the building
quickly and when we go to build the
second level of the building we can go
back and refactor redo any of the things
that we need to enhance the support of
the second story of the building right
this is a terrible analogy but it's
working for me just now and it
enables as as you because you don't know
how many stories your building's going
to have when you're you're you're you're
you're doing software engineering you if
you want to look up the building analogy
look up the Chrysler Building and how
the Chrysler Building was built because
it was effectively built in an agile
manner they didn't know how many stories
they knew roughly but they didn't know
exactly how many stories they were going
to put on it they didn't have all the
materials up front they didn't have a
plan up front um of the the building and
what they were going to do is a great
example of this in that that um physical
space but in the virtual space we can do
test driven development test D driven
development is not about building better
code it's about having better
architectures we create better better
architectures cuz we only create what we
need to support the things that we need
it to do doing pair programming means
that we've got more eyes on the code it
feels like it's going to be less
productive but productivity is not a
moment in time for the engineering team
it needs to be looked at across the
whole system and we can take what seems
like a a hit on productivity to do pair
programming because there's two people
doing things why can't we have them both
doing their own thing but we have less
problems that we need later which are
much more expensive than the pair
programming is at the at the start right
same with test driven development we we
build better architectures so it's
easier to add stuff going forward into
the future and when we do need to
refactor our architecture we have a test
infrastructure to validate at each
change as we make it to make sure that
we're not breaking existing things
existing stories that are supposed to
happen these
tools are fundamentally part of that
story of how do we build a a practice of
engineering Excellence within our
organization and enable enable enable
great things to happen we want to build
great products we want to make great
profits from the great products that we
build and the only way we're going to do
that is is if we do things in a way that
enables us through the future rather
than us getting to a point where we're
drowning under the weight of all the
crap that we've shipped to production
over the years and if you are currently
drowning under the weight of all of that
as the Azure devops team was when they
moved from their waterfall model that
they'd been doing from 200 what let C to
the for five years and then they moved
to continuous delivery to production
they had to go pay back all of those
loans that they'd taken out or for for
for for for the future right but what
they found was that in paying back those
loans they became so much more effective
because of the exponential cost of
taking out those loans they became so
much more effective that in actual fact
the the
the the cost of paying it back was
completely irrelevant to the benefit and
value that they got from it being paid
back that makes sense right they went
they went from from 25 features to
production each year with the same
number of people to nearly nearly 50
features to production each year and
even taking four years to get there holy
moly I would rather have 800 features
than 25 features right and yes the
features are smaller but it's more
experiment right it's more chances to
get something right it's more ideas to
see if they connect with the customer so
in the old ways you you you have to
stick with and focus on something even
when it's not quite the most optimal
thing but if you're doing lots of little
experiments you can find oh this thing
resonates really much more than these
other things with the customer let's do
more on that until it stops resonating
and then we move on to something else
and move on to something else and we
build a better product with more
capabilities so there are lots of tools
and techniques that you can use within
the context of modern software
engineering practices to build quality
in from the start and enabling your
teams to be as effective as possible to
choose the practices because they need
to be able to choose the practices that
work best for their
context that's something that naked
agility can help you with