Moving from a legacy mindset to modern
engineering practices is is more than
just technical, right? Engineering
excellence isn't just technical. It's a
cultural thing within the context of of
of your teams.
If if there isn't a a a a culture of
absorbing change, rolling with the
punches, if there isn't a culture of
continuous learning, of continuous
improvement, if there isn't a culture of
continuously adapting your processes to
what you learn, continuously adapting
your products and your vision to what
you learn, continuously adapting the
work items that you have based on what
you learn and how users engage with it,
then it's going to be very difficult to
move from from a from a a legacy
mindset, which is write it once and it
it's it's there for posterity. Um, to a
a continuously
refactored code base that adapts to your
business's needs in the same way uh uh
that your business's needs adapt, right?
Or at least as close behind as you
possibly can. Um, and that that
migration from um
I've got a legacy system because the the
reality the reality is that the Big Bang
rewrite is a complete fallacy. It hardly
ever works out and it hardly ever costs
what you think it's going to cost. It's
it's usually the most expensive way um
to to rebuild your software. And worse,
if you take all the software engineers
that built your existing legacy, poorly
coded, poorly architected product and
you have them rebuild a new product, why
would you think the outcome uh would be
any different? Why would the new product
be any more um um scalable, sustainable,
um adaptable, testable, maintainable,
right? All the ables. Um why would it be
more of those things than the old one? I
mean, it may be a a little bit more
because people learn over time, but it's
not going to be stick with it more. So,
the way it does work is you you need to
do you need you need to change your
product in place. You don't replace your
product wholesale. You don't build a new
version off on the side. I I see teams,
organizations do that all the time. I I
worked with an organization quite a few
years ago would be years ago and they
were on their fifth attempt at big bang
rewrite of this one product but they
were on their fifth attempt of it. Every
few years they had another attempt and
usually when times are good we're making
a lot of money and then something
happens in the market or whatever and
we're not making so much money. So
what's the project that we cut? this
this current existing product that's
providing us value and and cash flow or
this cost sync of a of an attempted
rewrite that is not providing any value
right now it's it's a total no-brainer
business decision you cancel the new
thing you and they been through six
attempts of it right this is super
common so what we do is we fix our
application in place
yes that's harder Yes, that costs more,
but it doesn't cost more than six
attempts at rewriting because you you
you do each thing right. You you've got
your application, you build a new piece,
you hook it in to the main application,
you do all the testing, validation.
Awesome. We've replaced that piece.
We've added value to the system. The
system is now faster, more scalable,
more sustainable because we've added
this new piece in and we designed it in
the way that solid principles that it's
adaptable and all those kind of things.
So we've got a new piece in but the rest
of our application is still legacy.
What's the next piece we need to go fix
and the piece after that? And if you
have many teams, you can tackle many
pieces at once and continuously
progress your um your your new
application emerges from the old one,
right? Um your new capabilities emerge
from the old one. And that's how you
build sustainable that's how you build
sustainable change. That's how you build
a sustainability mindset into your
teams, into the culture of your
organization,
that you're fixing things as you go,
that you're adapting things as you go,
that you're having to go back and clean
up your own messes, so don't make the
next mess. And that work to do that is
what teaches us, right, to to do it
better the first time, the second time,
right? when we're when we're
refactoring. Oh no, now now I now I've
built this thing. I realize how I should
have built it and I get a chance to
refactor it. I get a chance to change it
and do that continuously for your
application within the context of we're
still adding new features to our
application and you'll get to where you
need to be. It will take time. It will
probably take um longer than just
focusing on a big bang rewrite, but it's
less risky,
less chance of cancelling. Um and you do
both things. You rebuild your product
and you rebuild the culture of your
organization and the mindset from a
legacy mindset towards one of
engineering excellence. Um, and that's
something that I work with teams often
on the
that that idea of fixing things in
place, of adapting the things that we
already have. So, we're adding value,
not cost. And if you want your people to
be as ready as you need your platforms
to be, let us help you make that change
stick.