<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Training Courses on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Training Courses on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Professional Product Discovery and Validation Skills (PPDV)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/professional-product-discovery-and-validation-skills-ppdv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/professional-product-discovery-and-validation-skills-ppdv/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Applying Flow Metrics for Scrum</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/applying-flow-metrics-for-scrum/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/applying-flow-metrics-for-scrum/</guid>
      <description>In the &amp;ldquo;Applying Flow Metrics for Scrum&amp;rdquo; course, participants embark on an immersive learning journey, uniquely designed to integrate flow metrics into their Scrum practices. This course delves deeply into the vital flow metrics such as Work in Progress (WIP), Cycle Time, Work Item Age, and Throughput, unraveling their significance and application in the Scrum framework. Over several weeks, the course unfolds in an interactive, engaging format, blending theoretical understanding with practical, real-world application.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Applying Metrics for Predictability</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/applying-metrics-for-predictability/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/applying-metrics-for-predictability/</guid>
      <description>In today&amp;rsquo;s dynamic business landscape, the ability to provide accurate project timelines, minimize risk, and make data-driven decisions is crucial. Our immersive 8-week course, &amp;ldquo;Applying Metrics for Predictability,&amp;rdquo; empowers you to master agile metrics and forecasting, transforming your approach to project management. Unlike traditional 2-day workshops, our extended format allows for deeper understanding and practical application.&#xA;Over eight weeks, you&amp;rsquo;ll delve into the world of flow metrics, exploring concepts such as Work in Progress (WIP), Cycle Time, and Throughput.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Applying Scaled Portfolio Kanban</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/applying-scaled-portfolio-kanban/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/applying-scaled-portfolio-kanban/</guid>
      <description>Our &amp;lsquo;Applying Scaled Portfolio Kanban&amp;rsquo; course is a game-changer for organizations seeking to enhance their efficiency and effectiveness. With a focus on practical outcomes, this course guides you through setting up transparent systems, aligning work with strategic goals, and managing portfolios effectively. You&amp;rsquo;ll quickly grasp the reasons hindering progress, predict higher-level objectives, and identify opportunities for continuous improvement. By the course&amp;rsquo;s end, you&amp;rsquo;ll validate your organization&amp;rsquo;s effectiveness in delivering the right outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Kata Professional</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/agile-kata-professional/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/agile-kata-professional/</guid>
      <description>The current track record of agile transformations is not very promising. 75% of all agile transformations fail to achieve their goals and therefore missing out on the huge positive impact it has on employee engagement, customer satisfaction, operational performance and time-to-market (McKinsey 2022). Is it because companies see Agile as a business process update and not as a cultural shift?&#xA;Is Business Agility a huge buzzword in your organization, which is difficult to break down into digestible pieces?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Professional Scrum Product Backlog Management Skills (PSPBMS) Course with Certification</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/professional-scrum-product-backlog-management-skills-with-certification/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/professional-scrum-product-backlog-management-skills-with-certification/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to a comprehensive journey into the world of Scrum&amp;rsquo;s Product Backlog Management. This course is meticulously designed to equip participants with the expertise to understand their product&amp;rsquo;s essence, master the Product Backlog, engage effectively with stakeholders, promote transparency, and make data-driven decisions. With sessions ranging from stakeholder motivations to the intricacies of the Product Backlog and empirical decision-making, attendees will gain invaluable insights, irrespective of whether they&amp;rsquo;re Product Owners, Scrum Masters, or Product Managers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Professional Scrum Facilitation Skills (PSFS) with Certification</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/professional-scrum-facilitation-skills-psfs-with-certification/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/professional-scrum-facilitation-skills-psfs-with-certification/</guid>
      <description>[wpv-post-link] is an interactive course designed to help teams and individuals develop proficiency in facilitation skills, so that they can help teams better solve problems, build consensus and foster transparency.&#xA;Great Scrum Teams are self-managing, cross-functional and have the ability and skills necessary to drive to successful outcomes. However, team interactions don’t always go as expected and can cause conflict or roadblocks. Effective facilitation can help the team move forward toward their desired outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Professional Agile Leadership - Evidence-Based Management (PAL-EBM) Course with Certification</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/professional-agile-leadership-with-evidence-based-management-pal-ebm-with-certification/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/professional-agile-leadership-with-evidence-based-management-pal-ebm-with-certification/</guid>
      <description>Professional Agile Leadership with Evidence-Based Management (PAL-EBM) training experience uses a unique blend of self-paced learning, live classroom hands-on activity-based exercises, and community-based aftercare. With markets and customer needs constantly changing, organizations need information and evidence that helps them adapt quickly to new challenges and opportunities so that they can deliver greater value and achieve true business agility.The course goes beyond the topics explored in the Professional Agile Leadership Essentials &amp;amp; Professional Scrum Product Owner (PSPO) classes and deepens participants’ understanding by introducing the four key-value areas and a number of suggested key-value metrics that can help leaders guide their teams toward continuously improving customer outcomes, organizational capabilities, and business results.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Professional Scrum Master and Product Owner (PSMPO) with Certification</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/professional-scrum-master-and-product-owner-psmp-with-certification/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/professional-scrum-master-and-product-owner-psmp-with-certification/</guid>
      <description>Scrum Teams flourish when the Scrum Master and Product Owner accountabilities are well fulfilled. The 3-day Professional Scrum Master and Product Owner (PSMPO) course combines the key learning objectives from both the Scrum.org Professional Scrum Master™ (PSM) and Professional Scrum Product Owner™ (PSPO) courses. Merging PSM and PSPO together enables side-by-side learning in a way that is not possible when Scrum Masters and Product Owners are trained separately. These learners greatly benefit from having a shared understanding for one another and by blending the content, students avoid duplicate foundational content and have more space to focus on learning together.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Professional Scrum Product Owner (PSPO-A) Course with Certification</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/professional-scrum-product-owner-advanced-pspo-a-online-with-certification/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/professional-scrum-product-owner-advanced-pspo-a-online-with-certification/</guid>
      <description>Professional Scrum Product Owner™ - Advanced (PSPO-A) training experience uses a unique blend of self-paced learning, live classroom hands-on activity-based exercises, and community-based aftercare helping experienced Product Owners and Product Managers expand their ability to establish a vision, validate their hypotheses, and ultimately deliver more value to their stakeholders. The course goes beyond the topics explored in the Professional Scrum Product Owner (PSPO) class deepening the attendee&amp;rsquo;s understanding of the role by exploring the many stances of a professional Product Owner.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Applying Professional Kanban (APK) Course with Certification</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/applying-professional-kanban-apk-training-experience-with-certification/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/applying-professional-kanban-apk-training-experience-with-certification/</guid>
      <description>Embark on a continuous learning journey with our updated &amp;lsquo;Applying Professional Kanban&amp;rsquo; course, now offered as an Immersion Training experience. This innovative format extends the learning over several weeks with concise, live sessions, blending real-world application with reflective practice for a truly effective learning journey.&#xA;With incremental classroom learning, outcome-based assignments, and facilitated reflections, this course offers a practical approach to mastering Kanban. Ideal for those who thrive on applying and experimenting in real-time work environments, this immersive strategy ensures deeper understanding, collaborative growth, and the ability to make an immediate positive impact in your professional setting.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assuring Quality Using Azure Test Plans Training</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/assuring-quality-using-azure-test-plans-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/assuring-quality-using-azure-test-plans-training/</guid>
      <description>Azure DevOps Services provide a set of cloud-hosted tools that software teams can use as an end-to-end solution to plan, develop, test, and deliver value in the form of working software. Azure Test Plans enable a team to plan, track, and assess quality throughout the entire development effort. This one day course will demonstrate how an agile team can configure and use Azure Test Plans to effectively assure quality in web and desktop applications.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Managing Projects Using Azure Boards Training</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/managing-projects-using-azure-boards-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/managing-projects-using-azure-boards-training/</guid>
      <description>Azure DevOps Services provide a set of cloud-hosted tools that software teams can use as an end-to-end solution to plan, develop, test, and deliver value in the form of working software. Azure Boards enable an agile team to plan, track, and discuss work across the entire development effort. This one day course will demonstrate how an agile team can configure and use Azure Boards effectively. To maximize learning, students will work in teams, in a common team project, on a common case study.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mastering Azure Repos Training</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/mastering-azure-repos-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/mastering-azure-repos-training/</guid>
      <description>Azure DevOps Services provide a set of cloud-hosted tools that software teams can use to quickly plan, develop, test, and deliver value in the form of working software. Azure Repos provide public or private Git repositories that enable better collaboration and cleaner code. To maximize learning, students will work in teams, in a common team project, on a common codebase.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Practicing Kanban Using Azure Boards Training</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/practicing-kanban-using-azure-boards-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/practicing-kanban-using-azure-boards-training/</guid>
      <description>All software development teams have a desire to increase their flow and throughput. With the powerful combination of Kanban and Azure Boards, they can do just that. This one day course will introduce Kanban and demonstrate how an agile team can configure and use Azure Boards to effectively practice Kanban, achieve flow, and begin improving throughput and predictability. To maximize learning, students will work in teams, in a common team project, on a common case study.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scrum for Executives Training</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/scrum-for-executives-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/scrum-for-executives-training/</guid>
      <description>This instructor-led class is intended to answer three questions commonly asked by executives, managers, and other decision-makers: What is Scrum? Why should I care? and What will be expected of me to properly adopt Scrum? Through presentation and discussion, attendees will learn the answers to these questions. By forming into teams and collaborating on activities, attendees will further experience these truths.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scrum for Product Owners Training</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/scrum-for-product-owners-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/scrum-for-product-owners-training/</guid>
      <description>This instructor-led class is intended to help Product Owners be more effective in their role. Through a combination of presentation, discussion, and hands-on activities, attendees will learn the responsibilities and preferred practices of being the member of the Scrum Team who drives the value.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scrum for Stakeholders Training</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/scrum-for-stakeholders-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/scrum-for-stakeholders-training/</guid>
      <description>This instructor-led class is intended to answer three questions commonly asked by Stakeholders: What is Scrum? Why will Scrum be better for me? How will I work differently going forward. Through presentation and discussion, attendees will learn the answers to these questions. By forming into teams and collaborating on activities and discussions, attendees will experience and see the truth behind those answers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Professional Scrum Product Owner (PSPO) Course with Certification</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/professional-scrum-product-owner-pspo-with-certification/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/professional-scrum-product-owner-pspo-with-certification/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the Professional Scrum Product Owner (PSPO) course. This transformative learning journey is designed specifically for Product Owners, Leaders, Entrepreneurs, and Managers eager to deeply understand and incorporate Scrum values and principles into their work. The course offers practical case studies and engaging exercises to ensure a hands-on learning experience.&#xA;In the ever-evolving product landscape, a thorough understanding of Scrum is not just beneficial but essential for modern teams. Scrum practices equip organizations with the agility, responsiveness, and efficiency needed to thrive amidst changing market dynamics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Professional Scrum Master Advanced (PSM-A) with Certification</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/professional-scrum-master-advanced-psm-a-with-certification/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/professional-scrum-master-advanced-psm-a-with-certification/</guid>
      <description>The Professional Scrum Master II (PSM-A) course is a 2-day advanced Scrum Master class designed to support Scrum Masters in their professional development. The PSM II course is intended for Scrum Masters with at least one year of experience who are looking to grow their knowledge and abilities as a Scrum Master. This course is one step in that journey. The course also includes a free attempt at the globally recognized Professional Scrum Master II (PSM II) certification exam.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Professional Scrum with User Experience (PSU) with Certification</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/professional-scrum-with-user-experience-psu-with-certification/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/professional-scrum-with-user-experience-psu-with-certification/</guid>
      <description>Should UX be part of the Scrum Team? UX/CX plays a critical role in successful product development. Participants explore Professional Scrum and Lean UX through a unique blend of self-paced learning, live classroom hands-on activity-based exercises, and community-based aftercare.&#xA;Throughout the class and between sessions, students leverage Lean UX techniques focusing on the core design and research activities that illustrate how they come together with development and delivery. Attendees explore how these activities fit into a dual-track agile process (Design and Development) where cross-functional teams can work together to explore, experiment and deliver value-based outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Continuous Delivery Using Azure DevOps Services Training</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/continuous-delivery-using-azure-devops-services-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/continuous-delivery-using-azure-devops-services-training/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Managing Projects Using Visual Studio and Scrum Training</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/managing-projects-using-visual-studio-and-scrum-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/managing-projects-using-visual-studio-and-scrum-training/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Professional Scrum with Kanban (PSK) with Certification</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/professional-scrum-with-kanban-psk-with-certification/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/professional-scrum-with-kanban-psk-with-certification/</guid>
      <description>Professional Scrum with Kanban™ (PSK) training experience uses a unique blend of self-paced learning, live classroom hands-on activity-based exercises, and community-based aftercare. It helps experienced Scrum practitioners implement a Kanban strategy within the context of Scrum to help actively improve the effectiveness of their team.The course goes beyond the topics explored in the Professional Scrum Master (PSM) &amp;amp; Professional Scrum Product Owner (PSPO) classes and deepens participants&amp;rsquo; understanding by introducing lean practices.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Professional Agile Leadership Essentials (PAL-e) with Certification</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/professional-agile-leadership-essentials-pal-e-with-certification/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/professional-agile-leadership-essentials-pal-e-with-certification/</guid>
      <description>Professional Agile Leadership (PAL-e) Essentials is a modular workshop, adaptable up to 2-days in length based on the needs of your organization. The workshop provides a foundation for the role that leaders play in creating the conditions for a successful agile transformation. Leaders and managers are critical enablers in helping their organizations be successful, yet the role of leaders and managers in an agile organization can be quite different from what they are used to.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Applying Professional Scrum (APS) Course with Certification</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/applying-professional-scrum-aps-with-certification/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/applying-professional-scrum-aps-with-certification/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the [wpv-post-link] course. This transformative learning journey is designed specifically for Team Members, Scrum Masters, Product Owners, and Managers keen to grasp and infuse Scrum values and principles into their work through practical case studies leveraging the engaging medium of Minecraft.&#xA;The product landscape keeps evolving, and a comprehensive understanding of Scrum is beneficial and crucial for contemporary teams. Agile practices empower organisations to be more flexible, responsive, and efficient amidst fluctuating market dynamics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Applying Professional Scrum for Software Development (APS-SD) with Certification</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/applying-professional-scrum-for-software-development-aps-sd-with-certification/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/applying-professional-scrum-for-software-development-aps-sd-with-certification/</guid>
      <description>Experience the Power of Applying Professional Scrum™ for Software Development (APS-SD) in our immersive course. Get ready to embark on a hands-on journey where you&amp;rsquo;ll learn firsthand how to deliver top-notch software using Scrum, Agile, and DevOps practices.&#xA;In this dynamic course, you won&amp;rsquo;t just study theory but actively participate in Scrum Teams, engaging in a series of Sprints. Through real-world scenarios, you&amp;rsquo;ll dive deep into the Scrum framework while putting it into practice.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Professional Scrum Master (PSM) Course with Certification</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/professional-scrum-master-psm-with-certification/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/professional-scrum-master-psm-with-certification/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the Professional Scrum Master (PSM) course. This transformative learning journey is designed specifically for Agile Leaders, Product Owners, and Managers eager to understand and incorporate Scrum values and principles into their leadership repertoire.&#xA;The Scrum landscape is continuously evolving, and command over Scrum methodologies is no longer a luxury but a necessity for modern business leaders. Scrum practices enable organizations to be more adaptable, responsive, and effective in changing market dynamics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scaled Professional Scrum with Nexus (SPS) with Certification</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/scaled-professional-scrum-with-nexus-sps-with-certification/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/scaled-professional-scrum-with-nexus-sps-with-certification/</guid>
      <description>The Scaled Professional Scrum is a hands-on, activity-based course where students develop a collection of skills that can be applied to overcome challenges when scaling Scrum. Even after achieving success with Scrum, teams are still limited by the amount of work they can do and the value they can create. They need to expand, or scale, to a group of Scrum Teams working together on the same product. When doing so, they often encounter common challenges with cross-team dependencies, self-management, transparency and accountability.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Requirements Workshop</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/agile-requirements-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/agile-requirements-workshop/</guid>
      <description>This workshop includes guided discussion focusing on agile requirements management and planning practices for agile teams, projects, and products. Covers medium and long term planning needs and results in a backlog for the steps needed to establish a solid requirements management practice within your organisation.&#xA;We start by diving into a piece of work that has already been delivered. Hindsight gives the team the ability to really break the desirement down into the things that they really did deliver.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering Practices Workshop</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/engineering-practices-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/training-courses/engineering-practices-workshop/</guid>
      <description>This workshop includes instructor demo and guided discussion focusing on agile software engineering practices. The instructor will cover relevant engineering and ALM (Application Lifecycle Management) practices.&#xA;Request Course Download Syllabus</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
