hello
let's check
okay
it's working
foreign
thank you
blah blah blah
hey manjit
hey
yes did you get my replies
oh yeah here we go
so if you're if you're if you're in
if you're physically in the meeting the
breakout rooms is going to be disrupted
if you're not participating
so i'm
um i've set up
a way of recording that we didn't have
last time
uh that doesn't use
teams to do the recording because teams
doesn't capture the mural right so it
captures the right thing
so in in um i give you a link yeah to uh
a way you can
view
without participating
oh we're bringing it okay okay yeah
perfect yeah it's so it's a it's uh
that'll be
probably the easiest way to do the
recording as well although i'll probably
create a local recording too
[Music]
thank you perfect there's a little bit
of a delay
i think it's about 10 or 15 seconds
between
uh real time and that but i'll let
everybody know that it's being recorded
and all that kind of molarity
okay
magic you're okay with me recording it
aren't you
oh
it's gone
lua quiet
right let me go fix this
sunny how are you doing
how are you i'm doing okay
stanley as well
maybe
hi ah hey stanley
i am
hoping we'll have quite a few people for
this but you guys are the first ones
here um hi david how you doing
um
just to let you know we are
going to record this session so that
you can see it afterwards okay
so if anybody uh
has
has has a problem
let me know
but i
can't record so the reason teams
doesn't have a little record icon
on it is because it is impossible to
record with mural uh the way the way i
facilitate these things using teams so i
have a different method
that takes a feed
from teams a feed from uh mural
it combines them and creates a a special
recording
for us so it will only show it won't
show everybody it will only show the the
active speaker and myself as well as the
the mural um so that's all it's going to
show on the recording
does that make
sense i'm just going to um
manage it still here what i am going to
do is i am going to uh
create some breakout rooms to get us
started as people arrive
and we'll see how many how many people
we get so let me manually create the
breaker rooms
and i'm gonna do let's do five just in
case
sunny were you at the last session yes
cool welcome back
um
so let's see
let's do at sunny
stanley and
i'm gonna put you guys in room one
okay
and i'm gonna put uh jose
and david in room two and oh actually
wait a minute before i even do that yes
cancel um are you on the mural yet no
you're not on the mural yet uh so let me
send you the link for the mural
i just copied it again i'm gonna put it
in the chat
okay
so i put it in the chat that you should
have access to it there i'll make sure
it ends up in the meeting invite was it
useful me saying that meeting invite out
at the last minute
sonny was that was that handy to get
into the right place
cool
um unfortunately i can't send to gis
sjm the the the group
that manjie added
um but
uh
david's
david's here we can start
so
um
let me i'm just putting the mural in the
meeting invite just in case uh anybody
was unable to to find it i've put it in
the chat but you know how it is
sometimes you can't see the history of
the chat uh so i see there's a few
people in the mural uh i'm gonna summon
you to where we're gonna be something
called a fast pass
um it's just to get everybody everybody
started and while we wait for the for
the lagards
to arrive uh as people uh finish up
their previous meetings because you know
what it's like everything ends up back
to back
so what i've got is i've got five rooms
here i'm going to put you into to groups
of probably
three or so as we get started um so that
you can have
start having a chat and i'd like you to
talk about
these statements
that we have here on the mural so if i
summon everybody just to one of them if
you end up in one
right and it will say the room number at
the top of your team's window
and then go to the room one area and
kind of discuss each of these seven
questions and put either a tick
oh i zoomed in a bit there uh tick or a
cross on top of the statement on whether
you believe it to be true or false
okay
and just have a have a have a chat about
each one so what i'm going to do let me
let's see we've got one two three four
we've got five at the moment
so let me
where's my breakout rooms
assignments
what says we've got seven now but let's
see
uh
david
oh will we put two davids in the same
room that'll make things confusing david
jose and simona i'll put you guys in
room one
and then other david
um
stanley and sunny i'll put you guys in
room two
does that sound good
so i want you to to try and uh complete
that first
exercise uh
see what you know already about this
topic
because you heard of scrum
have you heard of scrum's honey this
thing that people do yeah
so maybe we have some assumptions we
probably know a lot of stuff already
because people have told us so
um
hopefully oh i need to click the open
button don't i that would probably help
so i've opened the breakout rooms
um and in your your groups just chat
about what you think
these statements are true or false
let me make that
oh well that's not the right button how
do i do a full screen in
teams now
in a
oh that's why function 11 there we go
manjit if you can uh hear me there are
uh six people
here um
i guess we were hoping for uh more
but just let me know
i'm doing a an exercise with them just
now so that they can um
just get it a little bit start and think
about some of these questions i might
have to pop in and help them but
um we'll see
is everybody here or are people another
in the other room
let me check yeah
nobody in the other room
okay so we have we have six people just
now
are you are you expecting more
well i think well yeah last time we had
uh we had this same people when my kid
then attended the introduction to asia
yeah
i don't know what's going
on so i was unable to send my invite to
the gis group
the the
the group email
oh okay so perhaps
i could only invite the people that were
exactly on the list so you might need to
to send out
that update if you copy the contents of
my
meeting
that's fine okay cool yeah yeah
let's have a look at what they're doing
well simone is there so is someone is
here
yeah
we have um
david bauer simona jose sunny stanley
and other davido david or maddie if
someone is there then she would have
received it
maybe there's another meeting going on
that's running over
[Music]
that's why i do this past beginning just
to get people people started
i i
i'm gonna go changing
okay i'm gonna go check on one of the
groups
okay
group two
not struggling but
you know
how to attend or or can
cancel still operate effectively but
that can be better
the upgrades are flexible for that
particular meeting now we know what to
do
right so yeah
but
initially we were a bit confused as to
why we're in this school
um developers
um commit to deliver the sprint backlog
at
the sprint planned event
yeah yeah i think um is that that's a
good team i mean but yeah i guess you do
yeah yeah yeah
and then at the davis scrum
the developers must
say what
did they do yesterday what are they
doing today and what what yeah and
what's blocking them that's those are
three questions to be asked for every
scrum
yeah quite strange why
we only got six people
that's okay i can work with six yeah
yeah
might make things less of a ruckus
uh looks like they've all answered the
questions so i'm going to close the room
and bring them back
three people from my team are i think
we're running the previous meeting so
they'll probably join soon
okay
welcome
jose sonny i can see you guys
how did you get on
uh yeah fine um generally we had
consensus um
this the values there
uh there is not consensus currently
between the two teams which is
interesting the two groups
so uh on number six the scrum master
does not have to attend the daily scrum
group one said uh uh well yes they do
have to attend and group two said no
it's okay if they don't attend and then
for
you must
finish
all of the things in your sprint backlog
by the end of the sprint group one said
yes
you must
and group two said it's okay if you
don't
why why why why a discrepancy
well we were coming from the basis that
if the scrum master has set up
objectives and these you know completely
defined targets and so on he doesn't
necessarily need to be there if the team
is in power to deliver i i i'm hoping
we're going to be answering the question
for you sonny on why the scrum master
should be doing none of those things
okay
definitely doing none of those things
but
let's uh
reveal
what the correct answers are
over here on the right
[Music]
so i'm just going to zoom in i'll summon
everybody so we're all looking at the
same thing
you'll probably remember what you put
scrum teams must not be bigger than 10
people
it's okay if you've ever taken a 12.
that could work it might be more
difficult jose for sure
right it might be more difficult but
it's okay there's nothing in the the in
scrum that says you can't do that
isn't there like an upper limit or is
that just sort of it's it's like a it's
not hard
i think the exact phrase the using the
scrum guide is
typically not more than 10
right right but if you have more than 10
and it works for you
who is scrum to say that that's not okay
right but you are right typically the
more people you have on the team the
more complex
things are but if you guys can handle it
you guys can handle it that's okay are
you doing well you deliver software are
you
finishing stuff
uh what was question two the scrum
master is there to make sure that the
developers take enough work and get it
done
no they're not there for that
they're there to help the team be more
effective
number three at the daily scrum the
developers must say what did they do
yesterday what am i doing today
and what's blocking them
i think the key word there is must
right i know that many teams do use
those three questions
but what what's the purpose of the daily
scrum jose
why are we there
well
my my thought is it's a sort of
coordination quick coordination type
meeting so that
everyone's aware
you know what's going on and um
i guess the scrum master can deal with
any blockers that have come up
okay
so
let's see
well uh if you take into account the
answer to number six
the scrum master does not even have even
uh have to attend the daily scrum being
correct the scrum master may not be
there
then they'll have to sort out amongst
themselves they'll have to sort it out
amongst themselves what's what's the
purpose of our sprint
what are we trying to do what we why we
there why is somebody paying us money to
sprint
because they want something at the end
don't they
they want some value
is there is there value for your
stakeholders
in what tasks we're working on just now
well in the sense that they contribute
to the
yes i
i i i agree
um
do
if we thought at the beginning of us i'm
not particularly picking on you i'm just
uh this is this is this is good this is
good um
what
what um
if at the beginning of the sprint
we thought it would take five tasks to
complete something
does that mean it will take five tasks
to complete something
maybe not right
so
the if the focus is on
me
i'm an individual team member
what have i done yesterday what am i
doing tomorrow and what's blocking me
where's
the team
what's the team trying to achieve the
team's trying to achieve completing
value
to deliver to the stakeholders at the
end of the sprint
so instead of looking at those three
questions right which are actually no
longer in the scrum guide they
definitely used to be right as a here's
one way to do that
but i i think it's good to focus on the
value here's the things that we're
trying to deliver for the stakeholders
where are they are they on track are
they not on track um and focusing on
that value can really help bring the
team together
to to focus on that so that's that
that's that's a good one for that josie
that was that was uh uh uh some good uh
interactions there
number four was um at sprint review the
developers present their work to the
product owner i think everybody had a
tick for that one didn't they
yeah
no
the product owners presenting their work
to the stakeholders
the product owner should already have
been involved with the developers
understand what's going on
know what they've built
you know
something that i've seen quite a lot in
sprint reviews
and that always
it kind of upsets me a little bit it
makes me feel sad for the team
and that's when the stakeholders turn to
the product owner and say why did you
build it that way
and then the product owner instead of
standing in front of their team and
defending the decision that was made in
the circumstances that we had turns to
the team and says yeah why did you build
it that way
how's that for passing the buck
who's accountable for value delivery in
scrum
product owner
they should they should be standing out
in front saying this is what i built for
you this sprint this is what my team
created
for you
yeah so it is
it's subtle right
from uh from a mechanical standpoint
it's subtle
but it creates a massive difference in
the way people feel
in the way people engage with the
process
uh and then we've got number five the
age old you must finish everything in
your sprint and there was definitely
mixed
answers there you don't have to finish
everything that you bring into your
sprint that would be ridiculous
right and i'll tell you why it's
ridiculous who's heard of the iron
triangle
i have iron triangle
so it's a traditional project management
[Music]
conundrum
right we have a triangle going to bring
a little triangle in here at the bottom
there
what are the
the vectors that we have on our triangle
in project management
we have um
time don't
we we get time
and then we've got
um
well sometimes it's it's it's often
called
resources but really it's money
right because people people are your
biggest cost when you're when you're
building stuff generally right i know if
you're oh
if you if you're deploying sap that
might not necessarily be true because
that thing's expensive oh i can't i
can't move them around never mind
uh murals being a bit of a poop at the
moment what's the what's the last one
we've got time resources are people
thank you for that i was trying it yeah
trying to move it over a bit so it's
inside the box but that it's okay
um
i need to refresh my role in order for
it to work for me
it's built in javascript
always causes problems
to get time resources what else do we
have
requirements
yeah what do we generally cut in the
project management world
scope
right
so
what what happens
if you have fixed time fixed resources
fixed scope
what's your experience what happened
sonny
fix time fix resources fixed scope
um
well it depends i mean if the scope is
fixed i'm likely to be able to deliver
that project if they escape free i you
know
i'm moving away from what we
originally agreed and then that's going
to impact my delivery together
if you if you have
complex cognitive work right if you
remember from the last session we talked
about this this building stuff that
doesn't exist yet is complex cognitive
work
what could we cut
in order to deliver on time on budget on
resources
if those things are fixed there's
something else there's actually another
metric that we can we can change
as a team
in order to deliver on time on budget on
scope
even if those
that scope is ridiculous even that if
that time is ridiculous even if the
money's next to nothing
sorry i couldn't hear that
i think somebody's mic's not working
very well it's very quiet i don't know
if ever anybody else caught that it
could be my ears
but it's a bit in the middle
is quality
right that's largely hidden
in complex cognitive work till you find
out at the end it's a big steaming pile
of
poop
right that's delivered to the customer
and the customer is like why is this
broken and this doesn't work and when i
click here i get this error and what's
going on why is this not working
right that's your quality
if you put people doing complex
cognitive tasks
under pressure
to deliver scope within a fixed time
fixed resources
they will continuously and increasingly
cut quality
to meet whatever ridiculous time frame
you give them
right have you ever there's a there's a
youtube video
of an artist drawing spider-man
right and it's just a hand pencil
drawing spider-man i i don't have the
youtube video or otherwise i'd play it
for you but it it's awesome if i if i if
you if you had this expert artist that
draws spider-man all the time
and it takes them usually about 10
minutes they can draw a pretty good
spider-man
right if you give them 10 minutes
you're going to get a pretty
nice-looking spider-man aren't you
what happens if you give them one minute
what's going to happen to the quality of
the product the scope is the same
the resources are the same
but we've reduced the time and it's
still fixed
so what can that person change in order
to deliver inside of that minute
quality
you can have a you're you're going to
have a lesser spiderman a lesser
delivery
what what would happen if you gave him
10 seconds
you're gonna have a little stick figure
spiderman you
right and that that's actually the the
the example they give in the youtube
video is those three scenarios drawing
spider-man 10 minutes one minute one
minute spider-man was
it still looked like spider-man
10 seconds spider-man 10 seconds
spider-man sucks
right and that's the software we're
often delivering the 10 second
spider-man
so in in scrum
right if i grab a little line
we've got a fixed time because we have
an agreed sprint length
right
in scrum we've got a fixed resources
because
we have an agreed team
right maybe
this sprint that you've got a team of
five next sprint you've got a team of
six the sprint after that you've got a
team of five right that could be the
changes between sprints but generally
you want to keep it stable at least
inside of a sprint
right you might have to call on external
experts and that can anything but you
want to keep it reasonably stable
and
so then then our only options for what
we can flex to deliver on time
is scope or quality which one do you
want to compromise on
which one do you believe
your cfo
who's looking at the capital expenditure
investment in
software would expect you to compromise
on
is your cfo going to be happy with
shitty quality
no
so
you're not going to be able to sell your
ceo on can we have a hundred grand and
deliver you 10 grand worth of software
right he's not you're not going to be
able to sell him on that so in in the
scrum world
we fix quality
right let me know how we do that in the
scrum team
with the scrum team there's a particular
thing in scrum that we use for that
is that the definition of done it is
absolutely the definition of done
right that's our sacrosanct commitment
from the team to deliver a minimum level
of quality
okay
and the level of quality since the team
to deliver on it they have to agree with
it
right but you might have organizational
standards as well like what's the main
level of quality your cfo expects your
products to have
in order because remember
your cfo's gonna put those products on a
balance sheet somewhere
right capital expenditure gets written
down he's telling the tax man
i spent 100 grand i got 100 grand worth
of stuff and it burns down at this rate
each year
what else if you like the pax man
regardless of whether you know you're
lying or not
does the tax man care whether you know
no he does not
he does not care
he would call that fraud and you'd be
not in a good place
okay so quality is really important like
it is one of the most important aspects
of this
so the thing that we can flex
actually the least important
piece of what we deliver
is often the scope and i'll hopefully
explain why it's the scope we go
right
um we want to achieve goals
not number of items
if we achieve the goal for the
stakeholders and the stakeholders are
happy does it doesn't matter whether we
delivered five things or ten things
if we achieved what they wanted no it
doesn't they don't care they don't care
whether they do five things or tactics
or hopefully they don't we need to train
them too
did that make sense for that iron angle
reference that i had
yeah
ah
we covered the scrum master not ending
doesn't have to attend
right what what happens um
oh yeah
developers commit to deliver the sprint
backlog at the sprint planning event i
think everybody had a tick in that one
didn't they
didn't we just fix scope again
we did we just fixed scope again
right
it's it's very easy for us to trick
ourselves back into fixing scope
you're always going to lose with fixed
scope you have to have variable scope
because we've got fixed time we've got
fixed resources we want to fix quality
so the only thing we can vary is scope
so that that i
there's nothing wrong with your answers
the reason i ask these questions at the
start
is they are super common
that this is how they get answered
yeah
that's why i'm asking them specifically
because they are they are
pretty common for that
so we have there are six of us
seven with manjeet if i can
con him into participating
um
so that makes eight with me so i think
i think i'd like to find out
what you already know
about what's required for scrum what do
we have to have
in order to be doing scrum
so there are some things that are are
maybe how did any of you read the scrum
guide i've read the scrum guide i think
manjit has
okay no so okay so we're going from
what have we seen teams do
what have we heard
them talk out
okay
does that make sense we've not read the
rule book we're trying to play the we're
trying to play the game
so we can only go by what people are
telling us they're doing
okay
um so what i'd like you to do we're
going to do something called a it's
called a one two four all exercise i
think we did one last time if you were
here at last time
so i'm going to create um
three
wait a minute there's eight of us
because i'm gonna call manjit into this
one
um there's eight of us
so i'm going to create four rooms
and
we're gonna
i'd like you to
we're gonna first do one minute
on your own creating a list of things
that you think are required for scrum
right and that required word is
important what is required
and then we're going to go into breakout
rooms with pairs
okay and we're going to merge our two
lists
we're going to merge them together so we
end up with one list and we'll have two
minutes for that
and then i'm going to merge two of the
breakout rooms so there'll be four of us
in a room okay that's five fingers four
of us in a room
right but two lists
because we already merged them and we're
gonna merge them together again so when
we come back at the end we'll have two
lists here
that we can then merge together does
that make sense
cool so i'm going to put a timer on for
one minute
for you to silently and you're on your
own uh create that list and whoever ends
up with me it will be lucky because my
list will probably be fairly
well i hope my list is fairly fairly
fairly good
um
sorry maxine can you repeat um
what was required for
just the
yeah so i'd like you to create a list of
uh
things that you know of that are
required for scrum that are needed for
us to be doing scrum
um
how much time have i got left
well time box expired i only got one two
three four five i only got six things on
my list but that's my typing capability
rather than anything else
i'm going to open the breakout rooms we
go into pairs
and get your items down on the mural
right if you did it in notepad like the
explanation then you can just paste it
in that's what i'm going to do um if you
wrote it down you can join them together
in your in your group and you'll have
two minutes in pairs and then i'll merge
the rooms together okay
david omari i'm sorry you draw the short
straw and you are going to end up in a
room with me
i will make sure that everybody gets
into the room and then i'll uh
pop in with you okay
so everybody will have two minutes okay
everybody's gone
hey
looks good
david
pick a pick a color
just tell me what it is
blue blue okay we'll have blue there's
blue okay uh what things did you have on
your list
scrum team
okay master
sprint planning
daily scrum
sprint review
sprint wrecks of rest breakfast tracks
product backlog
sprint backlog
product backlog and sprint back clock
can you see where i am on the mural um
if i if i asked to be false in fact
are you on the mural
i'm just gonna go back in okay
i've added the cards so we've got
product owner scrum master scrum team
developers product backlog sprint
backlog daily scrum increments
oh i've got to end up with two sprint
back clocks did i no scrum team sprint
planning sprint backlog sprint
retrospective
see where is it supposed to be wrong get
confused so if you if you at the middle
of the mural in the middle there's a
little picture of me on the far left
with a star if you hover over my picture
there'll be a follow button pops up and
then you'll yeah
there we go there we go
yeah i
just got um
sprint teams from master
sprint planning daily scrum
sprint review
sprint retrospect
[Music]
when we do the user stories and we do
the um scoring i've got the names that
we um
efforts now when you do the effort on
the user stories
uh
yeah just uh uh when you do the effort
at story points story points could you
add story points to the mural while i uh
organize all of the participants into
uh
i'll bring him into one
uh so
four
goes into one
four goes into one
uh
[Music]
three goes into two
three goes into two let's assign that
there we go move
and the new person coming in so
hopefully
this will all work out
so uh so did you add story points
um yes yes yes i was just moving the
rooms
four
yeah
all the way
definitely dip those things that's a
good idea
yeah otherwise
uh i see you've got story points there
i'm gonna bring i'll bring that one down
here
there we go
so we've kind of got people
artifacts and then some events are we
missing some events we've got
retrospective sprint panning daily scrum
would you find matches missing
and sprint review
two things we need is a
definition of readiness definition ready
for a story and in a dod
you can make
martian happy
yep i can't spell that definition i've
never been able to spell that word
but i did put them on there
it's just it's it's a dyslexic thing i i
spell it the way it sounds and that
doesn't work for the spell checker yeah
yeah yeah
anything else and where
what about like the stakeholders
shouldn't they be oh that's a good idea
yeah
stakeholders is a good idea would be
useful yeah
um
a release plan
what else
what else do we need
what do you hear your team's talking
about you need
gold spring gold
just under all just over a minute left
what else do we need
maybe that's it maybe that's it yeah
future timeline no that's not really
that's the kind of bike product isn't it
there are definitely certain things in
scrum that are implicit in other things
so they're not mentioned
right
so things like a a a a release plan
right that might be implicit in
something else but it's okay to have it
on the list because then we can figure
out what it's implicit in
right it's a thing we have
so we get story points user stories
definition of ready definition of done
beam velocity
oh team velocity
burn down
oh yep burn down
it's a good one
oh well i'm going to close the room
slide
where is this a spring celebration
i put a magic funded party on there
yeah yeah yeah
at the end of the sprint
i think my teams is working now it's
been a bit slow
being a bit slow
okay we've got quite a lot of things on
these
two lists
um so let's bring across
what the other uh group had
um
did maggie make it in or did she
disappear i think maggie disappeared
he said he has already attended one of
yours before okay uh sunny graham and
david just looking at your list you get
team members
um
which we don't have product owner uh we
have that on our list developer
is it developer or developers is that
the same thing
i think it's the same thing isn't it
same thing yeah scrum master we have
that over there
uh backlog
objectives i like objectives let's bring
that one over
uh
collaboration with the product owner
that is definitely an activity we need
uh stories in a definition of done uh
can we separate that out into two things
we have user stories
here and definition of done down here is
that okay does that cover both of those
yeah yep cool so we got team members
sprint length back clock
this is a pretty good list i think
oh let me see if i can make them all the
same
size which is this button
there we go now everything's the same
size
i think we're missing some things
i they're missing some interesting
things
do you remember
on monday
when we talked about
agility
we did an
exercise
with the the
agile manifesto
where we came up with a list of items
that
were valid for great teams
and they all ended up on the left hand
side didn't they
people and interactions the only people
in interactions here we've got is this
one collaboration with the product
owners
all all of this other stuff seems to be
about
rigidity and how we do things that's
processes and tools isn't it
[Music]
so so we're missing a lot of that other
stuff
where does it come in
there was a responsibility
probably i would say well we have we
have the roles but the roles in their
accountability
that's that's that's procedure
right that's uh that's a a practice we
should have a product owner because the
scrum guy tells us to
right isn't that processes and tools
that's that side isn't it but
to make a great team
you want
the roles that you need
i don't think that the roles are i have
worked on many great teams
that don't have anybody called a product
owner
maybe don't have anybody
called a scrum master
does that does a does a soccer team need
a scrum master or a product toner
yeah they're the captain
are they on the field with them
captain is here the captain is
so we are missing something and what
we're missing
is
a value system
we're missing values we want to
help
shape
people and behaviors
we want positive outcomes for people and
behaviors we want to get transparency
right and transparency is hard
sunny if i asked you to provide data on
how many hours per day you worked but
every day you showed me the number of
hours and i wasn't happy with you
because the numbers didn't look like i
wanted them to look
and i was your your your direct report
what sorry the other way around
what what would your behavior
result in what might that metric that
measure
you're always i'm american i think you
must do 40 hours a week you're telling
me you're doing 37 and a half hours a
week i'm not happy
what are you going to tell me
i would skew the data you would skew the
data yeah
yeah
so funnily enough i i used to work at a
little company called merrill lynch
and at merrill lynch being an american
company in order to get paid
every employee must
enter 40 hours a week into timesheet
system
it didn't matter that nobody in europe
worked 40 hours a week we had to find a
project in order to allocate the extra
two and a half hours
because we did 37.5 hours
they didn't care the systems were just
doing it that way that's the way we do
things here
so if you measure people
in a way
that makes it difficult for them to
achieve
or hard or impossible
they'll fuse the data
do you think that happens on the big
scale as well sonny
i would have thought so
our recent one is volkswagen
volkswagen was caught faking the
emissions data
why because it was impossible
for diesel cars to meet the emission
standards that were put on them
it was not possible to sell a product
that met the emission standard so they
faked the data
right it's just how humans work
so we need to figure out a way how do we
create a system
within which people want to do the right
thing they want to be transparent they
don't feel like they're going to be
victimized is probably too strong a word
right but um blamed
for
data not looking good data is about the
real world
so one of those ways is we have
something in scrum called the the scrum
values
okay
and the scrum values are courage
focus
respect
openness and commitment
but each of those
can't exist in isolation
if you have courage
without respect
you might call your boss an [__]
and that's not going to be conducive to
having continued employment is it
right so we need the balance of all of
these things
so in this
exercise going to be interesting because
i have not run it with only eight people
before so we'll see
uh uh how this how this uh how much fun
we have
um oh there's a little post-it come in
ah
somebody's already started adding
post-its you guys are keen
okay so in the scrum valve circuit
we're gonna break up into into into
groups i'm thinking it kind of needs to
be
groups of two
well maybe can we do three
no
because that would require nine of us
so it need to be groups of two
okay
let me create that so we'll do groups of
two
and we're going to do this scrum values
circuit think of it like a circuit you
would do at the gym do you go to them
jose
no
now okay so this is this is this is
circuit training we have we have five
stations here
okay for the circuit training and we
have three groups
okay
what we're going to do
and i am going to
so five and three
this is hard let's do
i'm trying to sorry i'm trying to get my
brain around the numbers because we need
to move between the stations
um
it would be better if there was six
values wouldn't it because then numbers
would add up better for me three
any odd number is just difficult uh so i
think yes we'll do we'll do three groups
and it will be one
one three and five that's what i'm gonna
do one and i'm gonna rename this group
from two
to three
and this one from three to five because
i think that's gonna work better or it's
gonna work just as bad as i think it's
going to work so let's see how that goes
so what we're going to do is when you
get into the the exercise
into the breakout room
i'd like you to look at the top of your
breakout room and you'll have a room
number
i'm going to tell you what it is just
now but the room number will be at the
top of your your screen
so david graham and david
randomly created
are going to be in room one that stanley
and manjeet are going to be in room two
and jose and sunny are going to be in
room five okay
i want you to go to the station
that matches your room number
so jose and sunny are going to go to
station five
and they're
um value is openness
and i'd like you to start adding
post-its around openness
for what effect what behaviors would you
see in people
if you have openness
right what are the behaviors that you
would see in teams with that with that
value being present
and then when the time box expires which
you're going to have
i think because of so few people we do
three minutes at each one we'll do three
minutes
for that at the end of the three minutes
you
are going to move to the next station
sunny if you're at station 5 and you
have to go to the next station and this
one where do you go
station one yes see i can read lips too
station one
and station one
will have already been filled out by the
people in room one
and you're going to review
what they've put and added additional
things you're going to bring your
openness context to courage does that
make sense
and we'll do at five three minute
intervals
right it really is like the gym sunny
with a five three minute intervals um so
you'll have seen all of the stations
does that make sense
cool
does anybody not understand
even better
okay
so go to the station that matches your
room you'll start in one three or five
it will say your room number at the top
of the screen um and i do i have the
text here i don't i will send you a
message you know where where you're
going next just in case you forget okay
just in case so three minutes
in each station so i'm going to open the
breakout rooms
and start at the station that matches
your
your room number
sorry for those that are uh watching the
feet
um or the recording
i am just
setting up i'm
setting up little messages that i'm
going to send
uh to the team as they go through the
the rounds
so that they remember
what we're doing because sometimes you
forget
but we can see
courage not afraid to speak up
um
being against the
conceived wisdom i think is going in
there that's pretty good
um
i'm not sure what's happening at three
with manjeet
and stanley
uh but you have a minute left can i just
message that one room
[Music]
but in openness we've got being able to
provide so sometimes with this exercise
um one room maybe the folks aren't sure
what we mean and they end up spending
too much time just discussing it as soon
as they move
to another room
that already has all states they
suddenly get it so we'll see if uh um it
works itself out it should do because
we've got so few people and we've got
gaps between the rooms that might be two
rooms before they figure it out but
that's okay
again it's three minutes each room uh uh
three five's 15 minutes total um
it's it's a good exercise so this is an
exercise i would do with with teams um i
would have them
think about how the values um affect
their team's behaviors this is the most
important stuff
in scrum everything else is the
mechanics that you can get from the
scrum guide so reading the scrum guide
you get
probably 50 of the way there for scrum
just following the rules of scrum is
some
let me
do
round two
announce
and
three minutes people have already moved
stations well let me take that post it
there out because the arrows getting
hidden there we go i'll take that one
out
so if you have more people obviously the
more people you have the more stuff goes
on but you can see there's quite a lot
of things in station five
um there's actually uh
quite a lot of things in
station three now
story refinement
i'm not sure
that
that group has a an understanding
of behaviors
so let me
um
i could jump into that room and just
help them out for a second
because they've got to collaborate in
commit
delivery quality
hey folks
think
can you can you think about the
behaviors that you would see in people
okay
yeah so
if people have commitment
what behaviors would you see in a team
if a team had commitment
what people behaviors would you have
stanley
they will collaborate
so
[Applause]
working together
right would be the behavior
rather than working separately
what other behaviors might you have
um
could you might you have holding each
other accountable
yeah
right if i if i'm on a team with you
and i commit
to helping you with something
right you would hold me accountable for
that wouldn't you
yes yeah yeah
that's that's that's the
types of behaviors that we're looking
for
all right okay
um
i'm gonna let you get on with it okay
okay yep
i'm back okay uh
so
i'm
not a huge fan of these ones
uh but it's 10 seconds left let me get
the next message going
round three
so
the folks that were at station one
who've done courage and respect will end
up in focus and they'll not be sure what
to do with those
so let me
iron three there we go db's off there
already
i just want to let them know that they
are right so let me pop into their room
i just wanted to make sure
that you didn't get caught in the red
herring and think you were doing
something wrong in the previous two
windows you weren't
okay just because
station three has things like
story pointing and sprint goal
that those one those ones are incorrect
it's definitely it's behaviors you guys
are correct okay yes yeah i just wanted
to make sure you didn't get distracted
by that
okay all right please we're trying to
keep our focus party yeah
i'm distracting you sorry about that
so the value in um these exercises doing
them
uh like this
there's no value in me just telling you
about scrum okay
you can read that in a book you can read
that in the scrum guide it takes less
than an hour to read it's super
straightforward you can get it in a
diagram i do have a diagram uh
nobody's following me cool look i have a
diagram down here a little scrum diagram
there it is you know you know scrum
right
the the difficulty in doing scrum
is how do we connect people
to the things we're trying to achieve
and how do we
get them to work together virtuously
right we want a positive
spiral of success
not a negative spiral failure which a
lot of teams end up in
especially if you end up in that fixed
scope
world you can end up in a negative
spiral of failure every sprint feels
like a failure to the team
do your team understand
why they're doing the work how do they
connect the work that they're doing just
now to the outcomes the customer wants
or the stakeholders want
can they make that connection do they
understand enough to make that
connection
because if they don't have that
connection when
you're an engineer working on a product
making changes to stuff or you're you're
writing a story right you're writing an
essay if you don't understand what the
outcome's supposed to be
and the context of that outcome and the
people that are going to read it who
your audience is
you're going to make lots of incorrect
decisions about how you put this thing
together
so how do we create
that understanding
so we've got the the scrum values that
help build
transparency
let me do round four
and
message there it is broadcast
there we go
uh
where was i
i don't remember
uh yeah so you you you have the scrum
values that build trust trust enables
you to
inspect and adapt right because you can
now see what's really going on
and you have people working together for
their success
right so hopefully we get happier people
if we then have and we're going to talk
about well
how close are we going to i'll talk
about it here but we're going to talk
about goals as well and goals are the
way that we connect people to the work
goals are the way we have flexible scope
we've got a sprint goal
to give us flexibility flexibility in
the sprint backlog and we've got oh and
we've got
the products all to help us get product
flexibility at the product level
so
um having uh
having those things is really important
they are the most critical things in in
scrum
goal-based the goal-based mechanics the
value-based mechanics that everything
else is just icing on the cake if you
had
the the scrum values and you had product
goals
you might find that many teams will be
successful anyway
okay they might not even you may even
not need to show them the scrum guide
they're gonna figure out how to solve
their problems they're going to have
focus
with the goals they're going to have the
courage to say when something doesn't
work and help each other and say no when
they're getting too much work
right and that's going to start reducing
quality because they're taking on too
much they're going to respect their
customer by delivering working software
they're going to respect each other
the leadership but it it's a virtuous
cycle that's what we want
so there's one more we're in round four
we are indeed in round four so we have
one more round five
and then i'll ask them
um
[Music]
i guess what
there's no right answers in here right
so it's an experience that you have to
go through at creating these items and
it's
what did you realize
going through this exercise what were
the things
uh um
that stood out for you
but i definitely need to add goals to
this uh this workshop we only have like
minutes left so
um
getting enough stuff
so we took 30 minutes on that
yeah it says 10. put 30 minutes
um but i thought that was valuable and
then
um we've got scrum itself what we need
for scrum
we got most of the things right i mean i
almost have really had most of the
things so
copy them down do that exercise yeah i
think we're good for time all right so
oh there we go uh let's put uh the last
time box on
what oh did i put five in that yes i did
five last one
last one
and then i close the rooms uh so let me
copy
these post-its down to
here
has mural fixed my ability to grid
everything no they don't connect oh
that's nasty can i put in a roll oh my
goodness me mural have messed up
really nastily
uh so let's put that
here and let's put that
there
now those buttons are supposed to grid
it but it's not working
no working i've reported it
they have a bug
but let's see what we've got let's take
a little uh a gallery gallery walk
before everybody gets back we've got
about two minutes
uh so we've got courage
um
constructive challenge not afraid to
speak up uh help overcome difficulties
right courage to help each other and
encourages openness right because that's
somebody coming in from the other one
not be afraid to fail seeking help if
you need it
that's good
um ability to take risks and innovate
courage to admit shortcomings right
these are courageous things
if we head into respect
don't abuse your position
everyone's opinion is important
um give equal space to each team member
appropriate body language right it's
really important uh living up to the
plan objectives respect other person's
roles responsibilities negotiating good
faith right and respect cultural
differences as well these are good
and then we're going to focus
uh
keep to the purpose right what are you
trying to achieve here
and it says ceremony but the events in
scrum are they all there for a reason
uh keep conversations and interactions
more productive focus on what's needed
to be done to deliver
improve independent work
retain focus on the methodology
okay
focus and then we go up to commitment
50 seconds
uh keeping to the quality as outlined
the definition of done um collaboration
working together keeping keeping to
schedule
i don't like that one
um
schedules schedules kind of
ah
yeah so commitment and schedule we're
into fixed scope
so let me put a little note on there
okay do i do this there's a way i can
make it have uh
do it this way
results in fixed scope i made that
smaller boop there we go
so that was the last ones i'm bringing
everybody back
uh
working together
commitment to maintain values yeah
greater engagement holding each other
accountable
attendance okay and then in openness
creates a mindset uh
okay welcome back
did that feel like a long time or a
short amount of time
higher amount of time
okay
what
what did you observe was that david
yeah what did you observe david
uh
did you feel that the vow the values are
valuable
are they gonna help teams do better
yeah they would yes
how do you feel
how well do you feel they're implemented
in your organization just now
is there a focus on them or is there not
a focus on them
yeah fairly silly that's good i don't
i don't have a particular opinion yeah
okay
i did notice one in commitment that i'd
like to call out there's one that says
keep to time schedule
and i added a little tag that's going to
result in fake scope again
right that's delivering things within a
time when the things we're delivering
have an unknown amount of time to
deliver them
what are we going to cut
to take something that we don't know how
long it's going to take we're going to
cut quality
or we're going to cut features that's it
that's our only choices
right this is a really
intrinsic learning point
to agility
right and it's not
that
waterfall can do it better
right because we know what happens when
we try and just manage to plan things go
wrong right
it gets extended because we don't know
how long things are going to take in
this complex cognitive world you're
effectively asking people to solve
puzzles every day
right how long is it going to take you
to solve that puzzle i don't know
i think it might take me about
a day because i've done a similar puzzle
before and that took about a day
but that doesn't mean this one's going
to take a day because it's different
from that one otherwise you would just
use that one you wouldn't build anything
new
so scrum values are there to support
the scrum framework because we can't
have scrum without transparency
and it is very difficult to have
transparency when you have disrespect a
lack of courage no focus a closed
mindset and no commitment it's almost
impossible to get
transparency
and transparency is the thing that we
build everything else on
have you heard of the do plan act
loop
right
you you if you can't see what's going on
how do you change your plan
you need to be able to see what's going
on you need to be able to see really
what's going on not just what people
tell you is going on because they're
afraid of what you might say or some
other thing in the organization
so i brought
um
these uh cards for do we need it
uh for scrum
down here to the bottom let me actually
make them a little bit bigger because
we've got we've got it we've got a good
set but it's not as many of them
as i sometimes have so let me just grab
them all
make them a little i i'm okay with them
encroaching into there go make them a
little bit bigger
so what i'd like to do something called
a quick sort
i have i have three columns here three
boxes really required by scrum right
that's things we
have to have to maintain our ability to
have an empirical process control system
right that's what scrum is it's an
empirical system empiricism just means
inspect and adapt that's your
look at it
inspect an adapt right
um
what are complementary axes things that
might help us but we don't have to have
so they're a choice
right and then there might be things in
here that have a negative impact i don't
actually don't think we ended up with
many negative things if any i don't want
to
coach it so i would like to do is just a
free-for-all a quick sort grab a card
is it required by scrum a complimentary
practice
or something that has a negative impact
just grab a card and put it in a column
let's see where we get to
it members yeah it's gonna be hard to
build stuff without team members isn't
it i'm going to add
scroll right
let's see
if you end up moving something into
the box and then somebody else moves it
into another box feel free to stick it
in disputed
um
oh maybe i made the cards too big
oh
i i don't know i think manjit funded
parties are necessary
whoa
okay
oh this is interesting
so i am
that's super interesting
okay
well that
i
so that burned down ended up in negative
impact shows how somebody feels about
burndowns right that's that's how they
feel about it
burndowns are in general a complementary
practice right but i do understand how
they cannot be valuable
does that make sense
right so just because it's a
complimentary practice doesn't mean it's
good in all circumstances
i have definitely seen lots of things
have have a negative impact uh so let's
look at what we've got in a
complementary practices
collaboration with the product owner
right
are you meaning the team's collaboration
with the product tour
who created that card or moved it
i i moved it there i i think it's the
team's collaboration yeah team
collaboration with the product owner i i
think that's required by scrum
if we're not collaborating with the
product owner we're not going to build a
product that the product owner can take
to their stakeholders not happy
stakeholders
yeah
if we build something that's wrong when
we could have just asked the product
owner is that what you mean
is that is that what you were referring
to
it's okay to stay off mute by the way
i'm not i'm not worried about
uh background noise um so we've got some
things in complementary practice that i
i agree 100 sit there
story points
um
are our complementary practice
um you don't have to have story points
it's not mentioned in in the scrum guide
burn downs complementary practice not
mentioned team velocity not mentioned in
the scrum guide
uh scrum values ended up in
complementary practice
uh an increment ended up in
complementary price
release plans that's definitely
complementary so i'm going to bring
these down because they're disputed
these all these are all things
oh
somebody keeps moving objectives over to
negative impact
right are you talking about kpis
or what do you mean by objective when
you put it over there
well i put the sticky notes initially
because the team needs objectives
but i don't know why
it's in the negative impact yeah
so um sprint goal
a sprint goal is an objective and that
ended up being required
but maybe when when when
somebody moved it over there they're
thinking
a kpi or some kind of measure that can
have a negative impact on the team
right so i i'm actually okay leaving it
in disputed because objectives are one
of those things that are super dangerous
right that they can be incredibly bad or
incredibly awesome
we need to have objectives but we need
to do them in a way that has a positive
impact um so i think we just leave it in
disputed put it kind of in the middle we
don't need a negative impact and but it
can go either way but what i'm more
interested in
is how come
scrum values the increment product owner
and refinement ended up in complementary
would somebody like to talk about
increment
what what do we deliver at the end of
the sprint
we deliver an increment at the end of
the sprint we deliver a working
increment of our product
so it's definitely not complementary
it's a absolute
imperative
product owners are also imperative
refinement
refinement is imperative
and scrum values are imperative so
there's quite a lot of things on the
left-hand side here
right but we've still got lots of
choices don't
we still get lots of choices
so the scrum guide
which i do recommend you read
is like any good game
right i've got a number of board games
behind me
it has a rulebook
why does a game have a rulebook cozy
sorry i just got back
oh okay no that's cool
so a game has a rulebook
so that we are all playing the same game
what happens when you disagree over the
rules
you're sent off well you get sent off
yeah yeah that might be in a soccer
match yeah you might get sent off
uh you might get a red card
right you disagree over the rules
so we need to have a set of
guiding rules scaffolding
that makes sure
everybody's going in the same direction
but we don't want to define too many
things
because then we end up in bureaucracy
right we want to give people lots of
choices for how we do things
uh so let me i'm just gonna
walk through
at the scrum process for you in the last
uh a few minutes
like i said reading the scrum guide
is the best way
to to to absorb this because there's
lots of nuance in here
but i'm going to do my best to do you a
scrum in two minutes
uh run through i think is
valuable right
um we've got this
outer box which is our sprint
right it's time boxed usually to two
weeks these days but no longer than a
month
and notice we have an increment inside
of that box
every sprint should result in a working
product
that meets your definition of done
and your definition of done should
reflect releasable
right doesn't mean released
just means releasable
right
i
am always going to coach teams that they
should be released
at the end of every sprint every sprint
should go to production right continuous
delivery perhaps many times to
production we have many increments
during the sprint but scrum doesn't
require that that's a complimentary
practice
okay
but in in in scrum we have a product
backlog our product backlog lists all of
the things that we think we're going to
do in the future
it should be shaped by the product goal
have you heard that term product goal
before
no
yeah it's new in the scrum guide
but the product goal is our intermediate
strategic goal
so that we can help people doing the
work connect to what it is we're doing
what are we trying to achieve over the
next few sprints
right that's the product goal
and the things in our product backlog
are refined by the scrum team
refinement is just all the work that we
do
that's not on the current sprint
so if we're gathering user research if
we're breaking down things in the
product backlog if we're adding new
things these are all refinement
activities
we're then going to have an ordered well
ordered backlog from our product owner
right with the most important
well-refined things near the top we go
into a sprint planning
in sprint planning we are going to craft
our sprint goal
right why are we doing this sprint what
is our tactical objective
this sprint
so we come up with our sprint goal the
team the developers are going to select
they're pulling items from the product
backlog that help them achieve that goal
and creating a plan for the first 24
hours
that would be an implementation plan
like break down into tasks for the first
24 hours
and then every day they're going to get
together and review the transparency of
that plan
does that plan still reflect
transparency of the present
okay so that's why i don't care about
the three questions although i don't
object to them right you might focus on
value you might focus on tasks you might
focus on people the purpose of the
dailies
is so that the sprint backlog still
reflects transparency of the future
right it's a small planning event plan
the next 24 hours
and then at the end of the sprint
when our increment meets the definition
when our product meets the definition of
done we have an increment
and the increment of working product is
what we take to the sprint review and
get review from stakeholders
you want to invite as many people as you
can anybody who cares the more people
the better and get feedback on that
increment
then you go into a retrospective
where we're going to inspect ourselves
how did we do things
the relationships between people we're
going to focus on the values we're going
to talk about the tools and how
effective they were
what can we do better
and then we may be going to another
sprint
if at the sprint review our stakeholders
believe we can get an additional return
on investment by doing another sprint
maybe we do another sprint
does that make sense that was scrum in
four minutes i did i did it in four
minutes instead of two but
that's the whole thing
the mechanics of scrum are not the
problem
it's the values it's the
the goals the objectives connecting
people to the outcomes that you're
trying to get to
measuring people well right these are
the things that are hard
yeah
any questions i know i i while i ran
three minutes over i know
a couple people had to drop
there is a recording of this and while
you were doing your exercises and i
wasn't in there i was
narrating
um so there's maybe some value in the in
the recording or maybe i was rambling
um but you have any questions
no thank you so i i really recommend
giving that scrum guide a read like i
said it takes less than an hour
takes less than an hour to read and it's
codifies the rules to play the game
right we should at least all understand
the rules so we're playing the same game
then there's lots of complimentary
practices to choose from
okay
yeah thank you thanks all for your time
thank you bye thank you very much
hopefully see you next time
why does manji disappear okay
okay so