I would definitely recommend the the PSP
Auto and entrepreneur
um I invite the advanced pspo as well
but the the
that that key focus on value
from the from the pspo and what add your
product management looks like
are all key things that an entrepreneur
needs to bring into their way of doing
things their story of how how things
happen for them because usually
especially for entrepreneurs their
organizations are very small especially
at the start and they're going to be
fulfilling the role of product owner and
they're going to set the tone for
leadership and product management inside
of their organization and even if later
on they're handing that torch off to
somebody else because they're they're
being successful they're making good
decisions and then they're getting a
little bit bigger and they're able to
hand that torch off
that torch needs to come with uh here's
what we're trying to achieve here's
where we're going yes we have really
thought about value and I think it's
even more important for an entrepreneur
because you want to get past that
startup phase
um and I don't know what percentage of
organizations fail I don't know the
exact percentage of organizations
startups that fail but it's most of them
right most startups are going to fail
and one of the reasons that they fail is
that they don't have that tight focus on
value they don't understand what's value
what's value to their customers and they
haven't had those conversations written
it down understand it discussed it and
we have loads of tools in the product
owner class that you can use as part of
that story how how do I figure out what
those things are how do I think about
those things in order to bring everybody
in my in my team along with me and help
us understand what it is we're trying to
achieve
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility