a common thing that I see happening in
scrum
teams and any product teams to be honest
any product teams is that they
have
contempt they have contempt for their
leadership they have contempt for their
company they have contempt for their
product they have contempt for their
customers and they have contempt for the
outcomes this is a little bit more than
they just don't care it's it's they they
actively
dislike uh have disdain for um choices
that are are are are made and this is
largely I think because those choices
are made in spite of their opinions and
their understanding of the product and
the future of the product and the dire
that the company needs to go and choices
are being made without
their support is not the right words
input might be the right
words um they don't feel like they're
listened
to on on on their on their teams or as
part of their organization and that
seems to be a trend of traditional
organizations right we're not we're
we're we're just going to we we're going
to that
pyramid right the the the alpha
organizations we're going to steer from
the top therefore we actually don't care
what the people on the ground say uh or
do or understand that's a relevant we're
making the decisions at the top and
unfortunately it's the people on the
ground that are tend to be closest to
the market it's the people at the top
that tend to be furthest away from the
market and this
constant
ignoring of the realities of the market
the realities of the situation the
realities of the product the realities
of the quality of the product breeds
contempt in the people that are doing
the work for the organization they work
for uh a great
example um is that I used to work for an
organization in the UK uh pretty near to
where where I live this was back when I
was an
employee and it was I think was it the
last employee job I had I think it was
no it wasn't the last one but it was one
of the last ones that I had um and there
was
absolute abject and constant
contempt by every single employee for
the organization they worked
for so much so much so that um they had
a nickname for the
company
uh the the the the company at the time I
don't think it exists anymore don't
think it exists anymore it was called
intelligent
Finance uh it was a like an experiment
it was one of the first internet
Banks but the nickname that the
employees had as a as a group or at
least within the bounds of what I was
interacting with for the organization
they work for uh they change the
intelligent to
incompetent and the F in finance uh to a
a Scottish term for somebody who's not
very
smart um yes one of those types of FWS
right um it's even in the dictionary
here uh so if you're going to think of
your
company as
incompetent what does that mean for the
attitude and investment that people
bring to work every day it's going to
mean that it's it's it's reduced or
doesn't even exist uh there was a number
of things that kind of led to to that
feeling um I remember while I was there
there was a new CIO for the
organization uh this new CIO for the
organization um admitted that he had
trouble with email
so this is the Chief Information officer
for the
organization admitted that he struggled
to leverage email as a
tool right it's it's just you you can't
make that up right you couldn't make
that up uh the guy I sat next to uh at
my desk a user
experience person ux ux person and uh he
admitted to me that he he felt like he
was
unemployable because he'd worked there
for 4 years and not done anything
new right think about think about those
things this was this was back in
200 I don't know 2005
2006 so we're pretty far into Windows
2000 right we're pretty far into uh uh
NET Framework and all of those those cap
abilities um five five years four or
five years into NET Framework and um I
had a I had an nt4 workstation as a net
developer nt4 does not
supportet so I had to it took me weeks
to get a badge and then I had to request
using my badge a machine to be installed
under my desk that ran Windows 2000 that
I could then remote into from my desktop
these things together that that
disconnect right that's the focus here
that disconnect between what the people
are doing and what the organization
believes is happening in the Direction
They believe that they're going is that
problem that creates that kind of uh
[Music]
um disgust contempt for the organization
that people work for they don't believe
that it's going anywhere they don't
believe that it's they're just there for
the paycheck and that's it um I I quit I
was the shortest employee ever at this
organization um I quit after 6 weeks um
and the the the
the I did not want to exist in that
culture of contempt for their
organization and one of my favorite
saying is change your company or change
your
company right so I went with my feet and
walked out the
door what is your organizational culture
how do uh if you're in leadership how do
the people on the ground see your
organization do they believe in what
you're doing do they feel like they're
engaged and involved in what it is
you're trying to achieve do they feel
listen too these are all the
things that create a group of people
that are engaged and want to see the
organization
succeed unhappy sad people don't build
amazing products they build unhappy sad
products so one of the roles one of the
core responsibilities and
accountabilities of leadership is to
create a happy engaged Workforce that
wants the organization to succeed and
you can't do that by just telling people
what to do thanks for watching the video
If you enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked
agility