agile is fundamentally about shortening
the time it takes to deliver your
products to users and to learn from it
traditional management practices were
developed during the Industrial
Revolution to manage the work of largely
uneducated Workforce while we can still
be somewhat successful when using these
traditional management practices they no
longer fit the type of work that we are
doing in modern organizations
my name is Martin hincherwood I'm a
professional scrum trainer with
scrum.org professional kanban Trainor
with Pro kanban and I've been a
Microsoft MVP in devops for the last 14
years
I want to create an understanding of the
two different worlds that we're talking
about here so during the Industrial
Revolution with a largely uneducated
Workforce we needed to make lots of
goods really quickly so we created a
model in our organizations where we had
the highly knowledgeable people at the
top of the organization who were
steering and giving direction to all of
the rest the people in the organization
that were largely uneducated
but the type of work that we were doing
the type of work we were physically
doing was was complicated
and this complicated work had a
particular characteristic right
um we could apply more knowledge
to it and it became
simple
right this work became simple so by
applying more knowledge to this problem
we made it simple so we created standard
operating procedures we uh um built out
common ways that things work and
optimized you know identified the
patterns and optimized for them uh we
pushed people into ability based groups
inside of our organization so we
actually we ended up not only with the
hierarchy of our organization but also
the departmental model within our
organization as well where we had the
CEO at the top giving direction they had
the absolute knowledge of the entire
business and how everything functioned
and they give direction
to perhaps the sales team or the uh
marketing team right and they had a head
who then farmed out that work to
individual people down the down the
totem
um and work work work was done and that
that works great in a world where the
CEO can give instructions give
instructions and we follow them and
things are successful but the problem is
the market is at the bottom
and in our new world and the market is
changing a lot more frequently than the
CEO is is is taking a a test on what's
going on so knowledge would have to flow
back up this chain and it's too slow if
your organization is unable to respond
to change as quickly as your competitors
you're going to fail and because the
markets have changed this complicated
work no longer really exists we can't
turn it into simple so every single
thing we do becomes custom which means
that that flow of information is
becoming heavier and heavier and heavier
up and down the chain in order to get
things done and it's just not being
successful
and that's because we're we're not
operating in this complicated space
anymore
things have changed things have become
complex
and no amount of
standard operating procedures or
processes or practices or ways of doing
things can turn
complicated work into simple
okay it never becomes simple what
complicated sorry complex work does do
is it generates
copious amounts of
surprise right that's those markets
changing so we need to be able to adapt
to it much more quickly uh than we were
doing before so that's that's the
different world so traditional
management and project management
practices were developed to work in this
space so you have things like uh PMI
uh uh prince2
um more more recently we have things
like
safe the scaled agile framework and are
all developed to work in this space
where the work is is is just merely
complicated and we can turn it simple by
documenting a process okay but in actual
fact we mostly most of the work we do
today most of the way our organizations
need to operate today is we operate in a
complex World complex markets complex
work delivering all this complex uh
creative things
and agile was a response to that
difference right
um agile's been around a very long time
the agile Manifesto was signed in 2001
which is 22 years ago 21 years ago
um scrum was developed in this space
and scrum has been around for 25 years
uh 2019 93 was the first rendition of
scrum but even before that way back in
the the new new product development game
uh article Harvard Business review
article I have a a definition at the end
um was 1986 I think 1986. so these ideas
have been around for an incredibly long
time and actually uh it started long
before that but that's that's too much
for for just now but if we exist in this
complex space we need processes and
practices that were developed for this
complex space and we need something a
little bit different
um because in our world of of uh
complexity
things are very unpredictable okay uh
there's a great lack of predictability
in those species uh so here I've
categorized the the types of things that
we would do in product development just
into three three key areas uh
requirements technology and people
um it's a very very broad categories I
do understand that
um but let's think about the
predictability of each of those items
and where it would sit
well we're no longer taking orders right
we're not having orders coming from
above in the organization and we just
follow it the customer
might say yes I want this uh but the
reality is that the chances of this
being what they actually need are are
are are very different in fact there's
some good data around that uh so the
Standish group in in Boston create the
chaos report
um and they've added a few things that
story one of them is that uh um
percent of our requirements
change over the life of our product not
only that but 65 percent of the things
that we build
are used little
if ever
think about the waste for every every
dollar of investment that we have we're
losing 65 65 cents on the dollar is
being lost just to building stuff that
our customers don't actually use so why
do we build things that our customers
don't actually use surely they asked for
them so they need them but the reality
is that they ask for things they don't
need and the reason they ask for things
they don't need is because we ask them
an unreasonable question we say what are
you going to need in a year's time in 12
months when we've built your product for
you what do you need and the reality is
they don't know they don't know what
business decisions are going to happen
over the next 12 months they don't know
what Market changes are going to happen
what other unpredictable world events
are going to happen over the next 12
months so their knowledge of what might
maybe happen includes a whole bunch of
things that they won't need once the
decisions been made or if a particular
event happens we need these hundred
features if it doesn't happen we need
these other 100 features and if we're
asking them up front they're going to
give us the full 200 features so there's
half of those things we don't need
so requirements while we like to think
that our requirements once we've signed
off on them are are fairly High
predictability the reality is is they're
probably closer to that 30 percent
predictable so we need to figure out
um how do we how do we adapt more
quickly to be able to take that into
account
uh the next thing is technology okay uh
technology could be our uh the the
software technology it could be a
product technology it could be
um
processes ways of doing things
technology right uh probably scrum sits
in that space kanban sits in that space
these are technologies that were
developed in order to help us do things
uh traditional project management
practices PMI and prints too are
Technologies right ways of doing things
but the reality is that even during the
life of a product the technologies that
we need are going to change okay so some
of those Technologies might be uh would
you would you run a product in exactly
the same way when you're building
something new versus you're supporting
something that exists versus something
happened in the market that you need to
adapt around making a change to what's
going on no we're going to use different
processes and practices and even in the
software technology
windows and visual studio are are are on
daily builds these products the products
that we rely on that we use as part of
our process are constantly constantly
changing now technology is probably a
little bit more uh predictable than
requirements
um I'll put this in the 50 there it
might be a little bit higher okay but
it's still fairly fairly low and then
our last our last predictability is
people right and I don't know about you
but I don't come into work every day and
operate at exactly the same level people
are not machines no matter how much we
want to say that people should just come
into work and be professional every day
that's not how human beings operate
people take vacation people take sick
days people have kids people have
arguments people have disagreements if I
have to work with somebody I don't like
I'm not going to perform as well as I
would uh uh if I was working with
somebody I did like right we're going to
collaborate more
what is that impact on on the world and
I would suggest that people are probably
the least predictable element here
um
and if you if you average this across
each of these different ideas these
different topics we get a we get a kind
of picture of very low predictability
definitely less than 50 percent now
imagine that you've created our project
plan uh for the next next 12 months
um we've created our bunch of mitigating
uh we've got we've got a bunch of risks
that might happen we've got maybe 200
risks that might happen over the life of
the product
um and we have a whole bunch of
mitigating actions that we've created if
this happens we'll do this
that
what if 40 uh sorry eight eight sixty
percent sixty percent of all of that is
going to change over the life of the
product and change constantly right what
is that impact on the body of work that
we've created and our look forward into
the future there's a lot of waste in
there uh things that we couldn't protect
those surprises are going to happen so
we really want to tackle it in a
different way
uh so in in this agile space we deal
with this predictability this lack of
predictability we deal with it by having
working product on a regular Cadence
okay so perhaps we have a regular
Cadence of once a month we're going to
deliver working usable product so
instead of just having that single uh
delivery at the end in our traditional
model we have continuous delivery of new
uh product working product that our
customer can use can work with in
production can give us feedback on that
will help inform the next piece of work
this gives us a whole bunch of
capabilities and I'm going to talk about
that in a moment but this is the
superpower
um this is the thing that allows us to
mitigate risk
is the only thing that allows us to
mitigate risk in this complex world
where everything's changing so much we
can't plan our way out of the risk like
we would in a traditional model when the
variance is very small when the variance
is high we need to create these working
usable products because then when
something happens let's say a market
change happens we can maybe do another
release very quickly after right we can
do more releases than we have here
perhaps uh there's a world event
happens and we need to do a bunch of
small releases in order to get these the
the the the the you know competitors
released uh new features and we need to
get it our features into Market very
quickly and these are
the tool that we use to mitigate risk so
let's look at what that looks like
so in um I'm gonna gonna go through this
first uh quickly with uh or with a
traditional mindset right
so in a traditional mindset let's say we
take that a pure traditional mindset
where we don't actually give the
customer uh we don't deploy to
production Until the End you've got 12
month project let's say it's going to
cost 12 million of whatever monies you
like dollars Euros or Pounds and we're
going to deliver on a monthly basis so
we're gonna have
um in a traditional model uh we're going
to deliver at the end of the 12 months
okay so what's the visibility during the
life of the product well visibility
normally starts high right it's going to
start high because we're writing the
documentation we're communicating what's
going on uh but then
right at the end we've got high
visibility because we've delivered them
working products but in between how much
visibility does the customer actually
have right what can they actually see
what can they use in the product what do
they really know apart from you know we
tell them things are going great right
we're 80 there and all of those things
so while visibility is not zero
it is fairly fairly low throughout the
life of the project and goes at low
fairly quickly
couple that because visibility is is not
higher ability to change also uh over
the life of the project drops fairly
quickly so our ability to change at the
end is very low right we've built a
bunch of stuff right so we have a low
ability to change it's more expensive to
change things but we drop very quickly
after we start work in a traditional
model because we start everything right
we're not creating those vertical slices
this is why things like Spiral came into
existence to kind of help with those
stories but this idea uh um is the the
change drops off very quickly we
maintain it for some time but it drops
off fairly quickly
and then our customers operational risk
operational risk always starts at a
hundred percent what is the risk to the
customer what's the customer's risk
they're looking at us going what's my
risk uh on whether these folks will
deliver what I think they're going to
deliver right so it starts very high
um and then it's obviously zero at the
end because we deliver our working
usable product at the end of every
project right that's that happens every
project but operational risk during the
life of the project remains very high it
maybe drops a little bit as they see
some of the things we've created maybe
there's a little dip maybe there's a
little dip there at the end as we go
into uat but the reality is we get to
the end and their risk drops to zero
only once we've delivered a working
usable uh product for them once we've
solved their business problem
and then if we look at realized value
how much value does the customer have
well it starts at zero they've got no
value and at the end of the product
cycle at the end of the 12 months they
have full value but during you know how
often do you actually deliver value to
the customer and I very specifically use
realized value uat does not count as
realized value uat does not actually
solve the customer's problem it's still
a pending problem so we don't have that
value realized until the end of the
product cycle
so hope hopefully you you agree or
mostly agree with the way I shape these
lines you maybe have little caveats but
I think it's not going to be that much
different from from what I've drawn
so let's take a another look and look at
uh I'm gonna put agile
but you might call it empirical it
doesn't really matter what word you use
agile's it's been agile since 2001 uh
before that it was just empiricism right
an empirical process
um and what we're going to do is at
least every month
at least every 30 days we're going to
have working product and it's going to
be in production okay
um so where where does visibility sit
well visibility
um sits fairly High throughout the life
of the project right so it starts high
and then every month we're going to have
I'm not probably not going to put 12 of
these little uh stars in there right uh
but every month they're going to have
that same level of visibility here are
all the things we created over the last
month please validate that it is what
we've created and during those sessions
you're going to have these uh little
little dips where we're not doing
anything I guess I could make that I
guess that could go all the way down
here right maybe
that kind of makes sense you know bring
it in line with the the the that idea of
not being able to see anything but we
have all of these touch points we have
12 touch points throughout the life of
the product where the customer is given
the ability to to give them the ability
to change potentially
also our ability to change over the life
of the product is is very different as
well right so we're going to start with
high ability to change in both cases
we've built nothing and in the end we're
gonna potentially have a low ability to
change in both cases we've built a
product right so now it's difficult to
change because a whole product exists 10
12 months worth of work versus uh no
work but the model is very different
because at the end because we're working
in in usable working increments at the
end of each month when we ship the
product the customer has the option to
change anything we've not started and it
has zero impact to our ability to
deliver it has zero impact on the
product and there's potentially zero
waste it's close to zero it's never zero
right but we have much lower waste when
they maintain that ability to change
anything we've not started so what you
end up with is you're still going to
drop because you're Building Product but
it's going to to be on a a kind of
different trajectory right we're we're
reducing our ability to change as we go
through the product but everything we've
not built yet still has the ability to
change and we even have the ability to
change existing stuff just like we did
in our traditional process
um but we're adding that to the ability
to change everything we've not started
if at the end of Sprint four month four
they want the customer wants to delete
our entire product backlog and build a
new one and that's what we work on
that's cool we can do that because
everything we have done so far is usable
and works it's production ready okay
that's that super power that we need in
order to get there
so how does that look for operational
risk well we're going to start in the
same place right and end in the same
place that's that that normal model
we're going to start in the same place
and end in the same place but in fact at
the end of the first month we've
alleviated some of the risk
right they have some working product
hopefully we've solved the most valuable
problem we can in the first 30 days
right what could we do in 30 days that's
what I do with teams is I get them in a
room and I say here's what the customer
wants what is the most valuable thing we
could do in this space in the next 30
days let's build that at the end of the
30 days you've got that you give it to
the customer and say are we going in the
right direction are we building
something that's valuable do you want to
change your mind it gives them that
visibility they can potentially we can
potentially ship it to production and
they can use it in production there's
all sorts of things we have to do to
allow that to happen but
what you end up with is this
direct trajectory
from top left to bottom right right
every single time we create a usable
working product we we have uh we
alleviate their the customer's
operational risk right we also alleviate
their fiscal risk their money is no
longer at risk because they have a
working product and yeah you might have
Sprints where uh you know something bad
happens and we we have a little Plateau
right that's entirely possible but
mostly you're going to you're hopefully
going to be delivering at the end of
every every Sprint a usable working
product that shows progress
right and then we've got
two things we need to talk about for
realized value we need to talk about if
we are in a traditional organization so
a hierarchical departmental model
top-down organization and we're we're
using agile practices in our team what
does that look like for the realization
of value realized value is value I have
so if you're creating value for me I
don't have something that you've
documented I don't have something that
you've built but not tested I don't have
it yet it's not value yet it's potential
value right that's correct but it's not
value for me yet as the customer and so
right at the beginning we start at the
bottom we go to the top and then we have
every month we're going to deliver
usable working products so every one of
these notches
is a delivery of value it's a delivery
of
it's a delivery of something that we can
use that we can get in front of our our
customer that we can have them kick the
tires on that they can have them tell us
that we were wrong or we were right and
there you'll be able to use it
so that's one option is we're in that
traditional organization where we're
handied here's 300 yeah well let me do
that here's the 300 requirements that
you want us to build and we're going to
build it
but in both of these models maybe a
little bit less in the agile model we're
still under that constraint of
so here we asked for we were asked for
300 things and we delivered 300 things
in both models but remember we talked
about the 65
that's used little if ever that's
included in those 300 things so what
could we do differently well what would
be great is if at the end of the first
month the customer gets the product and
they tell us about all of the things
that have changed right they get to look
at the product and decide they want
something different they get to tell us
about the way their business has changed
in the last uh uh 30 days
and perhaps there are a bunch of
features up here that they don't need
anymore right they made a business
decision and the world has changed so
they don't need those so instead they
replace that with something else and we
build
something else of value okay that's
probably too steep
that's too steep
let's do
something else of value and at the end
of the next month we build something
else of value because they decide they
don't need this piece and then we build
something else of value and perhaps at
this point right where we're almost at
that same value level as we created over
here they decide
we're done we were able to deliver early
we were able to finish the product this
is only possible if we're able to change
the requirements if the requirements are
fluid and in fact you don't want the
full requirements up front but we want
those fluid requirements so we can make
changes constantly and then hopefully
well that's a bad line we get somewhere
somewhere up here where we have this
much higher value product if we continue
to build it it's much more in keeping
with what it is that the customer wants
and we've minimized that 65 percent
of features not used we're still going
to build stuff that's not used and we
end up in that space
all of these things are predisposed on
having a working usable product at the
end of every iteration including the
first
that is not out with the bounds of every
single organization on the planet it is
something that for example the windows
team do on a weekly basis they create a
working usable product on a weekly basis
with four and a half thousand software
Engineers working on a product that is
just enormous if they can do it we can
all do it the only excuses we have is
the existing state of our system the
existing expectation of quality and
capability in our teams and in our
organizations okay we need to work on
those and we can all get these
capabilities and we can all be a little
bit more agile
so thanks for
um listening to my little rant if you
are interested in having a further chat
with me please use that QR code in the
in the top right there to book a free 30
minutes with me uh if you want our free
consultation that's cool if you want to
just have a chat about some of the
things I've talked about and how it
might be applied in your organization
others are wait to book a coffee on
there as well just book a coffee
all right two books that I really
recommend that you read is one is the
new new product development game that's
a 19 that's the 1986 Harvard Business
review article and also Stephen Dennings
book at the age of agile those are both
great works
you for listening