naked agility helps
organizations create culture of
engineering Excellence do we I I'm I'm I
I struggle with the idea of creating
culture culture is just what is within
the organization but what we can help
you
do think of culture as the shadow on the
wall right you need to change the shape
of the thing in order to change the
shadow in the wall and naked agility can
help
you understand your current system of
delivering value in order to
measure the things
that make an
impact on where you want to go and what
you want to achieve in order to create
the highest value optimization that we
can have within within within your
context so we do that by by monitoring
the system identifying what your system
is defining that
system of delivering
value and then creating or helping you
create metrics and understanding and
transparency of that system so that you
can see what's going on and make better
decisions that enable you to get to the
outcomes that you're trying to achieve
which could be it could be reducing cost
it could be maximizing value I would go
for the maximizing value to be
honest but this idea
of technical leadership and Engineering
Excellence within the context of
building software
products is that overall ethos of
understanding your system measuring it
so you can see what's going on and then
making substantive changes to that
system to see whether you're able to
optimize the goals and outcomes that
you're trying to achieve and those are
all things that we can help you do we
can help you control your costs and
Achieve technical leadership with naked
agility contact me today to get started
on your journey