I'm gonna meet a lock off I've got
caught by a quarantine yourself
pass me hide knock off to be the fancy
intro music as ISO News pain simply the
based on Twitter says girly yeah I don't
know it work through my head sensor I do
have some fancy intro music I just can't
push it through through teams teams is
not zoom zoom yes it's it was a ranger
RPS but just nobody use them I'm happy I
can't
[Music]
before singing sunshine only their
banana flies
ah did you not see that Donald it was
just a nice idea I guess they were just
emulating what was going on in Italy
today mm-hmm to be brutally honest it's
not like it's not like you have anybody
never to go to see him by the way at
seven o'clock so anybody please
what's the door probably going mutes go
get mark throw that from his end control
you and thank you let's can record it
yes it is going out live on LinkedIn
Facebook YouTube Twitter eagerly push
but I've started the live feed
okay but just excellent it's on it's
coming soon
nice I think well I will give out a few
minutes why not raro buttes you are you
gonna host an intro then SAS yes
what's that you've shared you know
posted in their digit Donald
I've got about four hours with the
content is that okay guys you've got
there you go I know Ellen you've always
got loads of content loads and loads we
could do another one later in the year
hopefully hopefully our face-to-face a
nicer they knew that be them pizzas you
know you're being well is that I think
you're ever hopeful they're sad 2020
stuff there's always there's always
there's always room for optimism yeah I
reckon I actually I actually don't know
if the stream can hear you as well
probably just visiting and you and me
can change facial expressions I'll be me
me talking to myself I think is what
everybody can hear right Phil enough
yeah I've got a unexpressive face that's
the chat as well people saying everybody
can get okay oh here comes go yes we can
hear both of you Bob thank you for that
[Music]
and see you if that's supple really
great right there it's good okay all
right a couple more minutes shall we
gents and they'll kick off no worries
[Music]
a mask off
anything for attention is there any
community and in Spencer instill sooner
lines
I'm gonna do the end mr. Coburn I work
what you not know I'll do that yet the
posted was a falling off conclusion the
time of the pod right he thinks he's got
planned but he hasn't done our web
conference with me before distant future
and I think I'll make a start right it's
ok I think we should start thanks money
to class yeah that's given a revealer
chance to jump back on right welcome
everyone thanks for joining us let's say
second event future work in Scotland
available a year this one obviously we'd
originally planted to do APA well then
you have used before but the
circumstances obviously speak it remotes
got there no thanks for being with us
this one has a little bit of other
significance actually because it's doing
it in collaboration with the VCS agile
methods group that's a phosphor date not
without she done as amethyst because
because our klieg and I both a part of
the the BCS agile methods committee and
this is a foster this is Nigel methods
event we've done in Scotland so are the
significance for some of us so that's
happened all cold air will do more over
the year over the rest of the year
time to come hopefully some place to
face was late in the year but to Martin
thinks I'm being optimistic we do have a
code of conduct and those of you who
have attended some other events familiar
with it we do have one so please do
familiarize yourself with it it's
available on the hive in short things
and they will do will do some community
showcase for some other father they
start coming up over the coming weeks as
well all confined to our homes Q&A so
just quickly we will do a Q&A at the end
once Martin's
fellows presentations so I think we have
a chat facility right here so if he can
start you know putting any questions
that come up as as Marcus doing his
presentation and Donnell denial can sit
through them and we'll reel him back to
Martin's week and he can answer the
questions that come up at the end so
hopefully that's a decent format for
everyone and with that I think just
introduce our speaker so tomorrow and I
for a few years now in fact I did
Martin's a scrum divorce a professional
scrum cleaning a few years ago now in
fact I think it may have been one of the
first ones in Scotland so Martin does
what's come to or training or what
consultancy Joe and DevOps and yeah I'm
really looking forward to is
presentation tonight giving one of its
personal experiences doing an agility in
the enterprise so with that I'll hand
over to Martin Martin folks
hopefully this is going to going to go
well it's it is kind of being recorded
it's streaming live on lots of different
platforms
I'm not sure how good the the Sundays or
whether anybody could hear SAS that
format
but yeah we're all here anyways so it
doesn't it doesn't matter
I'm both the professional scrum trainer
likes that said but also our Microsoft
MVP as well in DevOps and I kind of kind
of split that difference a little bit
between the technical skills required to
deliver deliver software it's skill as
well as the the the process ideas of you
know keeping it simple like we all try
and do so I create this presentation a
little while ago it had various names
sling the dragons and how to
successfully descale that skill is just
the most recent one I think it was
unicorns last year taming the unicorns
but the idea is the same
that we really need to China talked
about various things that are not just a
problem at scale but things that we know
work pretty well that you can try so
nothing here I'm going to say is you
must do it this way absolutely not
you need to figure out what works best
with in your organizational context and
that can be that can be difficult
depending on on what it is you're doing
so let's start off and if anybody wants
to get in touch with me later please do
any way you like I'm pretty much
everywhere I'm in Glasgow that's where
I'm based and that's where I am
currently confined like everybody else
so if you do do need something I'm here
and in the in the time zone and I did
see there's a few folks I know from
other countries logged on and I saw Anna
an organ did were logged on so it was a
few few people from further afield
European time zones
the thing that's behind what I'm talking
about is that that idea you've probably
seen this before firms today experience
a much high
velocity of business change business is
changing a lot more quickly and we need
to keep up and it's not just about
process it's a balance between process
and engineering without good engineering
skills we might build a lot of the right
thing but it will not be very good or
not meet the need and without the
process skills were maybe not build the
thing we're supposed to build so I've
got a little story first and that I've
used a couple of times before I I find
it quite well it's kind of amusing
cannon art but it's the story of how our
company with nearly 400 million dollars
in the bank went bankrupt in about 45
minutes because of a field deployment
some of you might have heard this story
it's from the knight Capital Group and
in in the US and there are fortune 500
or not fortune 500 was a Gulf New York
Stock Exchange company and I need a new
feature they were deploying to
production it was some kind of new order
handling feature that changed the way
that worked and and while they were
replacing all old stuff with knew they
had Cain Anna am a big legacy and you
you know what it's like in in in your
teams today there's usually anything
that's been around for a while there's a
lot of technical debt in the system a
lot of spaghetti code that ends up
sitting around for ages on last year
teams continuously refactor and focus on
engineering excellence so this idea is
they hadn't can a nine year old unused
code and they decided to repurpose a
flag in the system you know there's this
flag sitting there it's not doing much
let's just use that in order to turn
this new code on and and when they did a
deployment they were doing manual
deployments and the technician only
deployed to seven of the eight servers
so you can imagine when soon as they
turned the flag on something weird
started happening and it actually took
it took it took the whole system then it
wasn't operating correctly so they
weren't getting the the orders through
they were expecting and because the
system was down and they were losing
about a hundred and seventy thousand
dollars per minute and as you can
imagine that set off a lot of alarm
bells and they go - ever trying fix it
but when they try and fix it the the
they can't figure out what the problem
is because it's the amount of code they
deployed is too much the flag had
unintended consequences and the the
deployment to seven of eight the eight
servers even the technician that did the
work didn't really understand that
that's what they've done so there was no
visibility or transparency into that
because it was a manual deployment a
step or a couple of steps or something
was skipped and not noticed and I'm the
ended the day four hundred and sixty
million dollars down and had to file for
bankruptcy and I think the important
question there is what would be the
impact in your organization of a
critical system that folks write code
for or that deployed being being down
for for a day for two days some big
examples recently where some airlines
that was British Airways went down
American Airlines went down for three
days because of a mainframe fault that
you can't get any more technical debt
the mainframe sitting there and in this
particular case because it was a public
company because it's on the stock
exchange they have to do an SEC filing
for bankruptcy and you know that's how
we know so much about it you can go and
look up this filing and see exactly what
the what the problems were and 2013 is
not really that long ago
they really should have known better and
even around that in fact later than the
2013 timeframe I worked with an
organization in the Netherlands around
2014-2015 and they were an international
bank and they are real time banking
transaction system the servers five
servers around the world that govern
this weren't there so their code was not
under source control and the team they
organized it believed that source
control would slow them down and so in
order to make changes to this real-time
banking transaction system for an
international bank they would log on to
one of the servers open up their IDE
make changes to the code and compile it
on the production server I did ask how
do you share that code across all five
servers and the response was that's why
this five of us so each of the servers
are owned by one of the engineers the
engineer goes on to that individual
server that's their server and they
write and maintain the code on that
server so they've got five servers all
doing the same thing that all have
different code and different setup and
for me that was a huge business risk but
for the business the bigger risk or at
least for management of that group the
bigger risk was that this team was the
only team that understood what to do so
they get to write the rules and that can
often be the kids little fiefdom at
cropping up as well so how do we not
have this happen and we need to get need
to get better at it you need to practice
do it often do it all the time
that's kind of the moral of that story
automate everything you should have any
manual practices in your in your process
your delivery from developer committing
code all the way through to being in
production should be totally automated
you might have approvals along the way
but the approval should be you know
clicking a button ticking a box and not
actually following any technical steps
so can you can you think of any other at
really big crazy failures
like multibillion-dollar failures
because I can think of two the first one
was a failure of quality so this was a
massive product that instead of taking
three years to deliver to production
ended up taking six and they cut 80% of
the features they were trying to deliver
and their problem was technical debt and
that was Windows Vista and anybody that
used it when it first came out will have
felt some of that pain so that was a
quality issue and Microsoft worked very
hard to build up an engineering
excellence after that but the problem
was that they still didn't and they
still were building the right thing so
they ended up with a mismatch - customer
desires which was indeed Windows 8 which
was a massive mismatch to that idea so
it was after Windows 8 and that they
started focusing both on the engineering
excellence and on the getting the right
features into production which means you
have to get tighter feedback loops which
is where Windows 10 was born and Windows
effectively from our perspective Windows
10 ships to production every 30 days but
from the team that writes on it four and
a half thousand engineers and they ship
to production daily the code that an
engineer writes today is running on the
CEOs laptop tomorrow everybody inside of
Microsoft gets the internal build and
they can choose to install their own
machine and then not get the built in
case anybody's on here that Microsoft
and knows there is a there is an escape
hatch if you don't like that but firfer
for the majority of people there they're
taking that at faster build and for
those of you in the know a machine I'm
on just now is in the Windows 10 insider
preview so I get weekly dev builds from
the Windows boot from the dev branch to
the windows team that that is there's a
17 million people that do that so it's a
lot of people catching the tires and I
think that's the important thing is
getting stuff into production as quickly
as possible
and so I think this idea of learning is
something that you're all familiar with
and I want to just posit some kind of
kind of problems and challenges that I
think and many people seem to have had
and I particularly like this one because
you do a front release and then you
either get a smiley face back or some
strange characters but usually well that
this being Scotland it would just be
swear words but in most of the world
it'd probably just be swear words anyway
and what is this pile of crap that
you've I should I so the the three
things that I think posed this problem
and for for agility is what how and who
and if we break that down a little bit
the what challenges some of you will be
familiar with this data is from the
Standish Group and Boston that do the
chaos report and so no focus on on
product strategy and an effective
prioritization and I believe very few
organizations that say they're doing
agile actually have a prioritized
backlog so if you don't require this
backlog the engineers are just gonna
make up whatever it is that they they
want to do to work on it um those 65% of
the functionality that we build is not
used by our customers that's average you
could be worse or better
most people that think they're better
usually end up and worse when they look
at the data and 35% of your requirements
were change I'm sure you're familiar
with that figure as well and but weak
product owners poorly defined runs
responsibilities and product management
are key parts of that challenge so they
focus instead of focusing on a product
and making the right decisions for a
product they focus on time limited
short-term goals called projects
and those projects may or may not
provide benefit to the overall product
as the person running the project is not
measured generally by the overall
success of the product the measured by
the short-term success of the project
and in those worlds you tend to have a
long time to market can a long cycle
times I I would personally say anything
longer than 30 days time to market is
too long and there's another
organization that agrees with me I did a
presentation recently on detecting agile
[ __ ]
which is a Department of Defense article
you finding that did that last last week
people find that as well where I talk
about some of those issues I've got a
slide from it further on in the
presentation for you guys and the who
challenges who's doing the work and
apparently this is where we lose a lot
we lose 50 percent for ineffective
collaboration now I know many of you
work with teams that are trying their
best to be effective collaborators and
you're probably your number is probably
better than 50% an average across all
something like 70,000 IT projects
worldwide but that idea and you might
you might be not far off that 50%
depending on the way your organization
is is managed an effective servant
leadership that that idea of people
being managers instead of leaders inside
the organization is kind of key there
and is a big struggle and not having
good objectives you know that
misalignment of where we're going with
people's understanding of what it is is
is fairly fairly common and then we end
up with these hierarchies of
organizational structure that are based
on a hundred and thirty year old
terroristic practices that are really
out more deep for the modern modern
workplace subs the who there is also the
how in the how and we're really seeing
that growth of technical debt it's it's
systemic in our in our industry and even
big companies like like Microsoft and
who whose job it is to build software
and end up with significant amounts of
technical debt I like to use data I'm
not sure if I have that data in here I
can get it for anybody who asks for it
and but I have data around and how many
features the azure DevOps team in
Microsoft was shipping to production
eight years ago when they were still a
waterfall team and how many features
they're shipping to production now when
they were a waterfall team mounting
technical debt only deploying once every
two years they were shipping about
twenty five features to production each
year that's with six hundred and fifty
people and with the same number of
people now having spent eight years
paying back their technical debt so
moving that needle from fighting the
technical debt struggling with
complexity towards adding new features
they now add more than two hundred and
seventy features to production each year
so that just shows if they were spending
90% of their time struggling with
complexity pay back that technical debt
and you get a lot more done because your
teams aren't struggling with that so
much and that's a that's a common growth
of technical debt is one of the the
biggest blockers to that so you really
need to focus on that from an
engineering perspective but also I
mentioned anything that's automated
sorry
anything that's manual you want to
automate everything so manual testing
manual environment provisioning manual
building integration manual deployment
manual anything is a problem I did work
with a team in
Athens that was using a product called
starting to do their stars control don't
get me started we've moved them off star
team but and one of the features of star
team is branching and merging as you
would expect from our source control
system but the team didn't know they
knew about branching but they didn't
know about marriage so there was a 30-30
i between 30 and 60 people in this
organization that when they wanted to
bring changes from a branch across to
the main line
they were manually copying and pasting
those changes across there are still
teams out there who don't understand
some of these fundamental concepts and
need to start focusing on anything this
manual is a bad idea if we take all of
that that data that we saw there for the
different different challenges the thing
I like is this little graph here if your
input was a hundred euros
what would your output be based on 35
percent of your time spent building the
right features so then we've only got 35
percent left so I'd have a hundred
that's 35 euros and if we lose 50
percent for collaboration we're down to
17 and a half euros out of 100 and if we
spend 30 percent of our time building
new features and 70 percent of our time
struggling with complexity we end up
spending 5 euros 25 on adding new
features and out of a hundred that
that's that's a horrendous ROI and but
it's the reality for many organizations
out there but just to put that in
perspective for a million pounds spend a
million pounds on a project that's fifty
two thousand five hundred pounds of
value that's that's just not not good
enough and that's not just engineering
that's business processes that's know
focus on collaboration these are these
are super super common industry-wide
I know some of your teams might be
better than that but you also work
inside of wider organizations that may
still have some of those problem so we
want to be collaborative to be more
effective and that's why you know that's
why this little document exists the idea
of the agile manifesto was to try and
focus on the right things rather than
the wrong things that organizations have
been focusing on but it's still taking
taking time to get there
and one of the things that I see I know
this is the way we do things around here
is the common thing was it the cup
culture eats agility for breakfast our
culture meets changed for breakfast or
culture just eats everything for
breakfast that's part of that that
problem and so does this journey that
organizations undertake companies talk
about an agile transformation I don't
really like that phrase because
transformation implies some kind of
completion which i think is just
fundamentally not not true and I usually
think about it more as an agile
evolution as an organization you're
going to be constantly changing towards
an effectively an unknown goal and that
you can have an idea of where you would
like to go next where would you like to
go in the next few steps but ultimately
where you end up is going to be
somewhere different and I usually use
this kind of diagram I know the Snyder
model is not I'm not selling you on the
Snyder model for sure and it's just for
illustrative purposes that if we have
break our organization up into into
these kind of kind of sectors where
would you plot your company would your
company be in the more at controlling
space or in cultivating
people space is it based on competence
or collaboration what what percentage of
each of these would it be based on
there's no 100% anything but if your
organization was in a particular place
and you say you want to go somewhere
else it's not actually a straight path
like that it's more of our wibbly-wobbly
Road and I like to think of it as
orienteering you go off in a particular
direction you hit an obstacle you figure
out how to get round it and then you
figure out what's how do we reorient
take back to that important direction
that we're trying to get to and see
where we get to so it might not quite be
the same place you thought you were
going to get to hopefully it would be a
better a better place and so one of the
things that I think is really important
is you you can't I think I've said a lot
of important things and every
organization is is is unique you start
from a unique spot even if you use
Schneider you start from a new unique
spot you end up in the unique spot and
however you want to do that everybody is
unique so the idea that you can take a
methodology that somebody else has built
and apply it to your organization is
really a fallacy as its it's not going
to work what works for you might not
work for another organization for what
works for them might not work for
somebody else an experimentation and
iterating towards these ideas is really
important but that iteration towards
ideas that acceptance that our current
processes are imperfectly defined is
fundamentally it fundamentally means
that we can't just
use somebody else's process I have two
processes that I'm thinking of I'm sure
you're familiar with both of these and
one is safe
skill agile framework I know the newer
versions of safe my picture is v4 of
safe remember what they're on now there
may be as high as V but the ideas
original idea of safe was Dean didn't
living well implemented in an
organization how to do everything and
then documented it and published it as a
framework that folks could folks could
use and it quite often failed in in fact
mostly it failed in organizations that
it was implemented afterwards it might
have worked in the first organization
because that was custom-built for them
but then failed in future organizations
same with the Spotify model and the
Spotify model is not really a Spotify
model I mean the folks at Spotify would
kind of laugh if you said you
implemented the Spotify model because
what is written in that white paper is
not what those teams do today and the
white paper and the presentations that
the Spotify team did where a
point-in-time presentation a point in
time understanding of what what they
were doing at that point in time they've
moved on since then they've changed
their practices to suit what worked and
what didn't some of the practices that
are described in that white paper lasted
a couple of months some of them lasted a
couple of years some of them lasted five
minutes it just depends what what things
make sense and I think that's the
important thing
because really is something I like to
say there's no such thing as best
practices only adequate practices for
the situation at hand and there's
there's no guarantees everything's going
to be different and I really enjoyed I
don't know if anybody saw
if anybody's read and the the Department
of Defense how to detect agile BS but
it's an article that was written a white
paper sent out to all of the procurement
officers within the Department of
Defense to help them figure out whether
their vendors are actually telling them
the truth about being agile or they're
just saying they're agile because you
know that's the thing you have to say
now in order to get the contract and
something happened recently those that
those that know and might have seen this
already but I have a little US Air Force
I have the original memorandum that came
with this this was a clarification of
that that memo and I'm the the CSO I
can't remember what CSO stands for chief
something officer I can't remember
anyway the the senior officer in charge
of IT and for the US Air Force is quite
a progressive thinker and and he likens
safe to waterfowl it's a large bloated
prescriptive framework that tells you
how to go do something and you won't
find any large successful commercial
organizations doing anything that looks
like safe they've all built their own
custom process based on the way they do
things now I'm not saying that safe
doesn't have value I think it does have
value in certain circumstances and if
you see the like the fifth bullet point
down safe might be potentially might
potentially be used a useful framework
for teams who do not use DevOps
but a key principle of DevOps is to
decouple work in teams and only
synchronization required about donors
bhagavad I mean that's not quite right
but know what I mean and that idea of
having that monolithic process I
think really really works and that said
lots of organizations that are not yet
ready for DevOps not yet ready for true
agility um get a little way of the way
there but I think there's definitely uh
what's it called when you you think
you're you're there but you're not there
there's a false sense of security maybe
mmm I'm not sure what the word is and
but you have this false sense they
you're you're doing something agile when
you're using safe when safe is in fact
the complete antagonistic opposite of
agility
it's a prescriptive framework and I know
that new versions of safe are less
prescriptive but that's its source
that's its routes and you may as well be
doing PMI prints two versions of agility
and provide the same benefit I think
start from something that works a little
bit a little bit better so hopefully
everybody's read there's this idea of
five dysfunctions of a team it's an
awesome awesome book and I have that
presentation on detecting agile BS that
was into a little bit of that but the
thing that we tend to do in
organizations is we we we have this
complex world and I think however
however you-you-you understand it I
think this is the idea of software
development being product development
rather than product delivery you know a
car production line is product delivery
Toyota developed the the lean Toyota
Production system in order to deliver
cars not design cars the design team for
Toyota don't use the name Toyota
Production system because it's a
different sort of work in the software
world which I am that's my background
our production line is our DevOps
pipeline that's our from the time a
developer commits codes to the
repository till it gets into production
that's our production light or
everything before that the writing of
the code the merging everything together
those are those are creative endeavors
that sit in this complex world of more
is unpredictable than predictable with
emergent answers and many competing
ideas I'm sure you've you've seen these
before I know I've talked to Satpal
about these quite often but
organizations tend to use a different
management style the leaders job they
tend to use is best practice you know I
hear that all the time in organizations
this idea of best practices and
establishing patterns and optimizing to
them and you wouldn't believe the number
of organizations that still have a
command and control at hierarchical
outlook to the world it's it's very
difficult to get to get em organizations
to treat complex work like complex work
so in a complex environment you're
supposed to create a bounded environment
for action so we want to have some
boundaries so everybody's going in the
same direction but inside of those
boundaries we don't really know how to
solve the problem and so we need folks
to kind of get there themselves and
obviously we want to increase
communication because we're talking to
each other more we come up with better
ideas
so generating those ideas servant
leadership obviously to get things out
of the way for those people to be able
to do the work and do it effectively
create an environment for that to work
and so we need to start somewhere and
where we need to start and is probably
some kind of loose framework and my
background is a scrum I'm not opposed to
replacing every time I mentioned the
word scrum with Kanban I'm just using
this for illustrative purposes again and
I like scrum I like scrum with Kanban I
teach the professional scrum with Kanban
class from scrum dark I'm co-teaching
with Daniel Vacanti
we're gonna do an online class Ferb well
it was supposed to be an in-person class
in Edinburgh but obviously it's going to
be virtual
but I'm going to be teaching with Daniel
Vacanti in a couple of months and we're
going to dive into how do we take those
and complimentary Kanban ideas the core
practices of Kanban and apply them into
the the scrum world and so I don't think
I mentioned that in this presentation
but it's pretty good you can go and get
the cat the Kanban guide for scrum teams
which is a free website so we have this
idea of potentially using some kind of
framework I'm using the scrum framework
for a product inside an organization so
we maybe have one team working against
this product and and instead of being
part of the hierarchy they kind of
exists within a separate bubble I've
seen this done in organizations where
they've actually created a separate
company for the engineering teams to
work in so they can work in a different
way
i with the hierarchy of the rest of the
organization and I've seen this done in
KLM where they created a studio for that
work to happen and move the software and
so for teams into that and it used
services from the rest of the
organization so those shared services
might be infrastructure QA might be HR
might be any of those those things
outside of that and so you basically get
a small pocket of scrum inside your
organization a lot of organizations try
to do a massive transformation they
maybe do a small pilot project and a
massive transformation and generally
those fail usually they end up at
something using something like safe
because they need to figure out how to
do everything all at once and that just
tells you that
so this scrum framework is just a - I
mean the the scrum is just a tool to
help us create an empirical process
control system within which we can
inspect and adapt towards creating a
more optimal system
that's really what is designed for some
famous Kanban except a little bit more
make sense so do scrum well or do cab
Manuel is your first step
am i I do it well I mean that people are
really not good it even doing scrum at
all or doing Kanban at all I got two
teams all the time who say they're doing
Kanban and then you know they've just
got bored with stickies that move across
it that's not Kanban where your whip
limits where your your concrete
processes where are they not decided any
of those things so some interesting data
here which is actually from Forrester
Research and is only 22% of
organizations that say they've adopted
agile and are actually doing short
iterations if you're not doing short
iterations
you're not very agile only 13% do
retrospectives if you're not inspecting
and adapting what what are you doing and
only 16% of prioritized backlogs though
these are appalling numbers that are
that are only only getting getting worse
as more organizations move towards
agility and more snake oil salesmen and
charlatans convinced them to do the
wrong thing and I actually worked with
some some folks in organizations and the
their organization is sold unsafe so
they create something that they can sell
is safe but it's actually much more
agile than say if it's a custom process
for them so some organizations that say
they're doing safe actually aren't
they're doing their own thing and that's
okay I'm okay with that
just some extra data if we fix these
problems we can improve a lot of things
in our organization and try not have
just skin deep I like that expression
skin deep agile I think Ken and Jeff
call it flaccid agile I like that one as
well
I usually call it
mechanical I call it mechanical scrum
we're just mechanically following it
we're not actually doing the things
those are pretty effective so step two
is you need to enhance it you need to do
those things like create empirical
systems have our engineering practices
coding guidelines user experience
emergent architecture all of those
things and and once we've got good
engineering practices for me that's the
engineering practices parts you get
mechanical scrum engineering practices
and then introduce the values behind the
processes how do you build a system
within which you can have transparency
that you see the truth and these are
trying to trying to create that and so
whatever your you're doing you need to
focus on all of those things to get to
this idea of doing something
professionally rather than just doing
something and I think that's that's the
fault are in many organizations is they
don't focus on professional scrum
because we don't have time to do testing
let's just get stuff done or we don't
have time whatever the things we don't
have time for to focus on that
professionalism and then we end up with
with some kind of small loose framework
around which we can build our own custom
processes that's the idea I'm looking at
so we can then add multiple teams into
this bubble and that all work by
different rules use these shared
services and we've upskilled the
individual teams because the reality is
that skilled teams are 224 percent more
likely to be successful than unskilled
teams that seems like it makes common
sense but it doesn't necessarily make
common sense and a lot of organizations
they believe that scrum or Kanban is
just this unicorn that's able to solve
all of their problems and but it ends up
being you've heard the term scrum er
fall or many waterfalls and everything
ends up being a bit of a car crash
that's our very common thing I actually
do have the the Kanban stuff in here
they're mate and so one thing that I
always get teams to do once they get to
that professional scrum level is they
need to start looking at their floor and
optimizing for it folks on the call who
are agile practitioners who work in
these big organizations you'll know what
I'm talking about if you take a bunch of
amateur teams and try and get them to
look at their floor it's an even bigger
car crash you have to get professional
teams first get them all all going in
the same direction delivering a working
increment every iteration once you can
get there start introducing flow start
optimizing for smaller batches and focus
on that idea and I mentioned the
professional scrum Kanban the command
guide for scrum teams and it talks about
the five core practices visualize
limiting work-in-progress actively
manage items make polls explicit and it
proved collaboratively and those are the
core varieties from camera and so I'm
not talking about the Kanban method
which is from lku I'm just talking about
those those core Kanban practices and
something that can said recently was the
the only foundation to scale is
professional teams you need to get the
professional teams first before you can
scale and I'm sure you've seen a bunch
of unprofessional teams shoved together
and trying to build some software it's
always an amusing car crash and but
Steve Porter who was one of the
co-creators of the Kanban guide for
scrum teams added that manage flow the
only foundation for skill is
professional teams that manage flow
because the reality is of scaling is
expensive it's hard it's wasteful
ultimately don't scale scaling it is an
anti-pattern of software development you
need to avoid it at all costs
because scaling doesn't go linearly it
has this very quick tail off as you add
more people and then at some point you
add enough people that it gets too
complicated and you end up with
something that is just not a lot of fun
this is I think this is our P I planning
yeah this is the last P I plus the video
from the last pipelining that I saw so
you can scale continuously
as long as you do certain things and but
you need to do them all the time you
need to identify and remove impediments
i--sorry dependencies dependencies are
going to be your killer so anytime you
can create vertical slices so feature
teams rather than horizontal teams
obviously and but integrating work all
the time across all levels one of the
downfalls of office at 2012 was that
they weren't integrating every iteration
they had most of their stuff integrated
but not everything so then they ended up
nine months later with a big problem and
then create and inspect those increments
regularly obviously make sure your teams
have the tools and skills necessary to
do things at scale it's going to take
more tools it's going to take that more
time it's going to be harder to beat to
get get up get on board with that and
obviously keep keep inspecting and
adapting frequency frequently scrum dark
noticed that this scaling thing was a
problem they were very late to the
scaling framework party and the reason
for that was they wanted to take their
time and make sure that they had
something the in keeping with scrum is
the absolute minimum you need to make
sure you maintain the levels of
communication that you need to create an
empirical process control system so they
came up with something called the the
nexus framework
which is a lot smaller than a lot of the
other frameworks that are out there um
I'm thinking of a scrum at scale I'm
thinking of safe I'm thinking of other
frameworks because it's not going to
tell you how to go solve your problems
it's just going to deal with those
communication issues between teams and
I've seen Nexus and I've seen Nexus
implemented quite a few times with
organizations and it's very easy and
quick for people to understand because
it's only a little bit more than scrum
and it doesn't add a huge amount of
complexity or overhead you've
effectively got this idea of um you know
you you're gonna have to do refinement
now whereas if you get one scrum team
with three people you maybe don't have
to refine but if you've got nine scrum
teams of 10 people working together men
and you're gonna have to make sure you
have all of your backlogs in a good
state and then you need little teams of
teams to get together to make sure that
you have good communication so you can
see the Nexus sprint planning has a
little Nexus that gets together it's a
team of teams it's the right people
opens our open space rules and from the
scrum teams that get together to figure
out some dependencies to figure out how
we're going to move forward for the next
sprint and take it back to the rest of
the scrum teams which may or may not be
in the same time zone it's okay to have
multiple as long as the individual
members of your team are on the same
team on in the same time zone in the
same cool ok they don't have to be
co-located but it's more optimal then
more optimal is having those teams
together and then multiple teams in
multiple locations or in the world can
work together so I asked Nexus sprint
planning might run over 24 hours because
you've got that time lag we just need to
deal with that problem we need to figure
out how to do that obviously the closer
people are the better but there's the
realities of business and and then we
need a view on all of our work so the
Nexus sprint backlog
with a way to view individual teams
backlogs we only have one review because
we've got one product I think that's
important but even on a daily basis we
maybe have that team of teams get
together to discuss dependencies and
issues and then at the at the whole
Nexus level and then take that back to
the team's daily scrums again just a
15-minute before everybody else's daily
scrum representatives that make sense
from the other teams get together figure
it out take that information back same
in the retrospective you're going to
have but you're gonna have kind of
you're gonna have to one of the
beginning one at the end because you
might have a bunch of things that need
to be input into the team's
retrospectives and then the teams might
come up with all sorts of clever ideas
to go solve those things so that team of
teams gets together to bring all that
information back that's the idea from
Nexus it's just meant to be the minimum
I'm not saying it's the right framework
for you but it can be a useful a useful
tool that has those very simple added
extras to help you get that increment at
the end I didn't mention the Nexus
integration team because it tends to be
a very poorly understood the integration
team is not your DevOps team it's not
your build team it's a team of teams
it's a group of people who get together
to solve whatever problem is inhabiting
the team's ability to get a working
increment there's no point in the scrum
masters getting together
if the problem is merging code they're
not going to know how to solve that
problem you need the right people so
effectively a nexus integration team is
just representative some various teams
the right people maybe they're scrum
masters maybe they're engineers it just
depends on what the problem is they're
trying to solve it's not a permanent
team they're gonna go back and the teams
the individual scrum teams inside the
Nexus to the do the work that's the idea
behind Nexus and having these breaking
teams so then we can bring in a much
larger product into our story and you've
got lots of little small products use no
service
overseas and then we bring in a larger
product into that into that world so as
more than three teams working together I
don't know where that animation came
from never mind
so that that essence of scaling is we
need to anticipate problems by focusing
on minimizing dependencies that's your
your your almost most expensive concern
is minimize dependencies and then make
working software you're still a team of
people working together to make a single
product so if you don't have a working
increment at the end of every iteration
we're not there yet we need to get that
working integration so just inspecting
and adapting towards that world and
you're probably talking about more
engineering practices for absolute focus
on minimizing technical debt automated
testing continuous build and delivery
very very very important
some examples of teams that are using
Nexus Capital One has delivered some
products with Nexus and I like the
comment they are to less than an hour to
explain access to teams that are already
familiar with scrum it's not much more
than scrum so Capital One Kathy Pacific
Airlines and also use Nexus as well and
that that really helps so while I'm I
think this is a very miss Atwell I think
this is a misleading quote but small
teams of 32% relate to succeed large
projects are 600% and that's because
large projects are such a big mass that
they can get 600 percent improvement and
they probably both get a similar
improvement is just much more obvious in
a large project and I think small
project here is 50 people or less large
project is more than 50 people Gail's
reports that but what that is and so we
we came up with this kind of bubble
just back to my bubble of scrum in my
case or bubble of Kanban or even you
could have one team doing can add
another one doing scrum it doesn't
matter you know these shared services
there's bubble in which people work
differently and and potentially you need
to at some point you're gonna have
enough going on in there
that you need to start focusing on that
leadership ideas and and that's where
you start to look at how do we get the
CEO CIO involved in that and provide
agile functions of leadership like HR
finance and admin there are things that
the whole team can use in an agile
fashion rather than just using the
shared services from other projects um
how do you build this new type of
organization that is flatter structure
or not based on hierarchy and inside of
that and then this idea of bringing in
more products you might have some bigger
products that have multiple Nexus again
the windows team has four and a half
thousand people working on it and the
office I think has 300 scrum teams 300
scrum teams now they've come up with
their own way to solve that problem
that's okay too this is just a framework
that you could use to help you get
started but it's it's interesting to
note the the characteristics that I'm
showing here are things that these big
organizations that are doing agile well
whatever they call those things or how
they implement them they have something
that kind of fits this bill and and the
next thing we need to understand is how
do we know it's all working so something
that I think is very important is
understanding whether you're making
improvements the organization
organizations spend a lot of money with
us agile practitioners to come in and
help them get better at delivering
software how do we know we're making
things better well we need some kind of
metrics to monitor scrum that arc has
some example metrics and I'm really
stressing that super
a heavily example metrics in particular
categories but I think the categories
are the thing that's important we've got
to look forward to towards the future
with market value let's you get the
current value you've delivered in your
product and how you monitor and measure
that so you're gonna need some metrics
around current value how do we
understand that and then we've got
unrealized value value we don't know
that we need to have yet how do you look
at the market how do you look at market
trends and analysis and figure that out
build that into ability to innovate how
quickly can we innovate how much time
will we spend innovating in our product
so we need some metrics of own around
our innovation so I might be capex
darzee's our pecs is a super simple one
but I think it gets cloudy you're gonna
need some other measures in there and
then time to market how quickly can we
actually get our product in front of
users and I'll use the example of the
windows team again which gets their
software every thirty days in front of
600 I think it's is it not a billion
machines now yeah it was used to be six
hundred million machines it's closer to
a billion machines now worldwide that's
pretty impressive engineering practices
to get there I don't know why that
animations coming in I have some example
measures in the deck I'm not going to go
through them all and I'll just flick
across but you've got to figure out
leading and lagging indicators some of
them are more important than others and
these are just examples they might not
work for your organization I don't know
why there's animation again and it's
doing it on all of them but unrealized
value time to market so even um cycle
time release frequency leak time these
are a lagging indicators there are there
are leading indicators frequency of
build success might be a leading
indicator make sure you've got
understand your measures effectively and
innovation rate installed version index
is a good one if you have a desktop
product what percentage of your
customers are
the latest version of your product and I
think that's a good indication of how
versatile your organization or your
product is at getting getting out people
aren't taking new versions there's
probably something wrong is probably
technical debt it's probably hard to
install hard to support how hard to
bring people out to speak all kinds of
things like that so those are just
example metrics if you're gonna collect
some metrics just get started
don't worry about getting too detailed
collects the metrics monitor the data
and see if you're improving things or
not within your organization and I use
some of the metrics here with customers
I work with and and we monitor that data
to make sure that when we make changes
they're actually adding value and it's
okay to make changes and they don't add
value we'll just stop that change we'll
stop doing that thing but we need to
know that it's making a difference and
the only way you can do that is with
concrete measures and this time EBM
metrics evidence based management
EVM is something that actually comes out
of the medical profession about a
hundred years ago or actually a hundred
and twenty ish years ago the medical
profession decided that it would be a
good idea to makes decisions on your
health based on you know data like your
blood pressure and you know collecting
some data and figuring out how to solve
your problem rather than just making up
an idea and hoping it works so this
evidence-based management is for
managers and organizational leaders to
look at actual data make changes see how
those changes impact the data are we
taking the organization in right
direction like project cost per
iteration time to market innovation rate
how much time do we spend innovating
there see struggling with complexity
satisfaction of our customers and
employees is that trending up or is it
trending down product revenue and costs
these are all things that are
measures of organizational and product
performance and and we want to be
optimizing those things we want to
making those numbers look a bit a little
bit better and we can tell whether we're
making headway if we have balance across
all of those things that's why I had
four different categories of metrics
because we could have asked awesome time
to market but we're delivering a bunch
of crap to our customers so we need to
make sure and that we balance all of
that out yeah
just keep things simple and while my
diagram might look super complicated now
you saw it's literally just it's just
scrum are we to scale scrum very simply
and then a way to to measure it and
that's really the idea the SDK in there
is just and let's share some data so
it's probably a community of practice
across all of our teams to help share
some of those good ideas and maybe
create a starter pack for any new team
starting up where should they start
within the context of this organization
so every company will build something
different and frameworks are just a
starting point and it's okay for them to
start with Kanban start with scrum and
start with and whatever whatever makes
sense for them I had just some final
suggestions where is it there yep and
make sure you measure and focus on value
and outcomes rather than output and
progress and we can output a lot of crap
and not get to the outcomes that our
organization needs to get to celebrate
success improve the results get create a
holistic view of what you're doing and
try and improve those measures come up
with a hypothesis measures move figure
out if you're doing the right thing
maximize
learning and really just do the best you
can
I think Scott had a good comment is
sometimes you'll try something and
you'll just be wrong and that's okay we
need to do the best we can with the
information we have and see where we get
to that was kind of what I wanted to
cover and so just say I covered a bunch
of stuff around scrum engineering
excellence with the Kanban guide
next is framework so don't scale pretty
much is my advice and really I've
already at all costs if you can and then
evidence-based management actually make
sure you look at data and you can get a
copy of the slides from that link at the
bottom and that's already been published
for you and I guess we move over to
questions yeah we'll take questions
I've got a type was I talking to him
about any country no no no we don't any
come with chat so yeah if there are
questions you have we've got Tim to take
some yeah no II really enjoyed it it's a
really good insight I think just on the
nexus stuff because as you know I've
kind of been delving into the yes
grommets kill stuff lately yes in the
year and connect we enjoying the same
sort of ideas Nexus where you know you
want a really good kind of well-oiled
well so function and scrum team that's
doing it really well and then you're
kind of stealing it Oh Tiffin I take the
view that scrum at skill kind of is
similar to Nexus in that you know it
doesn't really add much more than just
you just got lots of scrum teams then
you've got some additional teams are
just supporting you as you scale up so
you start on the scrums and then some of
the government's teams but Nexus those
scenes are even more simpler than that
do you see any in
Challenge have you ever so implemented
Nexus somebody coming in and Nexus is a
framework I think you think Nexus lacks
so yeah there are tons of things that
Nexus lakhs it's supposed to like them
it's it is just a framework just like
scrum lacks what is your definition of
done yeah if you don't have a good
definition of done you're scrums not
going to be very good if you you don't
know where your backlog comes from and
how to get that and create a backlog
scrum doesn't tell you how to do that
and Nexus is the same it's it's trying
to be um it's trying not to be
prescriptive on your business practices
because the the the reality is that the
way sorry I've said that quite a lot the
reality is I'll strain stop doing that
and every organization is unique the
success or failure of an organization is
in that uniqueness so the idea that and
i know i'm i was pooping unsafe a lot
but the idea that you can have every
organization use the same blueprint and
be just as successful is is why Nexus
and scrum at scale and scrum are very
compact and the minimum to solve the the
empirical problem you want to create
empirical process control system so you
can expect and adapt to the best
possible outcome or at least the most
relevant okay bad idea and I think ken
and Jeff almost totally agree between
Nexus and scrum at scale and there's
just the some differences in the
terminology but definitely there's a
little bit more in scrum at scale that
can just didn't want to be prescriptive
about and I think that's that's okay I
think there's room for all of the
frameworks
and I will say if if you're using a
scrum at scale and you're going to have
exactly the same outcomes as you might
have if you use Nexus as long as you see
it as a starting point and a foundation
and not here's what we're gonna do does
that make sense
yeah I think so I think as you see the
best Fremont's are probably ones that
it's exactly in the definition of a
framework right it kind of give some
shape but it doesn't try to be too
prescriptive and it shouldn't be because
then it's good
yes it's dictating too much to unit it's
going to be restrictive right and
constrain you and every as you say every
organization is unique so you need to
have but room to maneuver to a little
needs and then that's a good thing yeah
it did any questions come in I'm gonna
get good ones here yeah I like this
first one so Mark Martin is asking
because I often have this conversation
myself so Mars is interested in soft
product owner opinions so if we pull
them from they always just don't some
other ones have common one say if we
pull them from the business you know
people gets appointed you know into the
rule and they tend to be economics bag
is there any ways of any good ways of
can I help and get them into shape in
your experience cuz you know what the
different types of deals right they come
in different flavors what are your
thoughts on helping app you get to the
place you might want them to so that it
affected yeah I miss equation I'm
definitely I'm definitely going to punt
the professional scrum product owner and
so you know I don't teach that one so
I'm putting somebody else these things
but I think that that many product
owners when when they first start and
even if they've been approached or for
quite a long time they have a very
narrow view of what a product owners job
is very narrow and
if you think about a product owner as
being fully fiscally accountable what
they choose to spend money on then that
idea of accountability inside of scrum
which comes with that product owner rule
accountability for value is is is key to
that so if they don't understand that
accountability or they don't enact that
accountability so they need to be
looking at the market market trends they
need to be looking at and how users are
actually using the product and a lot of
or quite a lot of UX comes under the
product owner world because that's how
users interact with their ideas these
are all business problems to go solve
the technical part actually hit that
tends to not be the biggest problem it's
getting those product owners up to speed
and I do have a company I worked with in
Australia a consulting company and and
they they themselves would pay for the
potential product owners from their
customers to go on the professional
scrum product owner class so that they
knew what was expected of them and they
found that that I guess 2000 Australian
dollars that two thousand dollar
investment made a massive difference to
the success or failure of their projects
with those customers because they really
understood the scope of that product
product owner role leti that comes with
it I'll tell you something
I've been through the part-owner class
and and I figured out that I wouldn't
ever want to be a product owner and I've
done it I've done the PSP you and I
think you're right I think if you're
really doing it there's a lot for one
person to be accountable for and just
you know the different dimensions to the
role yeah you know that there are so
alongside you to piece in some ways you
and a bit like they were
you know we talked about the the Nexus
mchugh the product yeah exactly so the
scrum at scale you know if you're the
chief product owner you might likely
actually be the chief exec and you're
cleaning that room
some organizations in it's like that so
yeah it's so I would say just as a final
product owner thing is your product
owner is the one that's accountable to
the business for value delivery not the
development team so if your development
team are have good engineering practices
and are delivering high-quality working
increments every iteration but they're
building the wrong thing the buck should
stop at the product owner not at the
development team because they don't
decide what they go work on having some
of those ideas engrained into that role
and will help if people feel that
they're they're responsible for spending
money they'll up their game misuk anyone
yeah not sure they get that's an
excellent put got another one for you
here oh yeah just about something so
cake leagues
I guess it's coming back to what you
were talking about earlier by we talked
about three more simple prescriptive
they are so if we avoid being
prescriptive do we risk never being able
to set a direction of travel
ie doing scrum badly as they accept it
norm
I think that is an interesting point so
that the question is if we're being less
prescriptive are we in danger of off
doing doing scrum badly as just
attempting that yeah um I I would say no
because what what are what are the
transparencies in scrum give you three
transparencies in scrum oK you've got
transparency of the future in the
product backlog do we know where we're
going and how we might start to get
there that's the part of the owners I
came to
so if you don't have an ordered backlog
if everybody in the organization that
needs to it doesn't understand what's in
that backlog and why it's there you've
got a problem you're not doing scrum
yeah that rule of product owner is not
doing its job
and you've got the the Sprint backlog
which provides transparency for the
present what you're doing now that has
its own things but not aware that just
no and then you get transparency of the
past which is the usable increment so in
this in software terms you need to have
working software that can be deployed to
production at the end of every iteration
including the first iteration does your
team have that if not they're doing
scrum badly they're doing agile badly
yeah you need to get that minimum bar I
and I think it's often overlooked the
minimum bar for scrum is a usable
increment you have to have working
software at the end of your sprint
otherwise that wasn't a sprint is then
you have no transparency you can't
inspect and adapt you don't have an
empirical process control system I think
in in this group we can have this
conversation but when you're talking
with customers you have to be a little
bit more pragmatic and say well okay
you're doing scrum because you tried
really hard to get a working increment
and but I wouldn't expect a team to be
on Sprint 30 and still unable to get a
usable increment every single sprint
that should be a no-brainer by then yeah
there's your DevOps team at Microsoft
which was 40 teams working together on
one product took about 15 15 was a 15
maybe less or maybe 10 10 to 15 Sprint's
together craft together but that was six
hundred and fifty people working
together on one product but since then
every sprint of the last
hundred and fifty odd Sprint's eight
years of sprinting has been deployed to
production that's pretty impressive
that's that's like your minimum bar so
so Craig I I think that's the difference
between mechanical scrum actually doing
it
focus on the the values and principles
building trust the transparencies and
good scrum will come out of that and but
it is difficult it's a long journey and
you need to uplift the skills on your
team and your product owner along the
way to get there and I would definitely
create look at the Kanban guide for
scrum teams
that's the bat size and flow
optimization that you might be looking
for to take your not so good looking
scrum to the next level that's a
question but I guess you know but you
know this whole idea kind of starting
somewhere right we get it right you know
you just make a start I remember you
said coming in stable one of these guys
had a kind of core a chairman still when
you start somewhere you do need a
relatively good starting point how do
you go about trying to at least figure
out what might be a good start
you know you do it you do need something
how do you identify that it depends what
your I would say it depends what your
focuses I'm a good consultant when
everything starts with it depends and
you you're if if I'm in as a scrum
master with a scrum team by my focus and
while I've got a site focus of getting
good product ownership that can be a
little bit bigger political not to crack
and but getting a high quality
engineering team is something you can
focus on and having a good definition of
done
is is for me one of the top starting
points if you can get the team building
good software even if you're building
the wrong software it's no longer the
team's problem if that kind of makes
sense
um so one of the exercises I always try
and do with teams at the start even
teams that have been working together in
scrum for a while um is to get everybody
together who has to stay it's okay to
release your software to production so
you get your team you get your change
dudes you've got your ops whatever
you've got get everybody together and
get everybody do our liberating
structure the one two for all liberating
structure and get everybody to write
post-its for everything that has to be
true to ship yourself or to production
what needs to be true get all of those
post-its on a board de doop it that is
in effect your definition of done that
mirrors usable increment yeah you have
to be able to ship it to production for
it to be usable therefore all of those
things have to be true and then draw I
have another board with a line on it
above the line is stuff you can do now
below the line is stuff you can't do yet
it's just not it's not possible to do
that get organized the stickies
what's above the line is your current
definition of done what's below the line
are opportunities for improvement
impediments for removal work towards at
every sprint at your retrospective be
looking at the things that are below the
line is there anything that we've done
enough engineering work we've upskilled
our processes our practices are called
enough to move something up to that
definition of done and put a pin in it
and I think that that's where I would
start with most teams that that initial
definition of done and what are our
options for later hopefully everything's
above the light then you have a usable
increment that you can deploy to
production with no further work required
from the development team
it's good sure great
that's hard though fraud yes yeah well
you get that right you know please you
do I was gonna say you look you know not
feel the good place I yeah yeah you
might be building the rain I don't but
you're in a fairly good Wow
comes by thought you said LA you wanna
add value to the customer all right well
not many other questions coming through
so I'm just conscious entertain some
minute um do you want to see a couple of
stuff you've got coming up
I've got coffee some things you've got
the paper in and all you're gonna have
to move to virtual and you've probably
done a bit of work to do on that front
but you want to just if we're we're
scramble here yeah we're scrambling
around a little bit trying to figure out
how to do this not just from you know
flip that switch and make it virtual but
how do we can actually deliver classes
virtually um yeah so I've got a bunch of
classes that I had a pre set up for
Edinburgh and I think in two weeks I
have a
PSM and a provincial scrum master and a
professional scrum with UX class and
they'll both be moving to virtual but
they're pretty near nobody signed up for
them yet mainly because of all the
things that are going on and so if
anybody's interested please let me know
about that and then Daniel Vacanti who
was one of the original Kanban method
founders a Corbis and who co-founded the
LGU with David Anderson it is going to
be teaching professional scrum with
Kanban with me meant to be an Edinburgh
class again but we'll be doing it online
and I think after that we have our Apple
II professional agile leadership
essentials which focuses that that
middle management layer in an
organization that doesn't work directly
with on a scrum team that works with
scrum teams how do they move their game
from management towards leadership
that's the idea so we've got some stuff
coming up you can find it on my
website you can find it on the scrum
that org site as well
my website is nkd agility calm and if
anybody has any questions
Martin and KD agility comm also mr.
hench
on Twitter and wherever else you can
find me if you google for me you'll find
tons of stuff excellent brilliant fried
tomorrow that's great right just talk so
just a couple of committee announcements
[Music]
what's gonna be hopefully these vervain
so next week Thursday the 26th our
friends at the heart of agile we talked
I've got an amazing event actually
they've got a nice soft cuny for
charleen we aren't gonna be hosting Jeff
Watts I'm sure many of you here have his
books and how it's gonna be that's gonna
be awesome
I'm signed up for that one there's me
really good it's a beast I'm on the way
yes yeah are you know I was in there
fast
so yeah eighty folks lined up for a
starts gonna be brilliant and then our
next event is in me know for that 57th
that'll be the right to left if any of
you've read that so that's by our friend
Mike Barroso he's gonna be doing a
remote event talk about some of the key
ideas and not so that's one for your
diary if you're interested not you'll
find all these on Meetup so yeah sorry
not before they fill up and I think
that's it really if there's any others
yeah we can start elected on to the
LinkedIn group if anybody's interested
in joining laughs you know Kieran keep
talking a favor
socially didn't swing you know it's it's
not be distant keep the conversations
going and thanks for joining us evening
and yeah stay safe look after yourselves
and your loved ones billion thank you
thanks guys okay everyone
south and it slowly thank you BCS is