one of the seven deadly sins of agile is
wrath wrath occurs in many different
forms uh in teams working in
organizations um most often it's the
inability for us to do things wrong it's
the inability for um an organization to
accept that we're not going to do things
right every time
Um this can kind of manifest in um a
example from Recently um we need to
working with an organization we need to
create uh some some some procedures and
practices around um doing a deployment
need to create procedures and practices
um and the team that I've been working
with wants to create here's here's what
we think is going to work let's try that
and then as we figure out more we can
iterate on this policy and procedure and
get it to be what we need it to be in
order to be able to to be successfully
in production and then we can reuse that
as we go for for future applications
right future things that we're doing uh
but the the the other side uh didn't
want to do that they wanted to uh you
you create your final draft we'll take
that we'll run it around the hundred
people that need to go see it and we'll
create a spreadsheet with all of the
things wrong with it and here's the
things wrong with it that you have to go
fix before we can approve it right that
approval process is is wrath right it's
you can't be wrong therefore the end
result needs approved before you can do
it because if it's approved it's now no
longer your accountability so we're not
going to blame you right so it's a blame
culture uh uh uh uh technique it's going
to run up the chain get approved and
then whoever's approved it at the top
it'll be beneath them to solve the
problem anyway so if something goes
wrong oh it's not the people down here's
fault because it was approved go up who
approved it oh the CEO approved it well
okay then well it was wrong whatever
right so there's no there's no
accountability it's a lack of
accountability results in Wrath uh uh
going on in in the
organization and I think this this
manifests in lots of different ways I
think that's the core thing but it
manifests in lots of different ways uh
one of them uh that I've seen happen
with a team uh was um I had it was
during a a Sprint review uh the team was
demonstrating their product and features
to the
stakeholders and um one of the
stakeholders asked the team why did you
build it that way right in a kind of it
was in a kind of accusatory tone like
why did you build it that way right that
kind of kind of like that and
what I would expect to happen would be
that the product owner would take
accountability for the value delivered
in the team and they would get out in
front of that and say well these are the
decisions that we made we can always go
back and change them um blah blah blah
blah blah that's taking accountability
but no that's not what they did um wrath
they passed the buck and the product
owner turned to the team and said no why
did you build it that way right and
that's that's not taking accountability
and I think wrath is a is a big reason I
don't want it to be my fault it needs to
be somebody else's fault otherwise
something will land on me I'll get
covered in the poop uh uh from the from
the mistake that happens um and I think
that lack of mistakes is a huge huge
part of that story so don't let your
organizational culture of
Wrath create this environment where
nobody will take
accountability thanks for watching the
video If you enjoyed it please like
follow And subscribe I always reply to
comments and if you want to have a chat
about this or anything else agile scrum
or devops then please book a coffee with
me through naked
agility