one of the harbingers of the agile
apocalypse is judgment and this normally
comes in the form of um
prescriptive ways of doing things this
this could be organizational
prescriptive ways of doing things but
quite often it's um these these top down
uh
totalitarian prescriptive phras works
that tell organizations exactly what to
do when to do it what practices to use
and I understand why organizations and
leaders uh love it um they they they
don't necessarily know any different
right they don't they don't know what
the impact is on the ground of a lot of
these tools and and and things that
people decide you're all going to do it
this way um they don't understand the
the whole problem of you're all going to
do it this way right that's that's part
fundamentally part of the problem is is
everybody doing the same thing at the
same time is a factory not a a creative
collaborative organization right um so
the the the the these prescriptive ideas
and whether those prescriptive those
prescriptive ideas could be scrum I've
I've worked with organizations uh where
scrum ends up in the contract Thou shalt
do scrum or um it ends up as a as an
organizational man everybody's doing
scrum because they've been told to do
scrum that's stupid scrum might not be
the right thing for every team it not
might not be the right thing for every
group in your
organization agility is not about scrum
business agility is about figuring out
how you can
effectively deliver the highest possible
value to your customers that's what it's
about everything else is the [ __ ]
you use to try and make that happen Okay
so one of those tools in your toolbox
might be scrum another one might be can
ban another one might be scrum and can
ban there are all sorts of tools that
you can have in your toolbox that your
teams can choose to use don't prescribe
stories or story points don't prescribe
planning poker those things are great
once or twice maybe for a little bit but
they're not the long-term solution to
your problem the long-term solution to
your problem is not in rules it's not in
prescription
rules beget
judgment right people are going to judge
you for breaking the rules or not
following the rules and thou shalt
follow here's the Commandments you must
follow in our organization Thou shalt do
scrum right um don't don't don't cover
covet your neighbor agility right your
other organizations agility don't do
those things because you will be judged
right what we need instead of
judgment is we need principles what are
the principles upon which you would like
people in your organization to make
decisions right so you create a set of
principles for your organization for
your ways of working be very careful
that they don't just become rules in
disguise right you should have very few
principles in your organization this is
how we're going to do business everybody
should be honest right we want honesty
in what we do we want courage in what we
do um we want openness and transparency
in what it is that we do these are these
are principles that can help us make
better decisions every single person in
your organization is then an effect
itive decision maker they understand
they have the access to the data they
have access uh to to the information
they need in order to make those
decisions a a great example of of access
to to data is I was talking to a some
product owners from a car company um and
I asked them so how do you get access to
the Telemetry that's collected from the
Cars you know not all cars have live
Telemetry right they might have with you
go in to take your car in for service
they plug in and download the Telemetry
right so it's dumped into the system but
how do how do product owners and things
get access to that Telemetry well at
their organization it took six to8
months to get access to the Telemetry
for for whatever request they made
because of all the legal the rules and
procedures they had to follow in order
to get there oh but they did tell me a
story about what happens in Tesla when a
product owner wants access to the
Telemetry data right that's all it takes
they just have full access open
transparent within the organization for
all of the product owners have access to
all of the data and they can go slice
and dice it however they like in order
to help them understand what's going on
what trends are happening what faults
are happening what do we need to focus
on in order to make better decisions
right but rules and
procedures get in the way of people
doing the work rules and procedures were
great in the old school of organizations
traditional management organizations you
had a largely uneducated Workforce this
is turn of the century Industrial
Revolution thinking right you've got a
largely uneducated
Workforce they are not educationally
intellectually capable of making
decisions about the future of your
business therefore we want to push all
of those decisions up the organization
and here's the leadership cater the
bosses who make all of the decisions and
the people in the ground just do what
they're told so we're going to plan
their work we're going to separate them
into ability based groups and we're
going to tell them uh and we're going to
going to have train them only in those
particular abilities that that they're
going to do right that's how we've ended
up with marketing departments and sales
departments and legal departments and
Engineering departments and testing
departments and whatever other buls
you've got in your organization right
they're slow down the
ability for you to do business in the
old days it was great right cuz you had
this group of people you could train
them in that one thing they just do that
one thing and our our our product goes
through that those Gates Right and those
things happen or it's it's co it's it's
uh designed and then the analysis
happens and then it's coded and then
it's tested and then it's deployed right
it goes through that that that process
but today we don't have the luxury of
that amount of time the markets move
much faster and those procedures that
were designed to enshrine the business
processes that we need in order to
continue to move forward with a largely
uned Workforce are now getting in the
way because you have a hugely educated
massively smart engaged Workforce and
they're looking at your rules and
procedures and going why do I have to do
it that way that's G getting in the way
of me delivering value for my company
that's getting in the way of me taking
advantage of a business opportunity
that's floating by right you they can't
take advantage of it what happens what
happens to you when you're extremely
frustrated with an
activity do you continue to like that
activity or does it really annoy you and
maybe you want to leave that activity
that's why your best smartest people
leave because they don't like working in
those environments you need to move
towards
principles based on the three key
motivators of people autonomy Mastery
and purpose
autonomy right people need to feel like
they're in control of their own work
that they're making decisions for the
betterment of the organization and are
able to support and engage in the
organization in order for them to engage
with your company for that you need
principles not rules and
judgment thanks for watching the video
If you enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked
agility