so what is the best application of scrum
in the world I I don't think I could I
could uh mention at best but the
implementation that I respect the most
is probably the Azure devops teams at
Microsoft
um that took a waterfall product that
they delivered once every two years with
significant amounts of technical debt
and over eight years uh moved it towards
this uh uh Club they they closed the the
the chasm they were able to build a
product that really resonated with their
customers and they were able to
um go from man it used to took them
20 plus hours to build their product and
they got it down to three and a half
minutes that's an application of
effectiveness