um so the question was what is devops
and how is it different to Agile and and
I I would say fundamentally it's not
right fundamentally devops and agile
um is is is really
the same the same thing
right we're solving the same problem but
we're just looking at it from different
angles so you'll usually find the the
folks that are very process orientated
are like oh yeah agile is the thing and
devops is you know part of that story
it's the the automation piece in that
story
but then you talk to the devops folks
and they'll be like oh devops is this
big thing and agile is the process piece
in this in this in this story
um and I think that that for me
indicates and having lived Both Worlds
and indicates that that it's it's all
the same stuff we're talking about the
same thing we're trying to solve the
same problem we're telling the same
story we're just coming at it from a
different perspective it's how would
technical people solve this problem and
how would uh uh uh
non-technical people solve this problem
right although there are non-technical
people a lot of technical people in the
agile space so
um I think of devops and agile as two
heads they're the the two sides of of a
coin right
um come at it from whatever angle you
want it's the core practices it's the
the principles that are behind it that
are the thing that we should be focusing
on everything else is just the [ __ ]
we have to do to make those things
successful right
um whether it's getting Tools in in the
devops space whether it's looking at a
shortening shortening cycle times it's a
big Focus uh in in in devops or it's and
systems thinking or in the agile space
it's more looking at um how do we
encourage people to take accountability
how do we encourage shared ownership how
do we
um build an empirical High hypothesis
driven mindset right though those those
two things are you can't have one
without the other they both go together
and if you want to be successful at
delivering software products and then
you need both agile and devops in unison
to be able to be successful
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility