one of the biggest issues with uh
migrating as your devops up to the cloud
is probably that you're only going to do
it once and because you're only going to
do it once um you're unlikely to have
the skills already in existence in house
uh to be able to do that migration and
it probably doesn't make sense to build
those build and maintain those skills in
house because it's something you're
probably only going to do once um so for
B
Microsoft's um um uh database migration
depending on the size of your database
it can get quite
complicated um doesn't quite hit complex
but when you start um running a lot of
the validation tools against it to make
sure that your environment is compliant
for moving up to Azure devops is when
you get a lot of wacky stuff um that
is there's rabbit holes you need to go
into to understand a lot of that stuff
because um there are things that perhaps
could have happened to your system if
for example in the past uh somebody had
a a particular version installed um and
Microsoft made a a mess up right and
they released a patch and
between the install and the patch um
somebody made the change that the patch
is supposed to fix but it didn't quite
fix the actual data then um you you're
left with a data and a little bit of a
inconsistent format and what you
normally need to do is run some commands
against the system um and understanding
those commands what they're actually
doing um can be can be quite a deep
Rabbit Hole to get into um but
ultimately um we've done hundreds of
migrations I've been working with aure
Ops since it was Visual Studio team
system and it launched back in 2005
2006 uh so i' been working with it for a
long time and I built the tools uh that
Microsoft recommend to do um the the
peace more peace bu migration like I
want to move one team I want to merge
projects I want to split projects uh
those types of migrations which that's a
lot even more deeper skills necessary to
be able to run that tool because it's
it's
um really really really flexible when
you have things that are really really
really flexible that increases the
complexity and the configurability of
that thing um so you you you need
somebody to spend a lot of time figuring
that out we we have that knowledge and
expertise because we built the Tool uh
so if you're going to
do one migration or a few migrations
over a small period of time time you're
probably better just hiring somebody to
do that work if you're going to do a
whole bunch of migrations over a long
period of time um I do also work with
customers where we we train people
within the organization to use the tools
and then we help them uh uh run the
tools on a continuous basis um help with
support because you always run into
crazy things that are specific to you as
a customer those data shapes that I
mentioned perhaps in the midsts of time
of your your TFS environment um your
environment the database was originally
controlled under the control of the
developers right because uh it's a
developer tool so maybe maybe operations
didn't really own it and the developers
decided to install TFS 2013 beta 1 uh
which was supported by Microsoft but can
cause lots of weird data things um and
then it's on track it's been handed over
to operations
uh but there's some weird ID
idiosyncrasies in there so bringing in
expertise for for those types of things
whether it's for training the people
that you have that you want to do
long-term lots of different migrations
or if you just want somebody to take it
off your hands and do it for you um
that's ultimately what we're here for
you don't need the expertise in house