I love hierarchies of competence because
they're based on they're based on
respect right they're not based on
control they're not based on telling
people what to do they're based on
recognized
competence and capability of the people
that are doing the work and
you you you you we naturally defer
um sometimes to those people or want
more information from those those folks
to help convince us to do things because
they've demonstrated that knowledge that
they are an expert in that space that
they can add value to the conversation
and that perhaps they have a more
um
holistic view of all of the facets of
the problem and are able better able to
to make that decision