here's what you need to know about data
integrity and is your devops
migrations um you can't have everything
depending on what it is you want to do
so there's a balance to be had between
Fidelity of the data that you're
migrating and the flexibility that you
want as part of your migration process
um so as your devops on Prem was TFS um
has a a database based architecture
right so you have a whole database of
data if you're taking that whole
Database The Collection um in in TFS and
Azure devops if you're taking that up to
Azure devops services in the cloud um as
one thing the whole thing we're taking
it together then we have the highest
Fidelity possible right we're we're
effectively taking the entire database
up with everything in it's in exactly
the same format that it is just now um
but for many organizations that's not
what they want to do they have a couple
of teams that want to go or they have
some teams that are able to go and other
teams that aren't um so part of that
migration uh uh process we've built a
bunch of tools that allow you to
selectively slice out the data that you
want to take uh but it does mean like
lower Fidelity because we're effectively
replaying the story of the data um
against the new environment right so
we're not importing the database we're
um replaying what happened with the data
and that means that there is a little
bit of data loss things don't always go
perfectly um but within that context of
taking uh the the the your choice of
data pick and mix uh from one place to
another it is the most flexible um
approach you can have