of why have I decided to go all in on a
massive learning experiences I think I
think it's because that's what works
right I I feel that time and time again
I've run
um today the traditional model which is
two day or kind of four half day classes
I've run those traditional classes and I
I feel like people learned a lot of
stuff during those classes right they
absorbed a lot of stuff perhaps it
planted some seeds that will eventually
someday grow into something but if
anybody's tried to grow seeds into
plants you can't just plant the seed one
seed and hope for the best right you
kind of have to nurture it and take care
of it over a longer period of time until
it's ready to stand on its own right you
might even have that you have to put
that stick in to make sure the plant
doesn't fall over until it stems big
enough all of those those things
are what immersive learning
um provides provides that extra support
perhaps provides that longer term
continuous engagement
um that hopefully also results in more
collaboration and communication between
the people that were involved anyway so
it continues beyond that
um that immersive experience so quite
often if you just do a two-day class how
often do you speak to the people that
you were in that two-day class for
um after you've been in that two-day
class right
um I bet most people never hear from
them again never speak to them again
never even think of them again right but
um if you if you went through an
immersive experience and the immersive
experiences for different classes vary
right from from six weeks all the way up
till uh 10 weeks right perhaps some of
them are going to be going to be longer
but if you you've had to
um
collaborate over that period of time
go and do assignments and kind of what's
the expression
barrier all I don't know how to how to
describe it that that thing where
you're you're you're talking to people a
group of people when you're debriefing
the assignments that you've had and
you're talking about the real
experiences that you've just had trying
to do that you're sharing part of
yourself with this group of people and
that should build over these weeks a
level of camaraderie with that the rest
of your cohorts right that that group of
people who've been through that
experience
and that it should enable a much greater
likelihood of continuous collaboration
but also there's a
much greater likelihood that you've
actually learned something because
you're able to we're basically
implementing double Loop learning right
where where you're able to to go and try
and do the thing that you've learned in
the class and then
come back around and say was this what I
was meant to do right what is the result
of the thing that I tried to do could I
have done this differently and got a
different result and then you're able to
then try it again so each of the the
different learner each week's learning
content has that Loop feedback loop
empirical process right bringing it into
the learning World
um empirical process to bring bring that
knowledge back so you can then do
something a little bit different and and
I think it also lends itself much more
readily to even outside of the context
of the fixed courseware right so there's
going to be an assignment at the end of
each session you go off and do that and
when we do a debrief when we come back
the outcome of that debrief might be
that you want to try something different
there's absolutely no reason that the
trainer wouldn't want to have a a
debrief of that you're trying again as
well as you know during the class we're
doing that debrief of the next exercise
but you want to still talk about some of
the things that you've tried differently
tried again in the previous exercise and
all of our trainers would be absolutely
happy to get on a call and talk about
that as well perhaps the whole group's
interested right that's something that
we can we can we can figure out how we
incorporate into that process so that
that idea
of of how do we learn how do humans
learn with
interactive continuous feedback loops of
those learning outcomes that's what
we're trying to bring into this
immersive learning experience and I
think again it's going to be a a a game
changer for
um for training and learning because you
it's not just a fire and forget right
you're not just uh getting that content
shoved into your brain and then it
atrophying over time uh you've actually
got that continuous loop back so you can
always ask that question right that
niggle that you have six weeks later
about something that you talked about
six weeks ago fine ask the question
right we're all right here we can we can
we can see what we think and I think
that's that important part that feedback
loop that empirical process in the
learning environment
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility