the second question that we should be
asking leadership of of organizations is
is there a product Vision that lays out
the Strategic goals and do all members
of the team all people doing work inside
of our
organization understand both of those
things and are they able to see how the
work they do everyday contributes to
both of them um this is this is really
lack in organizations it's probably more
lacking than creating usable working
product um most organizations that I've
worked with even if they do have a clear
uh uh product Vision vision for their
product and strategic goals for their
business it's not well communicated uh
to the people in the organization a key
key test for this is to go to folks in
your organization and ask them what what
the the Strategic goal is what's the
vision for the product what are the
Strategic goals for the business what's
the Strategic goals for the product and
if they aren't able to articulate
it then it doesn't exist in your
organization it it it might exist on
paper but if people aren't able to
internalize it and articulate it then
they don't understand it and it's not
there and the second part of that is
even more powerful and that's that
the people doing the work need to
understand how the things that they're
doing every day contribute to those
overall vision and goals right
because the doers in your
organization and management and
everybody in your organization are
making lots of little micro decisions
within the context that they understand
of what it is we're trying to do right
um they're going to make continuous
micro decisions software Engineers are
going to make decisions about what
architecture to choose about ways to
build things and they might talk to each
other or they might talk to nobody when
they make that little decision because
it's a little micro decision in order to
get somebody to help you with that
decision you need to impart the context
and quite often other people don't
understand the context because what
you're talking about is incredibly
technical it could be coding technical
it could be testing technical it could
be
uh uh Market technical it could be
marketing technical it could be could be
any sort of technical details so they
can't just go ask a boss ask a leader
ask uh uh somebody senior in the
organization because they don't
understand the context the only way to
enable those people because they're
going to make the decision anyway the
only way for you to enable them to make
more of the right decision and less of
the wrong decision is for them to
understand what it is you're trying to
achieve where it is we're going as a
business um what's our what are we
trying to do with our product where do
we think is going and that will enable
them to make more of the right decisions
and less of the wrong ones this is how
we maximize the amount of work not done
how we maximize the value that we
deliver to our to our customers because
the people that are doing the work if
they're not connected to that goal and
vision and what it is we're trying to
[Music]
achieve how do they value what it is
they're doing and they just turning up
for their day job and they're punching
you know like a machine punching cards
and then at the end of your day you go
home
or do you feel for the customer do you
understand the wants and needs for the
customer of the business of what it is
we're trying to achieve and part of that
is creating camaraderie creating this
story of are are we as a group all
working together towards a common goal
or are we potentially working against
each other because we all have our own
idea of what our common goal and vision
is and we're all doing our own thing and
perhaps pulling each other in different
directions within our business so do you
have that that alignment so that we can
share knowledge share decisions so that
we can um we're even decisions that we
make on our own are working towards a
common outcome and that's the very
definition of team right a group of
people working together towards a common
goal so you need to have clear product
vision and strategic goals and you need
to ensure that everybody that's working
on your product understands the vision
and the Strategic goals and also how the
work that they're doing every day
contributes to that so how can you help
them make those connections if your
answer to any one of these questions or
the answer of your business to any one
of these questions is no we're not doing
that then you would probably I probably
wouldn't consider that you're already in
the agile space right you're not already
agile you might be working towards it
and you might have put in loads of
effort but unless you can Mark every
single one of these six questions as yes
we do this this is how things work here
then we're still lacking we're still
trying we're still working towards being
agile now this is just a litmus test
dreamed up uh by uh the US Department of
Defense but they are probably the least
likely place for you to expect something
um with this High a bar to have come
from and I'm not going to um go into a
team uh and work with a team or a
company and if they're not doing these
things then I'm going to say well you
guys suck you're not agile because
you're not doing this that's that's not
how we work towards success uh but I
think it's hugely valuable from the
perspective of
self-reflection for you all to think
about the processes and practices in
your organization ation and are you a
how many of these six questions are you
able to achieve and what could you do to
make it a little bit easier for the
teams for the people doing the work to
work
towards this idea of not being agile BS