so the question is what does the
assessment phase of a Consulting
engagement look like
and I think ideally there isn't one or
not quite that it's asynchronous
a consultant should be continually
assessing the needs of the business that
they're working with and quite often
having that
if if we agree that we work in the the
complex space right we know less upfront
than we discover by doing
so anything that you do do in an
assessment phase
probably a lot of it is throwaway
because as you start engaging with the
customer as you start doing stuff you
start realizing that that's you know
that wasn't true or it wasn't quite
right or a completely different thing is
happening anyway
lots of customers like an assessment
phase because then you come in you
assess what it is that they're doing and
then they they they decide whether they
want your help in in fixing whatever it
is that you've identified
but in actual fact I think there's more
value
in just helping just getting started
just engaging with uh with teams just
engaging with with people and learn what
the current state of the organization is
by engage by by that in engagement right
through that engagement so so while I do
sometimes do
um that that kind of assessment phase I
would probably
it's not something that I would
recommend to a customer
um I just want to get started I just
want to help them I just want to
um get going so if we can get away
without it that's awesome if we have to
do it it might be there's a great
um
a a phrase like how much backlog do you
need it's the same idea how much of an
assessment do you need to do up front
and the answer is always the same as as
much as you need to convince the
customer to to work with you right
so if if you're going to do assessment
do just enough but not more
um that is needed to get the cus to
understand the customer enough to
convince them to to bring you on get
some help and then as you start helping
them and demonstrating your competence
and we can start saying well all that
stuff we thought up front is kind of
kind of irrelevant now and and let's get
started
um I I did a lot of work early on in
devops engagements I I worked in the US
for three years for for our devops
consultancy and one of the things that
um I always find weird at the time
because I didn't understand it
um but they would say if if they didn't
understand what the customer wanted
right they got on a call they they tried
to understand what the customer wanted
try to understand what they needed and
they just like either we don't know or
we think it's very different from what
they said right because that happens on
as well
um then they would they would parachute
me in to go figure out what what what
the customer needs because sometimes you
you if if we were doing very short
engagements with customers right so I
would have a weak Max with the customer
five days in those five days I have to
figure out what the customer needs and
deliver it
and it's not like we can extend it
because on Friday I fly out and on
Monday I'm at a different customer
somewhere else in the country so it all
has to be done within that time period
so how do you dynamically adapt to those
changing needs well you can't really
have that huge plan up front you have an
idea right you have an idea what you
need to do you have an idea what's going
on but once you hit the ground you have
to continuously adapt to what's going on
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility