if you're trying to unlock the power of
continuous delivery then you've probably
considered the type of benefits that you
get from it and perhaps perhaps they're
not the benefits you think while it is
true that continuous delivery can help
you become faster that's a lagging side
effect of um the work that you would do
the real benefit of continuous delivery
is the requirement for automation within
the context of devops and the real value
of automation within the context of
devops is you've not got a person doing
the deployment you've got an automated
tool during the deployment so you gain
consistency and
reliability of what is happening and
that consistency and reliability reduces
your risk if you're interested in how
much risk that is there are there's one
example that I always used to use which
was the the night Capital group which
was a a financially traded stock
exchange e organization in the US that
did a deployment of their software it
failed and due to various
reasons mostly to do with automated I
sorry manual deployments they ended up
losing about $10,000 an hour or a minute
or whatever it was but at the end of the
day they had to file for bankruptcy and
at the beginning of the day they had 450
million in the bank so that's the
example I usually use probably today I
would say crowd strike right if if
you've got unn automation that checks
that your system that what it is you've
created your teams have created is good
and meets the minimum bar for the
business right what's what's your risk
level that that's the power of
continuous delivery is cons consistency
and limiting risk you can
ensure that within your continuous
delivery
process you have the checks that you as
a business require to protect your
business right so there's there's
protecting your business protecting your
brand protecting your employees and
protecting your customers all of those
things can mostly be automated almost
all of those things that could possibly
go wrong can be automated you you can't
it's very difficult to automate legal
stuff so you would still have to there's
some some things in there but from the
context of I don't want my software to
fail I don't want it to send money to
the wrong place I don't want all of
those things we use testing we use
automation we use continuous delivery
continuous everything continuous testing
continuous deployment continuous
delivery right those are the things that
help you get faster feedback because if
it's an automated process you can go
around that Loop and the developers can
find out that it it it it that it's
broken or it's not doing the right thing
much faster uh great example of that is
the Azure devops team at Microsoft went
from delivering who 12 features to
production per year for per 600 people
uh to delivering
280 features to
production per year per 600 people right
so the number of people didn't change
but massively increased the the the
number of features delivered but part of
doing that was changing the feedback
loop right making the feedback loop
faster they went from an automated build
that would take days to get a response
from to one that took minutes and
seconds to get a response from they were
able to they used to have to run their
full full Suite of tests in I think it
was four or five days to actually get a
response for a particular thing and now
it's 3 and a half minutes for the entire
test Suite that level of feedback makes
feedback faster costs less reduces risk
increases Effectiveness right that's
that that that shortened the feedback
loop if you're also deploying and
getting your feature in front of
customers that continuous delivery piece
so continuous delivery means you're
getting your product in front of real
customers your moving to production on a
continuous basis even the windows team
which is probably the biggest most
complicated product on the planet is 24
hours they're 24 hours or less doing
continuous delivery from developer
cutting code to being in the hands of
real production users albe it inside of
Microsoft it's 24 hours it's a week
they've got it in front of real external
users it's a month they've got it in
front of 20 million external users and
then it's three months they've got it in
front of I don't know 850 million
external users if crowd strike was doing
what the windows team does they would
not have caused the errors that they did
continuous delivery the practices within
the context of devops that enable
continuous delivery are the things that
reduce risk increase Effectiveness and
give you faster feedback