one of the key things that new product
owners need to learn is how to manage
their product back clog it's a key part
of the story yeah I will point out that
you don't necessarily need to do it
yourself right you can delegate it but
you remain accountable you you as the
product owner are accountable for Value
delivery and if maximizing the value
delivery and if you have a terrible
product backlog regardless of whether
you delegated or not still going to be
you that's held accountable right so you
at least especially if you're a new
product owner you're going to want to
learn how to manage a product backlog
how to order that backlog how to write a
good backlog so that you enable
understanding with everybody who's who
who needs to who's reading it um so in
order to do that uh it it does a lot of
work involved in managing a product
backlog one of the key Concepts that I
think is often overlooked by product
owners is that the the purpose of the
things in your backlog is they become
ready right I some the team can take
them
on based on everybody's understanding of
it you can't measure understanding right
you just can't measure it you can't say
here's a Line in the Sand and at this
point everybody understands it it's a
lot more nebulous than that a lot more
fuzzy than that so you as a product
owner need to learn to to read the room
to to to know what language you need to
use in order to enable understanding to
know what what sometimes people don't
want to admit that they don't understand
your thing right so you need to learn to
be able to read when when people are in
that category and and maybe do some more
around it but there are kind of um four
key vectors that you need to understand
you need to enable for your for your
product backlog the first one is risk
how risky are the things on your product
backlog and that could be fiscal risk it
could be operational risk um it could be
lots of different types of risk what's
the risk involved and if things are
really high risk those are the things
you want to spend a little bit more time
on upfront to understand them better
break them down reduce the risk right
that's that's that that's key that's
part of refinement right refining your
product backlog is really
important you also need to understand
the value what are you going to get out
of what do you think you're going to get
out of it because remember everything
you think you're going to get out of it
is an assumption until you actually get
it in front of real users who are using
it in production okay so you need to
figure out what's our what do we think
the value is going to be and does the
value we think we're going to get
actually outweigh the risk right if the
risk is too high for the value perhaps
we don't bother doing it it's too
dangerous it's too risky for our product
another thing to understand is the size
of the items on your backlog how big are
those things um that can I'm not going
to tell you how to determine what big is
but I generally have a conversation with
teams uh the people who are going to do
the work right are your one of your
primary audiences
do they feel that they understand it
enough that they can deliver it in a
single Sprint that might be a question
to ask if they do understand it enough
to deliver it in a single Sprint you're
probably good to go if they don't
understand it it could be either because
it's too big or because there's not
enough information or they don't they
need more questions answered to be able
to understand it a little bit more and
that's where refinement comes in so we
talked about risk value and size
and the last item is how we solve some
of those problems is learning right is
there something that you need to learn
uh by doing right remember agile
Manifesto we learn more by
doing so maybe you can do maybe you can
try and build something small maybe you
can um take on a little piece of that
risk early on and try and do something
in the
product that hopefully alleviate that
risk or at least you figure out more
about that risk that's product backlog
management you've got this overarching
refinement you need to refine this
backlog to ready and then everybody
needs to understand it so that the team
can deliver it and the stakeholders
understand the value because if they
don't understand the value they're not
going to turn up at the review right um
so how are you able to do that we have
uh scrum.org have the new um product
backlog manag M course which is
specifically focused on this topic that
takes you through a whole bunch of
complimentary practices that can help
you with that story uh but there's also
lots of different tools and techniques
that we talk about in the product owner
class the advanced product owner class
around that topic heck even the
professional scrum with user experience
brings in that refinement story and if
you really want to get serious then you
probably want to bring flow mechanics
into your story as in have a caman
strategy applied to whatever your
process is for delivering uh uh your
product and enable um the the the
maximum throughput in your process while
you're also focused on maximizing the
value and that's an awesome combination
right ability to deliver and delivering
the right thing that's how you make
awesome products if you find it hard to
manage your product backlog and maximize
the value that you're returning my team
at naked agility can help or we can help
you find somebody who can don't let
these sorts of issues undermine your
ability to deliver value don't have a
poor quality not understood product
backlog use the links in the description
to get some help as soon as you can