[Music]
introduce ourselves before we bring
everybody else back there we go
sorry about that um that is my
incompetence in clicking the buttons
um so
we should be we should be online now i
was focusing on the people that were
here
so that's a that's a that's a good
indication that you should uh come along
and join the join the meeting rather
than just being a voyeur and watching on
the internet
um so my name is martin hinchowitz i'm a
professional scrum trainer with
scrum.org uh we're going to be talking
today about definition of done and i
have
an awesome
person to help me out anna would you
like to introduce yourself
yeah hello i'm anna i'm in spain i'm
located in spain and i'm a professional
investor
and yep today i'm talking just a little
bit for this time uh martin but this one
was with this workshop
and let's see where this takes us yeah
let's see how far we get
it's gonna be fun so i'm gonna i'm gonna
close the rooms they've had uh they've
had enough time i don't think
everybody's answered all the questions
but they've been having some some good
discussions in there
um
i don't think i created an answer deck
for this one
um
so let i'm just having a look and seeing
how people answered
hello everybody
hello
all right
bye
there we go everybody everybody's back
in the main room
awesome
how how how did you get on was that
were they quite difficult questions
no i i anna anna two is shaking her head
like nope those were easy
okay i think we got stuck on one but it
was good
yeah it's it's um
i think
definition of done
is something that is often
misunderstood and often confused or
conflated
with acceptance criteria
victoria i just popped you on uh mute uh
there just there was some background
noise popping in
uh just a note that ev everybody has
permission
to pop other people on mute
um so if you do hear a lot of background
noise it's okay to go to mute that
person uh but um
if you just don't like what they're
saying it's not okay to go put them on
mute
okay that's not a good reason to to put
me we're not allowed to meet you
you you can if you want you can if you
want and uh
and i can kinda can take over
that's right
so what
were there any
contentious discussions
in your room i got a couple of things
that i want to to to hit on because this
like 50 50 between the rooms
i think number four
number four
we we don't have to conform to any
standards
we don't like standards what's this get
these standards off me
that's that's
i think
standards are something that should be
built into any process
for everything we're doing
right too many standards might end up
being bureaucracy
so you need to be careful of that
balance
but having standards is a good idea
definition of done is one of those
standards um that we should have that is
a good idea
um
does anybody know what the scrum guides
says about definition of done
and where it comes from
eight i know you do
i think it's a
responsibility it's a responsibility of
income but sorry
we'll say it again
so um i've got a a little phrase here
i'm just gonna bring it in um it's
straight off oh well i put it on a
post-it that's probably not the best
place to put it i should have put it on
a text box let me change that to a text
box and then i can make the text bigger
there we go
well except i paused that
is that where did that go it magically
disappeared i will get a new one
let me make it bigger
there we go i've just put it off to the
to the to the bottom of our
um
start up and it says
if the definition of done for an
increment is part of the standards of
the organization
all scrum teams must follow it as a
minimum
so that for me implies two things
it implies that your organization should
have some kind of standard
for what your definition of done is
and it also implies that the team the
scrum team can add more things
than the minimum requirement
right so if you think about
definition of done should be applied
equally across your entire organization
so there might be things that you don't
put on that list because you can't apply
them across everything
and then each team depending on what
they're building
are going to have individual things they
have to add i'm thinking of an example
uh and i i think a good one is um let's
say you're an organization who
makes printers
but also makes pacemakers
right
the pacemakers
need to comply with a bunch of
regulations that printers do not
right the the the the
somebody has to i guess medical within
your country there'll be some medical
body
that imposes restrictions upon you
there'll be an iso standard for that
absolutely and there are a lot of iso
standards
which ones apply to your organization
uh there might be standards around
um
financial information
one that i've had to combat with a
number of times
is no matter where you are in the world
if you build software
that somebody in an organization that's
listed on the new york stock exchange
makes a financial decision
based on information you present them
your software must comply with sox audit
sars van oxley which is an absolute
nightmare
but you have to provide that data that
information that ability to see what's
going on it's about traceability of who
made the decision uh
and and what the data showed them uh in
order to have that traceability in case
something's wrong right
so that might be imposed upon us we have
no choice if we want to build software
in a particular market we have to comply
with standards
so it's okay for those things to be
imposed from the outside because they
might just be reality
uh another one i noticed that we we had
a little bit of two teams put a red
uh put across and two teams put a tick
and that was all technical debt is a
risk to the business
that's a phrase i've used before i kind
of kind of stuck snuck that one in there
is one technically that the risk or is
not paying it off or risk
it
well it's not not paying off continues
the risk
right so if you if you have money on
your credit card
that you've not paid off yet
it is a risk
even if you have the money to pay it off
at the end of the month something might
happen that makes it
dangerous right
um so it is a it is a risk all debt is a
risk i have a mortgage on my house
right if i can't pay that mortgage each
month i lose my house don't i
so there's risk there
and that that
debt
is secured against my house so i i'm not
i'm not going to
lose money i'm gonna get the money back
that i put into the house
but what is the technical debt in your
products secured against
who ensures
the technical debt in your product
nobody does it's completely unsecured
risk
that's a business risk isn't it if you
have unsecured risk that's that's
a big risk of the business
the problem is the business doesn't
understand that risk
so they don't know it's there because
you know we don't tell them
we don't have that conversation with
them about
well
you know i know you wanted you spent 100
000 on this product but actually you
know we didn't run all of the tests
every sprint
you know there's some features in there
that you know maybe they work
we don't know maybe they don't
what risk is that to the business
yeah
it depends how you think about the
question isn't it
i'm just triggered by the old technique
because sometimes not getting
technically depth is a huge risk as well
if you cannot ship
a new
so
it's not what i'm saying paying it off
as long as you highlight that you have
technical debt and plan to fix it
next sprint
the risk of not doing
reduces
yes but it only reduces the risk it
doesn't make it zero risk
the fact that it exists
is risk
your business might have decided to
accept
a certain level of risk
in order to meet the time constraints of
shipping in a market
right we've got to get some our
competitors have done something
we must be able to meet that constraint
we can't have our usual level of quality
because there's not enough time
and we have to get it out there
otherwise we're out of business we're
hemorrhaging customers
right so you might reduce quality to
meet that
there's technical debt
but we have to pay it back it's still
risk
that that i think is what i'm getting at
it it might be acceptable risk
but it still needs to be be quantifiable
as as risk
and we have a
short debate on this in my meeting room
that basically said everything
everything we've ever done has always
gone live there's some level of
technical risk you know a perfect piece
of software does not exist yeah you know
no matter how even even for pacemakers
you know there will be not necessarily
technical decks i think there will
probably be no technical debt there
because someone would have fixed the
problem that what they've got is a much
worse scenario which is they have
probably got bugs in that they don't
know about um
we're actually going live with bugs you
do know about and some are accepting
that and then deciding when if at all to
pay that officer is a i would suggest a
better a better view of the world
you know because you may deprecate that
bit of the product
before you need to pay the debt off so
why do that why not why not invest the
fixed money
in
make a better product money
yes
absolutely and and i agree
um
except under certain circumstances
what level of risk would you be happy
with peter for bowing
in there in their products they create
right
what if if you were the one with the
pacemaker what level of risk would you
be willing to accept so the way it tends
to work
is there is that level of risk there is
that reality
of cost versus benefit
and as long as you and your team
have done everything within your power
to make
to minimize
any risk to the level that's allowed
then you've done a good job
right
there always might be the circumstance
that a plane will fall out the sky
right that that we can't have that zero
it's not zero it is something
the the example i i usually use for that
peter is the the the food and drug
authority in the us
stipulates exactly how many insect legs
are allowed
per
i don't know how what power quantity may
be per ounce of food that you buy in the
supermarket how many insect legs are
allowed because zero is impossible
right because insects are everywhere you
can't have zero
so you have to specify and i think it's
it's it's two parts per million or it's
three
three legs per kilo of food or
what whatever it is there is a standard
for that
that has been defined as an acceptable
level of risk
but because
because i actually heard the guy who
invented the airbags
going on and saying um airbags with
american airbags need to stop a 200
pound linebacker whatever the hell one
of those is um
but the risk is they'll kill little old
men
and at the time he was saying this he
was about 70 something 80s like yeah and
he was there's a little man who might
well get kicked
yeah it's just an acceptable level of
risk we just agree that some people are
not going to come off as well as they
ought to if their outback goes off
because we have to stop big people
so uh
maybe a different way of doing that
would be to weigh the person
that's in the in the in the seat
and calibrate the airbag based on the
weight and they do do that to a certain
extent for example if i put a baby seat
in my passenger seat of my car
the airbag will not deploy because they
are not heavy enough
to trigger the airbag deployment level
right so they do all sorts of things to
mitigate that risk they do what they can
but there's a certain point at which
they can't do anymore
so i think we need to
we need to introduce
um a little discussion about the
difference between
acceptance criteria
and definition of done
i know
some of you are
veterans
of that conversation
okay i'm looking at you of you're
definitely a veteran of that
conversation
but it is something that both anna and i
encounter
all the time in organizations
which is a lot of confusion
what's our definition of done
for this backlog item
right it's something that i hear quite
often in organizations
has anybody heard that
i have
wolf's nodding
yeah
peter have you not heard that ever
no no
it's getting more and more common
if definition is universal
i heard what what what is a what is
applicable
within the definition of done for this
background lesson that that debate i've
heard and what does all documentation up
to date mean yep that no no one's argued
to talk about whether there is a
different definition of done
well we are we are going to have a
little uh exercise around this and i
we're we're going to introduce uh
a hypothetical organization and product
right and we're going completely
non-technical on this one we've got a
bakery
and in our bakery uh we make uh some
products
uh we actually make two products in our
bakery this is a startup so we only have
two products at the moment
one of which is
baguettes
and the other one is
banana bread because i don't know i
think anna likes banana bread that's
that's why we're good but i
so acceptance criteria
are
the
business require part of the business
requirements
for the thing that's on your back clock
so if you were thinking about it in the
perspective of user stories
right you've got user stories and
acceptance criteria
and the acceptance criteria is really
the conversation you have a story you
talk about the story you have a
conversation you record the things
the business things that you've been
talking about around that conversation
right as you're discussing that backlog
item
so yes you do have unique acceptance
criteria
for each backlog item
and the acceptance criteria for for one
backup item might look nothing like
the other
backlog item but peter is right
definition of done applies to everything
equally
okay it should apply to every single
thing on your backlog should be able to
meet the definition of done but again
you might have to you know is document
it uh you might have to have
conversation on each definition of done
like what what does that mean
within the context
of that item
so what i i have here is i have
uh a a number of uh
statements
statements things
here uh let's see how many people do we
have we have 16 people
16 people into groups of
three
goes how many times somebody who's good
at math needs to
help me out
five
but thank you very much for that i wish
by this
my math just sucks sucks really badly so
i'll do five
four five rooms
i'm okay with the and a bit i am of you
can go half in one room and half in the
other room or is it 25 in each room
something like there we go we've got
four
uh and then three three three
so that works
oh
but in fact i need to go find anna would
you like to go into a room anna with the
group yeah yeah
well that will that will that will solve
that problem so what i'd like you to do
is a little at card sort
and in each room i'll summon everybody
so we're all looking at the same thing
there we go
in each room
we have
baguettes
banana bread and done
there are cards
that are to do with baguettes cards that
are to do with banana bread and cards
that are to do with done
so hopefully in your room you've got
somebody who's ever baked something
right
because
we have a list of ingredients that might
be part of each of these items and i
felt it was fairly obvious
which ingredients go in banana bread and
which ingredients go in baguettes
but i that could be an assumption
because i bake
my grandmother taught me to bake
so we have
lots of different things
um and how much of each thing
you would put in each type of product i
think if you think logically we've got a
savory bread and we've got cake
right
we should we should be able to figure
out which things go where uh but then
there are some things that should apply
to absolutely everything
um so again go to the the room
that matches uh your
the the the room that matches your room
number uh when you get into
um your group
okay
so i've clicked open so i'll give you
five minutes to sort these so just do a
quick a quick sort and let's see if we
manage to to to get them
in the right place
okay i set everybody off i know you guys
are still
here watching me
uh
so
for you
there are um
should be it should be fairly obvious at
which things go in which category if i
if i zoom in a little bit i'm going to
release everybody so i can zoom in there
we go
so a couple of things uh where are the
things that are uh a kitchen was clean
at time of preparation
right
that's definitely done
uh and all ingredients
used were fresh
right that's done
but then
you know we've got things that that
banana bread uses plain flour
baguettes use bleached flour so white
flour
right banana bread doesn't rise like
bread does bread need yeast so you put
yeast and bread but banana bread uh
you'll probably put some bicarbonate of
soda you're gonna put sweet things in
there so the buttermilk you can see in
room five they've got the buttermilk in
there um
and
yeah so you're i can't remember whether
actually it's three grams of salt for
banana bread or 10 grams of salt but
they've decided it's 10 for baguettes
and three and a half for banana bread i
think that makes sense
um we're going to use eggs and banana
bread but we don't put eggs in baguettes
right
um
[Music]
we use butter in cake
and caster sugar yes there's more things
in definitely more things than banana
bread
um than there are in
um
i'm experimenting with my camera
in case you were wondering why it's
doing that uh
captain scarlett and the mistrans
flicker
i have a little tool installed in obs
that changes the camera based on where
i'm looking so if i look for long enough
at this camera over here it's going to
switch to that camera um
[Music]
and then when i look over here it's
going to switch back
i'm still working and tweaking
how
that works and the sensitivity of it but
it does seem to be it seems to be
working right so basically it's fate
detecting my face
um
so we'll see how that works let's see
what we've got
we are gonna bring them back in just
a moment
uh if you're on the
team's team for making breakout rooms
i'd like a little timer for how long the
rooms have been open
on each of the each of the rooms maybe
that would be handy
so i can see because i can see room
threes done
room one's done
ah there's five rooms so room six isn't
let's see there we go it did the switch
but it went ah
done like captain scarlet number ones
maybe i'm too old
but if i look here it switches back once
i i don't i don't get why it does that
i'll need to check the settings and
figure it out
so i think it's about time to bring
everybody back
it is
um oh nervous is following me let me un
follow narissa and then over here
let me remove that i have a i have an
answers
grid
uh baguettes take more salt 10 grams of
salt
yeast
olive oil
water
and strong white flour there we go that
was what was on there
so it's four four two and like nine so
it looks like most people are getting
there room three is not sure what's room
three
yeah they're putting all the salt in
baguettes
but they've got the yeast the flour
cool olive oil so
they're not putting any salt in the
banana bread
is uh
what they're doing so that's okay well
let's close the rooms that is pretty
good
uh click those they get a little warning
and then they'll pop back in just a
second
doing that a lot recently but just
guessing so uh
need to make this harder
oh
almost
every team got it perfect what did you
think
with anna cards
and there were some
i saw kind of a pattern
um
they were just thinking about
what does apply to both
but not in term in terms of
standards
right
yeah that's a that's a good caveat and i
can see that's happened in
room four
so in room
room room that was the room you were
um and in room four we're gonna put
370 milliliters of water
in both banana bread and baguettes
i'll tell you now that will not work
that that will not have the the outcome
you're expecting you'll have a banana
bread drink
at that uh uh that level of uh water
um and we don't put eggs in baguettes we
don't put uh eggs in bread
um
so that's that i have uncovered a little
answer grid
over on the right hand side uh but the
only other thing i noticed was that room
three wants to put all the salt in
baguettes
which will definitely work but you need
a little bit of salt in in banana bread
um let me check my answer grid as to
which of which
uh three three and a half grams of salt
in banana bread and 10 grams of salt in
in in baguettes
so
the
those that did it fast
figured out what were the done items
really quickly there are only two done
items on our list
one is all ingredients are fresh
right that applies equally to baguettes
and banana bread and the other one is
kitchen was clean
at the time of preparation which is
probably an externally imposed
standard right that we need to have at
least i hope it is depending on where
you are in the world
right
and martin that i would say not only
that but if we had any other
backlog item to that even if it doesn't
use salt or whatever
also that is it's going to apply
so
yeah
i i think the kitchen at the clean of
kitchen clean at time of preparation i
would like that apply
to anybody making any products that i
put in my mouth
right regardless of whether they're a
bakery
or
anything else i'm not sure it does but i
would like it to
i think my wife would impose a
kitchen clean at end of preparation
as an additional condition
oh yes is that a condition of you being
allowed to cook again peter
i am actually
tidying up actually
yeah
i i i like to have everything clean and
finished what at the end of the
that as well
right so
determining at which things are which
um are really really important
um so i think
i think where are we i think we should
do the
um the what don't we know
exercise
so i'm gonna i'm gonna i'm gonna
recreate again so we don't end up with
the same people that way if you end up
with somebody you don't like you'll be
with somebody else next time there we go
so i re re-jigged
we jigged the rooms
uh let me
do that there we go
um
i have a little little uh fast pass to
see oh forget the little round one round
two stuff at the top that's uh
left over from anna and i building these
uh
exercises earlier
well yesterday day before yesterday i
can't remember when we did it
um but i'll look at those three three
statements
and see if you can't come up with a an
answer uh for each one so what's the
difference between acceptance criteria
and done
right so i'm hoping you'll be able to
answer that now can it be done without
meeting the acceptance criteria
is the second question that might be a
little bit more contentious
and then how does definition have done
serve transparency
okay so i'm going to click to open uh
the rooms and see if you can't add a
little post post-it to the board uh
answering each of those questions and
i'll probably ask three people
when we get back what they think
um
we don't have time to ask everybody but
we can
get a few people
okay yeah i kept you here this time
yeah okay
it was nice being in the breakout room
i i like enjoy interacting with folks as
well but it's it's funny well especially
in in one one two four all is always a
nightmare for breakout rooms
because
you've got two minutes to reorganize
everybody into the new room so that
when you hit gold
yeah and people coming back saying what
is happening and then sending them yeah
yeah yeah that part's not fun that's i
so i turn off their ability to come back
when i'm doing breakout rooms so i don't
allow them to do that um
and what's the other thing that helps
with that oh i'll put a timer on let's
put a timer on for for
six minutes there we go
um
we've got a good good good grip good mix
it's definitely a topic people are
interested in all lewis has disappeared
yeah he said he had to leave ah
that's that's cool he's just he's just
popping in louis i
louis is our uh
pst
okay as well
um
so he was coming in to see what's what's
going on what's going on here yeah
what are these idiots up to
yeah i was seeing in the breakout rooms
that uh
the the way that they are trying they
were trying to organize the
the
the difference between acceptance
creativity and the definition of dunk
they were trying to find the
the common aspects
but not the standards yeah i think
that's dysfunctional in the way i
explained it at the start i think i may
be
it's based on experience yes
so maybe they were
guessing their decisions
yeah
and i i do find that confusion between
acceptance criteria and done is so
common
so common um
so when they i i see they're starting to
answer
answer uh uh things
um
on
the concrete practices section i don't
know if you noticed i i added some
pictures of pies
yeah so we're adding some meat products
to our um
[Music]
so that that
meat products come with additional
definition of done
stuff like you might start thinking
about how what temperature the inside of
things get to
which can also equally apply to the
baked goods
but is more important for the meat goods
that's that's that's what i was getting
to with with that one
um
so that introduced that as a
would you like to introduce that as a
change in the
in the the the corporate our companies
you do it yourself because you know it
better okay and it's for me so i don't
want to i don't want to
make them understand something that it's
not so
um i don't think there's any danger of
that
i will
do more next time okay that's
that's cool first thing through um
so then they're going to go into a one
two four all
um
to come up with additional things
uh i'm actually i've i've left
that should be covered
uh i just covered it i was that was my
answers grid
um so just they now we've introduced
meat
are they gonna think of the additional
things
um
that we put on there and then did you
see i brought in some
examples of definition of done and
they're software ones but
i just copied them out of the the aps
sd the software delivery one from
richard hunthousen's book
which is awesome
and they're just from from various
microsoft
test
products uh
so that should be good we're doing uh
pretty good on
right time yeah we're doing unusually
good on time which is good
because we have that the workshop to
explain as well
um so
i am actually gonna what i'm gonna do is
i'm gonna pull in a copy of your
workshop
okay which i didn't do that's my mistake
and then we can talk about it here but
then they've got the link for it in the
uh
i can't remember where i put it
oh no you you put it in the
yeah i got it
in the community
so if you're if you're watching online
you can just go find
uh that
um
definition of done tune up workshop from
anna
uh in
let me get a copy of that there we go
it's just a community portal so it's
community.nkdiagility.com
uh let me create a mural from the
template she's given us a lovely
template it's it's very pretty as well
it's got the purple we like the purple
that's ours
i use your purple
i am very predictable in
um
the color choice that i use
let me
make this a bit bigger and then paste it
in there
ah
i i i did another copy of it that was
actually a lot bigger
more like
probably
that big something like that
it's it's it's good for for zooming in
if you have to if you have to zoom in to
see cards and things
uh i try and make it as as big as
possible
so i i did this workshop um
last week with one with three teams
and um
and
the part i like the most we will talk
about it later but the one that we like
the most was the imagine that
how the definition of dawn could have
helped you if you had it like um
like in your daily work
yeah
that definitely i i quite liked i like
that exercise as well
okay so i believe that time is up i have
clicked to close the breakout rooms
okay there's a 10 second warning in
teams remember so they
they come back
okay
let's see
i did see we had a couple of people drop
out so some folks ended up in a room
with two
but at least it was a room of two and
not a room of one i was trying to make
sure that we don't have a room of one
um
[Music]
so i saw lewis dropped off
kate
what um
[Music]
what was your
outcome
that you thought of between these three
questions
what were your insights
um
so i think um
i think we were fairly clear on number
one but i think number two was you know
can it be
acceptance criteria are more of a
kind of a business requirement so
actually as you move through development
and you learn more things then actually
those acceptance criteria could change
so
yep or
certainly that's that's the case as i've
seen so you know
in some instances
if you if they don't then i guess you
wouldn't meet your definition of done
but
i guess maybe it depends if you have
must meet acceptance criteria on your
definition of done
true i i i do tend to recommend against
that but we'll we'll hear from a couple
of other people first
um let's see who was in uh uh to
uh andre
you were in room two weren't you
you should be out
the first one is uh quite sure
a certain character is specific for
backlog
[Music]
depends it depends so if the definition
of that is referencing to the absorption
criteria so a certain nuclear need to be
as part of a finishing of that so if if
it's considered done then
it should be
[Music]
mid but if not so
no
so it's depend
okay
and the third one is uh
yeah it's assist uh by not letting you
hide the income incomplete
i i like i like the way you phrased that
not letting you hide in complete work i
like the way you phrased that that's
that's a that's a good way to
um
to do that uh i think let's hear from
one more max
yes sir
what was what was your what did your
group discuss
uh i was trying to write it down um
victoria had a little uh victoria and
lisa had a better understanding of it um
can be done
without meeting the acceptance criteria
so
uh
i i think i might have to rely on
victoria because i think she explained
it pretty well
so what what happened to us yeah we were
having a discussion
of but what happens when the acceptance
ratio is not clear i think victoria was
telling telling us that she had like
experiences with the
developer uh thinking of something is uh
ready to go accepted
there were some
misunderstandings or like maybe like the
question would be how can we make this
more clear or
uh how do you do an acceptance criteria
that it doesn't create misunderstandings
that's correct
yeah
yeah and i think it's it's definitely an
interesting conundrum
because
the acceptance criteria is part of your
scope
right that's that's a that's a scope
problem
do we do we as a team
commit to scope
in a sprint
is that a good id
is that a good idea we don't commit to
scope peter
we commit to a goal
right which means we may have to do some
things to get there
but we don't commit to individual
backlog items and we don't commit
to things that need to happen for those
backlog items
so having acceptance criteria on our
definition of done
might lock us into
a scope that we maybe can't achieve
we're not focused on scope
with done we're focused on quality
we can deliver an awesome quality
product that does not do what the
customer asked for i agree
right but at least we've met the quality
bar
if i deliver a baguette
that does not have
uh that is a let's say i deliver a
baguette that's a circle
instead of straight lines
right using exactly the same
ingredients
but it it ends up being a hoop
right it is
still meets
our definition of done
kitchen clean it type of time of
preparation
and even if we had a taste test it's
going to taste the same
so it is the same
thing
it's not just it's just not in a format
that our customers might find visually
appealing or within the bounds of their
expectation
which still might be a problem
but they're not going to get sick and
die
i mean that that's ultimately what our
definition of done is to protect from
sick and die is obviously an extreme
version right whether you're building
planes or pacemakers or
food
but even
how does
how does your your stakeholders how do
your stakeholders
know what they're looking at
at a sprint review
you need to have some kind of agreement
working agreement on what does what does
done what does the quality bar minimum
quality bar that your customers will
accept look like
otherwise we could not do some of those
quality aspects
still deliver what the customer asked
for
and we've hidden
potentially hidden some technical debt
even if we didn't do it intentionally
sorry sorry on your example like how's
the acceptance criteria useful if you're
not using it
you you you are absolutely using it
right but the the the
the sprint backlog
is a guide
towards
the sprint goal the sprint goal is the
thing you're trying to achieve
right
um whether whether you do four of the
acceptance criteria or three
might not make any difference to your
ability to meet the sprint goal and to
deliver the customers something that
adds value to their to their product to
their lives to their
efficiency whatever those things are
that you're trying to achieve yeah
yeah
because we need that flexibility because
we don't know how long things are going
to take and things never take the same
amount of time than you think they are
so that variance
is part of that that thing we have to
accept but we cannot accept lower
quality because it's too easy to hide it
right now i think those are the um
quality standards are are so important
there's a whole area in the uk currently
i think jill i think you mentioned it
before uh but they they're they're
currently having to boil their water
because there's e coli
in the water supply
right does that meet your standard and
expectation as a customer absolutely not
right you do not
expect that to be true
yeah i think you are right here uh
martin uh i think i would like to say
one thing uh so
again your dod is again based on your
team development team and the agreement
between the development team and the
product owner so
in duty you can consider like if you are
like kind of uh
i don't want to make it like a very
extreme level of dod so you can say okay
out of
three three or three out of four maybe
uh acceptance criteria could be
considered for dod
but if you want to make a decision
then you can say no we have to consider
foreign so this is something
that might be a negotiation that we have
with the product owner
right no that might be just a thing that
we we have a chat about because
we don't think we can do them all let's
go to the product owner is this okay if
we don't have everything and we can
do something else later
that's that's scope is always negotiable
in scrum so what is on your sprint back
clock including the exceptions criteria
is all negotiable
so we don't commit to any of it so
that's why having it on your definition
of done
might not be such a good idea although
it's very common i do see a lot of teams
put meets acceptance criteria or
approved by the product owner on their
definition of done and but those things
will inhibit your ability to be flexible
victoria i'm just going to
mute mute you again just the background
noise
gin long
you've got your hand up
uh yeah the
you mentioned the commandment for
developers to achieve the is to achieve
the
spreading goal yeah they're
i remember something like their uh
commitment is also to achieve uh like
increment increase i increment
something like that yeah
so so um the this the scrum guide it has
some
weird phrasing around that it basically
says that your increment
is born when your product meets the
definition of done that's effectively
you have an increment when it meets the
definition of done if your product
doesn't meet the definition of done
you've not met the quality level for it
to be releasable
right regardless of how many features
you managed to deliver in it the scope
um but if you met the definition of done
then it's in a releasable state if we're
talking about software uh or even other
things as well if i if i was if i was
writing a a book uh with some colleagues
you know
julong you i peter and anna are all
gonna write a we're gonna write a book
we're gonna collaborate on this this
book about agile
right um we can we can
we can write
various levels of detail on our content
for the different chapters that we work
on
but if it is poorly written
bad uh language bad grammar
purely poor spelling
it's not really in a readable releasable
state
but i could write part of that book as a
blog post or a post on linkedin
to to to gain
feedback
from our potential readers and
stakeholders on particular topics
without having to write the whole thing
so that that's that's the quality part
is are you able to ship that thing to
production if that is true well we've
made our definition of done
and i think that will be reflected uh um
in anna's going to talk about the the
workshop that she's built to provide for
everybody
and that's part of part of that story as
well
but thank you for that that's
good yeah in fact uh i just have found
this sentence from the scrum guide we
were talking developers are the people
in the scrum team that are committed to
creating any aspect of a useful
increment interspersed usable yeah
that's the they has to be usable if it's
not usable
we've not mitigated any risk
that's our definition of done helps us
mitigate risk
working product usable usable product
and they do use that terminology because
they don't want to talk about software
anymore because there's so many more
people and organizations in the world
using scrum using it as a method for
organizing their own work
so they they definitely i think they've
done a pretty good job of removing all
of the the software focused but it does
mean there's some weird words
in the scrum guide that that you have to
go like what the heck does that actually
mean
um and then it's within your context
um i did did scrum training for police
officers in ghana
uh that were using
scrum as a method for organizational
change
right so they weren't building software
in fact
90 of people in the room had
not no idea what a computer looks like
obviously everybody knows what a
computer looks like but we didn't have
good usage even usage of a of a computer
with word or anything it's not something
they do on a daily basis everything's
paper-based
so the the thing was how do we change
this organization how do we iterate on
making incremental improvements to the
to the way the organization operates
yeah so you can use in all sorts of
places
um
i think we want to
introduce a new market opportunity for
our bakery
um
there is is is a huge opportunity to
steal the market in meat snacks
uh meat-based pastries
um but i'm pretty sure once we start
having meat in our products we're gonna
have to have some additional things on
our definition of done
okay because uh serving serving um
not under undercooked baguettes
while our customers might not like it
they're
not likely to die
but if we serve
poorly cooked meat products
that is certainly a lot riskier
right so maybe we need to tighten up
our our definition of done this is a new
market opportunities we need to figure
out what needs to be
on our definition of done
so we're going to do a little exercise
um
called a one two four all
some of you may have participated in
these in the past
um but let me
if i let me
fill the breakout rooms first because
there's a couple of people dropped off
and then we will recreate the breakout
rooms uh and i will do that in just a
moment uh but what we're going to do
ah
goodness me quite a few people have
dropped off
see that's that top that every half
hours and top of the hours is when
everybody disappears
um
so
we're gonna do
one minute silently and on your own
writing down a list of additional things
that need to be on our definition of
done now we're including meat products
so what needs to be
on your definition of done you can do it
on the mural you can do it on a bit of
paper uh you can do it in in one note or
word or whatever you like
um but silently and you're on your own
i'm gonna put one minute on the timer
and then i'll start breakout rooms in
pairs
uh
so
let's that will be ten i think
oh it will be five because i can't count
i can't count anna that's the problem
does he want to mean anywhere just do
this
this calcula is part of the fun
okay
part of the fun of being dyslexic
add in a bit of discalcula and you're
off to the races
it's even more fun peter when you add a
bit of dyspraxia in there as well
well i was thinking of actually
is there you're not got then
no
so do you know what's funny there's like
eight seconds left in in my parents
house it's an older house so it has the
door handles are high up remember in the
old victorian houses the door handles
were high up
and all of them in the house are bent
and the reason they're bent a little bit
is because when i got old enough
that like my shoulder wouldn't go
underneath
the door handle i started walking into
them
and i walked into them so much that
everyone in the house is is bent
part of the fun of growing up
in scotland
okay
for everybody
in the uk the rest of us in the uk are
fairly normal it's just the scots just
the scots
that's it's because that we've got all
the the the genius genes
um we invented pretty much everything
peter that's that's why uh
we've got all of these additional
things steam engine can we get the steam
engine
we can we can start we can kind of just
fight another occasion so two minutes in
pairs to merge your lists together get
them on the mural and add some more
items okay
oh well i did do
three okay okay
so let me do two minutes oh two
and then we have five rooms and that's a
pain in the butt to merge into
two pairs so we're gonna have a room of
more
um
so let me do the assign participants
uh so that'll be five five goes into one
five into one
four
where's um at
four goes into two
ah hold on yes cancel
somebody's
no it's everybody's there
where's amit
oh maybe already gone okay
do it again five into one five
into one
four
goes into two four
and then
three
just goes into two again
three into two
there we go so
i've got that set up i can leave it
uh they've got about 40 seconds left so
they're starting to create some items
um
there's test control coming in i think
there's a weird posted there haste
testing control
that's a good idea
uh utensil
cleaned and disinfected
i would say that's included in kitchen
clean at time of preparation
um somebody introducing some meat health
standards find out what they are include
them in our definition of done uh
properly cooked meat products properly
cooked i think we can just say all
products
properly cooked i don't think it has to
be meat products but we'll we'll get to
that
refrigeration if refrigeration might
become a more important thing how do we
store
our um
meat before we cook it
storing our meat
oh there we go
let me click the assign button move
there we go
and they'll get four
minutes in four pairs but it's not quite
four pairs because it's
funny-ass groups
we lost quite a lot of people at the
well 17 30 for me
that's
utc
so it depends which time zone you're in
but that might be
what i have done for the day or it could
be
it's too late i i know that um andre's
it's pretty late for andre
um for him it is
quite late i think we go to midnight for
andre
uh so he's just before midnight
we're getting a good group of uh people
in uh very different aspects i know
some folks are
have an engineering background software
background some folks have
no engineering or ite background
whatsoever and that's that's a good mix
uh coming into the the the session
um that's why i i kind of picked that
story of the the
um bakery
because it's it's a good non
non-technical aspect but as you see some
of the conversations have been trending
towards
phrases like technical debt which are
um very very
i guess geeky i guess yeah a little bit
so
we want to have um as few
purely technical conversations but
things kind of gravitate toward there's
a lot of software engineers
there but hopefully we have enough to
keep everybody else happy who's not a
software engineer
i'm definitely an enabler of those
conversations trending to finding to
technical uh uh gunther gunther
vermeulen when i was doing my t-prep for
the product owner class did kind of give
me into a little bit of trouble for
you know being a little bit too
technical uh but the space that i tend
to work in
tends to be a technical space i tend to
work with a lot of technical product
owners
um
so product owners building products for
developers
product owners building engineering
products
um i've worked with a few systems where
they're they're building always a flow
as a flowmaster
building
software that manages the flow of
liquids through oil rigs
or
kongsberg maritime building maritime
simulation software all very very
technical detailed um product domains
right they're not really building the
same level of commercial products that
you would get on your on your phone or
um
just going to
go to a website and buy but um it is it
is important
as a product owner to have an
understanding of the technical domain
within which you're working but you do
not need to be technical as a product
owner
as a scrum master you want to have an
understanding of the technical domain
within which your teams are operating
right um if you've got a bunch of teams
that are building software you probably
want to know what good software looks
like you want to know what continuous
delivery is and what it looks like what
are unit tests and what do they look
like right so you can help the team
but maybe you bring somebody in to do
that maybe
you don't have to have those
conversations i just think it helps
um if we're working in a software
company
regardless of the job we're doing we
probably want an understanding of what
software is what it looks like how it's
created
if i was working in a bakery
i would want to understand
something about how to bake even if i'm
just selling pies
right
somebody's gonna ask what's in the pie
somebody's going to ask
how do i cook it uh somebody's going to
ask those questions and i should be able
to answer them
or i feel like i should be able to
answer them i
tend to like to know
um
about the products that i'm working with
the products that i'm selling how
they're created how they work
um but that's maybe just me being a geek
right and
i like to to to to check up on mural see
how things are working talk to their uh
product owners uh give them improvements
i work with use mighty networks so i'm
diving into their documentation and
figuring out how it works how is it
going to support my business there we go
everybody's back
hello i was talking to myself a little
bit there anna
okay i tend to i do that quite a lot i
do that quite a lot
so
i see some very interesting things
on our our lists sorry sorry victoria
again there's just some background noise
or it's anu it's either agu
um i don't know if it's victoria first
name or or angular sometimes that's
depends where the comma is
uh so we've got a few things
clean cleanliness obviously an important
topic
um but then there's additional things i
i some things that i had not even
thought of in my wildest dreams
cross-contamination in the kitchen
is a good one i do have a relative who
is a celiac
right although that's not a meat thing
but you know
somebody's a vegan they're gonna get
upset if there's meat products in the
same area uh if they're a celiac they're
going to be incredibly ill
she just came back from a vacation and
she was so ill because other people if
you're not a celiac you don't think
about the level of contamination that is
required to cause a problem it can be
tiny
so we've got meat products properly kit
cooked i'd put that with meat health
standards followed
cross-contamination with utensils and
disinfectate
right i like that um
maybe different shelf life's applied i i
think the shelf life on bread
is shorter than cakes
um and meat products probably sit
somewhere in the middle i'm not sure
but now we've got to talk about
refrigeration
right maybe our maybe our baked products
we kept them warm
rather than letting them go cold
but now our meat products we need
refrigeration for the ingredients we
need refrigeration for
uh um the the the made products that's a
little bit more complicated
um some taste testing
that sounds like a good idea does taste
testing apply also to our baked goods
yeah
it does
i had i had a couple of things
on my here's some stuff i prepared
earlier in case we don't get everything
so i had a visual inspection
that would solve my
circular
baguette problem wouldn't it
i mentioned circular baguettes that's
not really what we think of as baguettes
uh one product in each batch has been
test tested
uh ensuring
uh
the there's an eu
standard that is their title is farm to
fork
right ensuring safety standards all the
way to to eating the product
um
and checking the that meat products are
cooked to the right temperature so i
think we covered
most of that
in the things we came up with
right we need to add more things to our
definition of that
yeah martin while we're having a
discussion because the definition of
gums should apply
to all but if we
say
meat product properly cooked it does not
apply to the baguettes because they
don't have meat
yes
i had the same concern for this one we
only focus on bread and the bracket and
maybe for next run when we talk about
meat we can add this one to the updated
definition down not for this round
i agree with uh
well maybe if we take
if if i take this example here i'll make
it bigger so we know which one we're
talking about there we go the meat
products properly cooked right if i just
take the word meat off there
products properly cooked
right regardless of what that means to
the individual products we want all our
products to be properly cooked
have you ever had a baguette that wasn't
properly cooked and it's still
yeah exactly exactly it still it applies
to both those products
um and then instead of meat health
standards followed we can just again
take the word meat off
right health standards followed
each product different product different
ingredients are going to have different
health standards and we need to meet
meet them all
or at least i hope we're meeting them
all for our bakery
um
so we we can
we do want to think about that as part
of our definition of done but i do agree
that it is
there may be things that are on your
definition of done
that don't apply equally to all products
peter brought up a good example right at
the beginning
he said documentation
right the amount of documentation you
need for the
the pacemaker firmware
versus the printer
right they're going to be different
right the level of documentation you
need who needs the documentation
i'm sure printers have to meet iso
standards too peter but they're probably
not as strict and they're probably not
as detailed as the pacemaker standards
that's just just the way it is if you're
building a plane
i hope you've got good documentation
so that does that make sense from how
you would think about
your definition of done
cool
so i just had a a few things uh here i
had i had some example at definitions of
done they're actually pulled from the um
ap aps
sd
courseware the applying professional
scrum for software delivery i'm just
getting that actually i should have put
the logo on there shouldn't i anna
i don't even have it there never mind
i'm going to try and get it quickly uh
but oh there we go
copy image paste
yeah so i just stole that from the from
the eps courseware
um
and really it's just
an expression that there can be
different levels of definition of done
even for similar products uh each of
these products listed here are fake
products right they're just fake
products but they have uh um
different levels of definition of done
but they're all websites
right
so it depends what your business is
willing to pay for it depends on the
risk
of how and where you're delivering
your product
right there is an expression that i i
use that i guess some people like and
some people don't
but i always say it's about risk
low quality adds risk to your product
and there is a risk
to the organization if you deliver a
crap product to production what's the
risk to your brand
right will your customers
still come back if you deliver crappy
product okay that's one
what about the risk internally to your
business
right what's the financial risk not
brand risk like what you look like
but also the risk of
your customers
in your product
think of think of boeing and the
definition of done they should have had
for the 737 max
right
they should have been thinking about the
the risk to their brand
massive risk
nobody thinks of boeing well at the
moment
the risk to the customers a bunch of
people died
right but also what's the risk
to the people working on the product
how many of the people working on the
that worked on that product
are going to see prison time
right there's an extreme example but
prison time
because they delivered a poor quality
product and maybe didn't do the level of
due diligence that people expect them to
do that the industry expects them to do
right so are your a your your developers
the people working on your product at
risk
is your users at risk is your company
at risk
how do we mitigate those things those
are things that need to go in your
definition of done
right hence why you want an
organizational standard
because it's not just the engineer's job
to think about those things
the people doing the work
right but we don't always start
with a good definition of done uh this
is a poster
here if you hover over it there's a
little open button in the bottom right
you don't have to click it but it'll
open up big pdf uh poster for yes we
have a definition of done and
it's awesome
right if you don't have a definition of
done
create a definition of done that you can
achieve which might not equal releasable
but you have to start somewhere
and i think that's the point where um
anna would you like to
there is a few minutes left
um
if we all follow anna
she can take us over to the workshop
i'm just going to follow anna there we
go if you you should have the ability to
summon
anna i think i made you a
facilitator i did indeed
i cannot
bring everybody to me
i will summon them there we go i
summoned everybody okay thank you
okay
so
well based on what we've been talking
about uh it may be that in your teams
you have a definition of dog or you
don't
uh and usually teams have a definition
of done but they don't follow it or they
have it somewhere in
in
hidden and and they don't use it uh
daily
so this workshop is uh to embrace the
definition i've done
and
if you click this is a link uh if you
click on it you will get into into the
into the community and you will see the
post on how to do this uh workshop
but uh well uh basically uh with one to
parole uh you will be able to to see
what you're what you're doing but what
what definition i've done you're
having right now even though you don't
have it written down or you're not using
it that the developers and all the spam
team has it in in their mind
and also you will be able to see what
things uh they would like to add and
yeah that that takes us to the to the
next uh so
just to point out that the this
particular
workshop the columns here do represent
a little bit more they're a little bit
more geeky a little bit more software
orientated uh so you've got
what do you need to do before those
codes
to be coded tested integrated release
releasable and then released what are
the things that need to be true
in all of those categories so that you
can build up a big picture of everything
that needs to be true to ship your
software um if you're not doing software
right and you're maybe doing marketing
content or videos or whatever it is
you're doing you you can change those
headings to whatever the the stages you
can think of that that work within your
product
yeah this way um it's basically to
create like a storyline for them to
think
on what they've been doing
uh
so that they can identify quite good and
wider stages they are applying those
standards so it really helps to guide
and don't just include your team the
scrum team in this conversation
include anybody who has a say
in whether your product ships to
production so that could be somebody in
the security team somebody in the
operations team somebody in the
messaging
team is our product on message
right whatever whatever whoever can
block your ability to deploy to
production have them involved in this
conversation
and also and
something that comes out of from doing
this workshop may also be that somebody
that it's not in your team should be
yeah okay so
this is uh like an eye opener when when
you do it
so uh
once you have uh once you have that once
you have
[Music]
all those post-its over there
uh then uh the all the everybody
involved will start dragging into what
they are really doing and the wish list
and there is going to be a good
conversation there because some people
think that they are doing it some people
uh do not and usually the people who is
more um
has more experience
um
it's more critical on on
on our heavy on on what is being done
and they they have a clear view on
on this so
uh this is also an eye opener
and after doing this uh you can run a
boat here to update the definition of
time so you will see what you're doing
embrace it and then
if you see that it's possible add
something else because sometimes you
need to check if
if you need to continue working with
that definition i've done
to make you more mature or you can add
more things that's um
there is a an additional psychological
trick i i would definitely recommend
here
and that's that instead of having a this
is a boolean proposition right so you've
got doing or wishlist
sometimes people will put it in doing
when they're only kinda doing it
right and maybe nobody argues
but if you make it a three-state problem
we're doing it
we've kind of heard of it and are kind
of doing it and then not doing it and we
know as the person facilitating it that
unless it's in the doing it category it
counts as no we're not doing it
right but it psychologically makes them
feel better for being able to put things
in that middle category we're kind of
doing it
you get more truth
i've seen a lot of sticky notes in the
middle of yeah
yeah yeah people want to hedge their
bets yeah
yeah
so uh
once you have done that you have an
agreement with the team
you have what you're doing and what
you're going to do and here this is my
favorite part because the other part is
like yeah building the definition of
dawn but my favorite part comes here
when it comes to imagine that and then
you link to the past imagine that we
have had this definition of done
in the past what could happen what could
how we could have done things better in
terms of
quality communication estimation
expectations and there is where the
the team really understands um
how it can change their daily work
and if you link it with the scrum events
uh you give them the the option to to
make them a stand in in in a real
scenario
where they could be using that
definition of done daily
and
just um
something else don't yeah make a follow
up even though you can use this workshop
once make a follow up um
and the first planning after doing this
workshop
to grab this definition of done into the
planning
and
put it on the table
to because they are going to understand
really what what it means in in in
planning
in in in adding things to the screen but
also building the plan to build those
things yeah when you first get a
definition of done
and don't expect everybody to magically
remember it and follow it
you you need to keep
hammering back to that when you're doing
refinement
does does all of these things are we
thinking about the definition of done
have you thought about testing did you
look at this what about security do we
need to do something with security in
this
keep pointing at those things until it
becomes second nature for the team
to know and they own their definition of
done
and that i think is one of the key
purposes of this exercise
is because they put the items on it and
they create it
and they specify what they can do now
versus what's on their wish list
you can then keep revisiting it either
at retrospectives
um and maybe you don't do the whole
exercise every retrospective
you might just take here here was our
wish list is there anything we want to
try and
put on our doing list get on to our
definition of done these are things that
we can't do yet okay
what can we do around that what can we
change
um and then
if you're just getting started and you
don't have a definition of done or a
brand new product
and you could pull this workshop out at
your sprint planning as well and just uh
figure out what your definition of done
is before you get started
one thing that i i found out in this
this workshop i got a question uh
from a team member uh asking me okay but
where where do we where do we check that
this
applies like if if we needed to have a
moment like say okay check check check
and
it is not for that it is it is really in
a team agreement uh
it's something to embrace not because
it's written in confluence or whatever
we have to go through the
checklist it's something more it's a
team agreement and we need to respect
all of us that agreement and then
they started to understand what the
definition of them
uh
meant
awesome
thank you very much for that anna
you're more than welcome so anna has uh
published uh a blow by blow
uh article uh on the the community
page uh with how to run the workshop um
as well as a link to the mural template
so it's just
this uh part of the workshop um so you
can use it with your teams
um however you like
okay
so so feel free to go
grab that and i marked the post that i
did as featured so it should be right at
the front of the community site as well
and give us feedback
yes
uh and not just not just feedback this
was the first uh session that anna and i
have run together i think there will
probably be more because we had lots of
fun
at running it
so we're always interested in in
feedback and other topics
or different types of exercises or
whatevers
um that you would like to to let us know
so please feel free to
um
add
any any comments you want maybe there
was an expectations gap between what we
delivered and what you expected when you
got here and maybe we can have another
sex
session that fixes that so um please
provide us uh with any feedback you
think
uh think we need
okay
cool well uh thank you very much i i'm
super happy we got so many participants
that's probably uh anna everybody's
coming here to see anna rather than me
for sure
um
i'm fairly positive
so i'm just gonna
wrap up the
[Music]
you