one of the great parts of immersive
learning is getting feedback from your
peers and colleagues we give an
assignment at the end of every session
uh something to do in your organization
to actually practically Implement some
of the techniques and when we come back
we do a debrief but it's a a facilitated
debrief so it's not just myself or one
of the other trainers doing the debrief
it's your colleagues in the class the
other people that are participating
who've also tried the same thing they're
providing their input their review their
Reflections on what you've tried and you
can provide it on what they've tried and
hopefully we can build a much bigger
body of experiential knowledge