we're going to install the release
management tools on my server btar here
and I'm going to start with the server
then do the client and then install the
deployment agent and set that up um so
let's get going with the
server it is a fairly straightforward um
install process it's a very small
install so let me just get that
going
awesome completed really quickly so we
want to launch that and configure it so
let's do
that now we have the configuration tool
up and we can um I have very few
settings to fill out I'm going to use
network service um I I prefer having
everything the default and everything on
one server in this environment so that
should be no bother and the web service
port I'm going to leave as the default
which is a th and then everybody knows
where it is and I need to put the DB
server
in and as it's just the local
server I can just put in the server name
and click uh
go here we go
so now we have a a release management
server all set up and configured it very
straightforward we're going to install
the client um so let me just run this
client installer again it's a very small
install we're doing it all in the one
server so there probably some of the
bits are already on
there there we go release management
clients installed I'm going to spin that
up and just do a a couple of config
configuration
steps here we go and as uh this is the
local uh machine we can just leave that
at Local Host we could change it the
server name and I'm just going to leave
it okay now we have the release
management client installed I'm just
going to pop over to
Administration and and going to go to um
the manage TFS I'm going to add the TFS
server or local TFS server so
oh I forgot the
beat and our default
collection is default collection um let
me verify that and that will fail and we
need to put in an account that's going
to be used to access this so in this
case I can actually pick our TFS service
account
always make sure you got the password
right okay so we put in our TFS service
account and we hit the
verify so the error message access
denied um TFS service needs the
following permission make requests on
behalf of others needs to actually be uh
applied at the collection level only so
let me open up uh
TFS
and to make things uh uh a little bit
more manageable at the TFS level I'm
going to create a new
group
called release management service
accounts and then I'm going to go to the
collection
level and I'm going to administer
security and I'm going to add that
security group that I just created so
release management service accounts and
I'm going to give it just the permission
to make requests on behalf of others now
you can apply this at the server level
uh but that's not recommended as it
gives uh uh somebody too much power at
the server level and if you make it just
at the collection
level there we go and then go to our um
um group group membership our release
management service accounts group and we
can add in whatever accounts we need um
at this level so I'm just going to add
in TF
service and now if we head on over to
release management and hit the verify
button we get our green Teck and all is
good so now I've added the the
collection in um I can have uh multiple
users access this and I'm just going to
add a group of users cuz the only person
that can access it right now is
me good Dem with
users add that in and if I go to manage
users I have a bunch of users that have
been given
permission awesome now we've got the
client installed um we can go over and
install the rest of the services
so we're now going to install the um
deployment
agent so if I just run the deployment
agent
here again it's a very small install
shouldn't take
long and there we go and we'll launch
the configuration
tool and in here again I'm going to pick
network service cuz I like to keep
things simple and we have to type the
URL of our release management
server and that should get us
there awesome we also have the release
management agent
configured now if I open up the client
tool
open up the RE Management client
tool and go to configure
paths I can go to
servers scan for
new find our agent register that agent
locally and that will take a little
while to to do the communication
properly um it'll figure out is online
in in a in a few
minutes and there we go we've installed
and configured um release management
server release management client and an
agent um in our release management
environment