so the question is um what is the single
most valuable outcome that a Consulting
engagement can produce
man I'm struggling because can it be one
thing right is it is it it
let's let's apply some lean principle if
we can't get to a thing we need to go up
one level so perhaps
systemic change
some sort of actual change in in either
the behaviors because you've changed the
system right I mean that's ultimately
what we're trying to do is we're trying
to change the system within which uh the
organization is functioning in order to
get some business benefit right whether
that's a business benefit of the
engineering teams are able to work
faster or it's a business benefit that
the company is able to respond to the
market more quickly whatever that
business benefit is
that's the outcome that you're trying to
achieve and you're only going to get
that by actually changing the system and
quite often that's really difficult in
organizations because lots of people say
they want to change but then don't
actually want to do the things that they
need to do in order to change
we kind of quite often feel comfortable
with the way things are right
um and that can be
um
it can be real just really difficult to
to get people on board but when you do
have people on board and they're willing
to try new things and experiment knowing
that not every idea is going to work out
right then I think uh the single most
valuable outcome for a Consulting
engagement is
some kind of systemic change to the
system that enables something some
desire that the business is looking for
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility