bringing um modesty and respect for
others into the conversation in agility
is going to help you build trust right
build those empathetic relationships
both within the team within the
organization and Leadership and
outwardly towards customers don't make
assumptions right that's the the the key
risk here is making assumptions um and
also cognitive bias although that's more
difficult to detect in yourself usually
you need somebody else to to to look in
on it to to point it out um but then do
you listen to those people do you
realize that perhaps other people's
perceptions um are are are are important
to our decision making