one of the most common behaviors that
will greatly impact on your ability to
be successful um at any process but
specifically having a a cad strategy is
is sweeping your problems under the rug
um so that's a most teams will not
necessarily
nefariously but hide or ignore their
problems that's why when we we talk
about retrospectives we talk about uh H
um reflection we talk about kaizan as a
phrase are we hiding or ignoring
anything right that's something to to to
actively look at and it's
because we we as humans are really
really good at ignoring stuff that maybe
we feel like it's too much effort maybe
we feel like we can't do anything about
I I I remember um a Time uh living in a
flat with my brother in the West End of
Glasgow and um we never cleaned the
grill because nobody wanted to do it we
effectively swept that work under the
rug and went N I don't I don't really
know how to do that right I mean that's
that's I've got to got to go figure out
this was before YouTubes right I got to
go figure out how to clean this perhaps
I have to phone my mom and ask her right
how do I how do I do this um what's the
best way to approach it what level
of detail do I need in how to do that so
both of us ignored it completely and we
used it all the time so what do you
think happened
eventually what do you think happened
eventually yeah you're right it caught
fire it caught fire
and we had a fire in the kitchen we
didn't have a fire extinguisher cuz we
also swept that under the rug and didn't
do that and at one point my brother had
grabbed a pan full of water and was
about to throw it into the grill and
then he realized no like it's not a good
idea to throw water on a fat fire right
CU if you've ever seen those
those adverts on TV it just explodes you
don't want to throw water on a fat fire
uh so we stopped called the fire brigade
fire brigade arrived they came up with a
fire extinguisher and Went Done Right
but we needed to clean the
grill that was our trigger to go do that
and then to continue to do it regular I
actually don't remember we were we were
teenagers I don't remember if we
actually continue to do it regularly or
we just did it once and then maybe then
wherever that cooker ended up up
somebody else will need to do it but
you've got to do the things otherwise
this cruft builds up right and that
cruft could be dirt it could be fat it
could be clogging up the system it can
be just getting in the way making things
a little bit more difficult it could
take the guise of bureaucratic processes
in your organization it could take the
guise of technical debt in your product
it could just be purely architected
purly designed stuff that you've created
and nobody goes back uh uh to to to to
resolve those things just sweeping
problems under the rug and ignore them
for you know that in every cartoon they
have that moment where they're cleaning
up a kid's room and they just open the
cupboard shove everything in and then
close the cupboard really quickly and
then at some point the cupboard door
pops open and all the stuff falls out
again that's what we're trying to avoid
that's why why we need discipline to not
sweep things under the rug to do
something about it we need courage when
things might be a little bit more
difficult to deal with a cban strategy
is not going to be effective if you or
your team sweep things into the under
the rug have the discipline and courage
to implement a caman strategy fully if
you're struggling to implement a cand
strategy we can help or help you find
somebody who can click on the link below
to get in touch