too much of anything can be a bad thing
and that leads us to one of our seven
agile virtues which is temperance you
need to take everything in um in measure
right make sure that you don't do too
much of something that that could
manifest in our world um as having too
much backlog what does it mean to have a
lean inventory in your backlog what does
it mean to not put things in there to
think a little bit more carefully about
whether something should be in your
backlog or not um what does it mean uh
uh to have H just enough and no more
that's a that's a common phrase that we
use a lot um especially in the scrum
space I I remember I I have this picture
in my head of Ken saying it to me many
years ago um just enough and no more and
I believe in fact he actually I think he
said that um no matter what quantity
question I ask
him the answer is going to be just
enough and no more doesn't matter what
the quantity question is right so how
much backlog should we have just enough
and no more how many developers should
we have just enough and no more how much
time should we spend on refinement just
enough and no more same for planning up
up front that
Mantra of
um
being focused on what it is we're doing
and minimizing our effort one of the the
um principles in the agile Manifesto is
maximizing the amount of work not done
right um and that's that idea of
temperance maximize the amount of work
not not done minimize your effort for
the maximum gain and always look to take
the easy path where you can but be
willing to take the hard path when you
can't if you are having difficulty
getting the most out of the Seven
Virtues of agility then my team at naked
agility can help you or find a
consultant coach or trainer who can it's
essential for you to find help as soon
as you can and not wait use the links
below to get in touch because you don't
just need agility you need naked agility