a common thing that agile teams do is
they use burnd Downs to figure out uh
how things are going throughout the
Sprint I've got to say burnd Downs are
agile
banditry the whole idea of burnd Downs
in order for a burndown to move from top
left to bottom right in a reasonable
linear fashion you have to have planned
the whole Sprint up
front right in order to have a project
burned down or a product burn down
moving from top left to bottom right you
have to have planned the whole product
or project up
front hopefully we can all be on the
same page that if we're doing if we're
building products that don't exist yet
right we're developing products that
don't exist then there's too much
variance too many surprises too much
complexity in what it is we're doing to
to really plan the next 6 months worth
of work it's always going to change more
than we would like and if we look at
data from like the Standish group uh
that do the chaos report for example
you'll find that that
65% of uh things that we build change
over the life of the product and in fact
even worse than that only 30% of the
features that we do build are actually
used by our custom customers the rest
are used little if ever right so that
bring those two things together we have
a massive amount of unknowns in what
we're doing it's usually always more
than 50% so we know less than half of
what we're going to have to figure out
along the way and that means that being
able to plan up front even the next
10day Sprint is just a ridiculous
exercise in making stuff up ridiculous
exercise in telling a fictional story
the reality is you should walk out of
Sprint planning with no more than is
needed to get started that's how big
your plan should be getting started in
the Sprint how big should your plan be
for your product enough to get
started right or enough to convince
somebody to give you the money that's
also you know you might need more for
that but that ability to get started is
all you need so you maybe walk out of
Sprint planning with 24 hours worth of
work we've plan the next 24 hours cuz
we're going to get together every 24
hours and plan the next 24 hours after
that so we don't really need more than
the first 24 hours to get started if
we're going to build a product we don't
really need that much more than the
first Sprint to get started what of the
backlog items we're going to do maybe
during that Sprint we can come up with
you know how far out into the future we
do want to look but you want it to be
minimal but sufficient you want to have
less stuff to manage less stuff in these
things that's why H burnd Downs are one
of the
reasons that you can't tell what's going
on this is the banditry part of H um it
being for Bandits it's that um if I if I
plan the whole Sprint right
um and I've get let's say I've got five
developers working on my product and
I've got five stories coming into the
backlog and each of those five stories
has 10 tasks that I'm going to write
down as part of my plan how many per
person right how many tasks do I have at
the end I have lots of lots and lots and
lots of tasks what happens on day two of
the Sprint when you figure out that your
plan wasn't that great and 50% of it
needs to change because you figured out
something
new it gets out of date and the reason
it gets out of date is because none of
your developers they they want to focus
on delivering the stuff because we're
under pressure to deliver the product
deliver the value and yet they need to
go and edit or manage these hundred
things that are in the in in the Sprint
backlog right don't have them there you
don't need them all you need is a just
in time just enough plan either for the
Sprint or adjus in time just enough plan
for your product in order to start get
started and get developing uh your
product so don't get stuck uh in that
rut of too much planning up front which
is what a burndown forces you to do stop
being a bunch of agile Bandits and focus
instead on continuous flow of value
through your system if you are being
ambushed by agile bandits in your
organization then my team at naked
agility can help or we can help you find
a consultant or expert who can you can
set up a no obligation consultation
using the links
below and don't forget to like And
subscribe if you enjoyed the video