my name is Kathryn Maddox and I am
astonishingly
healthy i what advice - compared to
training because I've linked them from
the first time with books high energy
pragmatics and really interesting and
really glad we did because even the
worst skeptics in the crowd were won
over and not shopped yeah I'm not
suggesting and I'm the CTO and calm so
after a lot evaluation of differences
from creating options we selected Martin
because I think he brings a unique
perspective they very close to what I
call the beakers engineer the dragons
are makers and he gains a great
perspective that's close to the makers
to the skunk reading session which is
what is thought about how about you know
everything else is hard making sure the
details of the builders are successfully
doing their best work and I think mine
does a great job in connecting with them
[Music]