you
hello welcome to my office hours 23rd of
June
okay so I do this event every Wednesday
at 6 p.m.
I collect as many interesting questions
as I hear during the week the week in
between so from Wednesday to Wednesday
and then I try and do my best to answer
those questions at this event as well as
answering it for folks directly as well
when they ask me and I have three
questions today that I'm going to go
over but I want to let you know that you
can ask me anything so you can either we
are at live on Facebook YouTube Twitter
and LinkedIn well I'm hoping we're live
on LinkedIn LinkedIn it's been a bit
funny I did a session earlier and it's
just a black screen so everything else
is working apart from LinkedIn so maybe
they're having a problem or maybe my
systems having a problem but we'll
figure it out ah the best place to
interact is on YouTube it has the best
experience and it's the least delay for
you watching if you have a question
please ask in the chat for this video
you can ask it on any platform I can see
theoretically the chat from all the
platforms I can't respond to LinkedIn
but I can obviously verily I just can't
reply we have again at YouTube is the
best place if you want to ask a question
anonymously you can use the link here
it's just our form of the text box and
you can ask anything you want about
DevOps scrum Kanban agile organizational
change metrics whatever you want and I
will
do my best to answer it I don't
guarantee I'll have all the answers but
if I do not have an answer to a question
I will go off in between now and Nix
Wednesday find out an answer and try and
get you something for next week if I
don't have one yet so just a recap for
what I've been up to on Monday Tuesday I
did my fourth third no fourth fourth
professional scrum foundations class
live online for 20 odd people and I've
done two in Dublin timezone and two in
PST so at California timezone and this
was a California so I am tired I am
waning now it's 6 p.m. in the UK and
that was just when I was starting the
class Monday Tuesday so it's it's been
very tiring but we had a great time
during that class I'm just thinking I
might show you the mural that we created
as part of that class as long as I can
type and talk at the same time I didn't
have to type in my password that was
pretty good the part of the mural that I
thought might be interesting for you let
me put that up there and then I'll zoom
zoom out is we had our discussion
where's my magic button there it is well
let me let me disappear myself we had a
really interesting discussion for I was
probably about an hour and a half to
build this part of the mural but a
really interesting discussion on the
roles artifacts and events around scrum
and how they all go together and we
talked about the ideas that Satya
Nadella
has been talking about a lot recently
which is the M it's better to trade off
features for productivity
productivity of your team's productivity
of your people doing the work is
actually more important than actually
adding features because in the long run
you're gonna get way more features by
focusing on productivity let the
engineers figure that out a good example
of that is the azure DevOps team who
eight years ago were delivering 25
features to production each year and
today after a massive transition towards
agility there are delivering nearly 300
features to production each year if
you're a product owner that's worth the
massive multi-year investment in
productivity and setup and so building
this was a lot of fun especially with
the the group of folk that I had we had
three teams two teams of six and one
team of seven in our group well I think
that's how it broke down there was 20
people and Russell Miller and myself
were facilitating that so it was just a
lot of fun and we had only two not
scrums scrum master accountable for
progress and scrum master assigning work
or just assigning work to people in
general so we had a lot of fun Russell
and I and we got some really interesting
ideas out of this team so and as part of
not just that training but the other
questions that have come up folks that
have got in touch with me since last
week and I get three things that I kind
of want to talk about one is the idea
that a lot of folks have that conflicts
definition of done with acceptance
criteria and so I just want to define
both of those things to make it make it
more more transparent I want to talk
about spikes versus refinement
that seems to be a common question that
comes up that's always a good one and
then what do we do about ad hoc work in
the sprint that was one of the
conversations that came up during the
training on Monday and Tuesday and
there's maybe the belief that scrum
can't handle I'd hoc work however that
is not the case so let let's I'll maybe
a leave this up I'll put myself back on
there we go
and I might I might use a little bit of
space there to to draw stuff if I feel
like it but I'll leave that up just now
so the first one is Inc definition of
done with acceptance criteria I see that
a lot not just from new people to
agility but also with people that have
long experience in agility a definition
of done an acceptance criteria are not
the same thing
they are only loosely related to each
other so our definition of done is our
measure of quality if you were to get
everybody in a in a room who's
responsible for shipping your product to
production or authorizing your product
to ship to production or signing off on
your your your product being shipped to
production if you had software engineers
you had testers you had analysts and you
had operations you had security legal
maybe and product management if you had
all of those folk in a room and you
asked them to make a list of all of the
things that have to be true regardless
of what we're working on but regardless
of that so nothing to do with the
acceptance criteria or what it is we're
going to deliver what's a list of things
that have to be true in order for us to
ship to
reduction do we need documentation how
much what needs to be in it do we need
to do testing what type of testing how
much testing is okay for us to be happy
to ship to production make a list of all
of those things that have to be true
that's effectively your definition of
done do we need to support 10,000
simultaneous users if we need to support
10,000 simultaneous users then the
performance testing for 10,000
simultaneous users has to have passed
and there's all kinds of things like
that that can go in there and we might
want to think about code quality we
might want to think about refactoring we
might want to think about readability
unit tests code reviews these are all
things that go to the quality of our
product so we're not talking about scope
or features just the quality and that's
what the engineering team the the scrum
team the development team is accountable
for the development team is accountable
for quality not quantity of work okay
and whereas the acceptance criteria are
the if you think of a piece of work a
product backlog item which might be of
any type you like your product backlog
item you're going to have some
conversations with the product owner and
with stakeholders and your acceptance
criteria are your measures by which the
folks that accept that your items have
been completed to the the level that
they desire and are met so I acceptance
criteria might be about features it's
going to be about behaviors you might
have a behavior based list of acceptance
criteria these are all customer centric
business centric ideas both the the
story the backlog item and the
acceptance criteria is around making
sure we understand what we're going to
go bill
definition of done is around the minimum
level of quality required for the how we
go build it I hope that kind of
separates those two things a little bit
and makes it easier to define those two
we need a definition of done having
acceptance criteria is not good enough
to also be our definition of done at the
same time we need that extra piece ah
okay
so that was the first question about
conflating definition of done with
acceptance criteria it's pretty common
for for that to be something that
happens the second question was around
spike versus refinement should we have a
spike or should it just be part of
refinement I get that question a lot how
do we handle our something we don't
understand we have a piece of work that
we need to do we don't understand it yet
we've identified that we need to do some
learning or we need to do some
experimentation around that piece of
work how do we represent that work
there's one school of thought that we
should create a product backlog item
that would be cut we would call a spike
which is a time boxed amount of learning
that goes into our sprint and we it has
story points and we get credit for for
doing that work and I disagree with
spikes
I don't believe spikes are necessary and
I believe that spikes reduce
transparency for the amount of work we
can get done it makes it seem like we
can deliver more work than we can
because we did a bunch of story points
that were just investigation work rather
than actual work that we didn't deliver
any value directly to the customer you
using a spiked spikes our informational
output rather than value output or
learnings output rather than value
output which I'm not saying that
learnings aren't valuable they are and
but they're not what the customer is
paying for the customer is paying for
value all the stakeholders are paying
for value so in scrum there already is a
mechanism for a time for the development
team to look at things on your product
backlog that are coming up in future
sprints and gain more understanding of
what those items are we call that
refinement it doesn't have a specific
event or time box the scrum guide
defines it as maybe you shouldn't spend
more than 10% of your time in refinement
but the reality is if you're and if you
really understand the stuff on your
product backlog you probably spend less
than 10% of your time in refinement but
if you find something on your product
backlog that's super-complicated that we
really don't understand that we're going
to have to work together work with a
bunch of other folks you know get some
technology experts in do some
investigation talk to the customer
discuss trade offs maybe for some things
we spend more than 10% of our time
during the sprint in refinement we'd
like to keep it to the minimum we need
but maybe we need a little bit more than
we usually do and that refinement is
just work that we have to do for things
coming up it could be part of our UX
work it could be part of our analysis it
could be part of a skiing the customer
questions it could be implementation
things that we need we have to order
servers we have to whatever those things
are and that for me is just refinement I
don't want it represented on my backlog
because there's an amount of time
that we have in the sprint our capacity
for the sprint based on the people that
we've got and any vacations and things
they have and some time is just taken
away for other things and that's okay
that's kind of the reality of working in
an organization there's not just one
product there's many other product I as
a software engineer may have other
responsibilities than just showing
progress on a particular product and I
might have some support work I have to
do I might have some training that I
have to go do I might have some some
business as usual stuff I need to do
some checks in the morning when I come
in this is all time there is not product
work and if it's not product work I
prefer not to have it represented on the
product backlog because it's not to do
with the product it's not providing us
with value everything on the product
backlog should be things that are
valuable to our customer defined in a
way that they can understand our
customer our user our stakeholder
whatever you want to call it and I think
that idea kind of bleeds in to our ad
hoc work how do we deal with ad hoc work
in the sprint and so what I the way I
normally try and explain this is with a
little bit of our a diagram okay so
let's say we have we figured out what
our capacity for our sprint is and it's
about it's about this big okay I'll move
that a little bit to the left there we
go it's about this big this is our
capacity for the sprint and that
includes all the people whatever
whatever we're going to do that's just
the box that we can fill and we're going
to have some things that we know we're
going to have to do so for example and I
might take 10% of my time for refinement
okay I've got a little bit of work doing
refinement
and that's that's work that's already
allocated I'm gonna make sure that you
know I know only have 90 percent left to
go do that
and then I I find out that um we've got
some BAU business as usual there's some
checks that have to be run in the
morning there's some data that has to be
analyzed and has to be done every day or
every second day or every week or
whatever that is and we look at that
work across our whole team and it takes
about 20% of our time we just take a
look at that and that's that's what we
feel it takes so this is 20% for what b8
for BAU I'm just gonna call that BAU
business as usual so I'm gonna stick
that in there okay okay well we've get
70% of our time left but we need to hold
some of our capacity we you know we're
not our quality level is not where we
would like it to be and we need to spend
some amount of time working on things
that are wrong in production so either
productions down there's a bug there's a
customer support request whatever those
things are they're just things that are
are not working properly
oh my creator posted let's take that
away so we're gonna spend 20% of our
time on support slash live issues you
can call that whatever you want but
that's effectively effectively what it
is support slash live issues okay so we
have 50% of our space left 50% has taken
by by other things that's that's that's
okay so let's say we have all of the
rest of that time is for our oh no no no
we've got we've got another thing we
need to look at let's say 10%
or at bunks you know those little things
that happen during the sprint or things
that get left over that we didn't really
spot that are too small to fit in a hole
sprint goal and but not big enough sorry
not big enough to justify our whole
sprint goal and but too small even if
you you know you don't want to have a
sprint that's a bug-fix sprint that's
gonna be a major problem so we're gonna
have that ten percent so now we have
forty percent of our time which is our
our work let's call it our goal our
sprint goal and we have forty percent of
our time to allocate to our sprint goal
is this okay does the scrum guide say
say this is okay it it does the scrum
guide doesn't say how much of your time
during the sprint has to be towards the
Sprint goal it just implies that as much
as possible this might be what's
possible we might only be able to spend
30% of our sprint focused on our sprint
goal so that's the focus for the team if
you think of the scrum values we want
focus and we've we've got some focus but
then we've got some leftover bugs I've
got those little little things that we
need to fix we'll get some support
incidents because some businesses
usually got some refinement okay however
everything I'm trying to think how I'm
going to represent this I'm just gonna
do align all of this piece here bugs ah
let's see bugs and live life site
incidents and be a you are and
opportunities for automation that's the
way I like to describe it okay
all except I can't spell opportunities
but you get the idea and we have
and okay I'm gonna get another word for
that let's see if it would let me do
that technical debt anything that's not
automated is technical debt so if it can
be automated and it's not automated then
its technical debt so maybe our quality
level isn't good enough that's why we're
getting 10% of our time spent on bugs
what can we do let's have a discussion
during our retrospective how can we make
that 10 percent smaller how can we
change our application change our
deployment change the way we do things
in order to have less bugs in production
that's that's one thing we can do why do
we have support LifeSite issues is there
something we've not automated in an
admin system that means we have to go do
it
is there some downtime a good example as
the azure devops team ran into an issue
where for example if the profile service
for Azure DevOps failed then the entire
system stopped working does it make
sense for you as a software engineer not
to be able to commit code because it
can't go pull your profile picture and
your friendly display name it doesn't
make any sense it should be able to
continue without those things so they
had to go and add some work to their
backlog they had to do work to change
their architecture to support the
circuit breaker pattern and that circuit
breaker patent allowed them to remove
that support time remove that support
work and actually allowed them to get
rid of some of their bug time as well
maybe some of their BAU too because it's
all wrapped up in that things are going
wrong in production and we have to go
sort Atty we've got to go monitor these
things because we're having this problem
so there's some time that we can save
there the idea is how can we make the
goal bigger and these other things
smaller
okay that would be one of the things
that I want the team to bring up at the
retrospective so to answer the question
how do we deal with ad-hoc work um it
just takes time away from the goal we
reserve some time for our ad hoc work
we're open and transparent about how
much time we're reserving I might I
might like to see something like this
diagram for my team and I want to be
able to focus on bring it up the
retrospective and focus on what can we
do to reduce those things so that was
really the three questions that I had
today there was conflating definition of
done an acceptance criteria they are not
the same thing they are separate things
definition of done is about the minimum
level of quality for delivering how
acceptance criteria is about adding more
detail to the what I talked a little bit
about spikes versus refinement you can
have a spike on your product backlog but
I think the the a better way is really
to focus on refinement as the activity
for figuring some of that stuff out so
you get out of Ament and and then as
part of that story because refinement
just takes ten percent of your time up
to ten percent of your time or not not
on average more than ten percent of your
time and I also talked a little bit of a
ad hoc work and how that fit into our
goal for scrum there sees other things
that we have to work on and how do we
balance that as a team as long as we're
open and transparent that's what counts
okay so I'm going to leave it there like
I said I was up very late I was teaching
till 1:00 a.m. last night in PST time
zone from GMT so I am tired and I've
answered all of the questions that we
have I would definitely ask if you've
got any questions that you
don't want anybody to know that you're
asking uh you could use this link here
to ask that question anonymously if you
are if you don't mind you can just ask
in any of the chats and I will hopefully
get to it and please let me know if the
LinkedIn video worked I don't know why
there's a problem there but for now I
will see you next Wednesday
unless I see you before okay thank you