[Music]
awesome
i love it when uh buttons don't work uh
so we're gonna
today's
uh session is around the idea of user
stories
depending on the level of knowledge that
folks have we'll see
which exercises we do and and what we
don't i have some uh
things that i've prepared and i know
that they're all but they're always fun
even if even if there are sometimes a
bit basic but is getting getting
everybody discussing which is the
important part
uh but the first thing i have here is
just a a fast pass a little introductory
exercise i can see we've got
five participants now that's that's
pretty good a few more we'll drop in
it's 5 30. um so what i'm going to do is
i'm just going to do a little assignment
to rooms
and i'm going to do two rooms there we
go
so i'm going to assign you into into
breakout rooms and on the mural if i
summon everybody i don't think
everybody's there yet but on the mural
um you should be able to see like five
hexagons with numbers in the corner and
if you go to the room
the hexagon which matches your room
number so if you've not used microsoft
teams uh breakout rooms before at the
top of the window for the breakout rooms
it says the name of the room and it's
just room one room two room three right
it's not not super complicated
um and i'd like you to oh tell you what
i probably need to lock all of these
things that would be a good idea there
we go
yeah that's always has a
i i found out anna a really cool tool
for mural
so you know sometimes when you're
dragging around and you end up dragging
an object that you didn't want to or
dragging a post-it around
if you hold down space
it lets you drag without moving anything
without interacting with the surface so
that's that
i learned that
today i think i knew it before but i had
to look up the keyboard command again
all right so we're going to do this this
icebreaker so there's the seven
questions that kind of cut seven
numbered questions in each room so i'm
going to click to open the mural it is
too late to go back now
uh the sorry open the mural open the
breakout rooms it's too late to go back
so they will just open and so make sure
that you access the mural in the
chat
yes there we go
ah
welcome
more
victims
uh
nelly and
mandar oh and erica hey how are you
doing
hello
are you
i'm doing good uh we just
started some initial exercises so i'm
going to pop you into a breakout room do
you have a copy of the mural
awesome
yeah perfect i'm going to put it in the
chat for those that might not have
experienced it
um
uh
naily and amanda are you able to hear me
okay
perfect do you have access to the mural
yeah i put a link in the chat and it
should be on the community page as well
um but i'm going to pop you into a
breakout room with erica
and it'll be breakout room three
so on the ice breaker on the mural erica
will know where that is
uh we can do that okay
so uh
three
and or three and
hell yeah three there we go perfect
so i've uh
turned on the breakout room oh it's not
opened yet that's okay right so now i
can open it there we go i've clicked the
open button so you guys should head into
a breakout room where you can start
answering at those
questions
i'm gonna put
i'll put eight minutes on the timer
because we've had a few minutes there we
go
perfect okay
so everybody's out in the breakout rooms
awesome
i can see people wandering around and
creating well nobody's creating post-its
yet but it's that's part of the fun they
maybe haven't had a lot of experience
with mural
um
i can do this ask to be followed
it's a balance on whether you send
people out right away or you have a
little bit more time to to explain mural
um
unfortunately for these
small workshops it takes
a lot of the a lot of the time
uh for
a live virtual class and we probably
spend i guess up 15 20 minutes just on
here's how all of the tools work and
what we're going to do and how we're
going gonna interact with it but
um
that's great for 15 minutes out of a
two-day class but not great for 15
minutes out of 90 minutes
yeah
so how is everybody today so it's three
four five six seven eight people would
get eight people that's pretty good
um so they're just often there their
breakout looking at these questions and
answers i can see the
the
mouse pointers
moving around for those that are here
and i asked to be followed so that they
went to that that place
um and hopefully they zoomed in
um i use mural for all of these sessions
and i i'm talking to myself but i'm
talking to you if you're watching online
either live or before anybody watching
live
nope just me uh saying we will be
starting soon i don't know if there's a
wickler away from me to see how many
people are actually watching i think i
can look here
let's see
how many of you are actually here
home
channels spinning
nobody
awesome oh no it's refreshing again
i don't know that it can tell on
linkedin so if you're watching on
linkedin or youtube but it should be
streaming on linkedin facebook
but there's none on facebook
none on youtube at the moment but that's
okay
that's okay the purpose of this
is for the people that turn up
not uh for you guys oh look i'm being a
bit
this is why i've ordered a new computer
i have uh ordered an
alienware aurora 13 because i hate
having
lack of processor capability
um so i'm just checking if there's
anything i can close and i can
definitely close
outlook let's get rid of that malarkey
and do i have a browser window here i do
let me kill that that's four browser
tabs gone
there we go
too many devices too many devices not
enough processing power
so they've got a
i'm probably going to close the room oh
it looks like
is sean
on his own
yeah that's the downside of oh no maybe
they are in the meeting are you in the
meeting
um
i'm gonna close the rooms and expire the
timer
bring everybody back
time's up
let me close that and i'm gonna have a
look at what were my questions
what are requirements what are not
requirements
i think at least one
yes anna
uh nothing we were just discussing
i think at least one of you gets stuck
in a room with somebody who left
that always sucks was that you sean
maybe he's gonna off to make a cup of
tea because he was in a room with nobody
that is that is that is okay uh we will
uh progress at forward anyway so i am
interested in some of the ideas that you
you talked about so there are a number
of questions there
in the in the mural
around
what are requirements what they're not
but it really all comes round to that
idea in the middle and of what are your
biggest questions
about user stories
because those answers will help me
figure out what we're going to do for
for the rest of the time
anna
what are your biggest questions around
user stories
i'm all would be the questions i just
don't know but are not requirements i
have no idea here
all other questions are fine
what are not requirements yeah
right because we
for requirements you may have also what
needs to be done the functional the
non-functional requirements but what's
not required
i don't know
honestly
so
um
yeah that's a good question i will come
back to that
erica
did you generate any questions
okay um
first of all um
i don't know uh
that
in general uh not talking about only
requirements but when i
when i start uh
working on a project and then uh going
to
go into the more details with the user
stories uh the main
parts of the questions
are
about the value what are the values
in
whatever we are doing or we're trying to
to
to put in the project so applying
applied to the user storage what is the
value related to
what we are asking for
and uh i don't know maybe your
requirements are you can have a lot of
different requirements functional
requirements
but not only functional requirements
it has to be
transforming something
provable let's say so whenever whenever
we have something that can be can be
shown can be
analyzed that can be
uh
i don't know
uh related to some to some retrospective
or to some feedback is a requirement for
me
okay
you can regard usability functions
but everything has to be that is to have
a value because you don't have a value
related to it you don't
you don't need it so you don't need that
requirement so it's not terrifying for
the project
okay
no no that's that's that's definitely uh
interesting sean
uh
for me it's one of the benefits of using
this story
okay
benefits of user stories
naily
if i'm saying your name wrong just beat
me up that's the best way
well i am like more concerned from
like in the beginning like how
can you start defining your user story
yep like how and how do you set like the
criteria acceptance how do you know
what to include on which on each one
yeah that's that's going to be that's
going to be interesting so like what
what to
hmm yeah how do you start and what to
include
start and
what to include sometimes there's a
different kind of process and i've been
in some teams that they want to add like
all the process in one
only user story so that confused me
okay
yeah you want to stick everything in a
user story so it becomes this massive
massive document of yeah yeah it's too
too big
yeah how do you know when to break down
a user story
that might be an interesting question as
well
yeah
so i uh
morning erie how you doing
well morning might be for you
it's my daughter's
team's name
too long oh but uh yeah
i was using uh my work uh computer last
time but this time i'm just using my my
daughter while
even though she is only seven but from
her school there are still teams that
my daughter uses
they have half their lessons in teams
and half their lessons were in google
classroom
and the teachers booked lessons over the
top of each other because the calendars
weren't in sync
so that was a lot of fun
so i i have a few answers here over on
the right hand side so i'm just gonna
summon i think i already did i'll summon
everybody on the mural are you on the on
the mural i'm
hold on i'm gonna need uh i'm gonna need
to post it because i'm gonna keep
calling you airy if i don't have a
post-it
loan uh yeah i
put my name in the chat
and uh i know it's hard to pronounce but
in fact if you try it it's not hard
no you're long any reason
luckily
no yeah you don't use it
to me yeah perfect it's very very cool
yeah i've now got a little post-it down
here with julong written on it
um
that'll help me out there
i do that all the time for my classes
now because sometimes
people have spellings that i can't
understand or just names i can't
pronounce
all right so you asked the question
and an hour you were concerned with the
question what are not requirements
and i have some things that i don't
think are requirements here a solution
design
is not a requirement
right if you're defining the solution
you've gone way beyond like what do i
need
um a decision about implementation
i guess that kind of goes with a
solution design right it's not decision
about
implementation
and it probably it isn't a definition of
what you're going to get
right i think that's the hardest truth
for organizations to to to handle but it
but it is a reality
um it's not a source of truth for what
the software does
they're not really requirements
if they were requirements
we would have to do them all
but most of the time we don't have to do
them all
right things change
over the life of the project
uh some of the things we do and we don't
need other things
so they couldn't have been required then
if we don't build them
so an expression that um my my good
friend david starr
likes to use is that they are
desirements
stuff we want the product to do
that it doesn't do yet
and sometimes we don't always get what
we want
right that's why that's why i like
desirement
uh that's a little bit better
yeah wishes what we wish
yeah i like i like i like wishes
um
i first
like
what we need to have before starting
with the user story maybe we need to
have a decision how we're gonna do this
requirement this ticket or something
like that
before we start working
and also or
how do you see this
uh could you repeat that sorry
the the first two stickers
into like more uh we need to have that
information before starting with the
implementation of the requirement
yeah so so
we want we want to leave
this
one of the purposes of user stories
right that was one of the other
questions
was uh like why do we want to use user
scores it's because we want to leave the
implementation
till as late as possible
so that we reserve the right to change
our mind
if we have the implementation defined in
the in the requirement in the in in in
the thing that we're being asked to do
that almost always locks us into one
solution
that might not be the right solution
when we get into actually doing it maybe
it's the wrong solution
so i'm i
there are lots of things
that i might
whiteboard
as part of my discussion in the team
right my refinement looking forward into
the future what's coming up next on my
product backlog we're going to have a
bunch of discussions around what these
things are what it might look like
right but we're trying to concern
ourselves with
what
we want to deliver rather than spend too
much time on how
right
so
i think
one of the mistakes that teams make
is they don't necessarily reflect on how
much detail
should be in the how
there's a lot more detail in the how
than people think there is in the how
it's true
right every time a developer has to make
a choice
between a and b
it's usually a business decision choice
that the business doesn't make
the developer makes because it's too
late to go speak to the business now
and that's one of the reasons we have
acceptance criteria
in our um
in our user stories as almost a
codification
of our conversations that we have
right we look at the story it's not
enough information to actually build it
right but it's enough information to
start asking questions and poking at
things but then as we get the answers i
i've sat with a team once uh where
they were asking questions of the
product owner and the product owner was
giving answers and nobody was writing
them down
right and i'm like
what's going to happen at the end of
this sprint the product was going to say
i said
that it should be like this and you're
going to have forgotten 10 minutes after
the
refinement session
by recording the session yeah recording
the session is a good way
right um we i resolved it with that team
by uh i kept
poking them and saying no you need to
write it down and they would go yeah
yeah we will
and i'm like no
write it down now
because you'll forget later or you'll
write it differently later
you won't get a chance to write it down
and then think oh
and i have another question
right
so writing that down recording that
information is really important and one
of the ideas of a user story is that
it's it's a card
right the traditional user story in the
physical world right that we don't often
work in anymore but in the physical
world was a four as a four by three or
six by four
card physical card and on the front you
write what it is you want and you have
to use like a like a sharpie
right so you can't write really small
and then on the back you start writing
down the answers to those questions that
you ask as you start having a
conversation about it
if you run out of space on the cards
it's time for two cards
right
it's time for two cuts but in the
digital space
we've got an infinite amount of
card on every card
so sometimes it's very easy
to see too many things
listed
so when i do exercises with teams on
breaking down backlog items
i normally i'm looking at what they're
creating and if there's more than
four acceptance criteria
i might start giving them a poke and
saying should this be two things
based on the estimation of its story
points it's like it's bigger than eight
then yeah you should consider
making it if you're doing story points
story points are
definitely a complimentary practice and
some people love them and some people
absolutely hate them
and don't feel they have uh value
i'm a little bit in between i i i've
used both ways story points i tend to
track towards more of a kanban strategy
these days
um but lots of people do still use story
points
um and yeah but it's a little bit
arbitrary isn't it it might be an eight
for your team but it might be a 22 for
or 21 for erica's team that's too big to
do inside of a sprint
in my experience uh storyboards never
work
i don't know if i i've been unlucky till
now but it never
works with uh with story points so they
we we make or the development team make
an evaluation and that makes an
evaluation and uh
especially at the beginning of the
project uh
the the
i don't know the solution for uh
for for success for being successful
from the beginning is being clear as you
as you said
i don't know
most of the time the problem is the lack
of
communication between the the customer
and the the developer
yep so i
we
speak different languages
actually so i'm i'm sure i've been clear
and the other two but
at the end so i can make a wonderful
evaluation in story whatever but
actually it's something different uh
from
what we we
both were talking about and
and it's easier when in
managing uh a pro and agile project it's
easier but at the beginning of the of a
project field
in my experiences that has always been a
mess with new people not
uh not used to working with uh with a
jiving
so
story points i don't know if only if
only if the team
it's you he is used to working
very good together he's a very
uh
let's say
very
i don't know the english word but they
they work uh if they've been working a
lot for a lot of time both the class the
customer and the development team of the
world drive team it could be it could
work but
otherwise
story points are
not very
i so i think it it definitely it sounds
like you've been unlucky erica but it
also sounds like anna's maybe been lucky
right that they've been that's that's
okay
um
the way the way i tend to to to look at
story points
is for me there's very little value in
the numbers that's not why i want to do
story points with a team relative
estimation
i want them to have conversations and i
want to encourage them to have
conversations
and one of the ways we have a
conversation is we need to identify
what do i know that you don't
right um and having doing that that
planning poker
exercise
where one team member says oh that's a
that's a that's a two that's super easy
right and another team member says
that's a 21 that's super hard well okay
we've got
somebody knows something that somebody
else doesn't
let's have some conversations around how
do we how do we how do we create how do
we create a cohesive understanding
across the team
and that's something that the the in in
scrum at least the product owner is
accountable everybody's understanding of
the product backlog items and what they
mean is within the accountability of the
product owner so it's in their interests
to generate as much of those
conversations as we need to
not
we're never going to get the exact same
story
from each other of what we think
something is and what it actually is
right because we all understand language
and ideas differently that's part of the
value of working in a team is bringing
those different different perspectives
but we can at least
get to some
um
level of agreement
on on what it is we're looking at how
big is that thing
that for me is the value in in in story
points but lots of people use the
numbers later for their velocity uh
and various things that's that's cool i
prefer the kanban metrics but i do work
with teams that use use velocity just
don't do what one of my teams did which
is sign a contract with the customer
where velocity was specified in the
contract and they had to be within 15
percent of their expected uh don't get
me started on mental things people
putting contracts
um
predicting the future
isn't it
so that that that's why i have this this
this idea of what what are not
requirements and a desirement being an
unenforceable formal expression of hope
that the software will do something
right
uh
i think the feedback loops
in agility that one of the purpose
of the feedback loops specifically
around the the sprint review
is to do that diff between
what did we create and where does the
product need to go next
right because maybe we created something
that wasn't what the users wanted
but was
more was a better way right than what
they expected to get
or maybe it wasn't
right maybe it was exactly what they
wanted and it still wasn't a good way to
build the build the solution
right just because we build what
customers ask for doesn't mean we're
doing the right thing
right i think um
uh one of the other trainers had that
expression day before yesterday i think
you know the the the the fallacy that we
are doing the right thing
if we build what our customers ask us to
build
right that's that's just not true we
should be building what our customers
need
what is the value
right and how do we identify value
values even harder
to identify and work with than than size
right how big are these things that's
easier than what are these things worth
to us
and user stories are trying to
condense it down into something simple
enough and small enough
that it's easier to answer those
questions
that it's easier to answer the question
how big it is and what it's worth
yeah
um
so that
i like the the story around what is a
user story
a card
a conversation and confirmation
right up on what basis are we going to
say that this story is is is complete
but also what does it look like and what
is it we have to have those
conversations
oh
i have a i have a psu issue on my
computer and this one of the screens
keeps going blank and then coming back
that's what happens when dell ships
machines with graphics cards that are
too powerful but not good enough power
supplies dale looking at you
um
so that what sort of techniques
do you use
to write your requirements
how do you make them transparent to your
team where do you put them
well we were using a jira so
just to put uh the description
in the description section uh to
describe what that story is uh talking
about everyone will answer and during
the planning
we will ask each team member where you
need to improve and uh to clarify it so
everyone can
have the ability to take that story so
that's
one of my changes
yeah
vera's jira is a really common tool
in the market it's one of the two it's
one of the two big ones and it it it's
it's huge it usually is driven by the
business because they have a lot of
business support and business tools in
the jira space as well um i do see it a
lot in organizations
anything else
um
also uml
yeah i
well we use uh jiren uh
in my companies uh it's a very powerful
tool but i don't i personally don't
don't really like it it's useful to
to to record
everything about the projects but if you
for the day
daily routine the daily work is not
user friendly i'd say so uh paper
powerpoint for the the daily work i mean
yeah it's
i find it more useful yes you need
something to
record everything especially especially
if you have a big project but
jira is the
the last uh the last thing we
we
update or is a huge if it's a huge
project with a lot of people
called agile but not really agile so
it's uh it i i find it's a very useful
uh tool for a waterfall project so if
it's if it's a small project
during just uh
i think i don't know the essential but
it's not the daily the daily work
is not for the daily work in my in my
personal opinion
depending on the on the size of the team
uml life for a complex for complex new
projects is very useful because it's
very
it's it's not a tool it's uh it's a
it's a methodology it's uh it's very
useful to uh to complex new projects
otherwise uh even the powerpoint is uh
it works
so if
it works for the theme if you don't have
paper because we are going to paperless
support if and then
yeah yeah what jira
jira was originally released in 2002
so the the chances of the teams that
built jira being agile teams at that
time is very low
for the size of organization
so most likely just like tfs team
foundation server and other tools out
there and they're they're they're
waterfall teams building a waterfall
product to support other waterfall teams
because that's their biggest customer
base at the time
and then they're bolting on a bunch of
capabilities to help agile teams
i do know some teams that use trello and
are super happy with it again just do it
simply
um and in fact uh erica i've been toying
around with some teams
of instead of
if you ask anybody in the agile space
what tool should you use
that all they'll do is hold up one of
these post-its in a whiteboard right
uh
cards stick them to the wall right but
we're kind of a little bit beyond that
now
while pre-covered we maybe could have
had that today it's just not going to
happen and that's not going to change
going forward into the future
and so i actually built a board the
other day for uh for a team in a backlog
uh just in mural
right so they they just have them as
cards on the mural and they can move
them around they can delete them they
can create new ones they can put them
anywhere they want there's no
bounds there's no controls over that
which is like having a whiteboard on the
wall
right that sometimes that well apart
from apart from the fact that mural can
integrate with jira let's not go there
right um like that that that to me is
not
that is not a selling point well it can
integrate with github issues as well i
wonder how that actually works let's not
go there um
for example the team's planner which is
very basic but we used it too so
that we didn't have uh
for project access
to morel we used it and it was it worked
that well
yeah sometimes sometimes just using
you might think well there's going to be
a lot of manual work
but the reality is that it just makes
things easier because you can do
whatever you want you're not controlled
by the tool and that's sometimes the
problem with the bigger more complicated
tools is you're you're more controlled
by the tool and then you control it
especially in the enterprise situation
where
um your organization controls
the configuration of your tool
so when i when i run with teams i'm i'm
usually using as your devops that's kind
of my my preferred tool if i'm if i'm
online for for other reasons microsoft's
mvp being one of them um but i i usually
give everybody on the team admin
i make the group
that is
uh for team members that team members
get added to i put it in the
administrators group for for that
project because i don't want them not to
be able to do something if they need to
be able to do it
right everybody should be able to
collaborate together yes
regarding uh like uh
if
like for example three development teams
and they are with one
business team they are going to work
together
and uh for sure the business team they
don't know the devops
right um
yes so i i i i just so i do uh uh uh uh
having a little engagement model where i
do just one hour of consulting for
customers
and and i had somebody
they can just book it on my website
right and this guy booked it i was
interested in what he was doing uh
they're they're using
azure devops
for their entire
business team
and there's no development there's no
software engineering going on at all in
this company
so they're they've got azure devops with
just the work item tracking they've got
everything else turned off
and they're using that with the business
teams and they moved to that from jira
because it's less complicated
right it's there's less baggage
so devops could be used for those
businesses
i'm not saying i'm definitely not going
to say it's a good idea for your teams
right because i don't know your context
just you know trying to learn new things
yeah
so so they they were using it very
successfully and the teams were super
happy the people that were using it the
the managers and leaders in the
organization that were using it were
super happy because it it
sometimes you don't want too many
options
right and sometimes i feel like and that
i am definitely biased against jira okay
so take it as uh how it sounds but
i'm not
happy at all
eric has said that i mean i was just
loved because you guys are not the first
one to see that every time i said that
everyone just felt like an idealism just
to give me this look why you're still
using that jira so because from my top
level yeah
pushed us to you that we have no kid
shows so
they are they are not you know expertise
we have to listen to them so i don't
have to control that so
erica said that okay i i understand but
that's the reality i have to you know
take it so well that's the nice thing
about some of these other tools because
you can integrate with the data without
you know pull the data out that you need
just work with it locally and then have
it pushed back that would be that would
be uh
nice
jira is like sap you you you cannot work
without it but you you
you can
[Music]
you don't have to like it at all
that is that is going to
really get a lot of people's backs up
saying saying saying jira is like sap
i'm not gonna sit here and disagree with
you
uh
but i think it's not quite as bad as sap
he doesn't swear
well
yeah but probable prob that is actually
probably true you're probably right
because it's younger
right um usually usually the younger the
the newer the software the easier and
simpler it is to use and the more it
targets your specific use case
um and i think there's definitely
a trend
towards
smaller tools that integrate with each
other
rather than bigger tool vendors that get
bogged down in
as soon as as soon as one of these these
folks get an enterprise customer
as soon as they get an enterprise
customer you suddenly see all these
features for enterprise users that the
rest of us couldn't care less about
right that bog us down the the ad
functionality or ad constraints
one of my biggest complaints in
microsoft teams right is that companies
can lock down
the way that their team members can use
it so people come into my class and i
teach all of my classes in microsoft
teams and they're like i didn't know it
could do this and i didn't know it could
do that and how come i can use this
feature
right and that's because you're in my
teams and i just turn everything on
there's even i've got one customer it
does make sense but they're the royal
air force in the uk so it's the the the
military and
if everybody in a team's meeting
is from their company
right is their accounts then cameras are
allowed as soon as one person joins the
meeting
that is not from the royal air force all
the cameras turn off
and they can't they're not able to turn
them back on it's automatic
right so that's a security feature
but obviously somebody's asked for it
and i bet i bet there's a company out
there that has chosen to implement that
feature that doesn't need it
right i can understand why a military
would need it if you're using webcams in
the office
right there might be something on the
wall that you don't want people to see
but you know
an oil and gas company doing it
doesn't necessarily make the same level
of level of sense
so one of the things that i think are
really important in user stories and
i
i think this is this is a definitely an
important caveat when we talk about user
stories is that um user stories were
developed
and
it's going to be a little bit weird way
to say it
by telling stories about how users
interact with your system
if users are not interacting with your
system
user stories are probably not the best
solution to your problem
okay
if
if you are if you are not
describing
users accessing your system
then probably using user stories is not
a good idea
right if if if
you're describing how apis interact
because you're building an api that some
development team hooks on to
i don't expect to see user user stories
in your backlog that is not going to be
conducive to writing things in a way
that everybody can understand it
right that's why
how many times is
user story mentioned in the scrum guide
does anybody know
no it's zero
user stories are not mentioned in the
scrum guide story points are not
mentioned in the scrum guide
these things are not mandatory
to be doing agile practices they're just
things that have worked for other people
and they've talked about
right and they may work for us and they
may not within our circumstance user
stories have a particular use case which
is describing interactions
uh so here i've got a a user interface
i'll just summon everybody to it
um
sean do you have a question
uh i was looking at it and i saw it in
the thing which says the acceptance
criteria is optional and scrum
will agree
uh i just want to check
what it what it says because sometimes
we can
definitely read the scrum guide in a way
that inter that triggers our cognitive
bias right we think it says something so
hold on
um
acceptance criteria
are definitely not mentioned in the
scrum guide
and they're not mentioned in the scrum
guide because they have nothing to do
with scrum
you don't need to have acceptance
criteria to be doing scrum you don't
need to have user stories
typically acceptance criteria
generally are paired with user stories
but not exclusively right having
acceptance criteria a way of writing
down and noting the conversations that
we've had oh awesome we've got another
visitor another helper
um having those
i we i couldn't hear uh
i couldn't hear
um so having having those uh uh
conversations um so i do not believe
that acceptance criteria are mandatory
for anybody if you think they're a good
idea and you think they add value to
your team
and add understanding
use them
if they don't
don't
okay
how do we
relate the
acceptance criteria to the definition of
done how wrong am i
very wrong definitely very wrong uh so
that that is a i i i common uh um
a common conflation between those two
things
so
acceptance criteria are to do with the
requirements
right acceptance criteria go on the
requirements definition of done is about
the quality
of what it is you're creating so
regardless of what it is that we deliver
it all must meet the same quality level
um but that's a really common one i
actually spent probably an hour and a
half today talking about that with
product owners uh and i've got there's a
if you want to dive a little bit more
detail there's a recording of was it the
definition of done workshop anna
so there should be a recording on my uh
um youtube channel uh with a definition
of done workshop and we talked
at length um about that specific
scenario and we did uh an exercise some
exercises around
um creating a bakery
right so we had erica's bakery
and at erica's bakery we had uh some
products that were creating and then we
had a definition of
it done and how we kept them separate so
i would go watch that
um
it will hopefully
we had one hour
session offline just on that yeah yeah
it's it's it's it's one of those things
there are there are there are so many
things
that
i i'm always surprised at the number of
scrum trainers out there who have never
read the scrum guide
right
and and get some of those things mixed
up so it's not surprising everybody else
does that's okay right
um but we just need to figure out how do
we how do we put those things uh
together
i spend more time talking about what's
not in the scrum guide than what is most
of the time
right no you don't have to do it that
way but the scrum guide says we should
no it doesn't go look
right
um so
uh
i've got a little uh a picture here of
up
it's a recipe website
right um i actually i i stole this from
my good friend david starr again i think
he did it at a conference uh but i have
a recipe box and there's a list of
recipes and you can enter ingredients
sorry that's a recipe and you can add
ingredients to the recipe and then you
can add some notes for cooking
right so it's it's fairly fairly fairly
straightforward but if we were to start
creating user stories one of the best
places to start is to draw the user
interface that you're going to talk
about draw it on the whiteboard
right what is this thing we're creating
what does it look like
and then you need to start having
conversations about it
right what are the things that we expect
users to do with this
uh so where's my where's my user stories
there we go i have a couple of user
stories down here
so here's my um
three user stories that i've created
as a recipe seeker
i want to search by tag values so i can
find recipes
ad hoc
as a recipe recorder
i want to tag my recipes so i can find
them via ad hoc tags
and as a recipe seeker i want to search
by recipe ingredient
so that i can find recipes for the
ingredients i have
all right so those are a bunch of
different scenarios
right there it's just
definitely a limited s
i can come up with about 10 more for
that scenario for that page but
is a limited set of scenarios
but did you notice
that it doesn't say as a user
in these scenarios it gives the user
purpose as a recipe
seeker a recipe recorder
there's two different personas
there two different mission statements
that that user has
and on the left hand side i've got
recipe recorder chef recipe seeker cook
with existing ingredients
right
might be a a scenario be as specific as
you can
and i see in some organizations they
might name a specific person if they're
a known person within the organization
right
the cto wants something that they
interact with or the cfo
wants something and in other other
groups
microsoft
used to have back in their waterfall
days
they used to have posters
up on the wall in the offices with who
the target users were for some of their
products
so you literally had a poster that had a
picture of somebody um and it said their
name ellen i think ellen
ellen the
something tester
right so this is for microsoft test
tools
and it had a little story about ellen
and who she was and what she was trying
to do with the product
so that
the developers could connect
empathetically to that story and get
themselves into the mindset of ellen and
what she's trying to achieve so when i'm
building features i'm thinking about
what does ellen need
and this is the same here what does a
recipe recorder okay so i'm in the
mindset of i'm adding stuff to this
system
what do i need to to to be able to do or
risk be seeker i'm looking for stuff
right you're adding context there
so not just the user that would be a
very uh a
cheap way to do it
so you've got as a user
some type specific
i want
what is it what's the user's goal
right and then why do they want to
achieve that goal
because that might add some additional
uh
context to your story
yeah so that's the typical makeup of
some user stories there
is that
how you've seen them used
or have you seen them differently
anna is this what your user stories look
like
some of them some of them right
not all
i also like in the user story to have
like the
business purpose like while we are doing
this
maybe linking to some greater purpose
yeah yeah like what do we want to
achieve with this yep and then maybe
it's nice to have this the the who the
what the why yep and after that the
acceptance criteria but there is no
people to write that
that's the problem yeah
so so um
this is not the whole thing
but this is this is this is the user's
story
bit of the user story
right when we think of user story as the
thing we might have more stuff
associated like each each if we were
putting these each in jira right
or gyra depending if you're in the u.s
or europe right um
then perhaps
perhaps this image that we have
of the user interface that we're
creating it for is attached to those
items to give them context
right oh well i've got this specific
thing okay but what's what's the context
within which it's working well it's this
is the user interface we're trying to
create
or this is the business proposition that
we're trying to fulfill that's okay we
can have that additional information
that's going to add value
right but the idea behind user stories
is keeping it really simple and concise
so that it encourages you
to create more of them
right lots of discrete elements that are
very independent
we didn't talk about it but um we
usually try and encourage it's not
perfect the invest
model
if you're not familiar with the invest
model um
your your things on your backlog
it could be independent
negotiable testable valuable estimatable
and small
i think i did that in the wrong order
but there we go
um i can't spell either so that solves
that problem
so we need to be they need to be small
enough that we can do them small enough
that we can estimate them right do we
understand it enough to estimate it
can we test it if we can't test it it's
going to be very difficult to validate
that we completed it or not is it
negotiable
none of these things are set in stone
nothing on your backlog is set in stone
it's about the future it's a description
of the future we would like
right but maybe the future we get needs
to be different from what we would like
to have
and needs to be independent so we
minimize dependencies
so if you do have dependencies maybe it
needs broken down into smaller things
right and then the last one was valuable
if it's not valuable don't build it
right so understanding value is super
important
but what does value mean to
your product owner to your business
that's something that for example scrum
is not going to tell you
it's just not going to give you that
answer there's lots of different ways to
determine value
but it's going to be unique to your
business what does it mean to your
business
[Music]
i think that one
originally from uh it's called invest
right yeah invest
it's for the the an acronym that the
letters spell uh i have a different uh
view of that here let me grab this
because
um i was good i had it all set out to do
a little workshop if we had lots of
people turn up but sometimes
he loves my workshops
okay
so yeah this is the the
[Music]
the way you would look at it
negotiable valuable estimatable
small and invest
right and the idea is it's simple to
understand
um and the the other there's other
options
right uh i'm gonna gonna give you
two other options that you can use
at july
nasa
nasa has their model
right their model is complete consistent
correct modifiable ranked traceable
unambiguous and verifiable
but try explaining that to your mom
that's going to be difficult isn't it
right yes
another one is the the ieee requirements
ieee
uh interfaces functional capability
performance levels data structures and
elements safety reliability security
privacy quality constraints and
limitations
also super easy to understand not
right
we're not dealing with engineers all the
time
the engineers are not the only ones that
have to understand the things on your
backlog
right the stakeholders need to be able
to understand it the way the way i
normally explain it
is
anybody who understands your product
domain your business domain
should be able to understand your
backlog
if your business domain is building apis
right
i would expect that level of complexity
in your backlog if your business domain
is building user interfaces right that
that your average person can use
then i would expect that level of
understanding to be required to read
them
right because our stakeholders should be
able to understand what it is we're
creating
because we're might be spending some of
their money
right
you don't want to bamboozle them with
with lack of understanding
so
that's just part
of a user story do i have the the
other thing that i wanted it's maybe not
in here let me pop over here
yeah
so we start off
um
with our our our user stories so there's
the three user stories that we had and
then we start to have conversations
right so if you think about this this
this user interface
here that i have
you know when i click on the home page
link
what happens
right
can we can we sort the columns on this
data grid
is that a thing we're gonna do
if there's if we don't enter any
ingredients can you click the add button
if so what happens
right these are all
business decisions they're not actually
technical decisions
the business should decide that
yes the add button should be disabled if
there's no text in there
or
does the add button enabled and we click
it and it does a model dialog that says
you have not entered anything click ok
right because that would be really
annoying
yeah but
you've we've all used interfaces like
that haven't we
that do things in a way that you're like
why would you do it that way
often it's because nobody thought about
it and the person doing the work made
the choice
because nobody told them what the answer
might be they don't have any way to ask
user stories are trying to
create that conversation so we start
engaging with our stakeholders engaging
with our business engaging with our uh
product owners right
what happens when you click the cancel
button and you've got stuff filled out
i've clicked cancel buttons and apps and
it disappears and i'm like oh really you
didn't ask me if i wanted to lose that
information
right
simple stuff like that what happens
right so here's a here's a one of one of
those specific
items as a recipe recorder
i want to tag my recipes
so i can find them via ad hoc tags
right so then we've got some questions
specific to this item
does this happen when i'm entering the
recipe
like where the heck am i doing these
tags
what about really really big tags
what's the maximum length of a tag
what about short ones can i have a one
letter tag is that okay
right
what about spaces how we're gonna handle
spaces in this tagging system
all right these are all questions that
engineers will ask
if you let them
right sometimes they you need to wind
them up to get them started but you'll
you'll get these sorts of questions once
you get people going in these events so
then then
do we just we could just write that
write the answers the questions and the
answers on the on the story
but maybe these are a little bit too
ambiguous
for our engineers because we all know
how engineers love specificity
right i could see geelong's an engineer
we like we like things to be bullying
propositions i'm either doing it right
or i'm not
right
and you you
if you're a product owner
you will get often maybe incredibly
annoyed and frustrated with your
engineers for being pedantic
they're not being pedantic they just
want to know the answer
right do you want it this way or that
way it should be a red button or a green
button
because that might be important to you
right left hand side of the page or
right hand side of the page well i just
put it somewhere
right but we're asking those questions
because they're choices we have to make
when we're building the product
so here is two of those
answers
written as scenarios
scenarios are a good way to write
acceptance criteria that helps us
be a little bit more specific on what it
is we mean when it happens and how it
happens
so here we've got the three character
minimum
given a tag value of less than three
characters when it is entered then it is
not saved and the user is alerted about
the tagline
there's quite a lot of information in
there isn't there quite a lot of answers
right that's describing how it works
describing the behavior of the product
these are business cases
given it yes
it's also kind of related with the
tester and the test cases
so
okay so one of one of the problems that
we run into
is that we end up testing quality in
rather than building it in
user stories and
scenarios
are about let's let's figure out upfront
what the product is supposed to do
because what what typically happens
right i'll give you a typical thing
is the developers go off and decide what
they think the product should do
the testers go off and decide what they
think the product should do
and then the testers run their tests
against what the developers have done
what typically happens
right it doesn't doesn't doesn't match
up
so this this technique is around test
first yes
maybe you should have testers involved
in these conversations and they're going
to ask other conversations that a
software engineer might not make
yes
yeah we're going to build these things
together acceptance criteria
right for me
i guess being the the
julong and i being the pedantic ones
right
the the the the that acceptance criteria
is the criteria by which you will agree
that we've built what you asked for
acceptance criteria on what basis will
you accept this
so if we if we can wiggle that
acceptance one of my favorite acceptance
criteria is from an exercise that i run
for teams and it says be generally
attractive
for a website what the hell does that
mean
right be generally attractive well
what's attractive for you what's
attractive for me they're different
things right i've used some
i've built some god awful websites that
i could say well okay i could agree it's
generally attractive
right it's not as ugly as it could be
so what's the difference between
acceptance criteria and scenario
the way the way you write it
though just the way you write it so an
acceptance quite sepsis criteria i would
normally see written as just bullet
point statements
yeah build point statements or
checkpoints right um scenarios are
let's take that bullet point statement
and write it in a way that we're
specifically seeing what behavior we
want to see
so one of the advantages of scenarios is
there are a bunch of tools out there
that can turn these into tests
automatically not completely
automatically we still have some work to
do
and but there's a spec flow i've used in
the dot net world where you can write it
like this and it generates the stubs for
unit tests that then developers fill out
the tests and if they pass we
it does that
right so there are tooling around that
but even just having it written like
this
julong was looking about at this going
yeah that's how i want it written
so that i know what i need to build
because again these are business
decisions
if you don't do that
then
who's going to decide what happens when
you enter a tag of less than three
characters but hit the save button
anyway
julong and i are gonna decide we're
gonna build it however we think it
should look
but are these two scenarios also
could be uh considered as true
exceptional criteria
yeah i
i would say that that that's
we're
using a technique for writing acceptance
criteria called scenarios that's the way
i would look at it
right so we can take our oh what's that
one
yeah okay
so we can we take our our our
user interface
we draw it
and then we start creating user stories
and for each user story we start
creating scenarios
what happens if you had 10 scenarios on
an user story
you'd be thinking that's too big
right that sounds like this is a really
complicated thing maybe i want to break
it down into two user stories maybe it's
fine the way it is
but it enables you to start building
that out
so the exercise that i do with teams to
help them
with this
is i go i go through some kind of
exercise like this where we're
we talk about invest and we talk about
scenarios and how you would write them
right
and then i get them to draw
a user interface that already exists in
their product
so just draw something that already
exists in your product
build the user stories and scenarios you
would have liked to have
to build it correctly so you're using
hindsight you already know what you had
to do
and you have you have everybody together
that you need so product management
developers testers who do you need to
tell that story
build out the user stories and scenarios
and if you're you're running that with
your team
you can go around and you can poke at
something and say you know i
is that the right user there or um
there's quite a lot of scenarios on that
is this quite big how big do you think
this is well it's ginormous okay you
want to break it down into multiple user
stories then you can encourage them to
do that
and then they end up with here's the
level of detail
that would have built
the right thing
that you ended up with
right yes
a lot of focus on what you said i mean
it could be considered as epic
and then
it could be invited right yeah but it's
just a picture
yeah it's just it's just a picture and
then you're you're breaking it down but
then the second part of the exercise so
once you've done that and they've you
know um i guess in in in in britain you
would say um and add you know they've
kind of you've they've thought about how
much details involved in this and how
and they're like yeah yeah this is the
right level of detail this would have
answered all of those questions so you
get them to to kind of review it and
talk about it
you send them off for lunch
right and then when they come back
because it's lunch time already right
when they come back
you you you
get them to take a user interface of
their product backlog
something that doesn't exist yet in your
product
and you say right
let's build some user stories
let's break this down let's create
something that we can
understand what this thing is that we've
made the business decisions that we need
to make
and they'll be surprised at how
difficult one how difficult it is
how much they don't know
about the things on their backlog
and then at the end once they've built
all of that and they see how much is
there you're like awesome this is how
refinement works
right this is exactly the type of level
of detail you want to be coming out of
refinement with to add to your backlog
so that the teams can take it and go
build it
and it's a lot more work than people
think it is
right they think that you can just write
something down give it to developers and
then go build something but that never
results in the right thing
we've got to have more conversations and
user stories
uh uh a a statement
a
car sorry card
a conversation and confirmation
is how we start down that journey
right if you think about the evolution
of a user story
you might put stuff on your backlog
that's really far down with just a title
like a little placeholder what's this
thing it's attached to anna's business
case right
and you go oh here's all the things we
don't really know what they are yet but
here's all the things
and then as they get closer to being
done
you know we the product owner goes in
and goes right this is what that user
story is and this is what this other one
is maybe gets the team together and
whiteboards out
the ui so we attach the ui to it
we've built out some user stories and
then as it gets closer to the top of the
backlog closer to being ready right
we we then go in and we start talking
about scenarios and build out the
scenarios turning any acceptance
criteria into scenarios having more
conversations about it
till that thing is ready
and then we can walk into sprint
planning
and we know what that thing is we
understand what the business problem is
we're trying to solve how complex it is
how many bells and whistles we need to
have on it
and then we as the engineers you know
the team taking it on can then just
worry about the implementation problem
they're not doing the implementation and
deciding all of the business choices
just let's just do the business problem
and then
we can figure out if we built the right
thing afterwards
yeah but i also think that we should be
careful and maybe have the input from
developers because it might the user
story be kind of big with a lot of
scenarios but to be easy to develop
like
maybe we'll spend more time in writing
it down instead of developing so um
definitely a thing you have to figure
out based on and this would be based on
your team the product owner the business
the context
is how much detail do we need
in our in our product backlog
right and the scrum answer is as much as
you need and no more because if you do
too much like anna's saying it's waste
right you oh you spent all this time on
something that's very straightforward
right so trying to find that balance
yeah i think you you understand that uh
i know by experience yeah experience
both on the business side and
development side it's easier because you
know what the pro what the main problems
are well of course book size
yep at the beginning it will be
complicated but
and mock-up definitely
works
when
drawing
throwing something and
making a stretch to
to make everybody understand for example
if it's something very new because
it's easy to
to understand for for the business side
and well the developers know the the
tricky parts and well it's up to the
team and then to avoid discussing about
that because it could be a strategy if
uh if the development team is not is is
trying to to sell to sell something to
the
to the to the customer but if in theory
it's not the case if you're in a in a
scram team so
yeah and yeah i agree it comes with
experience sometimes you'll do too much
work
and go oh that was actually super easy
when we get something like that next
time we'll not bother doing all that all
that work yeah so there's going to be a
little bit of waste at the smart start
as but it's not really waste it's
learning right we're learning at that
experience but always be careful about
the written words and i have a little a
little example here just to to to drive
that home um a little statement here
that you might have seen on any menu
i as an engineer
don't know what that means
i'll tell you why
because it could mean this
or
it could be this
couldn't it
right the written word
sucks for specificity
i may or may not get bred with my choice
depending on which one it is
right
yeah so so so take that take that into
account
right my favorite engineering joke
julong
is uh i'm gonna i i want you to go to
the go to the local shop
and i'd like you to buy a loaf of bread
and if they have eggs
buy six
julong's laughing because he's gonna
come back with six lots of bread if
they've got eggs
right
because that's that's that's
an exact interpretation of what was said
and
one of the reasons that a lot of
engineers gravitated towards coding is
because they have that mindset for
direct interpretation rather than
you know oh but i said it this way why
didn't the computer do it well it's
because you didn't actually see it that
way you said it this other way because
of the specificity
so sometimes we want lots of specificity
and sometimes it's okay for things to be
vague
but finding out where that balance is
for your team for your context will be
different
uh
and figuring it out is i think
part of the fun of building products
right it keeps it different every time
you're doing something and that that
um
feeling of figuring it out is part of
what makes a team
gives them empathy with each other and
uh
builds that that amazing presence
so
also the unwritten user stories for
example about the performance
if something somebody from the business
works for the first time or a project we
would probably never ask about
performance which is crucial
so uh either the
the development team the development
experts asked ask you about
performance or they they decide maybe
they want to decide because the
performance is normally
the most one of the most complicated
parts especially if the project is huge
so uh the the business has to know
that
that he has to
it has to to ask about uh performance or
just or
talk about performance yeah well it
but it yeah that's definitely one of
those things that the business very
rarely asks about
until they get it and performance sucks
and by that time it can often be too
late
to fix some of the performance issues
because they're endemic to the to the to
the way the product's been architected
and it's a big deal to change it yeah
absolutely um and that that that for me
is where
conversations around definition of done
come in
right so we we have a conversation on
what's the minimum level of quality we
need and one of the questions on that is
testing how much
functional testing do we need this much
what about performance testing oh
okay every page must respond within
you know
500 milliseconds
okay now we have a performance metric to
how many users do we have to support
oh as many as we like well we can't do
that
right we can't do as many as you like
you have to pick a number and we're
gonna measure based on that
okay 200 simultaneous users awesome now
i've got 200 simultaneous users 500
milliseconds i can put that on my
definition of done and run it as part of
everything we do
and then we'll always have that yeah
yeah you gotta ask those questions
and i've i actually um worked on a team
where our performance test
was everybody in the room opening the
webpage and then somebody shouted go
right to refresh or run the report and
see how many people it could run at once
yeah
no automation whatsoever
uh uh so that that you you want to be
able to build all of those things into
the
into the solution but if you don't have
the conversation
you won't ask about it
yeah i think that's why i
i related the definition of that to the
access requirements for me the
acceptance requirements has
a lot to do with crawl literally yeah
one
now i i understand your points it's uh i
completely agree with you but i think
that's
the acceptance the acceptance criteria
always has to be have to be
something
to do with the with the quality because
without the quality the it's it's
it's very difficult to
go watch go watch the definition of done
workshop because we we we talk about
specifically talk about why having
acceptance criteria on the definition of
done is a bad idea
it sounds like it would be a good idea
sounds like it would be a good idea but
it's actually a bad idea because it
locks us into scope again we spent all
this time in scrum trying to be flexible
on scope but then we must meet
acceptance criteria and suddenly we're
locked into
into scope again
well we are we are uh pretty pretty
close to uh at time
um
this was a little bit different format
because we only had a few people we did
a little bit of a different format where
we we basically just talked for
uh an hour and a half with some with
some help in the mural so hopefully this
was useful
for you as well
um if there's any uh feedback
that you have i would love it to get any
outstanding questions unanswered
questions because we can have other
sessions
not next week the week after next
uh we have a session on daily scrum
that anna is going to going to lead i
have seen some of the early early
workshop ideas and it looks pretty
pretty good
um so the idea is to to hit some of the
events in scrum and how they would work
i think we did
did we do sprint planning or did we did
sprint review i think we did sprint
review didn't we yeah and we did sprint
review before uh so we're gonna
yeah you want planning on the list anna
yeah we can definitely put planning on
the list
uh to have a a discussion around
planning and how it how it how it might
we might make it more effective that's
always
um
a whole point the whole point of the
scrum master is to help make everything
more effective
our working together
our delivery of software make everything
more effective
so
i am very tired i have spent four days
this week full days training
from nine till five so my brain is
pretty much dead
um
are there any uh
questions before oh ebm is on the list
and nexus
oh yes the elephant in the room scaling
if you've been me yeah yeah if you've
been following my linkedin i think i've
been pooping all over skate scaling
frameworks recently along with some
other folks but
um
there are definitely things that can
that we can do in scaling to help be
more effective so we could definitely
have a scaling talk
in fact uh for why so today
marking and since you have so many uh
exercises that we didn't do maybe you
can have the second workshop regarding
story oh well that's that's interesting
yeah i think that is just a waste if you
don't use this
exercise i found they are very
interesting i mean you might need to
continue to do that right people
some of them yeah
another we got our visitor back
some of them like the like the circuit i
i had a an invest
circuit
um you kind of you kind of need at least
er er er three or four groups for that
so we really didn't have enough people
um but
we had lots of interesting conversations
which i think is
well i think is still valuable so what
else did we put on the list sprint
planning technic manage technical debt
with scrum
hmm
that's an interesting one
in theory it doesn't exist but
so
sure but
yeah
i
remember
workshop i heard
you
i think it was
organized by boston
the boston agile community
which you you talk you talk
yes i did i did
to know something more about that
because i thought i found your
your idea very interesting
i don't even remember what i talked
about i don't even remember the topic to
be honest
but i remember doing it
what was the topic
i think it was
talking about the development uh
in devops okay yeah what was it yeah
okay
it was a couple of years ago maybe i
don't think it was that long ago i think
it just seems i'm pretty sure it was
this calendar year
boston agile
martin i think you would that'll
probably not get it but we'll see oh
uh
agile boston ah yes i did i did the
enterprise transformation that shows
that you can too
that's what i did
it was in june this year it was in june
this year
yeah june this year lock down
means we have no idea about time anymore
it's just
gone
yeah yeah not this year for sure last
year totally
so um
no no 21
june 2021 i have it here
really yeah yeah really
i just put i just put the link to it in
the
here's the link to it on agile boston
yes i thought it was this year
right um but anyway i have copies of
that uh same presentation that i've done
on my youtube channel um and i think
there's four or five different versions
because i've done it at a number of
conferences around the world and they've
recorded it and i've also done it
just online um but it's telling for for
those that don't know it's telling um
the microsoft azure devops story of how
they transitioned to agility
and and all of the things that they had
to consider and change
um so
i don't remember i think i had an hour
and a half for this one so i had plenty
of time
but sometimes people give me like half
an hour for that half an hour's not
enough for that talk you get through
about a quarter of the content uh but uh
yeah so that's that's quite a good
that's quite a good story um and yeah i
i
if you have a specific thing from that
story you want you want to do a workshop
on we can definitely do that
but there's a lot of things in it a lot
of things in it
some of the topics so you you introduce
there because they're super interesting
if you if you pick the topics we can put
them on the backlog
of that the how you manage the technical
but i i i remember you talked about uh
uh an overlap but not an overlapping
screens but it's a
to a pool dedicated to the technical
debt but you didn't expect you didn't
have the time yeah we were
you're you're you're you're right and it
was like it was less just technical debt
but it was the the um
uh
sre
so site reliability engineering
is a technique that was developed at
google
um originally developed at google but
microsoft have adopted it and changed it
slightly for their for their world
um but the way
they do it was they had dedicated
members of the team
who were the site reliability
development
engineers some they had some and that
crazy an acronym for it
um
but they effectively had a dual role of
delivering from the sre
backlog so the live site issues
backlog dealing with live site issues so
that you protected the team so they
could focus on value and then that
rotated through the team
so that you didn't have one person
annoyed at that yeah that's that's i
actually erica if you look on
um my youtube channel i think i've got a
talk
just on that topic from that team
ah perfect
i'm pretty sure i'm pretty sure i've got
one on my youtube channel
thank you if i don't let me know and i
can make you make you one
last question yes
any advice how we should deal with um
with receive tickets from customers
because for sure they will not have this
structure of the users
so that this mean that
each ticket should be reworked
or
so that that is
i i would probably not want tickets from
customers going directly on my backlog
i as a product owner i'm going to look
at that those tickets
and because there's a there's if that
ticket goes directly on my backlog
there's an assumption that i'm doing it
and i might choose not to do it
okay there might be something the
customer says i really need this to work
this way or i think you've delivered a
broken product when in actual fact we
it's the way we built it is deliberately
that way
or
um they they have a bug
but it only affects one customer it's a
big deal to fix
maybe maybe it's not worth our time and
effort to fix right
so so i don't want to have that
assumption
but i think
having a place where i can see all of
the user tickets and then break them
down into things that go on my backlog
i'm
i'm pretty good with that
um but i don't want i definitely don't
want a one-to-one relationship because
one user ticket might turn into five
backlog items or
you know
it could be it could be
various things that that it doesn't have
to be a one-to-one relationship
maybe i don't know
what what are you doing just now
one to one
and what about if they're really really
big
specific official system for
receiving these tickets we have two
because
but uh in jira we can split in different
one and just relate them well yeah
that's that's that's okay so the way
i've seen so microsoft for a while used
uh user voice
right so not just tickets so user voice
was for not for support tickets but for
uh i would like
right the customers desirements could go
on user voice and everybody could vote
on them and then they would filter the
ones that they wanted you to do into the
system
and they have a separate support ticket
uh that i think probably does the same i
mean it ends up on somebody's list and
then it's approved to go into the team's
backlog
um
yeah yeah
because
it also depends on the vision for the
product so not every requirement should
be accepted yeah
well thank thanks uh uh you long
good to see you again
yeah see you next time thank you
thank you bye
so so yeah i i i i i agree and if if
it's working for you and it doesn't get
too overwhelming then that's okay but i
can imagine
if if your product has a lot of users
and you get a lot of tickets it could be
somewhat overwhelming having the tickets
coming in like that
yeah we kept that okay yeah the backlog
is huge so
but yeah we'll see how we're gonna do
remember lean inventory control for your
back clock
right if you've got too many things on
your product backlog the product owner
can't know everything so if their
accountability is maximizing the value
it can be very difficult to find it
right like a needle in a haystack
right where where's the value i don't
know because there's 5 000 things in the
product back clock
um so definitely
apply some sort of lean inventory
control
right you want a minimum stuff in there
but just what you need maybe what you've
got is what you have to have
right but maybe it could be less
easier to understand or
yeah i don't like the idea of having two
backlogs but i also like the idea of
having too many things in one backlog
less
so maybe triage
yeah
yeah triash
because there might be some duplicates
also
yeah
and then it's hard once the duplicates
get into your back club because now it's
polluted
yeah and trying to trying to find them
afterwards as a nightmare
yeah
you're very welcome anna
cool
so uh will we wrap it up there
and
um i get to
to go get some get some sleep
that would be good
um so thank you very much for
for for coming today
and next week it'll be more popular
cause anna will be there and we're going
to talk about
the daily scrum
not next week the week after next it's
every two weeks
brains yeah
okay
so hopefully see you then thank you
all right thank you very much
[Music]
you