a hugely important technique for any
implementation of a cand strategy is to
visualize your work right you need to be
able to see what's going on you need to
be able to visualize that I'm a big user
of aure devops I know jira has these
features as well um but being able to
visually see your cards moving across
the board the the units of value we
don't really care about tasks at this
point right but your smallest unit of
value to see see them flow across the
board see where things are so if
somebody asks you oh where's this what's
that what's going on with this is it's
very obvious where and what it is
um that
visualization while super important is
actually super difficult to create
because we generally make assumptions as
a team about what each other think the
system is
okay so I'll think the system works like
this and another team member will think
it works like that but we'll think we're
on the same page we'll think we
understand each other on how the system
works but because we've never sat down
and had that conversation about how this
system works then we don't uh think
think about I I have a I don't know if
you've noticed but I kind of like board
games um if you were to take any one of
these board games off my shelf and throw
away the rule book and get four people
together to um decide they're each going
to decide how they're going to use the
pieces and move them around in order to
get points and then you're going to work
together to solve the problem that is
the board game you pick a Cooperative
one but we don't agree what the rules
are then how could we possibly have a
successful game right we're not all
playing the same game because we all
have not agreed what the rules are
that's why games come with a rule book
the first part of implementing a cand
strategy is you need to write your rule
book what are the rules of your system
how are you going to decide how things
work so even one of the first decisions
is what are we going to visual ize on
this what we actually going to put on
the board is it only things on our
backlog or is it bugs as well what is it
that's going to go on there and how does
it move through this system so creating
uh uh that visualization is super
important so what what I recommend that
you do is uh do a do a workshop get
everybody together sit down and just
build a board whether you're building it
in aure devops or you're building it in
um jira or Trello or just pop open mural
or Myro and use a digital whiteboard
right totally free
form make the decisions write the notes
and document your system how does your
system work and agree as a team when you
find differences on how your system is
supposed to work then at the very
least even if we've still got a system
that might not be optimal right because
this is where we are right now this is
what we're doing right now we at the
very least have a system that we all
agree is the same
system right because if we want to play
together we want to play as a team and
we want to be successful together we
need to Define what those things are we
need to Define how the system works and
we all need to be playing in the same
system if you're struggling
uh to decide how your system works and
create a definition of workflow then we
can help you we provide worldclass
camand training from Pro caman as well
as Consulting and coaching for teams
trying to implement a cand strategy if
you're a scrum team then we always
recommend bringing in flow metrics as a
complimentary practice and have cbang
classes from scrum the door