governance is important for
organizations to function safely too
many organizations if if you've got
extremely high levels of governance
within your organization you're probably
have going going to have a great deal of
difficulty taking advantage of
opportunities and dealing with surprises
right a surprise something that goes
wrong in the market or your organization
or your product or whatever it is is
going to take a long time and be much
more expensive to fix than it needs to
be um now that doesn't mean that you
can't do something because most
government governance is
self-imposed I'm going to explain that
because um it's something that I've seen
time and time again so in in most
organizations um especially if you're
siloed so if you have a governance
Department right this is even more true
um just like if you have Security
Department you've weird security
decisions there's uh this idea of local
optim optimization rather than system
optimization okay so sometimes when you
look at just one thing and you make a
change or make a fix for that one thing
you're actually making a change that's
better for this one thing but it breaks
something overall in the organization
right so I I I really say
example is let's say you have a a cog in
a
machine and you're looking just at this
Cog and it's slow to turn because it's
pushing against all these other cogs in
the system um what would make this the
most efficient Cog possible well if we
delete all the teeth from the Cog then
it can just spin
freely but now it no longer drives the
rest of the system it's no longer part
of the rest the system right we've made
a local optimization that that makes
this better but it doesn't doesn't help
us overall and that that's what often
happens when governance is a separate
department when governance is a a group
of people in an I'm going to say Ivory
Tower because the architecture one is is
very close to that but in an ivory Tower
and they're making decisions about
governance for the sake of governance
they're not making decisions about
governance to provide value Safety and
Security to the organization they're
doing it for the sake of governance and
what you find often happens is they take
the externally imposed regulatory
governance that you might be required to
meet right there might be government
regulations there might be industry
regulations there could be Hippa there
could be FDA there could be whatever the
things FAA whatever regulations you come
under socks audit right being one socks
audit is a great example
um and they don't what you're supposed
to do to meet a socks audit is you're
supposed to do the absolute minimum that
it says in order to meet a socks audit
so for example you have to be able to
trace uh who did what in the
system but it doesn't have to be easy to
trace who does what it just has to be
traced so writing a log file
for example is is
adequate if you have to go look it up
because you're being audited or because
something's gone wrong you can you can
look it up right it might cost you a
little bit more for that one time but
overall it costs you a lot less because
you don't have to build any systems
around maintaining the audit logs being
able to query the audit logs all of that
stuff is time and expense you don't need
so socks audit the people who created
the socks audit expect you to do the
absolute minimum you need to meet that
minimum bar which is the socks audit but
that's not what happens in organizations
what happens is over zelous and maybe
I'm bringing in a little bit of bias
there but overzealous compliance
folks think about well if this is the
minimum bar then we should be here right
we should be much higher than than the
minimum bar to protect ourselves but
that's not true you only need to meet
the minimum bar to protect yourselves
that's it you've met the compliance
right and that means that there's lots
of things that you do in organizations
that don't have to be there or don't
have to be like that fantastic example
is I worked with an organization I try
to remember where it was somewhere
somewhere in the US and and they had a
huge a big compliance need um so much so
that every meeting that we had the the
notes all get sent off to compliance and
then feedback came back and that kind of
thing so we were talking about my level
five we were talking about all those
things and the compliance folks uh were
getting a bit ansy because we were
moving from their old system to team
Foundation server and they wanted to
have change request uh logs they wanted
to have all of those things so I
invited compliant to the event where I
was talking about how the system worked
and in as your devops it
maintains um every value of every
variable that ever was on on a work item
every field the full history of that
field is maintained it's never lost um
it's never overwritten it's never it's
just it's always available and I talked
about that and the team was saying yeah
but we have to have this change request
work item the compliance person was at
the back of the room sitting working
away just listening and I just asked
them directly it is this good enough to
meet the compliance and they were like
yeah no problem that's
great that works so we just
removed the whole need for change
request work items for they had other
documents and assets that were around
that story of change requests that we
know longer
needed because we met the compliance
without
them and this company had been doing
them for for years so there's all sorts
of organizational crft that builds up up
so you want to think about lean
governance lean governance lean
procurement lean processes is there any
waste in the system you want to think
about organizational hygiene right what
do you need to do on IR regular Cadence
to minimize cuz some sometimes you know
we create we think something looks a bit
scary so we create a policy for it um
and then it's not actually that scary
but the policy still exists and then
another policy gets bolted on and
another policy gets bolted on so we need
to go through of organizational hygiene
where we divest ourselves of waste right
of the things that don't work for us of
anything that is getting in our way that
doesn't add value to the overall system
so that's that's that's that's one thing
for sure um we want to have as much um
compliance as code as possible so if you
can um have it built into your product
that it just complies um this is for for
times where you do need to have you know
just write that log um and meet that
compliance then then then have it in
there so these types of
governance should be met in the absolute
minimum required minimum amount of work
minimum amount of effort minimum amount
of code minimum amount of everything
required to meet the compliance and no
more