in order to be
successful we need to constantly
readjust to to our surroundings right
things
happen um if you're going through life
and uh you meet new people uh people
disappear uh things happen in the world
right medical things happen uh winning
the lottery happens all of those things
happen and we as humans are default
behav behavior is to adapt around those
situations and the same is true for for
for businesses right this it's basically
an
ecosystem your business exists within a
specific Niche that it um
developed into right your your business
grew into one or maybe many niches
depending on the size of your
organization and
and in those niches things aren't
constant things are continuously
changing so in the old days the niches
used to be there for a really long time
they used to change very slowly right so
if you were a carpet manufacturer in um
Islington then um you would be a your
Market was fairly stable your
competition was fairly fairly low but
today that's that's not true for any
organization they're very there are
organizations which don't have
competitive markets um but they are
incredibly rare you're probably not one
of them and if you exist in those highly
competitive highly Dynamic
markets you need to be constantly
adapting to the needs of those markets
in order to maximize the value that you
delivered to your customers and maximize
the the revenue that you create and
profit that you return uh for your
organization and that requires constant
adaptation constant adaptation to the
market constant adaptation to changing
circumstances constant adaptation to
things that happen in the world that
affect your business and I think that
the the great example of that is when co
co came along if you were an
organization um in March of 2020 uh that
had already embraced the interwebs right
you already had people working from home
you had already embraced modern security
practices so you weren't using uh uh VPN
tunnels into a a specific office
location um then you probably if you
were already in that modern Camp you
probably had and your business was
largely either doing business I.E people
working in an office um then you
probably had very little impact
to your business from the work from home
rules right because people could just go
work from home and it was cool yeah we
had to deal with you know we we lost
some productivity cuz the kids were at
home as well right we lost some
productivity because I don't have an
office in my house and I had to work on
the kitchen table right and there's
things going on around me but we adapted
right we adapted to those circumstances
we adapted um to to what it was we had
to do and we made it work
and that's the genius of of of humans
that's the thing that we're emly uh good
good at so you don't want to get in the
way of that inside of your organization
and the way we get in the way of that is
by creating
rules so companies
organizational uh
um controls or uh boundaries or
organizational boundaries should be
maintained using um principles rather
than rules if you use principles in the
way you do business um I a guiding
principle
then you're not constraining people to
the way we currently do things you're
leaving it open for people to choose
different ways to do things that those
you might have policies and procedures
and rules right you might work in a
regulated industry and here's a bunch of
stuff we have to do but how you
interpret those things should be fluid
based on the needs of the market while
still complying with the rules and um
that is probably one of the hardest
things for organizations to adapt to is
that old thinking uh the inter of the
century Industrial Revolution thinking
that we can just create a bunch of room
rules a bunch of ways that we work um
and have everybody follow it and we're
going to continue to be successful those
days were gone in the 1920s they're
completely eradicated by the
1970s um and we all all successful
organizations continuously adapt if you
continuously adapt to your Market why
don't you continuously adapt to the work
inside of your organization what's
holding you back from making that change
if you want to have a discussion about
your unique needs or situation then
please book a call or visit us at naked
agility tocom uh we also have our
immersive and traditional public classes
on our website and we'd love to hear
from you