so the immersive learning experience
helps coach people on the job because
it's done over a number of weeks
um usually I think the the PSM is eight
weeks the pspo is seven weeks uh the EPS
is 10 weeks so we have one session a
week at the beginning of the week like
four hours and then at the end of that
session you get an assignment that
you're able to then do within your
organization
so because you're doing it within your
organization you're then going to come
to the next session the next week with
uh you know stuff that didn't work out
so well or maybe it was all awesome
right but be able to get feedback and
iterate on some of those ideas
um so at the beginning of each session
apart from the first one obviously we
have a debrief uh for that for that
exercise which is why the immersive
classes tend to be a little bit smaller
right because we've got to go through uh
uh everybody's everybody's debrief and
make sure everybody's good and okay but
you're also going to have maybe up to 12
other well 11 other people as well as
myself for the trainer that you are able
to have a conversation with right and
see uh what did they try right if
everybody had the same assignment what
worked in other organizations maybe
there's more than one of you from your
organization and you find out that they
were successful and you were
unsuccessful and then you can figure out
well so what did you do differently in
the organization that was was worked out
and what did I do differently that
didn't and how do we share that
knowledge and share that experience so
that's that that iterative double Loop
learning that you get so that you can
collaborate not just within your
organization but without in the
immersive uh class experience
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility