so when you first open Team Foundation
server you might see a message saying
some features of Team web access are not
visible to
you and you click show details there's
an msdn article on how to to solve that
problem but it is actually very simple
to solve as long as you have uh your
administrator on the TFS server not just
on the collection but on the whole
server you can click on the little Cog
the top right to go in and administer
your
server and if you click all the way up
to control panel in the view there and
you'll see an access levels tab on
access levels and you get to configure
which users have permission or have
which licensing level so you have
limited access which is view my work
items and you do not need uh Cal or any
sort of access directly paid access TFS
in order to get this level um you have
standard which is currently the default
which is why we get the message to say
things aren't being shown this requires
a cal and so anybody in this
group uh which again is the default will
see all of those features there view my
work items standard features agile
boards backlog and Sprint planning tools
and the chart viewing and in order to H
get full access if I click on full and
you'll see that this also has um agile
portfolio tools team rooms test case
management there's a few extra things in
there over and above um this is only
available with the up level Cals which
is a a test professional with msdn uh a
premium with msdn an ultimate with msdn
that you need one of those levels to
access this so you can just add the user
accounts for everybody that
has H that version in there now I um
this is my local server everybody
accessing it has
ultimate so I can just set this as the
default level and if I go back to uh uh
my TFS server and click
refresh you'll see I get the extra
features coming in I get the request
feedback on here um I get if I view my
backlog I now have the features which is
part of the um agile portfolio
management and I have the test tab
which is also an additional
feature so there you go that's how you
configure permissions for the features
that you can't see