is feedback from users turned into
concrete work items for teams on
timelines shorter than one
month we need to engage with our users
we need to take the feedback that they
give us and turn it into something that
we can actually
action in a very short period of time if
we don't then we're probably not very
agile how are how long does it take for
you to get feedback from your customers
into your backlog changing those work
items that you're delivering so that you
can deliver something else something
better or more of the same maximize the
value that you deliver in your product
by collecting feedback from your users
and doing something with it