so what we don't need is any more scrum
Masters that don't have the experience
and understanding to be able to help the
teams that they work with uh we don't
need any more scrum Masters that
actively inhibit the maximization of
value and the effectiveness of teams
because of their lack of knowledge and I
think the scrum Master immersive class
is a perfect opportunity for people who
are aspiring to be scrum
Masters to truly try and understand what
it takes to be a scrum Master now now
don't get me wrong if you're if you're
thinking of being a scrum master and
you're not actually a scrum Master yet
the immersive class is probably not
going to work out very well for you
mainly because you as an aspiring scrum
Master are going to have difficulty in
enacting and working through the
assignments which are specifically
designed for people who are already
working as a scrum Master regardless of
their knowledge level already working as
a scrum master and um focus on them
becoming more effective at what they do
at helping their teams be more effective
so really um if you're um looking to be
a scrum Master then uh probably the
immersive class is not for you but if
you are already a scrum Master
regardless of your skill level then the
immersive class is an absolute perfect
fit to enable you to really deepen the
knowledge that you need to perhaps
become a great scrum Master if you want
to have a discussion about how immersive
classes can revolutionize your training
experience then please book a call on
our website alternatively you can find
all of our public immersive classes
listed there as well and we would love
to hear from you