so the question is how will the
immersive learning experience change the
game for people with a couple of years
experience in the field
um I think that's going to even level up
from folks that don't have so much
experience in the field and are learning
it for the first time because you'll
already be coming to the class the first
time round with those questions that
perhaps newbies are coming the first
time around you're coming the first time
around with questions that you already
have
um and we could perhaps enable even even
greater degree of double Loop learning
the first time round as well as the
second time round so you you're coming
with those questions we can talk about
them as part of the theoretical
experience I I don't know about other
trainers I know the trainers that I work
with we love it when people come
pre-prepared with a whole bunch of
really hard questions right because
that's what makes it interesting for us
we're not teaching the same thing all
the time it's something different and
specific and ideas and situations and if
we can
get the theory with some of those ideas
answered the trials and tribulations
that you already have in your
organization and then you get the
exercise the assignment where you're
going to try that new thing with that
forward knowledge in your organization
and then we can Loop it back again and
get that feedback do the debrief I think
it would be even more even more powerful
for folks that have have
been doing this for a couple of years
and and want to really understand it
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility