one of my friends tends to say that I
see agile and scrum everywhere including
in the including the forest and me going
to uh to one of my favorite activities
so mushroom foraging and yes I believe
we can learn a lot about agility uh when
we when we look at what I do especially
in the autumn in the forest
so first point you have to choose the
right environment right territory right
so
um you most likely will not find great
mushrooms in some of the forest so this
is the knowledge that you can either ask
someone there is some sources of of
knowledge how to find how to find the
Forest where there where there will be
some some mushrooms potential mushrooms
there some of the ideas you can quickly
cut out from your list don't go to the
city center don't I don't recommend such
places for mushroom for adding so some
of the places obviously will not work
and and when you are coming into the
forest there are also some other I would
say learned rules for me
so if you want to explore if you want to
find the best mushrooms well if you just
stay in the safety zone so close to the
edge of the forest
my piece of advice as an experienced
mushroom forager maybe a lot of people
have been there already
so if you want to achieve more if you
want to potentially find better
mushrooms more mushrooms
leave this comfort zone go deeper
explore and when it comes to how do you
do that well you don't run in the forest
because of many reasons and one of it
because you want to focus you want to
make small steps you want to sense
environment around you and trust me
sometimes I can even smell good places
where mushrooms can be found so all your
senses are needed your focus is needed
and you have to be patient so it happens
that sometimes you you are so excited
you have nice new buckets going to the
forest and oh well nothing in the
buckets but at least that's a very
healthy healthy sport I would I would
say
so being patient learn how to explore be
careful be focused and
be prepared that this journey will will
need more time more devotion uh
definitely you can learn more and gather
more mushrooms if you invest your time
wisely in that process