so how how good is the pspoa course in
helping leaders determine product
Direction and why
well I for me this is one of those ones
where well it doesn't right leaders
should determine product Direction the
course isn't going to tell them how to
do that
um but there are tools
in the pspoa
that will help
leaders and product owners
understand
what are the things that they're not
doing that they probably should be doing
right a lot of
product owners are not great product
owners
only because they
aren't necessarily focused on the
breadth of product ownership
so for for example many product owners
Focus solely on the aspect of of being a
great customer advocate
right but in being a great customer
Advocate they sometimes leave the
innovator to the site whereas they
should be an innovator as well
and that
Gap
means that they're not
being the best product owner they can be
what what are those those gaps
um
yeah I was talking about the difference
between the customer advocate
and the the the the innovator
and
the product owners quite often
focus on just that one thing when they
should be focusing on many different
things in the pspoa we talk about six
possible focuses not maybe the only
focuses but six possible focuses of the
product owner and we talk about them as
the stances
of the product owner what what's the the
the the position that they take on a
particular topic and it's important to
mix and match although we talk about
them in isolation
um but we talk about we talk about the
Visionary or the Steve Jobs type right
you're you're trying to figure out what
the next big move is that's not
necessarily driven by customer demand
because customers might be demanding
this route but actually the next big
innovation is is over here how do you
how do you get to that
um
product owners need to focus on
they need they need a lot of people to
agree and understand what it is they're
doing right product owner is a very
political position
because you've you've got you're you're
being given money by the business to go
build successful products
and
if the business don't believe you're
building successful products they're not
going to give you any more money if key
stakeholders go moaning to the business
that you're not doing what they want you
might be in trouble of not getting money
if developers don't understand what it
is that you're trying to create and are
behind your vision they're not going to
be involved in it enough and you're not
going to be able to actually get there
and get across that line
so there's kind of this box of the
collaborator
right of of of connecting all of these
people understanding what they need I
think it should be called the politician
rather the collaborator right because
you've got to get everybody going in the
same direction you've got a vision for
the product and how do you get everybody
behind it so that you can maintain uh
focus and direction
and I've kind of talked about the
customer representative that Relentless
customer focus as well that's important
right it's part of that story but also
just being able to make decisions I I
think there's a there's a there's a uh
is a parable is it a a it's a definitely
a phrase that's better to make a
decision that's wrong than not make a
decision at all
I've heard I've heard that before and
that's sometimes what a product owner
needs to do is there there are two ways
to build it and nobody can make a
decision and the product owner doesn't
have enough information so pick one and
try it
right pick one and try it or or pick
both and try a little bit of both right
just make a decision so that we can move
forward and if we move forward and we've
made the wrong decisions ah we made the
wrong decision let's go you know pull
back and go this other route that need
to be that decision maker
um and I talked about the experimenter
already right focusing on what's the
next big innovation so there's a
Visionary what's the next big innovation
but there's also this experimenter which
is what's what's the iterative
innovation of what it is we've created
what's the next little experiment we can
run to try and see whether
what we might get down the line and I
think bringing all of those together
as examples of what might be missing
from your role as a product owner or as
a leader in your business
helps open up those ideas and create a
deeper understanding of
what type of product owner people want
to be
and what direction they want to take
their business and their product and
their teams
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility