so the question is what's the one thing
that a pspo course focuses uh forces you
to focus on
um and that is 100 value it forces you
to think about what is value for your
organization
what different types of things or value
because lots of people think of value as
just money in my pocket right which
isn't necessarily the only forms of
value that there is and that very much
doesn't resonate with with public
companies or or not for profits and so
what are the different types of value
that are that are that are there and
then what does value mean to us and the
interesting thing is that's that's also
not something that I can go answer for
them right this is this is product owner
being
um demonstrating leadership in their
organization is how does your
organization decide what value is and
for most organizations they have no idea
whatsoever what what value is it's
whatever that boss feels like today is
what value is
so as a product owner how do you
um Define and decide what value is help
Express that inside of the organization
help communicate that and really become
a a product manager right you're
managing that product
um with a huge focus on on value
um and that value is the most important
focus of the product owner class
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility