so why is Satya nadala a better example
of agile leadership than Steve Jobs
that's a great question
um so
it's going to be very contentious
because of the the number of people that
that really like Steve
and Steve was great Steve Jobs was some
fantastic for Apple but I think the
difficulty that you s you see the
difficulty that that he created at Apple
and you see it today and that's that
um when Steve was running Apple
everything was awesome
they were innovative
creating new ideas
but they weren't really he was
he he was driving those that Innovation
and those changes with with almost like
an Iron Fist and the way treated people
was was very very very bad from the
measure of today right kind of toxic
working environment
um
but he was an apple that was successful
he left apple or he got ousted by the by
the the board I think it was then not
successful they brought him back it was
successful he died and then Apple
started to lose their Innovation Edge
so there was no
sustained
inbuilt Innovation
systemically across the organization it
was all in that pyramid structure of
command and control
whereas when when when Satya Nadella
took over Microsoft
he started and it takes time in
organizations of that scale and that
history he started making changes to the
organization to
um effectively but again I know
everybody says this right but
responsibility down the organization so
that the people doing the work have more
say in how the work is done
and you can see that across lots of lots
of different parts of the business I
mean the the the the the the the windows
team and the um as your devops team are
teams that I've I've worked with a
little bit with the the teams team
um and they're a lot more Innovative
it's Innovation across the board so
everybody and all of the teams is is
responsible for coming up with ideas and
uh trying to implement them and figuring
out what the smallest thing they can
change is but the real
um
the real the real push comes from
the non-logical systemic changes that
are starting to happen across the
business
so for for example they used to measure
the Azure sales folks they would get
bonus to based on the number of hours of
azure that they sold
and what they found was they would have
unhappy customers because customers
would buy a million hours of azure for
the year because the salesperson was
great and managed to sell them on it and
all the cool things they would use it
for and the ideas and all of those
things and then at the end of the year
they would get their bill for them for
the million hours of azure and realized
that they'd only used 50 000 of those
millionaires but they still have to pay
for them
um so so so that's a focus on as a
business on Revenue extraction
versus value creation the customer
didn't get value from that transaction
or a small amount of value compared to
what they paid
whereas a small change in the way you
measure the sales folks and what they
did was they changed the Salesforce
bonuses from
sale sales to usage
so the sales folks now get their bonus
based on the amount of
Azure hours that their customers use
which means the sales person is now not
the person who's got the biggest gift of
the passer to get clinched the sale and
get the deal they're the person who can
long term engage with the customer and
help them get better at using the thing
you're trying to sell so that they get
more value from it so they would do
things like I I've done engagements
where somebody in Microsoft sales has
hired me to come in and talk to the
customer about getting better at devops
and the benefits they would get from it
in order to increase the level of of of
of devops and adaption and change in in
the customer because that sales person
knew that that company's operations team
couldn't keep up with the Need For
Change therefore they would then have to
utilize services in Azure therefore they
would get more bonus right so the you're
turning the negative behavior measure
into a positive behavior measure right
the salesperson gets their bonus but the
customer also gets the value and you're
starting to see that change in other
parts of the business as well as they go
through and figure out what does this
actually mean to us what does this
change in Outlook change in attitude and
part of this comes from it's Saturday is
an incredibly pragmatic guy he's uh he's
uh he's an engineer in background so
he's built products he understands the
difficulty of being
um building products and having those
things imposed and he understands
the power of the people that are in his
organization that they're the ones that
are important to the business they're
the ones that are driving it and it's
not just a Satya versus
um uh Steve Jobs idea you can see it in
the way Richard Branson approaches his
his his his
companies he talks about his job is not
to look after customers his job is to
look after his employees their jobs to
look after the customers he doesn't have
to worry about that because if they're
happy they'll do that job and do it well
um and there's a huge
switch at the moment from I feel like
from
um
in leadership styles from this idea of
stuff focused leadership to people
focused leadership
right instead of focusing on more stuff
more money for the shareholders more
money for uh uh them
um more output of products they're
starting to focus on
um how do we enable the people in our
organization to maximize the value that
we deliver so that our customers trust
us over the long term and and Simon
seniak talks about this a lot he talks
about moving from the finite game to the
infinite game if you're playing a finite
game you you there's a moment where
um we all start count up score and find
out who wins right that's a finite game
all of all of my board games are finite
games they have a set of rules we all
play by the same rules a point in time
where we stop and find out who wins but
the infinite game is how businesses run
businesses run on the infinite game
there's no point in time where we all
stop the whole world doesn't stop we
can't have score and see who's who's
who's who's who's won in that world it
will will continue on infinitely so that
that's that that that focus on people
that focus on leadership that focus on
the long-term vision of the company and
the products
is is is that long-term infinite focus
and that for me is the big difference
between
um Steve Jobs and Satya Nadella and it's
actually the same difference between
um
um Balmer uh Steve Balmer previous CEO
at Microsoft and Satya as well