what is product Discovery and why is it
different from what we've always
done man I would say it's not different
from what we've always done but it also
is different from what we've always done
so product
Discovery is all of the work that you
do that's about planning for the future
right so
if in order for a team to deliver some
piece of work you need to do a bunch of
research or you need to create some
designs or um or whatevers right another
team has to do something before it gets
to to to to our team all of that from
our perspective is Discovery work that
may be work work for the other team
right but from our perspective it's
discover work it's discovering this item
it's making um uh ensuring that we
understand that item as much as
possible and not just focused on the
items that we know we
want Discovery also focuses on the items
we don't know we
want
so how how do we
find the
things that are going to enable our
product to be better that's going to
enhance our users uh um experience
that's going to um open up new markets
increase our user base um those are all
things that we would do as part of
Discovery um scrum calls it refinement
right although I think refinements
probably a little bit tighter scope than
than Discovery discover is a lot bigger
um but it's something that we have
always done it's just not always been
explicit it's not always been something
that we say this is that body of work
who's accountable for organizing that
body of work and in the scrum world that
would be the the product owner right
they're accountable for for maximizing
the value of the work done in the
product but in whatever
process you're
using somebody needs to be directing
that it's it's not
necessarily okay for there to be no
Direction so part of Discovery will be
figuring out what your what your goals
are what your vision is and what your
goals are what is it you're trying to
achieve as a business or what is it that
your product's trying to achieve um what
direction are you you are you are you
going and then what are the steps you
want to try and take to get there and
then figuring out what do you need to do
in your product to get there um a great
great
um example I think at scale is the Azure
devops team at least when I worked with
them a few years ago the the scale of
that team I think they were up to 90
plus teams at one point working on this
one big product so that's that's a lot
of work to feed that that that engine
that is delivering delivering value that
those teams working together hopefully
highly effective teams but
teams
so they set strategic Direction at the
at the high level and then there's a
bunch of discovery that has to go on at
that level like where are we going what
are we doing what are we trying to
achieve right think of it like that's
like portfolio what are your value
propositions for your product how how do
you think you're going to be able to to
to affect those and then they come up
with ideas through through the structure
this is what we want to build and then
send it to the next level down within
that larger product organization and say
this is what we're trying to achieve you
go figure out what's going to make it
happen so then Discovery launches again
at that level what do we think perhaps
this is a as your boards right we're
trying to help the business achieve this
outcome they're trying to achieve what
do we think we can do to help make
progress towards towards that that goal
or those goals right um and then they
might have 20 teams working on that idea
so they would create their level like
what is it we think we're going to try
and Achieve how do we want to move the
needles um and then they're going to
give that to the teams below and the
teams below are going to be like okay
here's what we're trying to achieve all
the way up the chain right all the way
up to the product Vision um what do we
need to do to make progress towards
those goals in that Vision actually a
really good example I I've got another
example which is maybe more people have
experience of and at the holistic level
and that's the the the windows team or
Windows Microsoft as a whole across many
products um has a a a like
a a strategic goal it's for six months
right they they um Microsoft calls it
the season B I don't know if they call
it this right but I looking in observing
what they're doing many people call it
the season based model um so they have a
a six months in a
season uh and they're looking out three
seasons current season plus two more
right so that could be up to 18 months
but somewhere between six and 18 months
they're looking out and one of the
things that they wanted to go after the
market shares that they wanted to go
after as a business um from their
consumer products was creators so there
are people writing books there are
people um drawing pictures there are
people making music
on on computers right we want to go
after that group of people that market
share and we want to increase our market
share in that space so they created this
idea of the creators update that's kind
of what they call it right that the
again they do a a spring and a fall
update across the board that's kind of
like that that Cadence of the Season
based model the six months so within
that six months they're overriding
product goal product Focus across all of
their products season focus is to
um help creators create stuff that's
that's that that overarching thing and
then each team each group each product
group and then each team inside of that
that works under that story is trying to
figure out what can we do to help
further that so I remember the the the I
don't have one here but the pen support
folks in Microsoft moved from uh
255 pressure levels to 1024 pressure
levels that was one of the things they
did so that required the people who make
the pen the people who make the screens
um the people who make the the operating
system right to all work together in
order to work towards this this idea of
improving pen support and that was to
enable artists and enable that and then
they have software that comes off that
and they create sdks and all this thing
so that other people can build products
on top of that that that was one of the
Endeavors in that and that was just for
drawing on the screen or writing on the
screen right
um that effort to all work
together improved their market share
right in the in the Creator space that's
what they were trying to do but then
they realized during right they've got
their three six months three seasons
planned out they just finished the
creators season so they their product is
shipped it's everybody's 950 million
people using Windows and I don't know
how many of them are creators right but
they're getting feedback and Telemetry
and uh getting all that stuff and then
they realized that they needed another
creators update because they didn't
quite move the needle as far as they
would like there was certain feedback
there was certain and then they're going
to do that again all of that is product
Discovery so it's it's really big it
depends on the scale of your
organization right how how much uh how
big the scope is but that is the scope
of product discovery that you and
everyone in your organization should be
focused on from the lowest person doing
the work all the way up through the
business to whoever is in charge of of
of of that whatever level you roll up to
right so that could be Azure devops
rolling up to the head of azure devops
um but then it eventually rolls up to
Satia right the CEO of the organization
and Satia has lots of products and lots
of different parts of the business from
from uh consumer focused parts of the
business to non-consumer focused parts
of the business seven business focus
part the business so how do we enable
and align all of these things so that we
are an entity that's all working
together towards these common goals
towards these common outcomes and that
is part of product Discovery because you
deciding what your product needs isn't
necessarily going to create the best
outcomes
because we're narrow we're narrowing the
choices to what you can
imagine if we expand it out to include
all of the people working on your
product we are
diversifying and perhaps generating more
ideas for how we can solve these
problems in more interesting ways and
help our customers even more and open
out new markets and new capabilities and
new ways of doing things and that yeah
product Discovery is huge it's huge and
it it is very underserved in
organizations it's not very deliberate
in
organizations um and that's one of the
things
one of the reasons uh that there's a lot
of shift in focus in the market towards
towards product many teams are good
engineering teams they're they're good
at building solid usable working product
on a regular Cadence um but if they're
not provided with focus and Direction
they're not going to go anywhere if that
focus and Direction doesn't provide
additional market share additional
Market opportunities then the investment
goes away right there's only so long
companies will invest in something that
they don't feel like they're getting a
return on so product Discovery is all of
those things that happen within the
business in order for people to figure
out what they're going to go build