so the question is what are the most
common challenges you are contracted to
solve in a devops Consulting geek
ah man it's pretty much the same as an
agile Consulting geek right it's it's
people aren't seeing working
products quickly enough
right they aren't they aren't able to
use the things that the teams are
creating perhaps it takes too long
to get from from an idea to delivery of
working product or even just just too
long from we've finished the product to
we can actually get it in front of our
customers and how do we close those
those feedback loops because that that
fundamentally
devops is coming at the story
the agile tells
from the perspective of people who are
delivering the product right the the the
the the actual delivery teams who are
getting the product through trying to
get the product through the production
line of of delivery and
the most common challenges or how do you
make that faster how do you automate
that process which which means people
often think about devops as purely about
the automation
but there's a lot of uh a mindset and
understanding lean agile practitioner
behind the story of devops that enables
you to make different choices and have
different understandings it's it's the
same reason that that synovsky had to
drag the windows team Kicking and
Screaming was his comment to shipping a
new version of Windows after Windows 8
right Windows 8.1 was a year later but
they didn't want to do it they're like
you can't release a new version of
Windows within a year can can you
imagine working on a product and
believing wholeheartedly that you can't
ship a new version within a year you
can't make one code change and ship it
to production within a year that's
that's an incredible
length of time for that to be true and
devops is really about closing those
feedback Clips getting that that oh
depends how you think about devops right
again I always come back to that that
story are you an agile practitioner
looking at devops are you our devops
practitioner looking at agile right
because a devops practitioner will say
that agile is part of the devops story
and an agile practitioner will say that
devops is part of the agile story right
that's that's different lenses they're
different perspectives but it's all the
same thing so I don't really count it as
a any different between it I do this
report for for organizations where I
analyze what they're doing and I call it
the the state of agile report if they
asked for an agile report in the state
of devops report if they asked for a
devops report and it's the same report
right it's the same story that I'm
telling it's all about shortening
feedback loops it's about uh getting
product in the hands of your customers
more quickly it's about think of all the
different feedback loops how long does
it take your developers to to to to
validate that the code they've just
written actually works
right I know teams where where that's 48
hours because of the tests they have to
run because their testing infrastructure
Is Not Great perhaps that should be
Rewritten
um for me the most most common
challenges are are anytime the customer
says
or anybody at the customer says
but in our
industry World company
we can't do thing because of some other
reason right those those are the big
challenges it actually doesn't matter
what you fill those gaps with they're
they're the big challenges most most
commonly
um is is we can't
um have developers shipping product into
production because of our
um you know we're a regulated industry
and we need to blah blah whatever
bollocks blah blah blah blah blah right
because because it's just fundamentally
not true if you go look on the azure
devops website uh at least the last time
I looked there were a bunch of articles
on
um socks audits
um and a bunch of articles on other uh
and I think there's the the federal drug
the US drug
stuff like you have to comply with a
bunch of stuff right
there's there's no mandate that a
different person has to test it from the
person that codied it not in any of
those actual things there's actually
socks on it is the big one right because
it's the financial world and it
it's crazy to think that an auditor
right who's a financial auditor would
understand anything about software and
put some restriction on and they don't
and the same is true for everything it
get the auditor in the room and ask them
the question if we do it like this
instead of like this is that still okay
and 90 of the times are like yeah it is
right yeah that sounds that sounds like
it gets me the same stuff I need in fact
that sounds like more than I need that's
pretty good right and that almost almost
100 of the time that's that's my
experience working with compliance in
companies external Auditors is that they
don't have the Outlook that you think
they do because you make we make a sound
pins and we don't ask them so the
biggest biggest common challenges are we
can't do that here
that's the biggest challenge and it
doesn't matter what it is it's always
the same challenge right
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility