how does my Consulting experience
manifest in the training environment I
think it manifests itself all over the
place to be honest when I'm when I'm
when I'm Consulting when I'm training so
much so that I I definitely
quite often
struggle to cover all of the content
that we want to talk about because
for most people
they're they're coming to training
looking for answers
right it might not be the answers that
the training was designed to give them
right
um that's that's that's also often the
case but if we do have time and we do
have inclination and even sometimes if
we don't
it's worth having a conversation about
particular instances in particular ideas
and particular Solutions and one of the
things that I feel that I bring to a
training class
um that folks that aren't actually
Consulting haven't actually been
Consultants kind of aren't able to
Leverage is those situational
experiences that I've had in
organizations with teams with leadership
groups where we're trying to figure out
how to solve a problem and they they're
they're doing some crazy thing I think I
think my favorite thing that I talk
about a lot is I've always got a worse
story than whatever the students bring
right I've I can for I don't think I've
ever encountered a circumstance where a
student has brought up some crazy
nefarious ridiculous thing that their
organization does to inhibit their
ability to add deliver value
that I can't pull out an example of a
worse one right of a a team or an
organization that is just
just worse right and and almost in
almost every circumstance from technical
things that are worse from cultural
things that are worse to to actual
implementation things in the way they
they do business that inhibits the
ability for for for teams and
organizations to actually get value and
you'd think that would be something they
would want right
um and I think that's that's the piece
that that differentiates
um nicodilities training from other
training classes and it's something that
I look for in all of the trainers that I
work with
um is that they they have to have
actually actually done the things that
they're talking about I don't think
there's any value in having a trainer
that has that that is just a trainer
right that's that's so that's somebody
parroting the content or parroting the
ideas that that somebody else has
written they actually has to have
understood them and lived them so that
they can not only tell you here's what
this thing is supposed to be
but also say but I understand that
you're over here and here's how I have
seen organizations
either split that difference do
something differently that gets them as
as good there as they can or perhaps
even an organization that has thrown out
their existing system in order to move
to that new system and what that meant
for the business and the types of of
conversations that had to be had so that
the students feel like it's possible
right that's the bit that quite often
there's a huge difference between the
agile and scrum and lean and kanban that
we talk about in training
and where companies actually are and
people find it very difficult to to
understand how do they how do they close
that Gap
um and that's what a trainer with real
experience as an agile or devops
consultant brings to the story
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility