so
um starting from the perspective of the
company that is uh the sending their
their employees for a course so
immersive class brings not only learning
but also coaching and supporting in
applying the knowledge so from company
point of view they will not just have uh
prepared for certification experts or
people with just theoretical knowledge
we will help their people to really
apply a lot of the things that we cover
during the course so I would say that
from value point of view this is a great
offering for the company because we
promise we will do our best to help your
people apply and make positive changes
in your organization thanks to this
class what is even more interesting
every single module will bring
opportunity to deliver value so it's for
instance seven times when the potential
value will be delivered for for the
organization and and this is just the
beginning right it's a longer it's a
longer Journey
and so about the second situation second
perspective so we have someone that
wants to become a better expert
this class can actually help you nail
your uh your interview your job
interview because again you will no
longer be left with Theory with some
fancy tools Concepts and ideas you will
have practical how-to knowledge that you
will bring to the interview you will be
ready to answer challenging questions
and what I believe is in the end of the
day the most important thing you will
start your job from the very first day
with already great great knowledge in
your head great Tools in your in your
hands and you know how to do that how
cool is that for this new company having
such a
such a new employee