technical debt is a huge problem for for
organizations I want to quickly Define
technical debt technical debt is future
cost that you incur
when you or your team
prioritize quick shortterm Solutions
over more robust long-term approaches
right so anytime you you make a choice
to do something fast but wrong because
you need it fast you're you're
introducing known you're KN knowingly
introducing technical debt you can also
unknowingly introduce technical debt I.E
we made some architectural choices they
were good choices at the time but now
they're no longer good choices technical
debt can appear over time
uh I'm thinking of a transactions system
and we supported X number of
transactions per second and our platform
of choice uh was reasonably priced was
able to support well beyond what we
thought we were going to transact but
now we're transacting a lot more than
that and we're reaching the limits of
the system that we chose a great example
a great example of that is the the Azure
devops team when they originally
envisaged work item tracking Fields so a
a a a work item was a row in a database
and Fields were a
column and those of you who are software
Engineers have already figured out what
the problem would be with that in that
you can only have 1024 columns in a sqls
database so they they not quickly but
they did hit limitations on the number
of columns that you could have for
custom Fields because who would have
more than a thousand fields
on a work item but yeah people do they
do exist and people do that and it was a
th000 totally within the system so they
thought we' never have a th fields or
somebody made that decision just like
the two-digit date decision back in the
day um so they had a lot of work to go
back and refactor not just refactor the
system but write the capabilities to
refactor the data on upgrade for their
customers in into a format where each
field was a row right in a database
rather in a column so then you have
unlimited capability um for fields and
data and those types of decisions either
knowingly made decisions that result in
something that's not not quite the way
it needs to be or unknown ones are where
most technical debt comes from there are
other issues that people call technical
debt which AR aren't necessarily
technical debt but most people lump it
all together and say technical debt I
think I often do as well and that's I've
written bad code and shipped it that's
not technical debt that's
incompetence right so so within the
context of a competent team there's
known technical debt and unknown
technical debt but there's another thing
that we call technical debt which is
just shipping bad code making poor
choices knowing that they're poor
choices and not doing anything about it
right shipping bad code stop shipping
stop shipping bad code would be the way
you pay that one back but for technical
debt you need to pay it back you need to
prioritize paying back that technical
debt uh think of it more as an unhedged
fund rather than a debt like a credit
card um most debt is secured against
something secured against an asset if
you stop paying your mortgage then the
bank comes and repossesses your house
and gets their money back right and
maybe you get some leftovers because you
paid some of your mortgage
but who's who's
ensuring your product quality who's
uring your product against your
technical debt there's no insurance it's
uninsured uh from from from that
perspective um nobody can magically come
along and pay back all the all the debt
it's not insured at all um or sell
something and pay back back we claim an
asset so it's something you're going to
have to deal with and you can't let get
out of control and there's a lot of
unknown technical debt I mean that
that's that's like I I mean I use the
eure devops team a lot as an example and
but they'd been a waterfall team for
many years shipping once every two years
and then they moved to a more continuous
delivery 3-we model and they found that
they they they made lots of poor
decisions right that didn't weren't
necessarily poor decisions within the
context of twoe but they couldn't really
see the impact
of the technical debt the choices that
they'd made deliberate and N deliberate
right on on their ability to deliver
product and their ability to deliver
value but I have a I have a I have a
graph um of I think it's 2010 through to
2018 for for that product team so eight
years of development and they
effectively go by moving to continuous
delivery moving to uh 3-we Sprints
moving to that faster cycle from a
two-yearly cycle and running into issues
with that and every issue they're
running into paying it back right paying
back the reason that they made those
choices which were perhaps valid reasons
at the time but you still need to pay it
back it doesn't matter whether it was a
valid reason or not and and paying it
back and doing the work they
actually went from 25 features to
production each year in 2010 to
something like 360 features to
production in 2018 so by by focusing on
paying back their technical debt of
enabling their Engineers to close the
feedback loops then shorten the feedback
loops three ways of devops right closing
the feedback loops first then shortening
them and that act of shortening the
feedback loops can massively increase
the amount of value that you can deliver
long term and that's the value of paying
back technical debt of managing
technical debt well is that you can go
from th removing those limitations to
maximizing the value that you deliver in
your product with the same number of
people that was the Azure devops team
literally went from 25 features to
production each year in 2010 worked very
hard to pay back technical debt um and
were able to even in the first year of
focusing on paying back technical debt
to get their new way of working up and
running they went from 25 features to
production to 68 features to production
within that one year and they weren't
even focused on delivering more features
they were focused on let's deal with our
crap and let's figure out how we deal
with those problems and they still
delivered more features that's the
benefit of paying back technical debt
that's the benefit of having a slick
Easy System system to add features to
your product and that's what everybody
needs don't manage technical Debt Pay It
Back