screen yeah it didn't didn't didn't
didn't work I'm going to admit all there
we
go bony how are you
doing morning
morning I see a few names I recognize
let me see if I can change the settings
on
this
because for some
[Music]
reason no it won't let me change the
settings
awesome uh well keep an eye on that
Lobby thing you want it wasn't supposed
to have a lobby but
uh and I can't load the settings so
there we go
um hey Richard um Arun
Phil there are folks I
recognize so welcome to uh
this event it is being it is being uh
recorded H I
think this matus uh it is been recorded
So hopefully uh we'll have a nice a nice
fresh copy at the end we'll see how how
how well it works this is this is our
first time using this Microsoft webinar
Malarkey um so we'll see we'll see how
how well it goes um we are going to be
talking today uh about product ownership
and lean product management and I am
probably expecting that you're going to
have lots of questions that Joanna and I
can field um but I have a small uh uh
presentation that I want to H provide
for you I put together some content to
like trigger I guess trigger some of
those questions um it's I'm aiming for
18 minutes of actually talking at you uh
so that you get a chance to answer as
many uh or have as many of your
questions asked as possible um if you
want to queue up your questions for the
end there should be a Q&A button
on the screen somewhere um and that will
allow you to to to to ask like have a
question and answer rather than it just
being a straight
chat I'm not sure if the chat uh even
well it says been the the the chat
should be working but uh we'll see but
the questions bit probably easier to see
which questions have been answered and
which uh questions haven't um I am going
to share my screen and I have a lovely a
lovely mural for what I want to talk
about today but I'll use it in
presentation
[Music]
mode oh actually let me do it the other
way around then I'm looking at you you
don't want me looking off to the side if
I I switch the
screen I use my primary screen there we
go now I'll be looking at you when I'm
when I'm talking that's a little bit
better uh so let me switch into we yes
but not that one I'm going to start
there let's start at the beginning that
would probably be a good
idea there we
go uh so uh the the main the main topic
of of of today is kind of two two things
that are really one thing is the way I
think about it um so product ownership
and lean product development are
two different tracks of uh like um
entomology where it came from but really
they're they're they're talking about or
trying to solve very similar problems
and if we bring the ideas from both
spaces together we can um hopefully have
an even better better outcome uh because
I found some interesting information uh
that nine out of 10 product releases are
failures I.E they're not they're not a
success and I know you you may have a
product uh that is a lot more successful
than that that is absolutely uh possible
but I'm sure you've been part of and
seen um lot product releases that are uh
not complete successes right there's
quite often well some things work but
then other things not so much and this
just ties into that that idea that in
actual fact 70% of all startups fail in
the first year right we have ideas we
try and Implement them in our in our
products right or build a whole company
around that idea and it's
unsuccessful um and in fact even
products that companies that survived
the first year 50% of what that 30% that
survived the first year fail in the
first uh five years so we have a pretty
high failure rate for whole companies
let alone individual individual products
individual ideas and did even even did
the product that you created actually
provide the value for uh for the
organization or for the users that was
expected uh uh from the investment that
you made right so it's it's it's a
um a big deal so so why why did they
fail to meet um their objectives um and
there's really a I feel like a very
simple answer for that and that's
because the product management role is
is not well understood in
organizations it's not um well
implemented in organizations and quite
often
organizational um traditional
organizational rules impede the ility
for that person to be able
to make the decisions that need to make
to maximize the the the value of what it
is that we're trying to trying to do um
but also not just the organizational
impediments but lots of people are given
this this this role to manage a product
or be a product owner and they really
have no no idea what that is what it
entails or what they need to be able to
do in order to fulfill it um it's quite
I feel a a massive issue because um of
that of that of the scale of the amount
of money that's being um invested in
products and how much waste there is uh
in those IDE so I I see it a lot in
almost every engagement with almost
every customer um that I work with it's
very difficult to find somebody who both
understands what the product owner is
supposed to be and is and is a and is
able to actually fulfill it within their
organization um quite often people do
understand those that do understand what
they should be doing aren't actually
able to do it because of because of the
way the organization is structured or
the way the organization is is doing
things um and I have a I have a quite
interesting uh uh blog post I did a a
post somebody asked me I was working at
a customer and they asked me um like
what is a product owner what what what
are they supposed to be able to do and I
wrote a blog post that really sounded
like a CV like a like a job uh job
advert for a product owner right so I
created a how how do you hire a product
professional product owner blog post um
and I spread it around a lot of the the
the scrumbled or trainers um and other
people that I I recognize as having
expertise there and one of the quotes
that came back was was from Frederick
that made it straight into the into the
post um and I think this is a key uh
thing for organizations to realize um
and you could put product owner or
product manager in this space I'm going
to going to talk about why um but I love
this quote the product owner is a key
position that sets the tone for product
leadership and the definition of success
in the organization if you don't have
clear and uh concise product ownership
you're not going to have uh success for
a product you need to be working towards
a cohesive Vision um you might I know I
work with lots of products where the
product is big enough already or um the
organization finds it difficult to
innovate so they innovate by buying any
competitors that come up with good ideas
right and absorbing it into their own
product um but really those those
products themselves are not innovating
it's too hard to innovate in the product
um so it's very difficult to be overall
successful and that that comes to that
uh uh comment that I made about like
product management and product owner
what like does these two things what are
they there was there was never any
intent uh from scrum.org
oh not from scrum from the scrum guide
uh for the product owner to be um a job
title right it was never intended to be
an actual job title it's it's an
accountability that somebody picks up
and it's probably part of the overall
accountabilities of the organization of
the overall accountabilities um that
that person has been given by the
organization for their role right so
what I would expect to see in
organizations that you have a you have a
job role and then you're given a bunch
of little individual accountabilities
and the product owner is one of those
accountabilities and generally it's part
of product management so I would expect
somebody who is a a product owner um
who's fulfilling that accountability
within the context of scrum they would
be a product manager and thus they would
be responsible and accountable for many
more things within the body of product
management and that's kind of expected
within the context of scrum this is not
something that that um is
is if if you you as a as as an
individual right the product owner is
picking up the accountability of
maximizing the value return from the
work done by the team all the things
that are in product management need to
happen in order for that to be
successful right so um that's why that's
such an important uh um thing like
distinction to make when when scrum was
created the product owner um was an
unknown term right the the creators of
scrum picked terms that didn't have any
baggage uh product owner and scrum
Master right um but over the last 25 30
years uh they've picked up tons and tons
of baggage um so our understanding of
what those things are is often different
from what it actually is because our
organization has put additional things
into that into that story I so just be
careful of that because uh scrum is a
very specific accountability from
product owner so disam uate my job title
as product owner from the scrum
accountability as product owner they
might be very different things uh within
within my my organizational construct
because you'll go to another
organization and it'll be different
again right and that's that that that
difference um so this is from the the
pspo uh class just just highlighting the
the the breadth of what it is we need to
know it kind of expands over over as as
you go further down in this this pyramid
um so empiricism is obviously founding
the thing that scrum is based on is
trying to be an empirical process right
so that we have all those feedback loops
and all scrum the scrum guide talks
about is that context how do I what's
the minimum I need in order to maintain
an empirical process right that's that's
scrums uh uh Focus but that's not the
only things we need right as a as a
product owner um in as a product manager
we're going to have to add a whole bunch
of other tools and practices to our to
our story um some of those tools just
come from product management right so uh
things like AB testing and market
research and business modeling and
product Visions are all things that have
been around for a lot longer than agile
has um they've been around for for many
years uh but quite often we want to look
at some of those things with an with an
agile lens on to say how do we instead
of doing this all up front how do we
integrate it into our process uh and
bring it all together and that will lead
into um um the other part that I want to
talk about as well um the the the the
Leaning product
management so I'm sure you're all
familiar with this uh scope time budget
um this is I if if if we measure um our
success uh by on time on scope on budget
um can all of those be true
and we're still unsuccessful at
delivering value to our customer and of
course it is right we can we can deliver
exactly what the customer asked for and
exactly the time they asked for it to be
done on budget right for the exactly the
amount of money and the business has
changed since they made the request
therefore what we've created doesn't
fulfill fulfill the need um and that
happens a lot more than we would like uh
we kind of had blinkers on uh when we're
thinking about that you know oh yeah we
were successful we delivered that that
product and it's like yes but did it
provide the value to the customer and
that value um is the key should be the
key focus of the product owner it should
be the key focus of product management
right regardless of what it is you're
building and on time on scope on budget
is are largely irrelevant measures to to
to denote success in that story um there
are other things that we probably want
to do um but what often
happens um and again this is this we
talk about this in the the PSO class uh
but the the this idea of um in a
traditional and I use that word really
Loosely but traditional project
management uh uh practices right we have
H um um project Charters we have uh uh
plans we have times we have budgets we
have Scopes we have Milestones right
these are all part of that story it's
it's how our our our traditional project
management practices um mitigate and
visualize risk right that's how we
figure out what it is we need to do when
we need to do it all of those things and
when we start organizations start
transitioning towards a a a more scrum
or agile mindset um they realize that
they're supposed to remove those things
so they they take those those pillars
away that are supporting the the the the
our ability to deliver high quality
lowrisk products or lower risk risk
right lower mitigate the risk um they
remove those pillars and then they
forget to replace it with anything uh so
the the the one of the core focuses um
that I I like to see organizations work
on is what are you what are you
refilling those pillars with if you're
not going to have time and budget and
scope and Milestones right if you're not
going to have those things what are you
going to do instead how are you going to
create that that iterative um reflective
process so that you can um um build
build products rather than just fall on
your ass which is what happens when you
take all the pillars away and there's
nothing supporting uh what it is that
you're trying to do which is
and the thing that we'd like people to
focus on is this idea of vision value
and validation do you actually
understand where you're going and can
you communicate it do you understand
what value it is um that you want to
create right not not time budget budget
and scope but what is the value what is
the problem you're trying to solve what
is that worth to the organization are
you actually making progress towards it
um and that comes through the the
validation did we actually provide the
value that we thought we were going to
create and do we need to work
differently on it bringing in those
those those iterative incremental cycles
and I find most traditional
organizations find this very difficult
to get their head around this difference
between um the the mechanism that we use
in used
before and the mechanisms that we're
trying to trying to use now
um so bringing in some of those ideas of
lean product
development um this is this is a typical
typical diagram if you search for lean
product development online like a
graphic for lean product development
this is this is the image you're going
to get build measure learn right um we
need to we need to actually create
something in order to see whether it
added value we're going to measure
what's what's going on and then we're
going to analyze the data to figure out
you know what what what do we need to do
differently in order to to to close that
value Loop and actually deliver deliver
more more valuable um stuff to the
customer but this this is is very
familiar right there's lots of
implementations out there of this exact
same story um in the scrum world we talk
about inspection and adaption and
transparency right we need transparency
to see what's going on right what what
is it that we're actually doing and then
we need to look at it right there's no
point in having all this data that shows
you what's going on um and not actually
looking at it and then if you're going
to look at it you you want to change the
way you do things in order to to
maximize the value and all of these
Loops are implementing is from from
different uh stories around the same
thing all of these things are trying to
implement exactly the same thing so as
long as we're focusing on this idea of
we need to actually build something to
figure it out and then we need to
measure it like if you're missing the
measures you're building in the dark
right you're building stuff and shipping
it and maybe uh maybe it adds value
maybe it doesn't maybe it solves the
customer's problem maybe it doesn't uh
so that that that is a core core needs
to that to that
story so we've got this idea of product
ownership which comes from scrum right
although it's been adapted and adopted
into that terminology has been adopted
into lots of different practices over
the years and then we've got this idea
of lean right um the the the lean
movement came out of of toyoto is is
really the foundation of what scrum and
AD is it was based on originally it was
an adaptation of those techniques from
lean manufacturing into the world of
much more complex things that we're
creating um so that they all have a a
Sim similar
entomology um and if we we we bring
those things
together I think I've got a missing so
I'll just go fix it if we bring those
things together
um we really have this this H fun all of
this information all those ideas it has
to go through this funnel and we
hopefully end up squeeze out some value
at the end uh but what is that thing in
the middle that has to happen um and
this is something that is it's
implied in the scrum guide because we're
maximizing the value right so this is
implied you can't maximize value without
this but it's not explicit because there
are perhaps other ways to maximize the
value other than just this activity but
it's key I think many of you here will
be software focused right so it's it's
kind of key to our activity um and that
that is to to actually release you need
to actually release your product to real
users not pretend users not uat um the
only way to realize value is to actually
get your product in front of real users
and that as well is really hard for
organizations
right because they want since we've
we've
traditionally um as an industry building
software we've traditionally sucked at
delivering high quality product so um
yeah why would they trust us to deliver
them high quality product if we've
continuously and repeatedly proven that
we can't deliver high quality products
that's of use to them right so they they
put a whole bunch of checks and balances
in the way in in order to prevent us
wasting their money um and perhaps
breaking production so things like uat
change requests um uh
uh maril Lynch I used to have to fill
out a release form right you're going
You're intent Define your intent to
release and it had to be 6 weeks before
you were going to do the release
otherwise it was considered an emergency
release right because of the the old
school thinking around preventing risk
preventing
change getting into those production
environments because it's going to it's
going to break something um but in our
our agile thought process our lean
thought process we actually want to do
continuous small changes and hopefully
the changes are small enough that we
don't end up with a big enough fault in
production um that that that it causes a
massive fiscal problem right that which
is what's happened traditionally and I
really like um if you've not read it
before you should uh read uh the det
protecting agile BS uh article white
paper from the US Department of Defense
um I believe it's a it's a
key I I think it's a critical critical
article in our in our space that really
talks
about the thing that we don't like to
talk about which is are we lying to
ourselves about whether we're agile or
not right because lots of organizations
will tell you they're agile they'll tell
you they do things in an agile way but
when you start asking them questions
about whether people can change the
process that they work under or whether
they can change the backlog or whether
they can actually talk to customers or
whether they can ship their product to
production on a regular basis um or
whether they even understand what it is
they're working on and what they're
working towards and these all of these
things are not true in their
organization or many of those things are
not true which affect ly negates their
ability to claim that they're agile
right um and I kind of like I I always
use this image which is the the kind of
litmus test that that article provides
you're either all of these things are
true or it's it's agile BS um it's a
pretty harsh lipus test but not many
organizations actually actually succeed
at it um but this is the lipus test that
um US Department of Defense procurement
officers are supposed to use when
evaluating a vendor's ability uh uh to
engage on a product um so they're
spending your money right that's that's
the thing if if somebody's spending your
money that that you almost can't have
too harsh uh a set of a set of checks uh
uh to put in there so I just zoom in a
little bit so these are these are
they're really really important and I
think um I've I've a few of you might
have been um at I've done this at
conferences where I've got everybody in
the room to to stand up uh or on Virtual
and put their hand up um and I I go
through each question and ask them to
sit down or put their hand down if if
it's not true right um for their
organization as as a whole right it
might be true for one product in an
organization but in the organization as
a whole is it is it true um and even I
did a devops conference in vinnus um 500
people in the room and at the end of all
all six of these questions there was
only two people left standing at the end
that could say all of those things true
uh we're we're half arsing half arsing
our implementations absolutely half
arsing them um and we need to recognize
that we are rather than telling the
business that we're agile because the
business doesn't necessarily understand
that we're actually not but because
we're lying to ourselves we're also
lying to them right that that that's
that for me is a is a is a big
deal uh so uh this idea of customer uh
centricity or centricity we need to we
need to all be on the same page we need
to be all focusing towards the same
thing that's my my my idea here and I
have a couple of things that I think are
quite important to consider that are
often not
considered um and one of my favorite
pieces is is this value um pyramid
there's a there's a b2c version and a
B2B right it depends whether your Apple
on the left or your um I don't know
Microsoft on the right that are selling
B2B Solutions
um these value P pyramids are about um
connecting people that are using your
product to what it is you're trying to
achieve with your product and that's why
um Apple was the Roaring success that it
was right because they they convinced
everybody not necessarily everybody but
many people to care about their products
people don't queue up outside of an
Apple store to buy for 2 days camping
out to buy a new version of the product
because because it's just a product I'm
going to buy it right they they it's
because they care they care about the
company they care about the vision of
the company they care about what the
Company's trying to achieve they want to
support that company in what it is doing
because we believe in the message that
you're trying to trying to present um
and that's one of of the core
superpowers of the product owner is
getting people to care about what it is
you're creating because I I'll tell you
this now that that that people doing
work don't do it very well when they
don't care about the outcomes of that
work when they're they're the the like
if I if I if I don't I don't care about
the thing that I'm trying to achieve how
much effort am I actually going to put
into
it not as much as I would if I actually
cared as if I'm actually trying I
actually want it to be successful I'm
actually connected to that product and
the same is true that's for for for
employees working on your product and
working towards the success of your
product but it's also true from the
customer side as well right are your
customers engaged with your products do
they care about the value that it's
providing them right your product helps
me do my job better therefore I care
about your product is it actually
helping me or do I if if I feel like you
don't care then I'm probably not going
to care either it's a whole whole um bit
that's missing from a lot of product
management a lot of that that focus and
you see out there organizations that are
doing this really well uh Spotify have
done this very well in the past um
Microsoft are starting to do this uh
well they've done it badly in the past
Apple have been doing it well for years
right there's lots of organizations out
there that are definitely examples of
not only product management but turning
around uh their their their previous
efforts at at at product management to
make it a better place
um and one of those things remember in
the the the the do measure learn we need
to measure right we need to measure
what's happening in our product we need
to measure what we're working towards we
need to really understand um the the
metrics which they don't make our
decisions for us but they do inform uh
the decisions that we make
uh so this is this is just an example
this is one of the measurement uh uh
systems out there evidence-based
management uh which has these four key
value areas that you should try and have
at least some measure in each of those
key value areas uh to try and make sure
you're not missing something right uh
current value is your product that
exists unrealized value is what should
be on your backlog ability to innovate
um is is how much time do you spend
actually making new stuff rather than
struggling with complexity and time to
Market is how quick quickly you can
actually get stuff out there so that
goes to you know uh supporting current
customers opening up new markets um
maintaining our ability to to to to to
create stuff and getting stuff out to
customers as quickly as possible um and
that's this the whole Quality quality
picture as well which I think is is
super valuable so if you're not familiar
with evidence-based management it's
definitely worth a look if you're
already familiar with it you probably
already know what you're what you're not
doing or what you're missing from your
from your story
um but it's always a good uh example and
set up um and on kind of to do with the
value perament um the next most
important thing to be uh uh focused on
to have everybody on the same page for
is is goals Vision uh um and goals right
where is it you're going what is it
you're trying to achieve does every
single person working on every single
part of your product actually understand
the work that they're doing today and
how it connects to the
overall outcomes of the product right
providing value and this goes partly to
that if you're focusing on people um you
know Dan Pink's Drive autonomy Mastery
and purpose this goes directly to
purpose right are do
people see how their work contributes to
the overall outcomes and that that's
really important that's also on the dod
um um article as well your Sprint goal
and your product goal and your vision
are tools to help people make those
connections they're tools for the
product owner to engage people and help
them uh uh uh a product management as
well um to gain that
understanding so uh I'm over how long I
wanted to be Joanna did warn me that I
had uh too much content but if you've
been to my presentations before which I
know some of you have you'll know I
always have too much stuff take too long
but I just have uh uh we're on the home
straight I have some challenges uh that
I've mentioned I just want to summarize
some and maybe introduce a few more um
one of the huge challenges in
organizations for product owners and
product management is
influence do you as a product owner or
product manager have the influence that
you need in an organization in order to
be successful do you do do you have
control I I I've got a little example
diagram um I use this one in the product
owner class we do some exercises with it
um here's one I've filled out right um
and this is where each of those I feel
each of those things would go for a
professional scrum team right an
organization that's invested in
professional scrum so you can see theyve
got the organization uh what they
influence uh the product owner and the
developers I've probably been a little
bit harsh uh to the organization but um
in in in this story you can see that
things like uh uh budget and uh um
Marketplace and customers and uh all the
stakeholders and competition are all
within the influence of the product
owner although some of it's within the
influence of the organization and some
of it's within the influence of the
developers right so from a product
owner's perspective are you able to
influence the budget right because if
you believe that a new thing is worth it
um does the organization trust you to
give you the money to to to to invest in
it and see if it is worth it right or do
they not uh lots of good stories about
how this this has this has changed in a
lot of organizations um organization I
work with which is a massive
organization that has massive Hardware
costs and I mean big big machines like
hundreds of millions of dollars for
machines has just pushed responsibility
all the way down to the shop floor for
purchasing of any amount of money so
somebody on a shop floor who needs to
replace a machine because it's it's worn
out they can approve $200 million spend
to go replace that machine because they
understand what the machine is doing and
how it works some bean counter up in
leadership somewhere doesn't understand
the ramifications and might deny that
request cuz it's not in their budget for
the year um so so that's really
important that people are able to do the
things and that's about influence right
can you influence those those decisions
and this is like this the scrum agile
story of where does influence sit um and
who influences what very very important
I think uh the other one that I
mentioned before uh the the 3vs vision
value in validation are missing like I
can't find them where are they uh in in
an organization um because once you've
you've come along and got rid of the the
yearly budgets Milestones um and those
older um Tech techniques for managing
risk what are you replacing with if
you're not replacing with anything
you're just
broken um and metrics what are you
measuring and not just what are you
measuring at the product level at the
feature level what do you what do you me
what are you measuring holistically in
your product right not at the individual
feature level and I find so so often
these these measures are just missing
they're just gone nobody nobody has uh a
clue how much the product costs to make
they don't have a clue what the revenue
is um if this these things are not
intrinsically understood throughout the
product structure how can the people who
are making the decisions every
day possibly affect the best decision
they possibly can if they don't
understand the the the the cost the
value what customers think of the
products you need to understand all of
these key
indicators and then uh scaling is a
massive absolutely massive problem that
organizations have um because they they
scale crap that's what they scale you
know we we've we've got purly performing
teams who do don't understand our
product because they don't have any any
any metrics they don't understand they
don't have goals they don't have a a
vision they're not aligned and yet we
decide to put 20 teams together to build
a product um and think it's going to be
awesome um if you scale mediocrity you
get even worse than mediocrity right you
you need to scale awesome you need
amazing teams who are really good at
doing what they do because as soon as
you put multiple teams working on a
product together you're going to add
complexity you're going to add inhibit
their ability to deliver value so they
have to be the best they possibly can be
before before they even they even get
there otherwise it's just going to be a
disaster
so that was that was um everything I had
for today so I'm interested in what
questions you have so I'm going to stop
sharing and I'll bring that back over
here there we go I went I went a little
bit over Joanna little bit tiny bit like
small end like a very small end yeah um
so Carla Carla had a question there or
it was just the latest one I saw there's
quite a few questions let me go back uh
no Carla is the longest ago so that was
31 minutes ago on my 18-minute talk so
Carla that was before I even started no
it wasn't it wasn't cuz I was I took too
long um so what is fail in that context
um it's not actually provide I would say
it's not actually providing
value to the
customer or Li of limited value
not
not solving their problem is
probably the closest I would get feel
free to come off mute everybody can can
can can come mute and Chim in chime in
um May
I I have my own I I have my own
definition of failure in general if you
fail to learn then Houston you are in
the biggest problems because in fact if
we look into the data well in my opinion
it's not reasonable to fight with data
pretend that the data is telling us the
opposite right many companies fail many
ideas fail the best companies that I
know personally they are masters of
learning and treating every single
problem every single bad decision as an
opportunity to improve and to make
future decisions better so in that case
I would say learning is an important
part of agility and looking for a for a
success in the future I I agree one of
my favorite quotes is from Sati and
Adela um and I'm going to try it off off
the cuff but he said he would rather
have his his best people and his best
Engineers working on the problems of how
to make everybody more effective that
learning piece um than working on new
features he'd rather have everybody
working on our own Effectiveness um he
called it productivity right but
leadership our own productivity than um
than adding actual features because if
you maximize your productivity you can
come back and add as many features as
you like and it's easy to add features
uh so definitely focusing on the right
thing is quite important oh Carla's got
all the questions um how how do you work
with an organization who is fixed on the
idea of having a product manager and
product owners and in a way seeing POS
more as backlog admins but not really as
a decision I I know I think I I know
where you're going with that um it just
sucks uh they're not really product
owners they're they're they're they're
admins they're product backlog admins
right which is not the same thing as
product owners it sounds like the true
product owner might be the product
manager who who then is delegating to a
scribe who's writing things down for the
as the product owner um and that we're
we're just not going to get the value we
expect I I don't know if you've seen um
there's a graph I'm going to try and
describe it but it's it's got um how
much how much value you're able to
create and time and if if you're doing
you're doing traditional right we're
going to deliver once at the end then
you've got that flat line of of we've
not delivered any value and then we
deliver all the value at the end the end
um and if we get onto
that um we're asking for a whole bunch
of stuff up front which I think is kind
of like what what you're talking about
it doesn't seem like that product owner
that that team has the ability to change
what it is they're working on right
because it's coming from on high product
managers have decided that these are the
20 things we need to deliver right so if
we're if we're delivering those 20
things but all we can control for
example is the order and the breakdown
of those things then we still have to
get to the same point as the traditional
but it's probably a slopey line you're
delivering a little bit of value all the
time as you go forward so you can at
least engage your stakeholders you're
getting a little bit more but in order
to really maximize that value you you
have to be able to change what you're
working on because businesses make
different decisions every day does that
make sense Carla I see yes thank you I I
was more looking for uh
what what would be the suggestions to
make to the organization or what kind of
proof can you show more uh more in that
sense that this this hierarchy of
product manager and the ler the slaves
you call product owners to work with the
scrome teams it it is not working out so
what kind of information you provide
them because this the situation is that
the product managers do not want to
interact with the scrum teams which
would be the best
situation yeah I definitely I definitely
feel feel feel you there um
speed on the the the
the traditional decision-making
processes in organ so this is completely
not to do with scrum and agile right
traditional decision- making uh has
decisions made at the top and doing done
at the bottom but the people people at
the bottom that are doing are the people
that are actually connected directly to
the
market so um something needs to be
painful enough for those people for them
to escalate it and at every level
escalate it to somebody who can make the
decision like your your product manager
might only be two or three up maybe it's
only two up and then they have to
instruct their
subordinates in a way that they actually
understand and they don't just don't
just go oh yeah whatever right we're
busy
um and it has to be painful enough for
them escalated enough it needs to be a
big enough deal for for that information
to then trickle down and a change to be
made and that that takes too long it
takes far too long it can take weeks or
months for those things to happen and
what's the cost of delay of not being
able to respond the Market's
changed and our competitors can change
faster than we can what's what's that
cost if you happen to be in a market
where none of your
competitors are are are changing faster
if you're changing faster than your
competitors you're probably doing okay
right you could always work a little bit
faster but you're doing okay companies
don't change unless there's a reason to
change it's going to cost money to
change right investment so um you need
to find is there a competitor that's
taking our business away and and focus
on that we need to be faster than them
right uh
Richard oh Rickard sorry Rickard I just
yeah hey Martin hey Joanna yeah um
I'm also thinking about if you have a
product man I mean a product owner who's
kind of the Scribe of the product
manager there's a risk that you lose
transparency transparency in theirs too
because you have one people this a
whisper game right you have one people
telling another PE another some other
guy what to what to do and he just yeah
that's what you told me and there's
might be some misom miscommunication
there and that will increase the will
that
will uh yeah risk transparency in in the
whole process right yeah it's I totally
agree totally agree Rickard um yes Danna
if I may uh well from practical point of
view because I believe Carla was also
looking for some piece of advice um in
my experience you will not sell the idea
talking about what we are having right
now like transparency you need to find a
pain Point H and what I love doing I'm
waiting for an opportunity when for
instance those product managers making
decisions they feel overwhelmed because
when they will be in this pain moment
there might be an opportunity to tell
them hey what about a small experiment
what will happen if you create some more
space you will allow those product
owners to make more decisions in a
certain area just for the Sprint just in
that case let's create constraints for
that process and then we we will come
back it's just an experiment right we
are not asking you to now change
everything in the company check whether
it will work because thanks to that you
will gain more more time for other stuff
obviously there's too much on your table
and let's see what will happen for this
scrum team so that might be also an
opportunity to create small steps and
help product owners get more more
empowerment in the
organization you you know the fun thing
is that this little kingdom of herchies
came because as a solution to remove the
overwhelm from product
managers yeah yeah and then now we have
a different set of problems but anyway
but but yeah it's a highlighting the the
pain points is is a great great advice
there are so
many I I I agree Carla that that pushing
people into ability B based groups
really creates those it maximizes silos
right um yeah it's hard it's hard but
when you are a silo it means that you
will have your pains trust me if you
haven't experience that and here comes
the opportunity to talk for different
ideas uh cool I'm just uh reading that
other question from gam I'm prob
probably mangling your name I that was
terrible probably oh that was that was
good oh was that okay oh awesome I'm
glad H do you he was kind he was kind
Martin kind yeah um do you have
recommendations on how to phrase frame
strategic goal for a product we often
see product goals defined as we will
Implement X capability or
workflow um we we go yeah we go from
product Vision straight to feature list
um it
the the the bit where I think you're
going to get traction there is when cuz
they're going to they're going to
they're going to struggle
to this is true for for Sprint goal as
well they're going to struggle to say
one
thing right if when you see a Sprint
goal that's deliver these 10 things or
even three things here's three things
that we're going to do this Sprint or
you see a product goal that's the same
or the the group struggles to create
that Focus for it's because they're
they're looking too low level right like
you're saying they're they're looking at
that feature level and deciding on
features and the features inform the
goal because they're working backwards
they're focused on what it is they're
delivering right and then they're coming
up to a why are we working on this and
that's the wrong way around you need to
think about why are we delivering this
what what are we what like what are we
trying to achieve and that informs the
contents of your backlog not the other
way around your backlog doesn't create
the goals your goals create the backlog
so you can you can do a test and say
what is it we're trying to achieve as an
organization with this
product right that's our that's our
vision right what is it we're trying to
achieve why are we here then and as a as
a simple statement then come up with
what's our first what's the first step
that we could take towards that that
would be your product goal and then you
look at your backlog and say what have
we got in here that works towards this
oh nothing well we're not working on the
right thing right we don't have the
right stuff in our in our backlog so so
trying it is a trap it is absolutely a
trap um to decide on your goals based on
your
backlog because it's that's that's you
still might be working on the wrong
thing
and and is there a specific format that
you would recommend that would force us
to I'm thinking we typically use value
trees to you know Express this is my
product and this is what I I'm going to
focus on right if I could enforce a
format for my business goals presumably
that will force people to think business
as opposed to feature if you see what I
mean if if your goal doesn't fit this
specific format it's probably not a good
goal does that make sense it it it does
and there are there are lots of tools
out there for for creating writing goals
um I'm working with an organization just
now that uses
okrs um also smart goals I did a a blog
post recently um gulam on on how to
write goals how to how to write good
goals it might help also might not
answer your question directly uh but I
think this is something that everybody
struggles with and Joan and I normally
do like a yeah fast goals we we nor
normally do a work a workshop with the
leadership team to figure out what those
goals are because only they know right
um and so it's something that you can do
yourself as well with your team is
is have you ever done um we do exercises
sometimes like cre a product box that's
a great exercise to have people align on
what is it we're trying to achieve if
your product was going to sit on a shelf
in the supermarket and you had to
encourage people to pick it up what
would the box look like and what would
it say on
it right that that that's that's the
what are we trying to achieve how do we
create a vision and then connect the
people with that vision and creating
that box doing that creative Endeavor
together of creating that box can be a
great way to get everybody aligned on on
what it is and if they're sitting there
arguing about what features should be on
the back of the box they're not aligned
right you can you can see that right
away um and I know lots of organizations
struggle with that because especially I
I know your organization quite well um
that that some of the products are
pretty big right so when it's a really
big product it's difficult to get that
that vision and I would point it I know
you guys use as your devops um think
think of what as your devops did to
solve that problem they they broke the
product down into Azure boards Azure
repos um Azure pipelines right here's
key value chains that we can understand
and compartmentalize a little bit and
kind of say this is what we're working
towards here or you know we can look at
the market for that we can look at
within the the the bounds of that which
sounds like what you're doing anyway
right don't know if that help thanks it
does
thanks
ah and then the last question there the
most recent one um it's kind of in
reverse order was from again from Carla
Carla you've got all the questions um
scaling Champion I've been paying
attention you see I haven't been
[Laughter]
multitasking uh so scaling um the
argument is very valid most people will
understand
it uh when it comes to life when the
time keeps running it's not feasible to
wait if I maybe if I explain you because
I I wrote it maybe too quick so um when
you were saying about scaling you
mentioned that if you scale the things
that are not working then you're going
to create a monster and this argument
everyone would understand it and
actually everyone understands that we're
not if we're not able to do things right
in the small scale when we scale we get
into big troubles however it the the the
the argument that comes back to this
very valid logic is that sure in paper
is is understandable but in real life
where the tank is running and we're
pressured by market customers and so on
so forth we just can't wait for the
teams to get a little bit better we just
need to get better as we do what do you
do to that or how do you manage this
situation yeah because the problem is
and yet we continue to suck right yeah
yeah
and yet we continue to suck we continue
to fail to to deliver we continue to
fail to have a cohesive high quality
product right and and it it's the very
definition of of of insanity Rickard
might have something I know he works
with an organization with lots of
teams yes so what we're looking at is is
is we're not trying we're not trying to
scale we're trying to descale how can we
simplify this we have enough complexity
as it is business rules
architecture and whatnot how are how can
we simplify this and that can be both
technical uh it can be organizational it
can be just alignment across lines of
business right so I think that's that's
your first protocol how can we
descale because that will buy you so
much more than trying to scale up if you
ask me and that that's that's the first
thing we talk about in the the aling
scrum class right because it it it's
it's it's much more complicated to have
multiple groups of people working
together so how can we how can we
descale our product and I think that
when I was talking to to gilam about
Azure devops that's how they descaled
right you've got this massive product
but if we say Azure boards is not as
massive as that Azure repos is not as
massive as that instead of having 42
teams working on one product as your
boards only has six teams okay well six
te teams is may be M much more
manageable than 42 teams right um and
and that that value chain that allows
you to to to make those decisions is is
is is a good way to do that but but
also I was just going to suggest Carla
that that um this the Satia quote that I
had from the CEO of Microsoft again if
you have lots of teams already which are
working on a product which is where
Microsoft was right they have have
Windows and they have devops these are
all big products uh office um they they
they change the focus from value
delivery to Quality
delivery and even with a focus and I
have some data around that that you can
have even with a focus on Purely on
building up our Effectiveness the Azure
devops team uh went from in one year it
went from 12 features to production each
year with the same number of people uh
to 68 features to production by the end
of that year and they weren't focused on
value delivery they were focused on
improving our
Effectiveness so there's good data out
there that shows that if you focus on
improving your processes on improving
the way you do things of paying back
your technical debt of just fix the
stuff that's
wrong you get the dividends right and
the Dividends are more features in your
product may I share another story so I
remember working with a customer that
was not so big it was a company of
around 20 150 people and uh CEO once
asked why we are not getting more value
and we are hiring more and more people
why I don't see great results in the end
of the day and we conducted some
experiments and started Gathering
metrics and you know what what was the
result of our
finding at least
50% of time efforts people were were in
their jobs was just business as usual so
it w it was meaningless to add more and
more people to doing business as usual
while there were great opportunities to
automate there were great opportunities
to rethink how we work and with just
small steps
suddenly the overall effectiveness
productivity has started to
improve would would you uh Y and Martin
Shar I don't know how you're going to
share the link for the recording but
together with that if you have this kind
of um examples on how focusing on
Effectiveness or or the kind of metrics
you were using to to measure uh the ways
of working that will throw results that
you know you you need to start looking
to the to to this scaling thing as a as
if it's the boogie monster and still
doing something
else we we'll definitely do that I yes I
don't know yet how we'll share the
recording that's my next job when we get
off is to go look into how does that
work with this platform again first time
I've used it um but uh uh evidence-based
management the ebm guide is a great
place to start it has a bunch of example
metrics in it it has an appendix uh uh
with a whole bunch of of of
places to start right they might not be
the right metrics for you but here's
here's a place to start and it focuses
on a commercial product um but yeah lots
of lots of good stuff in there um but
we'll we'll put together a a package and
we'll email when we send out the link um
we'll put together whatever whatever
that looks like I'll figure that
out yes so I already posted the link to
evidencebased management guide earlier
if you don't know that and in the end
there are the examples that Martin was
mentioned uh I can I believe I can give
you my own ideas and briefly uh briefly
write this experiment that I conducted
with one one of the companies and we had
those interesting results that were you
know changing completely the
perspective I just wondered H can
everybody see the chat yes yes awesome
cool I just wanted to make sure again
first time using the platform I already
received the feedback so we are learning
fast our
friend okay well I think um if there if
it it's it's totally at time I can see
people are still here um so I'm happy
we're H Joanna and hi do you have
anything pressing Joanna no so we have
nothing pressing so if you do have
additional questions we can hang out um
otherwise um we'll we'll wrap that out
up there for those that want to leave we
will send out a recording and included
in what we send out um will be a a
discount for our training classes as
well Joanna has an agile leadership
class uh uh coming up as well as some
backlog management because we had
questions around that right backlog
management uh uh class as well that's
really for the people who need to manage
the backlog right what is it that they
that they need to do um and we also have
a a product owner class coming up next
week an immersive product owner class
that's eight weeks uh one session a week
with um assignments to go out and try in
your organization and that starts next
week with Russell um so we got lots of
cool things coming up but I'll include
all of that in the email and a discount
code for for everybody as well Martin
these are all online courses right
they they are we do all of all of naked
agility training um at the moment is
definitely uh online and you can do it
from anywhere and we have different time
zones to suit all half day classes
excellent all right super hey this was
fabulous guys thank you so much I need
to jump out perfect thank you
guys yeah bye bye great job
great so uh we also have a session this
afternoon at one on agile leadership as
well we do at first but you
know Phil Tony Rickards did you have any
any additional things that you wanted
you're still hanging out either you've
left the call and you've gone somewhere
else or you're still here I don't know
I'm I'm still here ah you're always here
Ricard I'm always here always can't get
rid you can't get rid of
me no no that that's been great guys
nothing from my point but it's been
really good refresher for me thank you
yeah oh thank thank you for that
feedback Tony that was that was good
yeah yeah no I think it's good um that
that you do these webinars every now and
again just to yeah just to keep us as um
keep us honest U like you say you get
into a business an organization and you
start doing your job and you sometimes
lose sight of what the whole point of
this is all about uh so it's good to
have a refresher uh I've done the ebm
course and uh yeah that was that was a
really good as soon as I saw that slide
yeah yeah yeah I've got to chat with a
guy tomorrow about this yeah so I I'll
I'll find a way of inserting that into
the
conversation so we we also we also do
videos on YouTube so we have um about
five videos a week go up um with content
for for all of these types of
topics great all right thanks very much
guys anyway and you say you've got one
at one o00 this afternoon we do um this
is H H on agile leadership and agile
transformation which Joanna is going to
be first chair on that
one okay is is there a link for that
somewhere is that on the on the website
or uh I can I can put it in the in the
chat I just put it in the chat there for
you brilliant all right yeah if I'm
around I'll see if I can uh register for
that as
well cool brilliant thanks very much
guys I'm going to jump thank you thanks
Tony thank you
guys yeah me too I need to get some
lunch before some meetings but I'll be
at the at the next event too of course
oh amazing you're already my friend
Rickard same to you Yanna all right see
you see you there guys see you later
yeah
bye-bye