so what's one limitation of reading a
book versus attending a course
um a book can answer your questions that
that's a that's a limitation a book
doesn't have a bunch of other people in
the same position as you and saying
asking other and different questions
that also might be of value to you as
well as you're going through the content
um reading reading the book is great
there are lots of great books on agile
um I think the value in attending a a
physical class is that you're able to
have those discussions talk about the
different ideas share your opinion of
those different ideas and perhaps that
will sway the people in the room or
perhaps you'll be swayed by the counter
arguments