In many organizations that I work with,
uh, teams
test quality in, they don't build it
into their product. And that has a a
very specific um impact on engineering
excellence within your organization. So
when when you test quality in you allow
you're effectively allowing engineers
to to say well it's okay the testers
will catch that in the next piece. But
the problem with that is the further you
get from the engineer writing the code
the more expensive it is to fix right
with production finding something in
production being the most expensive
thing to fix. So even waiting until QA
validation where you've already gone
through
you might have uh working with a
customer at the moment and they have uh
uh working in a in a team environment.
They then push that into uh a pre a
preview environment. Um and that preview
environment is where the the the testers
run. But that's is already in Maine.
it's already polluting main by the time
the testers are getting a hold of the
the content. So if we find a problem
there, that's another branch, another
pull request, another uh change coming
into the system. Now, we do need those
testers to find those problems if we've
got them, but we would rather those
testers didn't find any problems. We
would rather find them sooner. And in
order to do that, you need automation.
you need integration, you need
continuous build, you need CI/CD, you
need all of those things. So, great way
um to validate your architecture right
from the start that you're making code
that is testable, that is just the code
that you need, that it does what you
expect it to do is TDD. Um testdriven
development is not a testing strategy.
It's not a replacement for for QA, TDD
is an architectural and design strategy.
Um, but you can also add on to that
things like static code analysis, right?
And although
you don't want to take a existing legacy
app and turn on all the static code
analysis because you'll just get a
million errors and error overload and
nobody will want to do anything with it.
But what you can do is turn on specific
things
and go fix those things through your
product. Do a little refactor every now
and again to get rid of one thing. Okay,
now that's turned on. If people get a
warning, it's cuz they're doing
something that we've gone through and
fixed in our codebase. And then keep
doing it a little bit at a time. turning
something on in static analysis that you
want to make sure that your engineers
aren't doing, fixing it throughout your
application and then having that enabled
so that developers get those warnings.
Um, also code review policies. Now
although and this is this is where we we
we I favor trunkbased development right
and long code reviews
are the antithesis of trunk based
development. You want to get things into
into that trunk as quickly as possible.
Whatever you call it maybe main might be
um might be trunk right but whatever you
call it you want to get things in there
as quickly as possible. Um so you want
to automate as much as possible. I use
pull requests um as part of the code
review policies to apply the policies
and those policies are generally
automated. So most of the time um a a a
pull request is automatically approved
and automatically merged into the system
and it's only not merged if there are
infractions um which need to be fixed.
And one of those checks that I do have
is an AI check. Um, so AI is checking
the code that we're writing against the
policies that we've written as a team.
Um, and flagging things that don't meet
those policies, right? So that then we
have to respond to those those things
and either we ignore them, which
sometimes we do cuz it's a little bit
overzealous sometimes, but a lot of the
times it catches things. But it means
that we don't stop at the pull request
unless um there's an actual thing that
we need to go look at, right? An
interrupt. So um that gives us that
balance between getting things into
Maine as quickly as possible and
validating that Maine is the right
thing, that we're we're we're that it's
good, that it's high quality. Um, and
for your team, you would need to decide
what that level is. But even catching
things going into main at the pull
request level is is too late. We want to
be catching them at the engineer level.
Shift left. Get as many things that
you're doing as close to the software
engineers and as fast as possible. I I I
love the story of the Azure DevOps team
when they were building Azure DevOps
when they first moved from a a 2-yearly
release cycle to a 3-w week release
cycle. One of their biggest blockers was
that their their full regression, their
their their tests, their equivalent of
selenium tests, um we're taking 24 to 48
hours to tell them whether they've been
successful. you can only run so many of
them at once. So now you're doing
rolling builds and bulking up developers
changes into this rolling uh uh uh uh
test enterprise, which means that there
it could be 48 hours for a developer to
find out that they've uh uh uh got a
problem or it could could be more,
right? It could be double that if you
just get a change in just after the
rolling build uh finished. it picked up
the changes before yours and now uh
you've got to wait for that 48 hours to
finish and then your changes are picked
up and a further 48 hours before you
find out um that you've got something
wrong. So those types of longunning
tests are not building quality and
they're testing quality and still it's a
that's a that's a lagging severely
lagging indicator from the engineers
perspective. So they had 36,000
something like that something like
36,000 of these longunning system tests
that they would run. Um and they worked
over a long period of time. It was over
four years paying back a little bit at a
time to slowly move those tests from
longunning system tests to fast running
unit tests with stubbing out with
mocking with all of all of the tools
that you would expect to use at that
level. And some of that is using if you
build products with solid principles
with good engineering practices then it
makes it more testable easier to do
those things with. So they they started
doing that and over that four years they
took it from
36 hours 48 hours sorry for um 36,000
tests um to 3 1/2 minutes for 80,000
unit tests and that gave them the same
level of security. I'm going to put it
that way. They designed it that way.
gave them the same level of security
that they had with the with the other
tests, the same level of confidence that
they that they'd not broken anything,
that they were doing the right thing,
that they had uh uh uh that in there. So
that means that fewer things were caught
by that longunning tests and eventually
they could just be removed um and they
no longer do that long long step of
tests because they're confident in their
in their shift left test infrastructure.
That that's what we all need to do. We
all need to move uh h these these tests
as far left as we can and then we need
to figure out which of these things are
taking too long and figure out for our
application and our context how do we
shorten those feedback loops and that's
the fundamental premise of of of agile
fundamental premise of scrum fundamental
premise of DevOps within all of these
contexts and Azure DevOps is a tool
designed ed by a team that went through
this journey for teams that go through
and have gone through this journey. So
it provides
capabilities that enable those practices
and enables those practices at scale.
And the Windows team use this. That's I
think it's 4 and a half thousand
software engineers, 15,000 people
working on a git repository that's over
350 gig at the tip. Right? These are
these are massive projects. all the way
down to
I've got a little repo, I'm doing a
little build, and everything can be done
in a few minutes. I have a a project I'm
working at on at the moment that my time
from uh uh cutting code to automated
build with a pull request is about a
minute and a half. Um, and then if
that's approved, another minute and a
half into preview. If that's good,
another minute and a half into
production. Right? That that that really
shortens that feedback loop. you have
those repeated cycles figuring out
earlier that we've messed it up. So if
you want to build quality into your
process rather than testing it in,
let's help you design an engineering
workflow that works for