so when when customers engage with us
they're quite often in a place where
they they've identified a problem
themselves right um they don't they
don't they don't call a devops
Consulting service um randomly they have
some kind of problem that they've
identified and they W help figuring it
out and and what's the next thing to do
um probably the
biggest
um engagement I guess that I I saw was
with a a really large organization in
the oil and gas world and they had a a
product um that would I think it's
$50,000 a license for this product so
it's a desktop product and the pro the
main problem that they had was that um
okay I guess what they thought their
main problem was and what actually the
main problem was might be different
things this is this is I'm thinking from
retros ECT right because I've been been
through it and one of one of the main
problems that they had was that um they
had they had 90
teams in 13 locations in nine different
countries working on this
product each of those teams had their
own long-term branch that they worked on
so things would diverge um and they were
really could diverge for quite some time
could be as much as a year and they were
trying to mitigate that with an
application of force that's probably the
way I would think about it they they
they tried to solve the problem with an
application of force so what what they
did was they spun up um they spun up a
devops team right a dedicated devops
team here's our devops Engineers they're
in this Central area right some of you
have already spotted the problem um and
then they have they're not they they
can't change what all of these teams are
doing but they have to figure out how
they solved the problem of we want
continuous delivery we want to to have a
daily build of our product that was
their goal so they ended up creating a
bunch of infrastructure to allow them to
do that and managing that infrastructure
and they would manage it right the teams
didn't have to do anything and if the
teams changed something that was their
problem to go fix right um so you had
this team I think it was I think it was
eight or nine might have been his many
as 10 people but I think it was eight or
eight or nine people on this team and
their whole job was building this
product um so in order to do that they
ended up building a system um
that facilitated about 11,000 build
executions a
day that's 1.2 million build executions
a year and that was just to have a
working product every day so they would
have these uh temporary brand bres where
they brought the code together and like
automated merging of code from all of
these different branches all of those
different teams these 90 teams were all
on different Source Control Systems
different not only systems but platforms
as well so they might have
had might have had 10 teams on git 10
teams on team Foundation Version Control
they might have had 10 teams on sub
version another 10 teams doing something
else another 10 teams doing doing
another thing um so they all had
different capabilities different
branching capabilities different merging
capabilities and their build system
their build engine had to go reach out
to all of these systems and pull
together a version of the code and then
build it to be able to then uh create
this this unified version of the product
it was insanely complicated insanely
complicated and super expensive I think
in order to for a developer to work on
the product on their workstation in fact
to run it in production as well um you
had to have
like 100 cores I can't remember exactly
what but it was 128 gig ram uh lots and
lots and lots of cores 24 core machine
type of thing um it it was just obscene
the the the the the speed of the machine
required because it was a massive
complicated product and you couldn't
just build parts of it you had to build
the the the whole thing to make sure it
worked the whole platform and all all
the things that were built on top of it
um and it was just hugely
unwieldly so we did we did a a devops
assessment state of devops assessment
for them um we identified those key
areas everybody's on different Source
Control Systems everybody's doing
everything differently um they had some
limitations because each I think there
was 13 different funding routes for this
product so they didn't have full control
of the the the whole thing but what we
were able to do was over and it was a
number of years because it's a really
big product a really big organization I
think there was something like six six
700 people working on it um and in
different locations and they weren't in
our in in the same reporting structure
right so you can't just tell them to do
stuff
and it took four
years to get everything Al lined into a
single Source control system right so
that we had we could do one build out of
this sord control system and result in
one version of the product and then how
do we fold down the branches so that
they don't have so many branches working
towards that model how do we work
towards this idea of Mainline
development right um it's these types of
ideas these types of outcomes that that
vastly
simplify the problem that companies are
trying to solve and it it people don't
get into these positions from a
nefarious intent
right um when this in this particular
example this product had been built and
worked on for 25
years they had
bought anybody who tried to compete with
them so bring that puzzle into that
piece into the puzzle right and you end
up with a massive product with a very
complicated architecture that's very
difficult in timeconsuming to work on so
you need lots of people that's very
distributed because all of these
different parts of the puzzle were
brought in from different different
entities that now all work for the same
company and they hadn't I'm I'm actually
going to get a phrase I'm going to
phrase it this way they hadn't taken the
time to pay back their technical debt
they'd acred debt you know you take we
we we use git we take on a company that
uses sub verion and instead of lets help
them migrate all of their stuff into get
and and fix all of the stuff that we
need to fix in order to bring it into
our system we're just going to leave
them as is and we're going to plug into
them and pull their stuff out and and
integrate it into our system so rather
than doing that work because it seemed
insurmountable at the time um they they
they they didn't do that they they just
pulled the stuff in and on top of that
perhaps things didn't exist 25 years ago
so they have a lot had a lot of teams
that were on their own custom inhouse
built Source control system because when
they started working on this product
there were no large scale Source Control
Systems you were probably talking about
s h visual Source safe at the time but
visual Source safe was developed at the
time of Noel networks and had a Max size
of about 5 gig this thing was
ginormous right so how how how do you
manage that well you have to build your
own systems when you go to try and
create an automated build perhaps there
isn't a commercial automated build
system so you build your own and then
once a commercial automated build system
becomes available you you adapt into
that but you're actually just calling
out to your existing thing because
you've not taken the time to rewrite
everything because that's an inable task
so we integrate it rather than refactor
right we're missing all of those
refactors over time and it just gets
bigger and bigger and bigger and more
unwieldly and more wieldly and more
unwieldly and sometimes it's difficult
that's a terrible expression but
difficult to see the forest for the
trees right all of these things like
what should we go fix where should we go
look where should we start what's the
what's our biggest bang for our buck
that we can go go fix and figure out and
perhaps lots of little things we need to
fix around the edge
so what I would
expect an organization to get what's
what's like the outcome and Improvement
that that our customers can
expect it's a more effective process
right we're talking about taking what
the organization is doing right now
within usually within the context of a
product when you're talking about devops
but it could be holistically across an
organization and figuring out how do we
eliminate waste how do
we ensure that we have automation that
we can automate
that that automation is effective right
because it's also you can have
ineffective automation like that massive
build system I was talking about um and
how do we simplify simplify simplify so
what I would expect the outcomes to be
would be reduced cost to deliver new
features reduced time to deliver new
features um
improved H um happiness of the people
that are building in the product because
they're spending less time struggling
with the complexity that we've created
over time and more time focusing on
solving the business
problem so the these are are
multipliers for your capability to
deliver a great example of those
multipliers is actually the Azure devops
team at Microsoft right so they create a
product called Azure devops used to be
team Foundation server when it was local
and back in 2010 before they started uh
doing much more frequent deliveries and
all the Automation and focusing on these
things before they brought devops into
their story um they were delivering
about 25 features to production each
year and that was with 600 people
working on it and they were delivering
about 25 new features lots of bug fixies
lots of little tweaks but 25 new
features to production each year
um fast forward to five years
later they'd spend a huge amount of time
investing in
um reducing the amount of time it takes
them to build their product from I think
wow I think it was like three or 4 days
7 72 hours plus to build their product
down to 3 and a half
minutes right those types of
capabilities enabl to go from 25
features to production each year to
nearly 300 features to production each
year with the same number of people and
the same people it's not different
people it's the same people right so so
what we're talking about is holistically
scaling up all of the people that we
have within our context so that
everybody understands devops everybody
understand refactoring and clean code
and what the impact is on all all of
these things so that we can make them
more effective over time um and yeah you
you will be you'll be faster you'll be
Slicker and it will be cheaper right
that's that's what we're talking about
when we talk about bringing devops and
the devops philosophy into an
organization but it takes skill we can't
install devops in your
organization you still have to do the
work if you can find a consultancy that
say is that they will do all the work
for you your people are not going to
learn anything they're not going to have
gone through the pain of actually fixing
their problems it's like getting a
cleaner in to clean your teenager's room
right is your te has your teenager
learned to clean up their room no no
they haven't they're just going to do
the same thing over and over and over
again when you do those big rewrites of
your product and you take the same
people and get them to rewrite your
product what do you think is going to be
the
outcome except a Rewritten product
that's in exactly the same state over
time as your existing product because
they've not gone through that Crucible
of learning the pain of actually
cleaning up the pain of pulling that
moldy plate out from under the bed and I
have to deal with this moldy plate and
maybe next time I won't leave the plate
because I don't want to deal with that
moldy plate right that that's what we're
talking about with engineering practices
we're talking about upskilling dealing
with our own
crap right dealing with it ourselves so
that we make less of that stuff in the
future that we do things in a in a
better way that enables us to be Slicker
and more effective