This workshop is for practitioners that are
interested in starting a career as a Scrum
Master, existing Scrum Masters, agile coaches,
and consultants trying to improve their use
of Scrum.
The Professional Scrum Master is an engaging,
enjoyable learning experience where students
gain a deep understanding of Scrum theory
and principles, the Scrum Master accountabilities
and why each element of the Scrum framework
is important.
Our training is delivered as an interactive,
activity-based course over half-day sessions
using Microsoft Teams, and Mural.
Between sessions, we provide additional reading,
writing, and watching activities to maximise
the learning opportunities and complement
the classroom experience.
After the conclusion of the class, we provide
access to a community of peers and continued
access to the trainer through office hours,
quarterly catchups, and constant engagement.
To maximise validated learning all students
are provided with a password to take the PSM1
assessment, and if they take it within 14
days and are unsuccessful will be granted
a second attempt.