<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Capabilities on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Capabilities on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/capabilities/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Evidence-based Leadership</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/evidence-based-leadership/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/evidence-based-leadership/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NKD Insights™</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/nkd-insights/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/nkd-insights/</guid>
      <description>Naked Insights™ is a pioneering tool to help teams improve by illuminating the quality of their teamwork continuously based on scientific insights. Diagnose one or many teams, receive evidence-based feedback and resolve broader organizational issues.&#xA;Get Started Now!&#xA;https://questionnaire.nkdagility.com&#xA;Team Dashboard&#xA;https://teamsdashboard.nkdagility.com&#xA;Coaching Centre&#xA;https://coachingcenter.nkdagility.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Private Corporate Training</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/private-corporate-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/private-corporate-training/</guid>
      <description>Elevate Your Team&amp;rsquo;s Performance with NKDAgility&amp;rsquo;s Agile &amp;amp; DevOps Training!&#xA;At NKDAgility.com, we&amp;rsquo;re committed to driving efficiency, collaboration, and innovation in your organization through our specialized Agile and DevOps training. Our programs are expertly designed to elevate your team&amp;rsquo;s performance in the rapidly evolving business world.&#xA;Our seasoned trainers delve deep into Agile, Scrum, and DevOps methodologies, customizing the curriculum to align with your specific organizational challenges and goals. This training empowers your team to foster a culture of continuous improvement, streamline task management, and accelerate product delivery.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Product Development Mentoring Program</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/product-development-mentoring-program/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/product-development-mentoring-program/</guid>
      <description>Dive into the future of product development with NKDAgility&amp;rsquo;s enhanced Product Development Mentor Program, now incorporating the cutting-edge practices of DevOps, platform engineering, and agile methodologies. This comprehensive program is meticulously designed to bridge the gap between traditional engineering excellence and the dynamic demands of today&amp;rsquo;s fast-paced tech landscape. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re at the beginning of your engineering career or looking to elevate your existing expertise, our program offers a unique blend of mentorship, hands-on experience, and theoretical knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Product Management Mentor Program</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/product-management-mentor-program/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/product-management-mentor-program/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure DevOps Migration Services</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/azure-devops-migration-tools-consulting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/azure-devops-migration-tools-consulting/</guid>
      <description>naked Agility is the creator and principal contributor of the Azure DevOps Migration Tools. Consulting &amp;amp; Coaching for Azure DevOps Migration Tools The Azure DevOps Migration Tools allow you to bulk edit and migrate data between Team Projects on both Microsoft Team Foundation Server (TFS) and Azure DevOps Services. Take a look at the documentation to find out how. This project is published as code on GitHub as well as a Azure DevOps Migration Tools on Chocolatey.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Business Agility Consultancy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/lean-agile-consultancy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/lean-agile-consultancy/</guid>
      <description>Our Agile consultants work with organisations to resolve problems and seize opportunities. We collaborate with leaders to identify what successful outcomes look like. We conduct health-checks to assess the current State of Agility within your organisation. We meld this discovery with our experience to advise changes to the existing ways of working, culture and tooling to achieve the objectives. We design training programs to educate teams and help them change. Following training, we can coach and mentor during the evolution that follows as everyone works towards achieving the outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DevOps Technology Consultancy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/devops-technology-consultancy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/capabilities/devops-technology-consultancy/</guid>
      <description>Our DevOps consultants work with organisations to help them get the most out of their DevOps strategy and maximise its effectiveness.&#xA;We conduct health checks to assess your organisation’s current State of DevOps. We meld this discovery with our experience to advise changes to the existing ways of working, culture and tooling to achieve the objectives. We design training programs to educate teams and help them change. Following training, we can coach and mentor during the next evolution as everyone works towards achieving the outcomes.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
