okay
[Music]
so the question is how much of an impact
can a strong skilled product owner have
I
oh ball game right I mean
it's it's
if you let
Engineers be engineers
they will do the engineering right we we
can we can it's it's fairly it's fairly
fairly straightforward I know that's a
generalism but it's fairly
straightforward to get a group of people
to build lots of stuff
right to to special engineering teams
Sops coders software teams testers they
want to get through the work they want
to build lots of stuff and you you can
you can move teams more easily towards
creating lots of stuff so now we've got
lots of stuff coming out the other end
but it's not the right stuff
it's not the valuable stuff it's just
stuff it's just what customers have been
asking for it's just what which isn't
necessarily the right thing
so we can get quite quickly to building
lots of stuff but it's very very
difficult to build the right stuff
and the difference between uh an average
product owner right which not a bad
product owner is just bad right there's
no point in having them an average
product owner is going to be focused on
how do I be that funnel
for for the organization the customer
stuff coming in to get a single story
right that's an average product owner
but when you have a real product owner
like a great product owner they're
they're they're they're not looking at
that they're looking forward into the
they've delegated that to their team
already right the team's doing that
they're looking forward into the future
they're thinking about
how do I
get things in front of the customer
when they need them not too late
because ultimately when your customer
asks you for features when they ask you
for capabilities in your product it's
already too late because it takes time
for you to deliver those features and
then by the time you've delivered them
that's the delay the cost of delay
between the ask or acos of player
between what the customer is asking for
and when you're actually delivering it I
mean it might be two weeks but it might
be a big thing and it's three months it
might be six months what what does what
does not having those features cost the
business from when they realize they
need them
so great product owners are looking
forward into the future they're looking
at the markets if it's a b2c product if
it's a B2B product they're looking at
the state of the organization they're
looking at what's what's happening in
the business what direction is strategic
direction is the business going
and building lots of little experimental
features
to figure out what resonates best with
the users in order to solve those future
problems and test those ideas
so that when customers do ask for
features
your answer is would you like us to turn
that on for you we've got our uh uh uh
you know uh we've got a version of that
ready to go for you would you like to
try it
or even it's already there right I mean
that's that's the that's the trick
that's um I can't remember the name of
the author but there's a book called
crossing the chasm
um and that's what it focuses on is how
do we
stop building for the laguards right the
people that that
um
they aren't the innovators they're just
the people there's table Stakes right
products must do those things how do we
how do we cross over and start building
for the early adopters how do we how do
we get early adopters into our story how
do we engage with those people how do we
find them so that we can start building
features for the early adopters because
what the early adopters want today is
what the laguards want in six months
time
right so then then those people that are
the early adopters who are early
adopters because they want to engage and
they want to play with new experimental
things
you're engaging with them and they're
telling all their friends who are the
laggards right all the cool stuff that's
coming down the line and they're like oh
that's cool but we don't need it yet
right we don't need that yet because
we're not using it but even just that
planting that seed of that idea
starts to lead to the market rather than
follow the market right so I and my
market I mean either external or
internal market so the the the
difference between
the thing that makes that product owner
great is that that they're able to
anticipate what the next thing is using
evidence-based techniques using
empiricism
Levering hypothesis driven engineering
practices to be able to get it one step
ahead of where everything else is the
the ultimate the ultimate Accolade for a
great product owner is that that
company's competitors are looking at
what they're doing and saying what are
they doing let's build that right that
means you're leading the market rather
than following the market and that's
kind of where you want to be