so one thing uh that a client can do to
ensure a successful agile Consulting
engagement is to be prepared to be
provoked
I think that's probably the most
powerful thing that a consultant can do
is provoke push nudge their customer in
a different way of thinking a different
understanding or even to just think
about what it is that they're doing how
they're doing it and why they're doing
it that way and the reason I use the
word provoke is because it it can be
very difficult and hard for them to hear
the things that might be incorrect wrong
or just that need fixing that they think
they're doing it great and it's really
not