I think
my best day as an agile consultant is
difficult to answer so I'm going to
answer it in two different ways
my most memorable
moment as an agile consultant actually
happened
about
seven years
after
the engagement that it pertained to
so I I did a an engagement in in Utah
where we did some some training and
workshops and Consulting with a a team
of Java developers at the time I know
nothing about Java but Java developers
and
I mean I thought it went well we helped
them understand scrum we help them
understand agile we did some user story
workshops we did some engineering
practices workshops I I actually I did a
tdd
um
uh uh uh explanation and lesson and we
did a tdd Kata together even though I
was writing in.net because I know
nothing about Java and they were writing
in Java and they were still correcting
my code on the projector right
um
but but about seven years later I got an
email from one of the participants of
that
um just to let me know how much of a
game changer
that experience was
for him his team and the organization
and that that experience I think I was
only on site for five six days
um but that experience for them was a
felt like to them
as a catalyst for so much change inside
the organization
and I still speak to people that are
from
that engagement and hear from them on
occasion and they always they always
talk about it in in that way and I've
even I've done gigs for people that have
left and gone to other companies and
they've they've asked me to come in but
kind of nothing's compared to that one
which is funnily enough that was the the
first APS class I ever taught
um which was which was a lot of fun
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility