question is why do I think that four
half days is a better format than two
full days
um I think it's a better format because
of two two things one is that it allows
um people to spend a little bit of time
absorbing
the content of maybe maybe reading up on
some questions and additional ideas that
they thought of during the class so over
four half days even if they're
consecutive
um people are able to
um
rearrange their filing cabinets I I I I
remember somebody telling me that our
brains are like filing cabinets it's
just a metaphor right but brings all
that filing cabinets and during the day
we're pulling stuff out and looking at
it and leaving it lying around and then
at night when we're sleeping our brain
goes and refiles everything uh
processing all of the events of the day
and that can solidify knowledge generate
more questions right so those that's why
I really like that four half day format
but in fact the four half day format is
is sub-optimal as well we're doing doing
everything within within one week
um so we're trying to move towards other
formats that might be more valuable
um so we're already starting to
introduce uh especially for private
customers
um classes of
um maybe maybe over two weeks four half
days over two weeks right so do Tuesday
uh Tuesday Wednesday Tuesday Wednesday
or
um longer immersive classes over a much
longer period of time so maybe maybe
eight half days over eight weeks
and that gives much more capability for
the people that are participating in the
class
to go and try stuff with their team try
stuff in their organization and then
come back around and in fact in the
eight
um half day format specifically for the
pspo the product owner class initially
um we're going to be giving them
assignments at the end of each session
so part of the next session will be a
debrief of the previous assignment and
That might be quite a lot of the time in
that session right here was an
assignment you had to go into your
organization try to do something
different try to work with the teams in
a different way what was the outcome of
that what's your feedback and and what's
going to be your next iteration on that
story so it's effectively the same as
the traditional product owner class but
we have the extra time to do the to do
the assignments and do the review of the
assignments the the debriefs and
hopefully
and create something that allows
more Loops of learning right
people are able to actually try things
with their teams close that feedback
loop with the trainer and perhaps learn
even more than we would in a normal
class