what are the bariers that prevent
Developers
from fully accepting a product owner as
the final decision maker wow there's a
lot of barriers to that I see that all
all the time at the moment
um
other other people not respecting other
people who are perhaps more senior not
respecting the product owner is probably
the biggest barrier right it's it's
other people coming down and saying
something different to the team from the
product owner or
um going behind the product owner's back
or agreeing with the product owner in in
in person but then get it in a larger
environment with more people and perhaps
recording is on
um than disagreeing with them and seeing
it different uh I didn't experience
recently where
um a product owner the product owner was
really really frustrated uh because
they'd
um been collaborating with somebody in
the organization to to to to to get the
backlog all like this is what we need
this is what we're doing and they've
been collaborating them with them quite
heavily they've had lots of private
meetings with them where they
collaborated and literally written the
backlog items word for word like that
key stakeholder that's the way they
wanted it and collaborated heavily on
that and then
um they get into
the the the the the the Sprint planning
and the stakeholders like no that's not
what I want
and it's like
that that is explicitly there's a couple
of things there right apart from being a
bit douchey right that's that's there's
that that's one piece but because it's
then in that group team Forum it
undermines
the ownership of the product by the
product owner right that totally
undermines it
and if the developers the people doing
the work
see that the product owner is being
undermined well I can't really listen to
the product owner I still have to run it
by Bob or I still need to speak to Janet
or whoever it is that that is doing the
undermining and as more and more of
those things happen
the less unless the developers are able
to to feel that they are able to respect
product owner as the final decision
maker right
and if you look at the scrum guide
who needs to respect the product order
as the final decision maker everybody in
the organization everybody not not just
the people below them
but also all of the people about them
if if you're above a product owner and
the product owner is consistently not
making the right decisions
get rid of that product owner and get a
new one that's your call right you've
hired somebody to do a job if you don't
think they're doing a good job you don't
undermine them
you get rid of them
right and that maintains that respect of
product management that respect of
product ownership
right that the team sees that the person
that's appointed is respected by
management even if management might not
necessarily 100 agree with all of the
the the the the decisions that are made
but if most of the decisions are made
result in value delivered to the
business because that is the true
outcome right what what you what you
find yeah I I I'm gonna add an
additional bit because what you find is
that that disrespect
or undermining of authority of the
product owner comes from a position of
of maybe one key stakeholder not one
thing to to
give all the information not wanting to
take accountability for their decision
right
um and it
it just results in nobody
having any capability
leadership doesn't take the
accountability the product owner can't
take the accountability because they're
continuously undermined or the ideas are
changed without their knowledge or
understanding and the developers
there's no credibility in that story so
then if I were to come back to the
question and answer it in one word uh
what are the barriers there's only one
what is the barrier that prevents
developers from fully accepting a
product owner at the final decision
maker and it's accountability or in
three words a lot
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility