One of the the big stories around Azure
DevOps is around governance, security,
compliance, and scalability. And it's
one of those things that um actually for
me is one of the massive value
propositions of Azure DevOps that a lot
of those things you just get out of the
box, right? And that's a really powerful
story. So I I I
it's it's a little bit anecdotal but um
I
teach the um applying professional scrum
for software developers um and it's a
program a a a training class where we
actually set up and use um DevOps
tooling within the context of of of the
class and the people participating in
the class actually work on a on a
product uh that paper that's very
dissolial, right? Um, and they have to
make changes and they have to do stuff
and and and ship product within within a
short space of time, think 45 minutes,
they have to make changes and ship
product. And there's two there's two
there's two flavors of that class.
There's the net flavor of the class
which effectively uses uh um Azure
DevOps as the back end and then there's
the open source flavor which you can use
whatever tools you want but the the the
the preset up tooling um it takes the
trainer
hours and hours to set up and validate
the environments that they need in order
to facilitate the open source class
because all of the tools don't actually
talk to each other, right? They don't
they aren't actually integrated. And
while in lots of contexts, open- source
is a great solution to your problem,
sometimes it's the worst solution to
your problem. Um, Azure DevOps is
totally integrated. Um, all the way from
your automated builds, updating your
work items so you know which work items
are in which build output. Um these kind
of things are invaluable when it comes
to to traceability. Um inside of Azure
DevOps, you can turn on it. It has
logging out of the box, but you could
turn on additional audit logging and it
will tell you exactly who's done what
action within the context of Azure
DevOps. So somebody's changing your
process, adding fields, removing fields,
you'll be able to see uh uh who who did
all of that. So that that governance,
security, compliance and scalability.
Again, the Windows team used this with
15,000 people in one project in uh Azure
DevOps. Um the Azure DevOps team
themselves are I think they were 900
people at one point and the developer
division at Microsoft is about 5,000
people. So the these tools have been
designed to work at scale. While the
most git repos in the world are in
GitHub, the largest get repos in the
world are in Azure DevOps. um as it's
the only thing that really um supports
that type of scale and because it
integrates fully um with Entra ID um
because it was designed that way
that security compliance and scalability
is just there out of the box, right? So
you can use all of the things you would
expect to be able to use within that
within that context.
So if you need scalability, security and
compliance built in,
let me help you build that in with Azure
DevOps and apply governance within the
context of your DevOps strategy.