automation plays a massive role in
enabling your your your your teams to
develop faster and more effectively
right automation is almost
the the thing that supports your ability
to do that and you should automate
everything if it can be automated it
should be automated if it can't be
automated you want to do the work in
your product to enable that thing to be
automated right so automated deployments
automated testing I I use aure devops as
as an example a lot because they've done
a lot of this work and hit a lot of
these problems one of the things that
they started doing was they wanted to
automate the the the changing of
security right so on every deployment
every security key every certificate
everything is refreshed
every environment every server you know
so infrastructure is code everything is
refreshed so you never
deploy they never deploy to upgrade the
version of their service on an existing
environment they build a new environment
and put that in and take the old
environment out right and these these
sorts of
automations enable you to continuously
be as slick as
possible right and it means
that one thing that's really important
to understand is that humans suck at
following a set of steps in the same way
every time that's what robots are for
right robots follow a set of steps
continuously that's what automation is
automation follows a set of steps and
always follows it the same way and
always follows all of the steps right so
if you get an exception or you a problem
there's a problem with the steps right
um when humans are following a set of
steps manually for example then you
don't know whether the problem is with
the set of steps or the problem is with
the human following the
steps and that's a risk you don't need
it's absolutely a risk you don't need so
a great example of that is the night
Capital group in the US it was a company
in the US they had 450 million in the
bank at the beginning of the day and
they were doing a deployment of of of a
new new version of their system and a
lot of a lot of things were not quite
right they were repurposing some some
code in their product they were H doing
doing a bunch of silly things because
they didn't have good quality but they
also were doing a manual deployment and
the the engineer that did the deployment
deployed to six out of the seven servers
that they had
so the system then started behaving
oddly because six of the servers had the
correct code and one of the servers
didn't have the correct code so if you
can imagine a load balancing situation
where you're trying to you're trying
you're looking at the system it's not
working it's not functioning properly
but you can't figure out why cuz some
calls are working and some calls are not
and it looks kind of random because it's
the load balancer that's load balancing
between the servers it took them all day
to figure it out but they'd started
losing thousands of dollars every second
and with 450 million in the bank at the
beginning of the day by the end of the
day they had to file for chapter 11
bankruptcy they were listed in the New
York Stock Exchange which is why we know
what the problem was because they had to
file that as part of their bankruptcy
filing that would have been
prevented by automation it would have
been prevented by automated testing it
would have been prevented by automated
deployment
it would have been prevented by
automated checks a more recent one that
had a massive Global impact was Cloud
strike right that would have been
prevented by automation it would have
prevented by automated deployment it
would have been prevented by automated
checks it would have been prevented by
these types of capabilities that we're
talking about as you increase the number
of deployments that you do you're forced
to deal with these types of scenarios
right how do I roll out to a smaller
group of people so that I can figure out
whether one of my favorite quotes is
from a gentleman called Brian Harry
Brian Harry was the product unit manager
for the Azure devops team so he ran that
whole developer division at Microsoft
for many years and his his one of his
mantras was that there's no place like
production you know like kind of Dorothy
type of thing clicking The Red
Shoes there's no place like produ
no matter how much testing you do no
matter how much validation no matter how
much money you throw that throw at that
no matter how much time you throw at
that you're going to have production
issues you're going to have production
issues because you can't simulate
production it's not fundamentally
possible you can do your best and you
can spend an awful lot of money trying
to figure out how to simulate production
as much as possible but there's always
gaps it's not possible to simulate
production to simulate the type of
transaction simulate simulate what users
do it's not possible so a better
strategy than testing quality in is to
build quality in and if you're building
quality in you want to get that product
in front of real customers in production
as quickly as possible I I Google Google
does no Facebook it's Facebook I was
thinking of Facebook do a really
interesting thing where when a
developers rolling out their their new
version of the the the the product they
have a point in time when a call into
Facebook is executed twice it's executed
with the current production version and
then it's executed with the new version
that's not in production yet so it
execute execute execute execute execute
execute and then they can turn up the
dial and go from a small like 10,000
users up to 10 million users up to 100
million users doing this and developers
can see the
Telemetry for what's happening with this
is it is it performing well is it doing
the right thing is it having similar you
know comparing the output from the two
and what they what they they actually do
is they do it completely automated so
the time from a developer committing a
new capability to it replacing this
production capability that's there is as
I understand about 13 12 to 13 minutes
and that's with full test Suite full
regression full validation of do they
operate the same way do they have the
same output that we need do they work in
that contact do they perform and scaled
out across the entire platform in about
13 minutes so they can have these small
changes small fixes go out really
quickly and then when they work on
bigger things perhaps they're using
feature Flags or they're using other
capability
so automation that's an automated
process automation is
absolutely critical to your ability and
your product's ability to to have fast
reliable the fast reliable ability to
add features fast reliable ability to
deal with problems to deal with
surprises and opportunities as they
arise in your Market