what is
caman there
are lots of different definitions of
caman and there are lots of
misunderstandings about what cban
is and it's at its
core um caman is a
strategy not an actual system of
delivering stuff so that's that's what
one of the common misunderstandings of
cban is that it's a system of delivering
stuff it's not it's a strategy to help
you understand your existing system of
delivering
stuff and help you optimize that system
of delivering stuff so quite often I'll
I'll sometimes describe it as a meta
process right it's a process that lets
you monitor a process which just messes
with people's heads but effectively um
canman brings the the the the the some
rigor and some metrics and some analysis
of those
metrics to allow you or your team or
your
organization to look at any system and
what's happening in that
system and um adapt it in a good way
right so you can see when we make a
change to the system how does that
affect the data how does that affect the
flow of work through that system and if
you've made a positive impact you keep
doing that thing and if you've made a
negative impact you you stop doing that
thing right go back to the old way so um
you could also say that caman is a work
limited pool system but that's a little
bit nobody understands that terminology
the easiest way to describe it is it's a
way of looking at your existing system
and helping you as an individual ask
more interesting question
questions about how that system goes
together in order to have a more optimal
system to have work full through your
system more effectively right so caman
uh a cban strategy can be
applied to any system doesn't matter
what the system is if the stuff going
through a system uh whether that is um a
checkout at supermarket right that's a
system with stuff flowing through it or
um your engineering team and you've got
work flowing through it or your creative
team and you've got work flowing through
it it doesn't matter what your system is
cban brings that caman strategy that you
apply brings a little bit of rigor to
that system and some metrics that allow
you to monitor that system uh so for
example one one of one of the key things
that happens at the beginning of any
cand discussion is that you you you
create what cbang calls a definition of
workflow right all that means is you
write down how you work that's it that's
all the definition of workflow is you
you you've got your way of working for a
particular thing that you do it could be
a team with work going through it it
could be a a a machine that processes
something it could be
a check out a supermarket right and you
write down the way everything works in
that system cuz what what a lot of
people even just the act of doing that
can create optimizations in the system
um
because if you've got five people
working in a system and you've never
written down how that system
works what do you think the chances are
that everybody working in that system
uses the same terminology makes the same
same or similar decisions applies the
same rules to playing the game H yeah
that's a great example actually I like
that one as well so if you if you went
out and and and bought Monopoly I'm not
suggesting it by the way there are way
better games than that but if you did
buy because it's the most common thing
right you can find it in every Super
Market if you went out and bought
Monopoly and you
immediately tore up the rule
book and you just guessed how to play
the game and you had four people playing
the game and everybody just guessed
based based and Monopoly is a good one
because everybody knows how Monopoly
kind of works right everybody knows how
monoply kind of
works would would everybody be playing
the same game would everybody be playing
by the same rules would everybody have
the same understanding of the mechanisms
of the game and how it's How how it
actually works no they wouldn't right
they would they would each come up with
their own way of doing it and if you've
ever been at one of those family dues
where you've got Monopoly out you argue
over how the rules work you argue as a
group as a family about how you should
play the game because you're not you've
not agreed as a group how to play it
right that's that's what the rule book
that comes with a game is it's here's
the way you play the game so what what's
where's the rule book for your team for
the way your team Works where's the rule
book when a new team member comes in do
they also just make up how they work and
then you tell them when they're doing it
wrong and hopefully they end up figuring
out how to do it right doesn't make any
sense you write it down so what that
typically what that typically looks like
we we've all see what what what a lot of
people do is they draw a board on the
wall right or or in jir or in Azure
devops and it has a bunch of columns and
they call that
cat that's not a cand strategy that's
just a board right anybody can have a
board and have work flow through the
board part of the campan is deciding
agreeing what that work what that what
that workflow
is right and once you've agreed what
that workflow is you can and then um
apply some metrics and monitor what's
going on in that
workflow right and once you're
monitoring what's going on in that
workflow right just looking at the data
is not enough empiricism remember right
you have to actively manage the work
that's going through the system so you
actively make choices about what is
happening within the system in order to
to to to optimize the outcome
and then you're going to look at the
data to improve the system right so you
look at the data and then you actively
make changes to the workflow so you've
written down how you think you work
right now right that's where you start
that's why they there's an expression
they use in camman which is start start
from where you are right that's that's
the expression so where you are is what
you do right now so write down what you
do right
now that's your current definition of
workflow you build the board you
visualize your work in process your work
that's going on and then you start using
it and you're like oh crap we didn't
think about this oh oh oh oh that
doesn't quite work like that so you
start making changes so that it more
accurately reflects your definition of
workflow and then because you're
visualizing your work you start noticing
things humans are really good at visual
uh uh um seeing when things aren't quite
right or the way you think they should
be and then you can go look at the data
and go no no no no we should actually
change this we shouldn't have two
columns we should have one or we
shouldn't have one column we should have
two and then you make those decisions
you're changing your workflow you're
actively managing your work and you're
changing your workflow and that's what
creates the the the the the the the this
it's not really a cycle like a Sprint is
but it's a continuous Improvement Loop
right of optimizing your process making
a little change did we make it better
yes a awesome let's let's see what's
going okay we use it for a while okay
but this is still broken this doesn't
work right okay well let's fix it let's
try something different okay now does
that work right yeah yeah yeah that
works great right so this this this
application of It's actually an
application of Little's law you can go
look that up later but this application
of uh um a cand strategy to any system
will help improve it if your current
system of work is failing you then you
would benefit from creating and applying
a cranb strategy don't wait the sooner
you start the sooner you'll improve get
in touch below