so the question is how does a scrum team
decide on a Sprint goal
if you were to look in the Sprint guide
it says it just happens but we all know
that's not going to be true right it
doesn't just magically pop into people's
ideas
uh some people would attest
that
the developers and the product owner
work together during the Sprint to come
up with a Sprint goal and I would say
that's partially true I feel like if you
walk into your Sprint planning and you
don't already know or don't already have
an idea about what your Sprint goal is
going to be you're already at a
disadvantage I would normally discuss
what a probable Sprint goal for the next
Sprint would be at my Sprint review with
my stakeholders I'd probably be talking
about
um what it is we should be working on
next what does that look like how does
that fit into the strategy so when I do
walk into
Sprint planning and we already have an
idea which direction we're going and
then perhaps we're writing we're writing
the Sprint goal right we have an idea
about what it should be and now we've
got to get it down on paper we've got to
quantify it and then we've got to select
the items that go towards it I can
definitely see circumstances where you
walk into Sprint planning and you don't
know up front what it's going to be
perhaps stakeholders just dropped a
bombshell on you at the Sprint review
perhaps the market just dropped a
bombshell on you at the Sprint review or
after perhaps you just don't know yet
right it's just too up in the air and
you you you you didn't know enough and
it's going to be a really long Sprint
planning because we've got to figure it
out
um but how does the team decide on a
Sprint goal they collaborate between the
product owner and the developers with
significant input from the stakeholders
from with significant input from the
market in the business contact next
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility