one of the key aspects of a caman
strategy is improving the system
improving your workflow so after you've
defined what your workflow is you've
written down how you're going to uh work
your system and you've started actively
monitoring uh the work that is underway
you'll hopefully start seeing
patterns if we're using the metrics from
the flow metrics from a cand strategy
then we should be able to see when
things are sitting around for too long
and they're too old we should be able to
see patterns of delivery we should be
able to see um groupings of things that
are perhaps not quite where we expect
them to be on the graphs that we might
use to visualize that data and that
allows
us to ask more interesting questions it
allows us
to lift the carpet and see in the dark
see in the dark that's a great a cban
strategy is like
a torch shining the light in the
darkness of your system to see where
things are broken where things aren't
working as optimally as they could be to
see what's going on on where it would be
opaque normally um this is especially
true for teams doing scrum scrum has no
metrics at all um and the metrics that I
would always recommend would be the
caman flow metrics right because cban is
designed as something that can be used
to monitor any system it's a monitoring
tool it's not the system itself it's the
tool you use to observe the system think
about if you were building software and
you wanted to understand which features
of your product your customers were
using so that you could choose which
parts of the product to continue to
invest in and which not how would you do
that well you'd need to put some hooks
into your application and collect a
bunch of telemetry and then analyze the
data right so you can see what's going
on you need to increase transparency and
a cand strategy is that tool for any
system so regardless of whether scrum is
your system that might be your starting
point or that might be where you jump to
right you might start from over here but
you jump to scrum or you've got a system
that you just made up right that's
totally cool that's what lots of people
do we have a system that we just made up
then we can use
caman to gain insights and understanding
on what what's going on in this system
by monitoring it by collecting some
Telemetry on how our work happens so
that we can see better what's going on
it's it's it's I don't understand why
teams try
and manage their system from a position
of opacity right they can't see what's
going on they're looking into the fog of
war and they can't see the problems
and a cbad strategy and particularly the
flow metrics part of a cand strategy and
the visualization of the work remove
that fog of War so you can see what's
going on you can actually see when
things aren't working properly and it's
obvious look here's a problem here I can
see it it's visually triggering my brain
and I can see it so hopefully being able
to see all these problems will encourage
you to actually do something actually
make a change and we're effectively not
implementing a cand strategy of we're
not improving the workflow right imp
improving and making changes to the
system in order to see the numbers
change in a more positive or more
likable manner right so caman supports
continuous Improvement by giving you the
the the the torch to shine on the
problem The View through it's your radar
that lets you see through the fog of war
and be able to make better decisions if
you're struggling to create create a
pool based system of work then we can
help you we provide worldclass cand
training from Pro caman as well as
Consulting and coaching for teams trying
to implement a campan strategy if you're
a scrum team then I we always recommend
bringing in flow metrics as a
complimentary practice and have cbang
classes from scrum.org as well