hello hello good morning Luca oh good
afternoon
actually it's afternoon for me the
afternoon for Luka yeah it's also
afternoon and there's Mona hello
Mona the serial test
taker oh D I just signed up to the new
course and I'm doing that on a 31st
why the product
break don't don't ask why and this
weekend I'm doing another course and
next weekend I'm doing another C don't
and I'm actually to get a really good
deal just before Christmas so the three
days before Christmas Even the weekend
I'm doing a three-day coaching course
because it was half price because no one
else wants to do that over Christmas do
they apart from
me some unless the rest of the globe
that don't celebrate
Christmas sometimes the way to do
it and luuka it's been a
while uh
yeah uh I I haven't done any
courses uh in the meantime but I've
started applying uh
ebm on on quite regular basis yeah uh I
have some strategic
plannings in the next uh in the next few
few weeks so uh and I've already started
one but it's it's an iterative planning
so we're going to be we started last
month and I hope we'll finish it by the
end of this
one
ABM is the great Direction high five my
new friend yeah I like it very
much especially after Martin taught us
how to how to use the metrics ah when
the expert supports you now more and
more things are getting better right
yeah I think that hard the hardest part
is is picking is choosing metrics right
because
although ebm has a bunch of example
metrics they might not be quite right
for your org and trying to figure out
how to and get people to do it as well
it's super hard i' i' I've um I've been
using the liberators uh scrum team
survey okay and getting people to fill
it out is an absolute nightmare
really absolute nightmare I've got I've
got a I I I'm doing a a
psmo at the moment and it's a it's a
immersive
psmo and they have four teams and all
it's the the the product owners and and
scrum Masters that are in the training
and I said how about I just give you
three months
of this Liberator scrum team
survey and we're two weeks into them
sending out the URLs to fill it out and
there's three people on between the four
teams that filled it out
[ __ ] it's how they present it internally
and I can't see that part right if it's
here's the survey people I don't give a
[ __ ] right if it's if it's here's
something that can help us identify how
we can help you then it might get more
push
but I mean usually when I'm uh giving
out a survey of any
sort uh I tell the people who I expect
to fill it out that this this survey
serves what we want to achieve in this
this and this way and and then usually
they're collaborative but uh next week
I'm starting with with a series of
Discovery interviews for uh for this
strategic planning which they think is
going to be a strategic planning I know
it's not going to be a strategic
planning just possibly some alignment
sessions or whatever so they uh they did
strategic planning last
year uh it's a small uh it's a small
Media company they publish uh uh they
publish a website and it's 15 of them or
something like that 15 or 16 so they did
the strategic planning last
year and the guy who uh who facilitated
the planning he gave them a
survey uh of 30 pages
long and they filled it
out so we had this sync call and they're
like okay Strate you don't plan on any
surveys and I'm like if you don't want
to do surve
totally fine by me it's 15 of you I can
do 15 Discovery
interviews uh in the end they're going
to pay for it
so yeah get totally fine by me uh but I
I I I didn't get why they are so uh so
against surveys and then they sent me
the the last year's materials and I was
like my eyes were
bleeding and then I I called and I said
okay no surveys for you till at least
2025 you did your you paid your
du yeah service service yeah it's a
great topic by the way for another maybe
talk and webcast I also have my own I
believe some interesting stories what
about we start with today's topic shall
we okay so I'm going to share my
screen where am I here I so uh today I'm
welcoming you on behalf of Martin
hinwood and myself and we are going to
talk a little bit about agile leadership
and agile
transformation uh so during our webcast
ER there is a possibility to to write
questions uh you have the options to I
believe the chat should be working so
you can uh use chat you can use
um the option with Q&A so um the plan is
as follows whenever you have any
question feel free to um to ask feel
free to to write it and uh after my
short talk like around 15 minutes or so
I'm happy to together with Martin of
course to uh to answer that questions to
to have deeper
conversations um I hope that my
presentation will trigger some of your
questions so uh can you see my
screen yes no yes you stuck to me yes
wonderful so let's do it and our today's
Story start with my window why my window
is important because as you can see on
the left hand side of the slide we have
some some things happening which is
pretty pretty close to to uh to the flat
to the apartment where I live some
construction work is happening and when
I was looking through that window I I
realized that there are different people
there with different
helmets and those helmets will play an
important role in our today's uh today's
Journey so majority of the people have
yellow helmet Ms some of them have blue
greens uh but the people that we will
focus on today are the the owners of
white
helmets why they are
important well because those helmets
bring some important message about this
process so the owners of white helmets
are uh different kinds different levels
of managers
um people who inspect direct the process
and how does this process look like well
uh White uh helmet owners they uh they
take uh this process very strong in
their hands they pay attention to the
process every single day there are some
meetings in Polish we call them oprava
which means briefing checkin they talk
to the team they tell them what to do uh
the team focus is focusing on doing
everyday great job towards uh towards
building um next floor towards towards
building next Parts they are just um
following the rules there are people who
own the rules and in fact for that
special group certain mechanisms work so
for in instance if we will be really
focused and they we will be lucky not
many people will be sick most likely we
will be able to finish this current
floor quickly and we may get an
incentive so long story short the more
bricks the quicker we build the more
money potentially is is there on the
table so those are the tools that those
white helmets owners can can use and
based on some conversations that I had
in the past they might be might be very
very useful in that
context but this is just my window right
what is happening in the world when you
when you look at different places well a
lot of things is happening so on one
hand we have uh a lot of automation
robotics happening so by the way this is
the picture uh leftand top one from from
um the work that was uh actually I was
involved in so this is this is a robotic
robotic company from Poland that is
helping automate uh tedious repetitive
work in
warehouses uh a lot of Industries are
already automated to such an extent that
actually a lot of manual work was
replaced we have code we have
applications we have software products
that helped improve people's life and
they uh they made um a lot of work that
that is repetitive that is resembles
itself we we see some patterns that work
started to be uh to be replaced by
machines by automation but different
tools not to mention the AI thing that
is happening a lot of fantastic powerful
tools what does it mean for us well what
is left for for
humans ER brings important topic to our
table so this
work is a bit different we need a people
to be very creative to take the best
what the humankind brought to this world
so ability to create innovative
solutions ability to think out of the
box ability to connect certain dots that
maybe they haven't been connected so far
so what does it mean to the companies
well seems like although a lot of
interesting challenges are coming for uh
for for different experts different
Specialists employees are getting
frustrated so here you have a bunch of
data taken from different service from
uh Gallop Institute and what we can see
here well oh well only 22% of employees
truly trust in the leadership of their
organization
13% of people claim that their direct
supervisor or in general ma management
leadership those people are the reasons
why they are leaving the job if you dig
into the details there are more reasons
that are directly or
indirectly uh influenced by managers by
the
leaders so uh we also have a huge impact
on employees
engagement uh we also know
unfortunately that many many of the
companies fail they fail to uh to stay
in the market they fail on their Journey
uh to
succeed and seems like we have people
who can change those numbers because
well my personal feeling is those
numbers are a bit scary
so why we are meeting today and why we
believe this topic is important for many
of us because guess what we are not
robots and I can tell you as a person
who holds PhD in robotics yes we are not
the robots we are not the robots and our
work is now getting more and more
sophisticated we can offer a lot to the
companies and we need people people
right people to help us flourish to help
take the best out of us out of experts
to create fantastic company to build
amazing
products fun
fact yesterday um one of the biggest if
not the biggest ad conferences in Poland
ended I had a pleasure to
participate in that conference I had my
own Workshop
and you know what is one of the most
important
findings some people were missing in
that conference we have plenty of scrum
Masters agile coaches uh some product
owners product managers but the people
that we should start focus on and have a
great collaboration with them they were
missing so we are speaking about manager
leaders directors and so on so with that
uh we would love would love to uh to
advertise like there are people most
likely uh around you in your
organization that can influence the
organization can help create right
environment and the numbers that we just
went through they are telling us
directly there is a huge opportunity for
improvements
there
so seems like a lot of things changed
and although some of the people still
wear white
helmets a lot of managers should forget
about the helmet and replace it replace
it with true agile
leadership what does it mean for for the
company for the people
uh well the tools techniques that our
white white helmet holders uh use we
should change them we should
adapt uh we are going to help people go
through a challenging Journey we are
going to show them direction we are
going to lead by example and help them
make more
decisions use this fantastic parts that
they bring into the
company if you don't believe me
fantastic don't do that let's take a
look at data let's like take a look at
experts so pretty already I would say
pretty old book by Daniel Daniel pink so
drive the surprising truth what truly
motivates us give us very short three
answers to that questions and this is
fantastic book if you haven't had a
chance to read I strongly recommend
because it's not based on what the
author thinks it's based on the research
so we have our answer autonomy Mastery
and purpose this is what truly motivates
us if the companies want to benefit from
hiring amazing talents if they want to
uh retain those great talents
they need to to go back to basics and
understand how to create this
environment so what do our teams need
well we have uh here uh we have here an
idea so if we
compare autonomy Master autonomy master
and purpose from Daniel pink we have
clear boundaries that will help us in
self-management support to grow because
we want to become a learning
organization and it's not just a
buzzword it's about right conditions for
creating hypothesis for conducting
experiments and for recognizing that a
lot of those experiments will end up
with this is not the right direction for
us we need to remember that learning is
a journey on a very bumpy road this is
the truly learning
organization not just waiting for always
amazing results how we are supposed to
create amazing results in in a very
complex
environment we need a purpose so this is
extremely important motivational
aspect what do the leaders managers can
or should do they should provide
Direction so they can help to create
company Mission Vision make sure that
the teams understand their goals and
their goals are consistent with
company's mission and vision so if you
ask someone uh who is just you know
cleaning the floor in let's say uh
robotic company why your your work is
Meaningful why why is it important
you want to hear I'm enabling a lot of
companies for instance logistic
companies to automate tedious repetitive
work right so understanding that my job
matters and I'm doing important stuff
for others not only for myself but also
seeing the value that we are bringing
seeing this
customer uh and what what we are
actually doing to change their lives
this is also very very important and can
build amazing
motivation so uh a quick a quick test
for you or maybe a quick question who's
your favorite Barista do you prefer a
smiling committed person uh willing to
chat willing to support or rather um
grumpy head trying to discourage you
from ordering
coffee I guess that you would love to
rather avoid a cat and have a nice kind
supportive person you will be most
likely going back to the company where
you believe people care about you about
your problems about delivering solutions
for you and this is a powerful
difference that can make a really
competitive huge change in your
company show the people help them
understand that their work is important
is Meaningful and help uh help them help
them be a part of what is what is
happening that that commitment and they
they great motivation can bring the huge
difference so what is one of the best
things when what what I see and actually
it happened to me recently uh I was in
the pop everyone was drinking a beer and
I had a stomach ache and I really really
needed mint tea so I asked the waiter uh
could you please uh could you please
make a mint tea for me he does not have
any proper uh any proper tools and uh
ingredients prepared for that but
instead of telling me qu qu qu qu qua
it's a pop qu qu Qua we don't have mint
tea qu qu qu he decided to tell to tell
me I will figure it out and I will find
a
way and in a five minutes he's coming
back and instead of using mintty leaves
for for uh moito he created a really
nice tea for me and this is the example
of ego Behavior so instead of blindly uh
blindly following rules that are
actually um actually protecting you from
making the best possible
decisions you interpret the rules you
think about what you actually can do and
you find the solution and I would go
back to that pop because I love such
people last but not least important
Point why we need agile leaders because
even if we speak about agile
transformation seems like in some of the
environments people are even tired of
listening to Agile agile
transformation let's
transform think about it even
differently forget about the wording
what we want to do we want to deliver
valuable products we want to create
happy teams committed teams that will uh
will uh make customers happy happy with
our uh with our product if we just stick
to here is Scrum Master here is product
owner here's your team do your job uh
this is another team do your job that
will be fine most likely we will land in
so-called local
Optimum we need to work
together and this includes great
collaboration with Leaders with managers
to find global Optimum so that we can
maximize the value of the whole company
working
together the challenging part because um
I don't want to make a wrong impression
that it's yes it's simple yes let's do
it it's very difficult to sing the right
song uh so let it go and forget about
the white
helmet um however we believe it is
possible um and we are happy to to help
you find Find Your Way help you um when
it comes to collaborating with your
leaders
managers so with
that I'm happy to start questions Q&A
session and maybe I will stop sharing
and I will see you better right now yes
it's a
amazing so do we have any
questions challenge
ourselves Luca what's your
experience of uh
um trying to talk to leadership about
agility uh first uh Yanna and I hope
that I'm going to pronounce it corre
correctly
dardo for the presentation thank you I
spent some lovely time in Poland yeah
eating perogi
mostly uh uh yeah that uh what you asked
me is what I wanted to ask uh how how to
get into their heads because uh the uh
the best the best slide uh was the Let
It Go and the white
helmet because they what's my experience
is they would like both they'd like
agility and to remain in
control uh so uh
just earlier today I um uh I had this
conver I had this conversation and
uh I Tred to convey the the
message uh that uh what we want to
build uh
in in in this transformation is a
support structure and you had something
like that also in in your in your
presentation so that that was like I
felt validated a lot uh I was like you
know uh when you when you grow
tomatoes and then you can put a net or a
stick uh that they use to yeah to grow
and I was like so that's what we are
going that's what we're trying to do and
uh the manager is like but yeah then but
then we can't steer the the the process
and like well do you want to steer in
the process for the rest of your life or
you want to build something that's
sustainable and uh that can let you go
and have at least two weeks of vacation
exactly yes every year yes that's a very
valid point so uh I used to work very
closely to to some of the sea level
groups because the companies were were
willing to help me see the word through
their eyes so um I can tell you that
what helps me is that rephrasing what
you said so instead of thinking like
they want control there is some
something else underlying reason and
what I've learned is uh trust issues no
coincidence in the scrum guide we are
saying directly about trust so this is
something that is very typical H there
are also some sometimes old habits or
lack of proper training tools so I
recall a company where the majority of
experts were trained using great
trainings having mentors and so on and
when I realized that uh all top
management and middle uh middle leaders
middle level leaders they have never
attended any course on leadership
some of the things you know became clear
so they haven't had a chance to see
things through different perspective so
um what what really works for me is to
to gain a trust in the collaboration and
asking them what are your worries when
you wake up in the morning before you
start work what are the first questions
that you set right and for instance they
care um startup issue uh we have
sponsors and they are asking questions
they demand results and we need to show
something otherwise we will lose money
so having this conversation with them
was was very helpful when we we started
to uh to talk about their problems
directly and in fact we introduced in
that
company well to a pretty high level
radical Candor so they've learned to
talk to the teams like hey this is the
situation if we are too pushy we are
sorry but this is the problem that we
are currently handling so when CEO for
instance organized and I helped to
facilitate lean coffee with employees
from different parts of the company that
helped him a lot to to have this
openness trust and they together were
working on Solutions so when you have
committed people you're you're typically
hiring smart people right and they
understand why you are worried it opens
a door to a completely different level
of
conversations yeah right you have to be
aware that especially when it comes to
top
management they are worried about money
and not because they are dragons that I
want to have give me more gold right uh
but because they care that this money is
needed to run the company they want to
pay salaries to their
employees
yeah yeah that that's true uh also
another problem I encountered was uh the
shop floor wants wants the
changes and the sea level wants the
changes but then there's middle
management ah I see and see that's also
and then so it it's
basically
um I always tell them okay you're
thinking of agility that's great you
want to go to a transformation that's
great it takes a lot of time and it
takes a lot of money so if you're not
sure don't do it because it's better not
to do it than to do it halfway and then
resent it for for a long
time and that's that's where they but uh
I'm I'm trying to I I like this example
of yours with With The Lean coffee
because I'm now I'm come coming to
conclusion that I have to find some
strategies to to open to open the
discussion and to give
them uh uh to give them some space and
time in which they can uh to give them
the support structure so that they could
uh get the the get to the conclusion on
their own yeah yeah thank you thank you
for sharing so I I I heard somebody
recently refer to that middle management
as the Perma
Frost right that that that kind of solid
layer you're trying to get to The Good
Earth underneath
from leadership and you're you're you're
stuck chipping away at the permafrost
trying to get the message through yeah
it's very
difficult yeah so by the way that is one
of the reasons why uh pal e course which
by the way we have in our offering is
advertised for Middle managers we' have
seen as the whole a community that uh
top management at least from time to
time they are attending some s they are
talking to each other and they got
inspired by ideas right so it might be
that even the Need For Change might be
even coming from them the teams when
hear them wow but middle managers got
lost especially when they are not
trained they feel
like we are useless right sometimes I'm
the person you know telling that
directly that I I felt useless once
right because this is what we see they
they feel uncomfortable and we help them
find the way because they are needed top
management can not do everything and
people still need great supportive
leaders it's the art to understand how
to do it
properly I think they quite often feel
sidelined yeah there's all these things
going on and the people on the ground
seem to understand it and the people up
here seem to understand they're asking
for the same things and I'm in the
middle going I don't know what this [ __ ]
is right and that's that's that can be
really difficult cuz nobody's taken the
time to to explain it to them nobody's
taken the time to to sit with them and
say this is why your job's not going
away this is the transition that you
want to make in order to enable I it's
going to be I think it's actually a
really interesting time because there's
not just the agile story now that's
putting middle management in danger
right because you you you might need 20
managers but do you need 20 leaders
right that's that's right and now ai is
coming along and taking away a lot of
the rot work from behind the scenes and
going well each individual person can
now be 60% more productive because they
don't have to do all of this manual
stuff anymore um and and it's they're
worried about their job security they're
worried about their ability to to to do
stuff I I had I I had an activity
yesterday that I had a list of um H
letters and countries associated with
letters um but in my in
my business we use Le you know like
letters for different grades of costs
plus currency and plus country code not
country name so I just fed that data
into chat
GTP and said can you switch this to
country code awesome can you apply these
currency rules to it awesome can you and
literally 20 20 less 20 less minutes I
was able to have all of the data
massaged into the format I need with all
of the information I needed looked up
and associated with it and that was like
good 4-Hour task if I had to do it
manually so those are the types of
things I don't know if you've noticed
but lots of middle managers are sitting
with their spreadsheets and filling out
their spreadsheets and editing their
spreadsheets and updating their
spreadsheets and joining this
spreadsheet with this other spreadsheet
so they get this data out and it that
stuff is all gone not yet it's it's what
would you call it it's it's it's it's
dead work walking right it's it's dead
just not everybody's CAU on to how dead
it is and it's going to be a really
interesting time for
organizations
um because what do they get all these
folks to
do that are that are that are there in
those in those in those
positions going to be
interesting there is a space to do
different things right but again
learning organizations organization is
learning and individuals are learning
right teams are learning Microsoft um
when Microsoft made a lot of changes in
that middle management
space they enabled people who had been
managers for a while you know that
expression that people are promoted to
their level of
incompetence yeah it it's it's not even
a pretend thing it's actually what
happens because people are seen as doing
a good job so they get promoted and they
keep getting promoted until they're seen
as not doing a good job anymore and then
that's where they stay so that they're
no long they should be one level below
right or two levels below cuz that's
where they're actually continuing to add
value um and Microsoft
offers anybody who's in a position to go
do the work of the position below for
the same pay as the position they were
promoted into
um in order to allow people to excel at
something
while you know we they've been given
that pay rise and then you can't just
take it away cuz that's that's bad and
lots of people when they moved to Agile
engineering teams lots of people in
leadership positions moved back down to
being Engineers working on teams helping
with the architecture doing much more
technical things
but they'd been previously promoted to
much higher levels of of of of
leadership position and I think it's
important to have a story around that as
an organization you need to have that
conversation because it's not going to
be a good idea globally just to get rid
of all the people you don't need right
all of these people being dumped onto
the market and we're going to have other
problems out of that yeah yeah indeed
and please remember this is another rule
that I share with managers and leaders
uh how you treat your ex employees or
employees that you are going to say
goodbye to this is actually a very
important feedback to your current
employees what kind of thoughts will you
trigger if you're just okay we have a
problem let's just fire people right
maybe there is a place uh for certain
movements and I I also been in that
situation with one of the managers after
a work of our collaboration
I talk talked to him and he said like
it's an amazing opportunity but I'm not
ready and the company did a great
decision they they allowed that
transition smoothly back now he's a
fantastic senior engineer in the team
and he's happy the team is Happy company
is happy because they did not uh lost a
talented
person so Mona I've seen your message in
the
chat however I'm curious would you like
to comment that is there a question
regarding
that I guess it's kind of like how do
you take them on the
journey
um you know I guess I've come from an
environment where everything is about
money you know every dollar counts and
you got a report against every
dollar and then come in somewhere where
it's a completely different and and it's
like you know they some places have done
like no product development for years
and it's okay and we've lost money and
it's
okay um and there's just not that
emphasis and drive
and there's just no alignment like as
soon as the word agil come in obviously
they've just gone don't need anything
and like they even questioning like why
I'm here just like
really um so yeah it's a bit difficult
so it's kind of trying to take them
through the Journey and going you know
these are the fundamentals these are the
basics and this is the only way you're
going to kind of Survive and Thrive and
grow I I I I I wanted to add something I
would suggest that you never mention the
words agile or scrum or any of those
things at all in your conversations
ever um it it it's while we understand
the theory
is like I might talk about
empiricism right because that's a
fundamental but the tools on top of that
are largely Irrelevant for for for for
these folks and they don't understand
what they are it's easy to explain
empiricism right it's easy to explain
but as soon as you mention any word from
scrum you've now got a 4-Hour
conversation to explain scrum so try and
avoid that terminology even loaded terms
I trying to avoid like product owner I
say product management right don't say
scrum master I say lead or um you know
some some depending on what how your
organizational structure the one of the
customers I'm in right now you're you're
either you're either a a lead or you're
a product manager or you're a team
member that's that's it squads and it's
squads not teams right yeah same here so
you use use their lexicon that comes
from Spotify spotify's fault
right use use yeah use use their
lexicon but in
introduce the fundamental theories right
because then they'll build their own
stories on top of it and maybe scrum
will fit or maybe something for magu
will fit maybe this but that's that's a
story for another day so I I I talk
about
empiricism right if asked right
empiricism I ask this all the time how
you measuring that yeah I it all the
time and also um qu questions how are
you measuring that um what are you going
to do with that data when they when they
say they're going to measure something
oh we want to add this field to this
thing what are you going to do with that
data what decisions are you going to
make differently with this data who's
going to look at and I've been in
conversations where no like they want to
add this metric to the system that's
going to impact on everybody using the
system that they have to fill it
out and they've get no answer to the
question of how they're going to use the
data and what they're going to know what
they're going to do differently based on
the results of that
data they're not thinking empirically
right empiricism is fundamentally
scientific they're not thinking about
why ask those
questions that's that's that's why
you're there right that's why um you're
you're you're you're in that position
and it it we shouldn't have to be there
right there should be no such thing as
an agile Co I think I wrote a blog post
ages ago that that agile coaches show a
systemic lack of leadership in your
organization you shouldn't need agile
coaches leaders should just
be the agile coaches that's that's who
it should be um
so I always try and think about not
being a crutch and being an
enabler yeah and have you guys faced
scenarios again I think it because it's
very new and obviously some people have
had some training around like product Le
and it's now like any decision is down
to product and everyone else is kind of
stepped back and I'm like no no no
you're just creating more silos now you
still have to collaborate and talk and
make decisions just because it's product
L doesn't mean they make all the
decisions yeah and I think again this is
a language thing that's kind of stuck
without understanding what it actually
means so how would you try and take
that I I tell people nobody cares about
their
goals the only way you get people to
care about your goals is you make it
their goals too and that doesn't mean
just telling them they have to buy it
they have to buy into it they have to
feel like it's their goal they have to
own they have to like I care about this
outcome if they don't care they don't
give a [ __ ] about your goals you know
not going to get
anywhere and that that's super hard
that's effectively marketing and sales
skills right for those people to sell
their goals their Direction their
strategy to other people it's not good
enough to be a boss anymore it just
doesn't
work sorry I stepped on that one Joan
you probably no no problem at all and
actually Mona I believe uh based on what
you said that you have a very powerful
tool option available because if your
company cares about money so um Martin
emphasized like why do you need what
you're going to do you may do something
uh
complementary calculate the cost of
doing that and ask how much value do you
believe you will get out of it this is
the strategy that helped me uh help me
prevent some of the changes in uh
people/ Finance processes uh because
they were claiming it's only 15 minutes
a week for every single specialist so I
just open you know uh the Excel sheet
years ago maybe today I will ask Chad
GPT for support but I did the math and I
told them okay this only 15 minutes will
cost you this and this amount of money
roughly
currently what kind of value do you
expect and what uh what was the fun fact
I became a product owner of a small
internal product because I offered them
that we can automate that it this will
this is my forecast I have a clear goal
I need a support of one or two engineers
in two weeks you will have a solution
automatically no longer asking people
and out of the sudden when we started
talking money it was uh conversation
with uh C Level
leadership wasn't easy but they agreed
that actually I care about company's
money and that's good
right I also think that that um having
the conversation about risks and risk
mitigation is something that is real
powerful when talking to management
and scrum in
itself tackles Risk by doing this
incremental right incremental we do
something well build what is it build
measure Val U can't remember now
but thank you thank you yeah uh so I
actually had this conversation with one
of the leaders on why we're doing this
and trying
to I've been been saying this me for
months now to to the same we have to
start
doing we can't can't plan ourself of
this the pickle we're in right now we
have to start doing stuff because uh and
that's empirism right we have to start
doing and start start learning but
there's also risk risk mitigation there
that we actually know what we're talking
about we get that
data about forecasting out uh products
how when we will done with the products
when will this and that be done so that
that's
and that conversation you can take the
risk conversation all the way from team
right up to to the CEO right everyone
knows about risk they have different
risk uh lenses on and but you can have
that risk the risk discussion with the
CFO right we're having a risk of losing
this much money then the CFO will listen
to
you so that that's that's something that
you can carry all along up the
organization if you ask me yeah and
that's the one person I've managed to
bring on board ah there that's a good
start to yeah stop the win so far
yeah so do you you can you do you have
any like tips on okay when you have to
talk to manager risk is one thing right
are there any other areas that we can
kind of lean into to make them to make
them care as Martin say to make them
care about
this um what helps me is also uh showing
them that we are making a lot of
assumptions and there are a lot of
ambiguities and this is the part of
complexity right so how how will you get
the answer in the complex world you have
to you have to try how to
try formulate an hypothesis run an
experiment so that that was also
something that uh I love including right
risks is a one powerful tool think about
what are the assumptions and I believe
we take you might even try to have this
conversation with your beloved ones try
to understand how often we are making
assumptions based on our
beliefs how do you know yna that someone
would love to read that blog post uh
because it's interesting do you have
data do you believe that there are no
already great blog posts about
that okay right you see we are making a
lot of a lot of assumptions and we have
a lot of beliefs in our backpacks it's
good to make it clear what kind of
assumptions are we
taking I like
that okay any more
questions thoughts complaints I'm polish
we love complaining I can I can take all
of your complaints if you need to
complain
Lucas coming in on camera he must have a
complaint yes give me
complaints please no the the only
complaint uh that I can uh uh give to
you since you're polish is uh zova and
p uh I see and why ZKA many people like
jka uh uh it tricked me or I was tricked
into drinking too too much of
it I see I see you know good things are
addictive yes yes I can imagine never
more basically uh but yeah thank you
this was uh this was really uh this was
really great and uh and inspiring and as
I told told you
already uh it helped me in a sense that
it validated uh uh some conclusions or
hypothesis that that I came to uh
earlier uh on on my own so uh I'm I'm
looking forward to uh to applying it and
then measuring the success of
course and yeah uh I I like uh I like
Martin what you said about uh mirroring
it's it's basically a coaching technique
isn't it you mirror their uh their
wording um you speak to speak on to
speak on their own
terms uh and not to not force uh not to
force our uh technical terms uh on them
and I'd say it it can be uh one of the
one of the strategies to um uh to
boost the success of communication with
the
management yeah
indeed I can tell you shortly another
story so there was a group of people
that were hating scrum and agile so what
my colleague did instead if instead of
as Martin proposed telling teaching
about scrum uh she asked the team after
two weeks of work three weeks of work
would you like to hear the feedback
would you like to to understand from the
users yes yes so are we inviting them
and we will show them the product yes
yes let's do that do that so
stakeholders came they were talking
about the product they gave the feedback
and you know what that was proper Sprint
review without even connecting it with
scrum and agile and they were happy
because the stakeholders said we love
that part something is strange here we
don't understand that and the team was
amazed and here you
go Sprint review without Sprint review
probably better review than a lot of
teams have exactly yeah
absolutely proper wording right yeah
then you can just say would you like to
do that again in a couple of
weeks yes let's do it and they did they
they are they are just meeting with
people interested in the product this is
the
name so what was the outcome of what was
the outcome of this uh of these uh these
sneaky little Sprint views that you put
in there uh sneaky yeah sneaking in the
Sprint views uh I mean uh was the
customer happy uh was the team more
happy yes yeah because team uh you know
whenever you show the team that someone
cares about their their outcomes you may
potentially increase motivation the
team's motivation increased and uh
stakeholders are were also starting bu
to build trust with a team right they
are showing something valuable to us
they are asking for the feedback so if
you think about great proper Sprint
review this is what was uh was happening
there without connecting to scrum
without vocabulary but with exactly the
same purpose yeah exactly the same
outcomes that should be expected from
sprin TR
yeah we just rename everything in scrum
and just go for no I'm just
kidding you know that that's the tool
right and ability to find the common
ground is I believe oh my God I will
tell that as a PST this is the most
important thing right to find a common
ground to focus on valuable goals to be
committed team willing to work together
this is actually the essence of
agility not fancy names right they never
were supposed to be fancy
yeah it's
true yeah great group I love trainings
in small groups because everyone has a
lot of space for discussions well and it
feels safer as well right because
there's not a bunch of other people that
we don't
know yeah natural Vegas rule right well
chin in Polish what happens in choin
stays in
choin so Mo Moana all of our all of or
many of our new classes are using the
immersive
format um which is the multi-week
sessions um so I I guess it's not as
conducive for I want my I want to pass
my certificate as quickly as possible
Right but I think it's much more
valuable from the perspective
of I I I want to I want to learn the
stuff and figure out how to apply it as
well and get help with applying it um so
I know it would be a a longer investment
right but um I think it can be more
value at the end of the
day but also sometimes you just want the
certificate
right we have short classes
too no I definitely think it'll be like
useful and I think like through like the
courses that I've done it's just like
even building like group of people that
you can kind of connect with and kind of
share thoughts and challenges it's been
really useful just to kind of have drop
in
sessions um but yeah but it's just it's
just very interesting when you worked
somewhere for four or five years and you
worked and you've implemented and it's
you know and you go somewhere else and
it's completely different and it's
completely different
challenges but at the same times there
are things that are exactly the same
right yeah this it a lot of the problems
that pop up are kind of the
same uh yeah there
both well I for one need to drop I have
an Azure devops drop in clinic for a
customer in a few minutes um although I
see people have already started joining
but there you go people join early um
it's because it's set it 5 minutes past
the hour it's one of those weird ones
the the the people go oh it must be at
the time so um hopefully you
enjoyed the
discussion um and if you do if you do
know know anybody who's interested uh
there is the the agile
leadership class the immersive one
starts in a couple of weeks 14 days
something like that uh two weeks on
Friday two weeks on Friday I think um
and Joanna is going to
be the awesome trainer for that one you
you won't you won't be stuck with me so
you'll be you'll get an
upgrade more hair not sure if more
experience definitely not but different
perspectives for
sure but I'm I'm going to I'm going I'm
going to drop off H Joanna if you can
just close the meeting when you're when
you're done yes well do awesome thank
you so much bye thank you thank you bye
bye
byebye