so what what what is it this can this
devops Consulting thing that we offered
um I've been doing devops consulting for
quite some time
um I started back in 2010 when I moved
to the US providing as a devops
consultant I was employed as a devops
consultant by a boutique consulting
company in the US in Seattle
and I did Consulting for three years
operating out of there and when I moved
back to the UK I started offering that
that service to to myself to other
customers and it really takes a bunch of
different forms right some of it is just
helping people understand devops so I do
I do presentations I do workshops I do
just conversations right around devops
what it is what it means to
organizations
um quite often that's with leadership
teams it depends depends who who turns
up right but I also also offer a lot of
or to have done a lot of Consulting in
the Azure devops space a lot because of
my background as a Microsoft MVP in
devops right within your devops space
and my history with the Azure devops
team and Azure devops Consulting
um so quite a lot of people that come to
me definitely have a a a Microsoft tint
in their way of working it's not
exclusive right it's not required but
that's that quite often happens if
you're known as an expert in a
particular tool then people tend to
gravitate towards you that way which is
a lot of fun and I love talking about
Azure devops and how it works so some of
that Consulting is tool based right what
is azure devops how does it work how can
it help an organization how can they use
it better how can they uh help people
and their teams adopt it better
um but the tools and techniques the
techniques that I talk about are can be
applied to any tool whether you're using
jira right or team City these are all
tools that I've worked with and helped
companies with as well
um
and
as your devops Consulting kind of takes
a number of forms because there's a bit
in potentially understanding what it is
that you're you're doing some
organizations want
um like a report right where are we are
we actually doing devops do we actually
generally understand what it is
um and I've come in and done uh uh they
used to be called dpses Microsoft had a
name for it because there was some
funding for it for for Enterprises uh
deployment planning services and
effectively it's it's a state of devops
report what is the current state of
devops in your organization and I would
come in uh spend a week with folks in
your organization interviewing them
talking about how they're building
products uh uh their ways of working
um and then I would build up report on
what's the current state of devops in
your organization and uh what are the
things that you're going to need to
tackle what are the opportunities for
improvement places where things aren't
going so well
um and what if you only did three things
what are the top three things that's
quite a common one I've done that a lot
both devops and agile right that's
that's the same same story Works in both
places
um but ultimately
Consulting is about coming in and
actually provoking change inside of an
organization so the most common thing
that I do is just coming in and talking
to folks got one recently
um kind of on a little bit of a retainer
with a with a large manufacturing
organization in Switzerland they're all
over the place but the people I work
with are in Switzerland
um and we we we we talk that's that's
really all it is for for from my
perspective we talk I answer questions
we engage on different topics we
understand how talking about how they're
doing work how they could maybe change
the way they do work how could they
change the way they do the work better
then they go off and try things in their
organization they change the way they do
things see if it works for them and then
come back for another session with more
more feedback more ideas more problems
and we discuss and and figure them out
um I have quite a few customers that are
in that that that that category so
that's that's
the devops Consulting
um I also provide some technical help
and support that's maybe something of of
note I actually still write code today
that's Martin still writes code yep uh I
I I uh builds built
support and maintain a product that
allows you to migrate data around in
Azure devops so taking a project and
splitting it or merging projects
whatever it is that you want to be able
to do
um been working around since 2016 before
then 2015 2016s when I started that that
product and lots of people use it so
sometimes they have questions about how
they should use it what capabilities
does it have
um can they get any help and support
with it do they can they get training
for it so I do provide that as well and
I kind of include that in devops right
because it's part of that that they're
they're doing devops stuff and they want
help with their devops stuff
um so really it's quite broad devops is
this very broad Consulting area where
um I might just talk to people or I
might go all the way to helping them
with their tooling and helping them
figure out how to use it better
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility