so one of the Seven Virtues of agility
is Chastity and in in our context in the
agile context at Chassy is really about
taking taking your time right don't jump
into um thinking that you've been
successful doing uh uh we're doing agile
and we're going to we're going to take
all the things you want to think about
the impact and the effect within your
organization of the changes that you
make so there are there are loads of
implications of agile that go far beyond
the actual
mechanisms um for your
organization um so things for example
like the
democratization of the workplace
involving more people in the decision
making is something that you need to
take time over you need to think about
how you're going to change your
organization you need to involve the
people in your
organization in that story otherwise
they're not going to be interested uh in
what it is you're trying to achieve
nobody really cares about your goals
they care about their own goals and the
way you get them to care about your
goals is you make their goals your goals
right you you they want to be part of
that story so taking your time and
looking at
um there there are tools out there uh
like
um uh open space agile that allows you
to
involve the whole of your organization
in your decision-making progress uh
process as you move towards a greater
degree of agility and that uh H time and
thoughtfulness and
inclusivity is going to be the thing
that enables you to get the most out of
your agile strategies if you are having
difficulty getting the most out of the
Seven Virtues of agility then my team at
naked agility can help you or find a
consultant coach or trainer who can it's
essential for you to find help as soon
as you can and not wait use the links
below to get in touch because you don't
just need agility you need naked agility