so how easy is it to get started with
caman to to have a pilot to to try
something it's it's it's super easy pick
a team apply a cman strategy it's really
that that easy um sometimes it's
difficult to convince people uh people
behave how they're measured so normally
it's the the the the traditional metrics
and measures within the organization
that prevent you from doing some of
these things but there are tools out
there that can help if most folks today
most are probably using either jir or a
your devops uh to to to manage their
work since most of us work from home
quite a lot of the time right uh so we
don't have the boards on the wall
anymore we don't have the opportunity
for that um so
using get get get access to some of the
data analytics uh in both jira and uh
aure devops and look at some of the data
look at the the camand data look at the
graphs um and see what's going on in
your current system right that's that's
see what's going on and then get
together and run a workshop run a
workshop on Define creating your
definition of workflow defining how the
way it is you work just now start to
have those conversations but don't think
absolutely do not think you can have a
two-hour workshop and then you're done
that two-hour Workshop is just a start
for for starting people thinking about
how they work because most most people
don't really understand how they work
they don't understand how they work cuz
they just do it they just do it the way
they do it they've never had to write it
down they've never had to discuss it
with each other and you start having
very interesting conversations with the
team that Arc of conversations kind of
needs to play out right in order to get
to consensus of this is the way we agree
how we work once you've got that
agreement you're you're you're you're
doing caman but you can just start with
the
metrics right Sometimes using metrics to
kind of Drive people's behaviors can be
super valuable so if you started
recording the cycle time from when work
starts to when it finishes in the system
and just start looking at that data how
long does work take on average to go
through the system how long does an
indiv idual item take to go through the
system and then you can look at
something like a cycle time scatter plot
and look for outliers right this is
something that you actually don't need
any Buy in from anybody in the team or
anybody in the organization to do load
the current data from Azure devops or
jira into a a tool that lets you
visualize the cand metrics and look at
what's going
on start asking more interesting
question
questions during uh uh your your
meetings and events that you have with
the
team right when you see those outliers
that that piece of work that took uh you
know we do we do two week Sprints and
there's a piece of work that took 430
days to complete right ask that question
at the retr why did this take 430 days
what what could we have done differently
right that's asking more and using the
data to ask more interesting questions
and as you start asking those more
interesting questions hopefully somebody
on your team or in your group or or a
leader will ask how do you know how did
you see this where how did you spot
these things and you can start
introducing little pieces of Camp say
I'm using this psycle time scatter plot
it's showing that all of these items are
above the 95th percentile these are the
outliers so I'm asking questions about
these and and why are they like that and
how how do they how do they go together
oh that's really cool is there any more
data like that well yes there is you can
start having those
conversations so it's I think it's very
easy to start using caman in the
organization all it takes is any
individual on the team to start
analyzing the data and looking and
suggesting optimizations for the
team trying bu build some credibility so
that you can start having discussions
about definition of workflow you can do
it Ninja right you can say well how do
we pick you know doing the retrospective
I I I'm interested in how we all pick
the next piece of work we're going to do
oh well I do this and I do that and I do
the other thing start pulling on those
threads just start pulling on the
threads so ultimately how easy is it to
create a cam pilot in your organization
super easy just do it it just needs one
person to start looking at the data one
person to start asking more interesting
questions if your current system of work
is failing you then you would benefit
from creating and applying a cand
strategy our professional cand trainers
and Consultants are ready to help don't
wait the sooner you start the sooner
you'll improve getting touch below