so the the question is why is it so
important that senior leadership teams
are engaged during an agile Consulting
engagement
um and I guess
it really it really it really depends on
what systemic change you're you're what
you're wanting to get in the
organization are you actually looking to
transition towards a more a business
that is faster at reacting to changing
market demand that that's that's
effectively what we're talking about
right and if we're talking about I mean
often quite I come into organizations
and we're talking to engineering teams
about how they can do that
but can you imagine a circumstance
where I could talk to anybody any team
anywhere in any organization in the
world
and talk about
them getting faster feedback from their
customers to enable a greater degree of
adaptability to what their customers
need and we're not gonna have to have a
conversation with the business right
we're not going to have to have a
conversation with leadership it just
doesn't exist right that's those
circumstances where you just know
they're not actually going to be able to
get the things that they're looking for
and you're gonna have to figure out a
way for them to get the best they can
within the bounds of the constrained
system because leadership's not involved
and not interested
the the only way you can transition
towards
um that that faster Market engagement
which is the purpose of agile right it's
just a tool to help us get there a
philosophy to help us get there
um is is to have everybody in the
organization change
participate and be willing to change
potentially any business practice in the
business in order to help us get there
and if leadership's not involved all of
those things are off the table
um so quite often I and I've done this
in organizations where I've only been
involved at the the team level I've just
asked where's the CEO's office and gone
and knocked on a door right and and said
look can we have a chat about what it is
I'm doing and what I think you need to
be involved in understand and help with
um actually CFOs are way better
right CFOs are way better if you if you
get the the the the the person with the
money on board who who signs the checks
and decides how money's spent uh then
you're you're totally rocking in that uh
at that space because who wouldn't want
to optimize
the value that you get from the money
you put in right who better to
understand that than somebody somebody
who's fiscally minded
um hopefully CEOs are fiscilla-minded as
well but you know what I mean
um and I think that's that's why it's so
important for
um senior leadership and this affects
the entire organization there's a great
example of this
um your devops team at Microsoft
um adopted agility
if you don't know I've got some videos
and posts about it
um but they they they they changed the
entire way they do business and when
they were asked right what did they have
to change the answer is everything
we had to change the way we sell the
product we had to change the way we
Market the product we had to change the
way we build the product we had to
change the way
um our our parts of our business operate
we had to change the way we engage with
stakeholders we had to change everything
about how they did business in order to
get to the point where they were able to
continuously deliver valuable usable
product to the customer get the feedback
and have the autonomy to be able to make
the decisions on what they focus on and
what they need to build and how they're
spending money right pushing that
responsibility down the organization and
that's super hard
you need a senior leadership involved
you need to have
um
align all the way up the organization to
the to as high as you can possibly go
ideally the very top uh to be able to
get the
I'm gonna say permission right because
in a lot of organizations you don't have
permission but for to to be able to get
the permission that you need in order to
make the changes that are going to best
benefit the organization
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility