that's a great question what is a
product vision and why does it matter
if you were getting together with a
bunch of people
and you were gonna go do something
and nobody has any clue what it is you
want to do they have no clue where
they're going
why would you think they would all be
able to organize together to go in the
same direction
whether you're organizing a pub crawl
or you're organizing your your your your
your your business around the product
if there's no vision
there's no
understanding of everybody involved in
where we're going and why
then there's no way for those people to
Focus their skills and knowledge and
capability
to help you move in that direction right
they're all going to come up with their
own story of which direction they want
to go and they're going to you leverage
their skills knowledge and expertise and
going in that direction and it might not
be it may be antagonistic to to the
direction that you want to take things
so really a a product Vision I don't
think there's any one thing that is a
product vision
but I would Define a successful product
Vision as everybody
working on or with the product
understands where we're going why and
how the things that they're doing every
day contribute towards that overall
success that's a product vision and
that's why we need one
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility