so the new uh product backlog management
course from scrum.org um has been a long
time coming it's going to be awesome
it's one of their new skills based uh
style of classes which are shorter
classes they're they're eight hours uh
rather than the usual 16 hours and they
focus laser focus on one particular
skill and in this case it's product
backlog management um and in product
backlog management we have a number
number of things that we cover in the
class uh we're going to cover um where
where these backlog items come from
we're going to cover how to manage those
backlog items how we write those backlog
items how we break them down into
smaller units of work uh that are maybe
easier for the team to consume easier
for people to understand um and in that
how we maximize the
transparency of that product backlog by
enabling the understanding of everybody
that needs to understand it to be able
to understand it right um and then how
do we work through it how do we how do
we order that backlog um how do we make
it the best backlog it can possibly be
within the context of what it is we're
doing and what we know and what we can
do within our organization uh so it's
it's it's an awesome uh little uh class
that helps us get to grips with some of
the nuances of product backlog
management how do we make sure that we
minimize the amount of things that are
in that product backlog in order to
maximize the value that we get from it
if you want to have a discussion about
your unique needs or situation then
please book a call or visit us at naked
agility tocom uh we also have our
immersive and traditional public classes
on our website and we'd love to hear
from you