one of the key components of creating a
cand strategy is whip limits if you
don't have whip limits it's definitely
not a cand strategy that you have so
when you when you visualize your work
when you do that Workshop where you
figure out what are the the the the
columns the states the activities that
happen for any piece of work that flows
through our system and you create those
columns you're going to have to decide
what your whipit is in each of those
areas is and coming up uh uh with a whip
limit is a little bit of an art right
it's like
um coming up with what's the what's the
goldilock zone for this particular
activity and I actually found out that I
I really fundamentally thought that
Goldilocks and the Three Bears was a
completely
ubiquitous uh story um but I was working
recently with a group in Romania and
they don't have Goldilocks and the three
bearss as a bedtime story it's not a not
a not a not a thing uh so kind of what
we're talking about and actually this
was the bit that resonated the best for
them was um think of what they describe
of as the goldilock Zone in planetary
physics I know I'm sounding like a
nutball here right but bear with me um
in in in planets when they talk about
planets being in the goldilock zone they
mean it's between water freezing and
water boiling right so you can have life
when there's water but you can't have
life when it's steam or in general
that's where
they yes I know that's possible but
let's you've got that that that that
zone if the water's frozen it's probably
very difficult to have life if the
waterers steam then it's very difficult
to have life so what is the Zone within
which it's just right that's the
goldilux zone you can go look up the
story The Fable later right but the
idea is that um we need to figure out
not just our whip limit for the whole
system but are whip limit for individual
stages in the system and the whip limit
for the individual stages if we create
individual stages will probably inform
the whip limit for the overall system
right because you just add them up and
that's the whip limit for the whole
system so um the ideal whip limit right
there is an ideal whip limit if
everything is perfect the ideal whip
limit is one the most optimal whip limit
um in a in in um flow is one single
piece flow right but that only works
when our
um that only works when our system is
perfect when it operates exactly like we
expect in the timing we expect when all
of those things are absolutely perfect
in the whip limit is one uh the the the
the thing I usually use to visualize
that is I I do the an a version of the
coin game with teams if you've not done
the coin game it's a great H exercise
where um you give people you give a
group of people uh 20 coins they flip
them all to heads and then they it's
it's a batch size exercise right so they
um flip them all to heads and then they
have to flip them all to Tails pass to
the next person they have to flip them
all to Tails pass them to the next
person so you've got this simulation of
a production line right something
happens in this stage the next stage
happens something happens there next
stage and in an ideal world you just
want one flip the coin move it on flip
the coin move it on flip the coin move
it on and you'll
have the maximum number of coins
going in action at any point in time
does that make sense right you've got if
you do batch size of 20 and you've get
20 coins and you've got 10 people in a
row you've got one person working and
nine people
waiting at all all the time the whole
time if you do a batch size of one
you've got 10 people
working and you'll get the fastest
delivery of the first unit of work and
the fastest delivery of mult of all the
units of work work okay but the world
isn't made up of flipping coins right
we're not that's not what we're doing
all day we are writing code we're
solving problems we're painting pictures
we're uh waiting on customers to reply
there's all sorts of things that make
what we do non a nonlinear thing not a
thing that just happens at once so
you're going to have to figure out for
each of those columns
what the most optimal whip limit is
based on your ability to keep things
moving and the need to identify when
there's problems if we make the whip
limit 100 in every column it's going to
be difficult to identify problems
because we'll maybe never hit it we'll
never hit the whip limit we deliberately
want to constrain the work to slightly
less than we can do so that we create
slack in the system that enables us to
see more of what's going on ask more
interesting questions and figure out do
we need to increase this or reduce this
one those are the types of discussions
that we want to have um and whenever we
run workshops where we run simulations
around this that's the kind of
conversations that people have in the
groups is who should we create the whip
limit bigger yeah but if we create the
whip limit bigger then there'll be more
stuff in here and there'll be more
pressure on this part of the system the
people in the groups are then a they're
able to visualize those things and see
the impact of those things which is the
whole point of a cand strategy that
everybody in the
system understands the system that
you've created better and it allows them
all to have more rational more
interesting conversations about how the
system goes together and how we might
change it in order to improve it or or
attempt to improve it and then the
impact of those improvements you're able
to monitor them at that that is
really picking whip limits just make up
some numbers at the start pick stuff and
see what works increase them if they're
too small make
them smaller if they're too big and
figure out where that optimal level is
um if you're really searching for Martin
what would you recommend as our whip
limit I I would say in any
stage as a starting point if you have to
have a Martin says we should do it this
way if you have to have that uh then
pick one less than the number of people
that you have performing an activity in
that in that area so if you have four
people pick three as your whip limit and
see how you go if you're struggling to
create whip limits so that you can see
what's going on in your system then we
can help you we provide world class
class cran training from Pro cran as
well as Consulting and coaching for
teams try to implement caman strategy if
you're a scrum team then we always
recommend bringing in flow metrics as a
complimentary practice and also have
caman classes from scrum.org