okay so we're going to update a
video um I have
pre-prepared um an issue on GitHub uh
what you do is you just click new issue
when you get here um put the title in
add the copy as markdown um you can just
paste from word and then you'll have to
to make it look like markdown uh here's
one I prepared earlier I've got
the video I D cuz that's where we're
going to find it I've got the new title
I've got the Old Link the current page I
just past pasted that in and then I
added the copy in here as uh
markdown so let me edit that there's the
copy you can add links and stuff in
there you can do all of those things and
they'll copy copy across um what's more
interesting if you're internal linking
to other posts that are the same um we
need to have conversation about that cuz
there's ways to do that to make it work
nicely uh but what I did what I didly
did was I created a
new um workspace I created a new Branch
so over here there was a button that
said New Branch I clicked it I just
created it locally um and it said do you
want to open in fact let's uh
let's delete that Branch just
now
delit it's gone
okay
so here's my content um I'm going to
create a new Branch it's going to create
a default name for that branch and I'm
going to say open in code space so I'm
going to create the branch
and I think I'll need to copy that
because I think it'll open in this
window and I still want a copy of this
so I can go back to
it so now it's opening um a code space
what it's doing is basically it's a
virtual machine in the cloud it's
getting your code um the code for the
site getting it locally and building um
building that environment you just wait
for it to
open you can see on the bottom left it
says opening remote and there it is um
it's ready so it's built it's going to
do some Jiggy pokery behind the scenes
while we're while we're doing some other
things but it should be should be all
working so what I need to do is I need
to find um where this video is and if
you remember I used this code um for the
for the pages
so uh all of the code for the site is
under site
all of the content for the site is under
content so there's
capabilities company outcomes
resources okay so that's all the the
content for the site don't worry about
these ones these are for um yeah don't
worry about those ones uh so I'm going
to open up resources and then I'm going
to open up video and then we have a
folder called YouTube which is where
these are automatically added and you
can see it's got all the YouTube IDs so
I need to find one
1886 so if I just go down
1806 there it is and I can see it's got
the data file which is the stuff that
got exported out of YouTube and then
it's got the built uh content file okay
uh so this is it here what we're going
to do is we are going to uh do a couple
of things but let me walk you through
this file so this is the original title
and you'll notice uh you put a dot in
the title on YouTube so it pulled it in
here and it means that we've got this
extra little Dash on the end there to
represent that dot uh so that that
should all work um I've already added
this to the aliases in preparation for
us uh um setting this up so there's a
few changes we need to make here and we
need to update the copy so let's get the
copy first I'm going to edit this here
is our content going to copy that uh
markdown go over here um if you if
you've got markdown in
um chat GDP will output mark down and
you can just stick it in here or ask
whatever tool you're using to create it
as marked down so we're going to replace
uh this content here so I'm just going
to do that select it all boom there we
go I've
updated um the file with the new content
I keep this this is the video link
that's what renders the video at the top
uh you could put
it there that could look uh look good um
the default is the is at the top right
so I'm just going to leave it there and
then there's a couple of things we need
to do in this content if we leave it the
way it is um we've not updated the title
we've not updated the URL and this will
get overwritten um when we reprocess at
midnight okay so what you need to do in
order to prevent
that is we're going to take the
title and we're going to add it to the
title here okay so that will be the
new
title then we're going to remove the
slug so this manually set the
title The like the URL the bit at the
end end um to what this was if you
want you can make a new slug that's the
same as this and put it in here I think
it's unnecessary so I'm just going to
delete it and what it will do is it will
take this whatever's in here so if you
change it later um you need to remember
to do some stuff it will take whatever's
there and it will uh turn it into the
URL of the page so any special
characters anything like that will get
converted to dashes and it will do that
okay uh I already added this which is
the old URL so the redirect is already
there um so you don't need to worry
about that but we do need to remove the
canonical URL that's what I search for
when we're updating the content if
there's no canonical URL it's not going
to try and update this file and the last
thing we need to do is change the
priority from four one below half to six
one above half um so that Google and
everything knows that we have uh updated
this content so there's a do not don't
change the date um there's a hidden
value which is when we save this it will
automatically take that the last uh uh
time we edited it as the um the date in
there so that's fine and that's us if I
save that file and close it we've now
changed the file but we need to publish
it so I need to go over here you'll see
see it says one file pending changes
this is our source control so if we go
into Source control um we've got our our
index um and I'm just going to
grab this
title in fact including the little hashy
bit the whole
thing and I'm going to say uh updated
new new copy
for
this okay so it's this will link
everything up and make sure it's all
connected properly you don't have to put
it uh but you have to put some text in
here and then I'm going to commit
it would you like to Stage all your
changes yes you could say always I'm
just going to say yes this effectively
you've got changes stage changes and
then you commit the stage changes that
way you can have changes that you don't
commit like you could make packages if
you're doing lots of changes but don't
worry about it now we've saved it
locally we've published it locally but
we need to push it to the server so I
click this sync
changes
okay so now it's pushed that um to the
server so if we we go over
here go to pull requests you'll see
here's
our copy we've it's now published into
Source control in a branch we need to
get it onto we need to start the process
to get it published for reals so we
create a pool request and it will
basically take exactly I'm actually just
GNA fix that there it always does that
because it's just long
um going to do that draft
it there we go so now that's going to
publish a canary version of our of our
product okay um so this is where we can
see like what are the changes that we've
done what do they look like how are they
how are they how are they used so if I
go along here you can see it's got the
ation so if we have to have a chat about
it we can do that in here um we've got
the commits so what are the the the
number of changes we've made only made
one and we got the files that we've
changed which is only one so if I click
on preview
changes it will actually show it's kind
of a weird view cuz it's in line it will
show all the changes that we've made so
minuses are rows that are deleted plus
these are rows that are added so we kind
of deleted the title and added a new
title um we deleted the four and added
the six and then you'll see it's kind of
doing it line by line um but we replaced
with the new copy that's much
longer okay so that's all looks pretty
good um what you would do I and we can
probably set it up as a as an automatic
um but you can
ask I can't ask myself for a review but
you'll have me in there so you'll be
able to just click on me uh and ask it
for ask me for a review um what we're
waiting for is for it to all
publish right so you can see there that
it's done some stages already it's uh
done run data yeah it's building the
site right now and building the apis and
then it will publish the site once it's
finished publishing the site we'll get a
little um
message in here to tell us it's been
published
okay so this it's finished publishing
the site you can see all the checks have
passed so everything looks good now we
can go check out the new page so I'm
using control again to open this and
this is a special copy of the whole site
146 just for
you so we're going to go in here you can
see it will say Canary at the top and
there's our pool request number and
we're going to go
into
videos and then uh we could
probably we could probably just find it
but what I'm going to
do is I'm going to Nick the URL we're in
videos I'm going to put that on the end
there we go so now this page is the
hidden cost of pro quality code and how
to turn it into a super power is the new
title
um so there you go there's the new site
published so we can come back here um
somebody will approve it and then we
need to it's ready for review and then
you submit for review
it's all good we've checked it like you
can check this and then make a change
okay um so let's say we weren't happy
with what it looked like and we wanted
to make a change I would go back to my
code space over here and I would go
edit this uh this file again so let's
say um I don't know let's say I did want
this to be
here so I would make that
change I would go over here put a cop it
commit it locally push it to the server
this would start again a new post will
get made because this will be refreshed
with the new version and everything will
be good but we're not going to do that
I'm going to merge that pull request cuz
we are in fact happy with it so I'm
going to merge it it'll ask me how do
you want to merge it I just want to do
this
confirm there we go so that is
all merged in that branch that we were
working on has been deleted therefore
the code
space uh it's still there but I'm pretty
sure that will vaporize in a little
bit um and we go back
here and we're done that is heading to
preview site so if you want to know when
it is done you'll see this one here on
Main is uh heading there and doing all
the stuff so this will publish it to
preview and then we need
to manually publish it to live um but
this is a good way to see that so
that'll end up on preview there you go