welcome to MVP
rocks my name is Martin Henwood I'm a
visual studio Alm MVP Visual Studio Alm
Ranger and professional scrum trainer
and I'm here to talk to you about Canan
with TFS
preview TFS preview is Microsoft's
cloudbased TFS offering it's available
on TFS preview.com it's free as long as
you've got our live
ID once you're logged in and you'll get
to choose your um account name my
account name here is Mr hinch once you
log into your account you get to create
a new team project your team project is
the bucket H within which we're going to
do some work and you get Source control
work item
tracking a little bit of
reporting and
tests so now that I've got a a team
project called MVP
rocks I'm going to um go to my
backlog and I'm going to add uh a few
generic items into my backlog these are
product backlog items I'm added they
have a number of fields and most of
which we're not bothered about just now
we're just filling out title they do
have a state however and the state will
default to new um while I'm adding the
items you can see that there's a green
line on the uh list that's the the place
within which items are going to be added
once I have all my items added I
probably want to Stack rank them in some
way so I can reorder my backlog and that
will just automatically save back behind
the
scenes I'm going to go to my can ban
board and you'll see that I have a
number of columns these columns
represent the the states that are
available within that work item type you
can see also that there's a little
number um at the corner of each of the
columns this is my work item uh limit or
whip limit uh work in progress limit I'm
going to set that to two and committee
to two but actually I just want to set
approved to h four that's my backlog
that's how many things are going to be
in my queue to do and lots of new items
we don't care about them we care about
what's in the approved column what's
been approved by the product orderer I
can just drag items into the correct
board or into the approved column you
can see that the column goes green as
I'm dragging the items in um I'm going
to put four items in there and then I
probably want to move a couple of items
into to my committed State and so let me
move create team
project and add some backlog items and
you'll
see you can see that I've met my uh work
in progress limit for my committed
column I have two of two and it's still
green if I drag try and drag another
item across you'll see it'll go red it
will actually let me break the rules it
won't enforce the rules that's okay I'm
smart enough to know that I shouldn't be
breaking them so I'm not going to move a
new item in I can however move an item
over to done and you'll see it goes
green to indicate that um if this is all
complete we're we're in the Happy Happy
State now that I have free space in my
committed column I can drag a new item
across and I'm still within the web
limits um so I don't get it doesn't go
red I don't get any warnings so these
new features are only available in TFS
preview right now you won't find them in
the RTM version of TFS or visual studio
um TFS and visual studio are both moving
to a tighter release schedule they're
releasing new features every 3 months uh
so you will see it on premise uh within
the next 3 months cuz we've already had
the first uh RTM shipped version of TFS
so things like the new uh cumulative
flow diagrams that you see there I don't
have any data yet but you see it there
um will be available very soon uh on the
on premise TFS but you can use it right
now in the cloud by going to TFS
preview.com and signing up for an
account for