so the question is what's the most
valuable thing
I've learned
training people
I think I think it's that
there's two there's two things that are
kind of related
one is no matter where you are in the
world everybody's got the same problems
when they're when they're implementing
agile when they're
um trying to do scrum when they're
trying to think about
the implications of empiricism and a
value focus on their organization
everybody runs into exactly the same
walls right everybody runs in Texas they
think their walls are unique but
everyone runs into the same walls but
the value that I find
for for for me is
I I love
the engagement that I get
in Multicultural
multi-time Zone
multi-country training events much more
than I do
from single
Country Events because I feel like
there's a little bit of echo chamber
in a single country event
that there aren't as many I different
ideas generated
I think it kind of demonstrates that
that value in globalization right that
you're you're you're teaching a class
and you've got
you know even even you've got you've got
five people from the US uh five people
from the UK and they're they're they're
bouncing off each other and then that
one student that's from Eastern Europe
right will say but what about this type
of thing oh
never thought of that right because it's
not even within their sphere of
experience
and
those those ideas coming in I think
helped me
I guess appreciate the diversity of of
of of cultures that but it also results
in better
training experience for the students
because they get more conversation more
topics more not disagreement
disagreements not the right word but
more ideas
coming in there
um
and for me that for me that's the most
valuable