naked agility can be your partner in
creating engineering excellence and
Technical leadership within your
organization in the last few videos
we've talked about a number of
different ways or things that we focus
on that are part of part of that story
we talked about that that high cost of
of of bad quality of mediocre product
right not even mediocre poor quality
product there's lots of poor quality
products out there that have a massive
cost particularly in your brand
recognition right people don't want to
use products that they have a envisage
in their head to be of poor quality we
talked a lot about shifting left and the
different components that we would shift
left not just uh testing and test
automation but continuous integration
continuous delivery we talked about user
experience shifting left we talked about
security shifting left architecture
shifting left all of these things need
to move as close to the engineering team
that's making the decisions the people
that are making the decisions and doing
the work all of those things those
skills those capabilities those not need
to be built up in those teams in order
for you move to move towards this idea
of engineering Excellence right we we we
need to not manage technical debt but
pay it back deal with it deal with the
technical debt when it happens own up to
it when we make a mistake be transparent
and open about what the problem was and
what we're going to do it and build that
culture of quality build that culture of
engineering Excellence within our
organization your purpose is creating
value for your
customers our purpose is value creation
for you through building the technical
leadership and engine ing Excellence
that enables your value creation and
that's what naked agility can help you
with