I'm going to configure release
management to use um a a new uh Team
Foundation server so I'm going to go
ahead and open the release management
client I'm going to head over to the
administration
Tab and on here I've got a manage TFS
options let me go in there so you can
see we already have the Faber cam fiber
collection added I'm going to add the
tail spin toys one so if I click
new I can just put in the name of the
server here or I can put the full URL
you'll see that it kind of builds the
URL down at the bottom you can see at
the top as well I'm going to put the
collection name in which
is Tail
Spin
toys
collection and you'll see here I've got
the default path and port number and
this is just all on the default setup
and it's local to this box so I
shouldn't have any communication issues
however if I hit the verify button
you'll see I get a common error message
box pops up and this Box gives you
possible reasons for the communication
problem one is you you know you filled
it out correctly or the TFS server
unavailable and the other one is that
the password is incorrect which is the
case here I have no connect as account
name and password in um so I need to go
over here and I need to fill out
um
my user let me just check name there we
go and
my
password and click verify now if that
still doesn't work and you don't get a
green tick you might want to check uh
obvious things like the spelling of your
server and collection name and and
whether you can access those things the
easiest way to do that is to copy this
URL open it up in a browser paste it
in and see if you can actually access it
on that URL and indeed uh it can be much
easier to get access to it than just
copi it off and I can make it easier so
now that we have that I can hit save and
close and I now have two active uh uh
TFS
connections