If you're building products um at any
scale, whether it's small scale or large
scale, it's really important to make
decisions based on actual evidence. And
that evidence can come in the form of
hypothesisdriven practices at the
business level, at the value level, or
it can come all the way down to to flow
metrics at the delivery level. And
that's one thing that I I would probably
say Azure DevOps is a little bit
rudimentary in that space out of the
box, but we can absolutely get those
things and augment those things. Um so
one of the fundamental um
understandings that I've gained over
many years of building software and
helping teams build software is without
visibility, you can't see what's going
on. And without being able to see what's
going on, you can't make effective
changes. And you also can't see the
impact
and effect of those changes on the way
that you work.
So we need telemetry. We need data. Does
some of that telemetry comes from your
product, right? Building uh um open
telemetry into your product, collecting
specific and deliberate telemetry from
your product. Um but we can also use
telemetry on the way that we work and
Azure DevOps is a fantastic system for
gathering gathering that telemetry. Um
so in Azure DevOps um every value of
every variable that ever was inside of
your work items is collected and stored.
Okay. So um it doesn't matter what field
it is. If you add a custom field, no
problem. The full history of that field
um is available uh within the context.
So that allows you to pull and collect
any sort of data you like in any way you
like. Okay. Uh that's the powerful part,
right? All of that data is there. Um the
visualizations that are built into Azure
DevOps, we can they're they're a little
bit rudimentary, but that's that's
fundamentally Microsoft's premise,
right? Microsoft's premise is we're not
going to build everything for you. We're
going to build the data layer, the API
layer, and then we'll build some
examples of here's what you can do with
that data that that that meet the table
stakes. We'll build the table stakes and
then let partners um build the the the
value ads that are specific to your
organization. So I work with customers
that have a large internal ecosystem of
custom
boards, controls, dashboards that they
build internally and ship around the
organization. So they have an
engineering team who builds
augmentations for Azure DevOps. They
support other teams who build
augmentations for themselves in Azure
DevOps and allow those to be shared
across the organization. And Azure
DevOps has has capabilities for that as
well, right? That's for people that are
really big. If you're really big, you
can absolutely do that. If you're really
small, you don't want to have to do
that. You want some vendor uh uh to do
that for you and you you absolutely um
have that capability. So there's a
couple of things that you can do within
the context of of Azure DevOps. So out
of the box, it does have h lead time and
cycle time. Okay. And there's a little
bit of work in process. So, at the top
of your columns on your your boards,
uh the board uh the I guess they're
called Carban boards, right? But they're
not really they're just boards. The on
the top of the boards, they have a a
whip limit. It is not enforced. It will
just go red if you go over the limit.
And the limit is for each column. They
don't have a system limit, right? So,
that's a limitation. They don't have a
system limit, just a limit for the for
each column.
uh you can add uh cycle time and lead
time to the the dashboards and it will
give you a hover over uh view of your
average just the average uh cycle time
and lead time. Um I don't like the
average. I like the 85th percentile and
it should have all of them but it
doesn't. So that's what I mean by
sometimes it's a little bit basic and
rudimentary. It's opinionated. They pick
one thing. Uh so they have they have uh
that but you can hover over individual
items and see see where they are and
then they have a cumulative flow right
which is again straightforward just
visualizes the the cumulative flow
that's out of the box you get that for
free uh Microsoft is opinionated on when
work items start and when work items
finish. That's beyond the scope of this
but um we can we can definitely talk
about that in another another video. Um
but there are all of all of that data
that they use to make that is stored in
the system. So you can access the APIs
and access the PowerBI the analytics. So
everything be loaded into PowerBI and
build whatever graphs you want. Right?
So that's one. But if you're small
enough, you don't want to build it
yourself. Um, I recommend two, there's
two, um, tools that I definitely
recommend taking a look at. Uh, one is
called Flow Viz, and that's effectively
some pre-built PowerBI reports that you
can load in to your to your PowerBI
environment. It connects to Azure DevOps
and pulls your data and displays all of
the cool stuff. And it's free, right?
Flow Viz uh, gives you that capability.
Great. Go try it out. uh download it,
install it. The other one is actionable
agile metrics for predictability. So
actionable actual is a plugin, an
interactive javascriptbased, no data
goes anywhere but your system uh uh
plugin, but it's $20 per user per month.
I recommend that one, too. That's what I
use because I just want an easy visual
indication uh that I can just add a
plugin to to Azure DevOps and go spelunk
people's uh people's data. So um that
get both of those tools give you much
more accurate accurate is probably the
wrong word but much much better much
more more features many more features uh
for for lead time cycle time for
percentiles
um for seeing your work in process
seeing your your flow. I particularly
like in actionable agile it has a view
uh which is work in progress and you can
see the overlay of your percentiles on
your work in process. So you can see the
things that are much
which are most likely to be in danger uh
within that context. So using Azure
DevOps you get all access to all of the
data and some visualizations. then
bringing in some third party tools. Uh
on top of that, you can make it really
light up and create any sort of data
visualizations you want. If you're a
coder, uh Ben also has a I think it's
called the um Azure DevOps admin tools.
He has a little uh command line toolkit
uh that you can run that will get you
most of the data as well and give you
your cycle time, leak time, build your
graphs, all of those things from the
from the command line. Um so if you're
developer, you can you can use that, but
it's not as friendly for for everybody
else that might be using the system. So
I if if
with all of these options, it can be a
little bit difficult to navigate. So if
you're ready to move from making
decisions based on gut feel to more of a
data delivery data driven delivery story
um give me a call and let's uh make your
work visible.