if if you're worried about compatibility
problems once you've moved from TFS on
Prem to Azure devops um I probably
really wouldn't worry that much about it
um everything that works on Prem Works
in aure devops um it's more the other
way not everything that works in aure
devops works on Prem where there's more
likely to be compatibility issues uh but
there are certainly if you're on an
older version of Team Foundation server
um we did a migration recently for TFS
2010 and they had some
customizations that they built they had
some customizations um that they' bought
that are just no longer a thing um
they're no longer a thing in newer
versions of on Prem TFS uh so we had to
plan
around what are they going to do
differently
when they move to the new location right
um because even just an upgrade of TFS
they're going to lose that functionality
and they have to upgrade TF 2010 I think
was out of support five years ago maybe
longer um so they were they were really
hurting for for from that perspective
they need to you need to be in
compliance if you want support data
Integrity these are the systems that
hold your company's IP right um you you
you you need the the the the code to be
able to build your product um and that
needs to be safe and secure this is your
organizational asset if you're if you
have any building of software going on
this is a very expensive asset to to to
work on so you need to make sure that it
all works um as you move up to the cloud
um you will have still a bunch of on
Prem stuff going on you probably have on
Prem build agents you probably have um
other things locally those can largely
just continue to function as is uh the
agents will just connect to uh um Azure
devops in the cloud and it's a one-way
system so the agents talk to the cloud
the cloud never talks to the agent so
you don't need to punch any holes
through your firewall um and then you've
got to consider all of your own in-house
customizations that you've created it's
very easy and has been for oh 14 15
years to create uh extensions plugins um
other systems that bounce off uh TFS uh
so you'll need to take into
consideration what are they going to do
in um the new model of working with the
cloud these are all things that you can
just resolve they're they're not that
difficult