are teams empowered to change the
requirements based on user
feedback if not then you're probably not
very
agile we need to be engaging with the
people that are building the product and
as we understand the work better as we
understand different ways to do things
as we gain more knowledge and context
about the product and the market and
what it is we're trying to achieve we
need to be able to up update the backlog
update the requirements change them
delete them as well if we're not doing
that then we're not going to be able to
maximize the value that we deliver to
our customers and the people doing the
work the people creating the product are
really important to that story and their
input is just as important as the
stakeholders are you maximizing the
value that you deliver to your customers