foreign
how
how do I help organizations pitch the
idea of agile internally
I guess it depends whether you're
managing up or you're managing down
right
um so if you're if you're managing up
I.E you're working on a team or with a
team or at some level where you're
building products and you want to do
Agile but your organization is not yet
there yet is not yet understanding what
the difference is or what the impact is
um then having conversations with them
in their language is the most important
thing you can do
um you need to
like there's no point in talking about
agile or scrum up the organization
because they're words that then you then
have to explain right the other person's
like well what the heck is this crap
right I need to you need to tell me what
it is then and you end up having to stop
all the time so you need to use their
language so if you're talking to people
with uh
um like a business value Focus
then talk about
um delivering more of the right things
less of the wrong things
um talk about uh responding to the
market more quickly
I'll talk about
um
how to
um deliver
happier more engaged customers right
that's that's that's probably what
they're they're focused on that's
probably what their their metrics push
but find out what their metrics are
right what are they measuring as success
in the business and go look at that
if you're
um business if you look at those metrics
and your business is a totally fiscally
focused right apart from just being
screwed right you you you also need you
you you need to look at
um what are the benefits from a fiscal
perspective that you can get from agile
I I feel like if your company's focused
on just fiscal stuff then that's not a
good thing anyway right that's Revenue
extraction rather than value creation
but
um that's that's you can only get to
that conversation once you convince them
so you want to be talking about reducing
fiscal risk you want to be talking about
because quick fast iterations of of of
actual value they provide reduces
operational risk reduces fiscal risk
um it it
increases the value that you've
delivered and in most countries there
are tax benefits to to write down
Capital expenditures right for example
it's here's a simple argument
I'm going to spend uh uh 12 million
dollars capital expenditure to to build
a product
um
at the end of 12 months I'm going to
deliver that product into production
and at that point and like I can start
writing down that capital expenditure
right from a tax perspective normally
you can only start writing down so it
depreciates over time right you can
write that down and claim tax benefits
for it most countries I don't know about
all countries but UK US definitely have
have have these things in there
but if you remember in school when you
do that uh um compound interest
calculation right and you're always look
how big the money grows the the opposite
is true for
um writing things down
so at the end of if you're if you're
delivering monthly right to production
it's costing you a million dollars a
month on a 12 million dollar yearly gig
at the end of the first month you can
just you can start writing down that
million dollars
and then at the end of the second month
you've already had a month of writing
down a million dollars and you start
writing down the second million dollars
and then at the end of the third month
you've had two months of writing down
the first million dollars two sorry
three months of writing down the first
million dollars two months of the second
and you're getting into the the third
right so you end up with this compound
right I've never met a CFO
um who you can't convince that agile's a
good idea if you use their language what
data are they looking at how could being
more agile shift those metrics and use
their words to describe it so that's
that's managing up
um if you're in leadership in your
organization and you're looking down in
your organization and you're trying to
figure out how do I
um engage all of these people in this
change activity in moving towards a
different way of working
um and the answer is get them involved
in that process you need to create an
event
whereby you're asking them
what it is that we need to do
differently getting them to agree what
the action steps are to move forward
getting them to choose the processes and
practices that you're going to use
because only by them choosing it them
being involved and them deciding
will they care enough about the change
to get behind it and support it and help
help help
make that change otherwise they'll
they'll they're not in they don't care
about your objectives right they care
about their objectives you have to make
it their objective or help encourage it
to be their objective so I use things
like um open space agile and there's a
concrete implementation called open
space beta which helps helps with that
as well
um so yeah it just depends whether
you're managing up and rising down