the question was what is Terrorism and
how did it influence project management
and I think that's an interesting
question because
um taylorism let's let's quantify that
first uh taylorism is it's the name of a
gentleman called Frederick Winslow
Taylor
who back in the 1880s 1890s he was kind
of like the thought leader the
Management Consultant of the time and he
uh worked with all of these big Factory
owners he did a Time In Motion study
um about the work trying to figure out
how do we get better at delivering more
stuff because in those days the outcomes
were guaranteed right because you had a
factory that made uh um clocks and you
know you're gonna get clocks out the
other end of the factory we just want
more clocks supply and demand but in
that in that world
um during the Industrial Revolution the
demand was much higher than the supply
so we had very very uh um sparse markets
not so much competition
um we didn't have that globalization so
if you were making clocks in in in in
Europe you were selling in if you made
clocks in the UK you were probably
selling in the UK if you made clocks in
China you were probably selling in China
right they didn't have that
globalization so competition
um was very low and customers didn't
really know much about the products that
they were buying so they just bought
what they were provided right they
weren't asking for different things they
weren't trying to get
different stuff
so you had this very low uh Dynamic low
Dynamic
um low competition Marketplace and a
whole bunch of tools and practices were
developed around this space
um so Frederick Winslow Taylor is what
we call it taylorism uh developed a
bunch of these techniques started
developing them and one of the
fundamental basis basis that they worked
with
was because
um people doing doing monotonous factory
work because they disconnect from the
work
you find that they try everything they
can not to work
so there's this famous quote uh from
Taylor
Let's uh let me think uh not a competent
worker can be now a competent worker can
be found that does not devote a
considerable amount of time to studying
just how slowly they can work and still
convince their employer they're going at
a good pace and I'm sure
listening to this you're all thinking of
those companies that you've worked for
and with that have that ethos at their
heart that employees are inherently
untrustworthy they're inherently not
going to do their job unless we're much
watching them
treating people like Factory workers
right and and we need to keep an eye on
them we need a foreman to keep an eye on
the people and then maybe we need
managers to keep an eye on the foreman
and managers to keep an eye on those
managers depending on how big we get and
hierarchy is born right you get
hierarchies and then because we're going
to put the thinkers at the top of the
organization and the doors at the bottom
of the organization because the doers
don't need to think right they're just
making more stuff we know what we're
going to create we're creating clocks uh
then we can we can create these
hierarchical steering uh based
organizations where budget comes from
the top decisions are made at the top uh
Direction comes from the top
and then that that kind of progressed
through into uh through through the
Gantt chart in 1906 from from uh
um Henry Gantt uh through into the 1950s
where the US industrial military complex
took a hold of many of these ideas and
started uh incorporating them into the
work the way they work so you want to
divide people into ability-based groups
um you want to standardize the processes
that they do train that group only in
those processes and hey ho we ended up
with uh departments across our
organizations with the sales department
and the marketing department and the
um coding department and the testing
department and the operations Department
right let's keep them separate train
them only in those ability-based groups
so out of those ideas was born those
traditional project management methods
now a lot of work has been done recently
to try and
curtail or morph many of those uh
traditional uh uh outlooks to a more
people focus because it was a staff
focused Outlook
um and that's but that stuff focused
Outlook is still at the heart of a lot
of those uh those techniques yes I do
know fantastic fantastic project
managers
um that don't focus on the stuff they
focus on the people and they get great
results but in my experience those those
folks are super rare they're booking a
trend uh they're not the mass produced
uh project manager that you find
um out in The Ether and what what's
happening is that project that plan
becomes the gold standard rather than
planning becoming the gold standard
and so
taylorism is really the source of if you
if you if you read about taylorism uh
you read about the the the the the
Scientific Management method you'll see
that influence going through all of the
um stuff up until the the modern era
even through the lean Toyota production
system right which was an adaption of
those techniques for the more modern
world of the 1950s when uh at markets
were getting more crowded right so they
needed new techniques to be able to move
even faster
um and that was a lean Toyota production
system but as we move into the the the
modern world
um and even even
May 50 60 70 years ago and there weren't
really any of these these markets that
were
um low competition left right
everything's High competition high
demand High uh variability in all the
things that we do people starting to
want demand custom capabilities from
their organizations which is why car
manufacturers are increasingly adopting
agile practices so that they can
start delivering these custom
capabilities dynamically and quickly to
their customers incorporating the design
of the products into the actual delivery
of the products rather than keeping them
a separate things right design it and
then deliver it they need to constantly
be adapting and changing
um so taylorism created Created was the
source of those uh um traditional
project management practices but there
are many practices Tools in traditional
project management that are still just
as valid today throughout the baby with
the bath water but try and figure out
how to increase your adaptability reduce
your bureaucracy
um reduce the plan
increase planning and deliver more value
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else add your scrum or devops
then please book a coffee with me
through naked agility