the question is does cban integrate with
a scrum environment and I I I want to be
super clear hban integrates with any
environment any way of working whether
you're doing scrum or you're doing
waterfall or you just made up a way of
working all of these things can benefit
from the application of a cand strategy
right
the the scrum in particular doesn't have
any metrics there are no no metrics in
scrum go read the cang guide there is no
mention of velocity no mention of story
points no mention of time no mention of
any of those things the only thing
that's about as close to a metric as the
scrum guide talks about is it it says
that um uh the team should have
discussions to understand the size of
things that are in their backlog that's
it right how you define that size all of
those things are are are are up to up to
the team teams generally pick things
like story points and velocity and
unfortunately those metrics have damaged
our ability as an industry building
software industry in particular damaged
our ability as an industry to have
conversations with customers have them
understand what we're saying and be able
to actually answer the customer
questions it is absolutely
unreasonable for a customer to come to
you has given you and your team a bunch
of money and says when will it be done
and you say we're doing scrum we don't
have an answer to that question that is
completely unreasonable and if I was
that person I would say fine I'm not
giving you any more money I'll go find
somebody else who can answer my
questions right
so
caman a caman strategy enables you to
actually answer those
questions right you're definitely not
answering it with absolutes right
because that's impossible we understand
the cone of uncertainty we understand uh
uh uh that those difficulties but we can
start to use probabilistic
forecasting fantastic tool probabilistic
forecasting to help us answer those
questions of when will it be done or
what will I get by this date right these
are these are such important questions
uh Daniel Vante who's one of the the the
creators of uh uh Pro caman uh the
creator of the caman strategy um who who
worked with scrum.org to create the cban
guide for scrum teams and uh H caman for
scrum teams
course he has a book called when will it
be done that's how important that
question is to your business business
you need to be able to to answer that
question when will it be done and the
tools that cban gives you the metrics
that you have to monitor enable you to
then get those answers to those
questions very specifically right um so
does cban integrate with a scrum
environment I think cban has to
integrate with a scrum environment in
fact scrum is not not as good without a
caman strategy i i i i for
me this is this is a pairing that that
that is just has to happen if you doing
scrum you should be using a caman
strategy um I don't really have any
um what would you call it like well
maybe you should use no you should be
using a cban strategy everybody should
for every system in every workplace
everywhere you should be using a cand
strategy that's how you understand the
flow of work through your system so that
you can make the optimizations right
that's where you get the continuous
improvement from when you're doing
scrum right you you you have a
retrospective how how do you how do you
know what optimizations you should make
how do you have convers ations about
what the problem is if you've got no
data how do you um um see whether the
things that you've decided to try
actually provide any benefit or not you
need metrics and you need data and story
points and velocity and burndown charts
are completely useless to answer any of
those
questions are we on track are we doing
well do we need to improve none of those
questions can be answered with burndown
charts and velocity don't even try
they're a waste of time what you need is
cycle
time you need lead time and you need
throughput you need work item aging and
you need work in process that's
it those are the metrics that you're
looking for those are the metrics that
you need if your current system of work
is failing you then you would benefit
from CRE creating and applying a caman
strategy our professional cand trainers
and Consultants are ready to help don't
wait the sooner you start the sooner you
will improve get in touch below