when you're doing a migration of data um
for your devops um downtime isn't of
always great concern for organizations
if you've got 5,000 software engineers
in your collection um you don't want it
to be down for an extended period of
time and your your engineers not able to
not able to work I'm going to put that
in air quotes because it's not really
true not able to work uh for that period
of time so there's a couple of things
that you do need to kind of understand
in this this this context um even if TFS
slz devops is
down like offline your engineers can
still work it's just more difficult for
them to collaborate together uh so if
they're using git as the source control
system which is the primary source
control system in Azure devops and TFS
then um
they're able to even share code in a way
that works within the context of the
tool even when they're offline um that's
how Linux was created there was no
Central Source control system and they
sent patches to each other over email
right uh so get fully supports that
obviously they wouldn't have access to
the work items uh so they would need to
have you know know what it is we're
working on for the time that it's down
but um I will point out that if you plan
it right uh downtime can be absolutely
minimal uh the largest migration we have
done was uh uh 2.5 terabytes uh
collection that we moved up from on Prem
in Europe uh on Prem to asure devops and
we took the system offline because it
needs to be offline to do the final part
of the migration we're actually moving
up to the cloud uh we took it offline at
5:00 p.m. on Friday um and we were back
online uh Sunday morning uh the
engineers came in over the weekend to
validate uh that things looked good
right they did their cursory checks you
everything's in the right place that
that that's working this is working
that's kind of thing um and we they were
back up and running Monday morning so
that's probably one of there be very few
people out there that have collections
that big um but if you plan it right and
that took in order to do a 2.5 terabyte
uh um system in that time we probably
took 3 to six months of planning and dry
runs and validations and making sure
everything's good in the data um dry
runs are really important for that sorry
that's practice runs right um to get the
data out of the data center in a timely
manner get it up to the cloud in a
timely manner or get it processed cuz
that can be quite failure prone you want
to have done a dry run so that that
always you know that's going to work um
and perhaps have Microsoft on hand to
help out if if there are any issues um
so that that was minimal downtime I
think that was about 5 and a half
thousand software Engineers um and they
really really had no downtime 5:00 P p.m
on Friday uh back up uh uh uh in the
morning but they were a global company
so there was some downtime for some
engineers in some regions um right
because that's just unavoidable but we
minimized it as much as possible