um so the question was why Minecraft
makes it so awesome
I started teaching the aps with
Minecraft 10 years ago 12 12 years ago
um and 12 years ago
if you got a group of people together in
a training room
and ask them the the default
um
case study was an animal website
right so build an animal website we
break everybody up into teams they would
they would pick an animal mascot and
then they would have to create a website
about that animal and everybody got the
same set of requirements
but 12 years ago that was hard right you
were probably in a in a in a room with
limited internet access right if the
students were all turning up in our
particular office if there was internet
it wasn't fast
and they had to actually go build
something right they actually had to
crack open Visual Studio or eclipse or
whatever their favorite tool was and go
and go bring all of those things
together to create a website
and and that's not true anymore it's
just it's just that's not what happens
anymore what happens when you ask people
to create an ammo website is they go
create a Wix site and they're done in
five minutes they go create a a Google
sites
um or whatever other platform is out
there and they're able to solve that
what used to be an incredibly complex
problem in a very short space of time
and then they're just adding new pages
and the only thing we really have to
pick on is that
[Music]
um
the only thing we have to pick on is the
the the the teams
quality right so are there broken links
are there half finished pages is the
text too small to read right which which
is a little bit I don't know it's just a
little bit [ __ ] though it made the class
go from this awesome experience where
you had this hugely complex problem that
you were solving uh because you had to
do it in 30 minutes right so I'm a
website's not complex unless I make you
do it in 30 minutes then it's complex
right and it just became simple
so Minecraft brings in that complexity
again
um it it it it levels the playing field
and there's actually two massive
benefits one is that it levels the
playing field for everybody in the room
understands complexity it simulates that
that a complex situation that they have
to organize around to solve that complex
problem within the bounds of of
Minecraft so we're not teaching the
whole class in Minecraft right it's just
the the case study the Sprints that
we're doing in Minecraft and when you
come back from that you can dive into
the relationship problems the way people
approached the problem you can dive into
um how they communicated with each other
all kinds of really interesting aspects
the additional thing is that everybody
can now participate
so what would tend to happen when the we
were during the Sprints of the animal
website uh there would be a few of the
participants would be the actual coders
who were building the website and the
rest of the people on the on the team
were either just helping them or doing
their email uh uh or helping them for
five minutes and then doing their email
or collecting some information emailing
it to the developer right it goes into
that black hole of the magic and Magic
Black Magic developer over there who's
going to going to build the thing and
then they would have nothing to do
in the Minecraft space every single
person can participate every single
person can do something it doesn't
matter what skill level you have when
you come into it with Minecraft in 30
minutes you can figure out how to
provide some value figure out how to add
it you're learning as well so we can
diagnose some of those learning
techniques it's just fantastic
experience for everybody