one of the common uh myths in scrum um
is kind of a a a proxy myth this proxy
myth is you know why do we spend so much
time working on story
points um when story points measure
complexity and not time and then we have
to figure out how many story points fit
in a Sprint right and I I 100% agree
with that that part is not a myth the
bit that's a myth is that story points
are even a scrum thing in the first
place they're not story points has
nothing to do with scrum it never has a
part from as a practice potentially
complimentary practice that teams choose
to take on in order to get to an
outcome when you find complimentary
practices are not adding value you
should be be stopping doing them not
continuing with them so if you're in
that position where you find that story
points are not adding value great stop
doing them and choose something else
choose a different way the guy that
invented story points or that is
generally accredited with inventing
story points has a public apology online
for creating them in the first place
because of how they are tend to be used
within organizations as a pseudo proxy
for time to beat developers around the
head with right they were originally
invented as a reasonable way for
developers to sit and have a
conversation and find out figure out
what they don't know that's the purpose
in story points we can all get together
we we maybe use another complimentary
practice called planning poker and all
that really is is we we keep our cards
to ourselves right we we're not going to
tell each other what story point we're
going to pick how complex t-shirt sizes
right whatever you pick how complex this
thing is and you've got one developer
that says this is a small or a one right
you've got four developers that say that
this is a five or a medium and then
you've got one developer that says this
is an extra large or a 21 right and the
idea is what do they know that we don't
or what do we know that they
don't that's the
purpose of story points and complexity
conversations it should be used almost
solely during refinement in order to
enable teams to right size their backlog
items and decide do they fit in a Sprint
do we understand them or do we
not after that delete the numbers
they're
useless don't use them anymore that's
their purpose for that one context don't
bring them into the wider
context thanks for watching the video If
you enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else add scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked
agility