you can't order a
hierarchy in this video I'm going to
demonstrate why hierarchies in backlog
management inhibit the ability for us to
manage them effectively and how we can
think about backlock differently my name
is Martin hinwood I'm a professional
scrum trainer with scrum.org a
professional caman trainer with Pro
caman and I've been a Microsoft MVP in
devops for 15
years a backlog is just a list of things
you're going to do but backlogs have
some uh special characteristics one of
those main characteristics is that it's
ordered in some way uh you still need to
decide how it's ordered but your backlog
should have an order IE there's a
distinct first item second item third
item there are no items in your backlog
that have exactly the same level
therefore it is a flat list of what it
is we're going to do next or what the
most important thing is the order of the
backlog informs but does not control the
selection of the work uh that the team
is going to work on at any time there
may be other things that come into that
story at selection time not just what of
the most important things uh that are
there there might be other implications
in uh uh technology um state of the
product other things that are going on
that we need to consider as we move
through our product product so why is is
hierarchy a problem uh the most common
thing that you see in teams is uh if
depending on the product they're using
to manage their backlog uh they might
have epic breakdown into features break
down into into stories or backlog items
they might have features break down into
epics break down into um backlog items
you might have any any number of other
things going on you might have um I
don't know initiatives that break down
into something that break down into the
theme Here is that you've got things
that break down into other things I.E a
parent child relationship if you have a
parent child relationship in a a tool um
it's very difficult um to to manage it
in a way that allows us to use that
context with without that context
inhibiting our ability to do stuff in
the tool so I'm going to going to show
some examples and this is also not just
a tooling issue but a mindset issue as
well if you're thinking about your work
as a parent child relationship the
tendency the easy thing that happens is
that we end up with a work breakdown
structure um which is not effective uh
because ultimately it's not value for
focused and that's what we're trying to
achieve all of uh uh agile whether
you're using a specific agile framework
or you're trying to follow the agile
Manifesto or you're thinking about lean
and caman any of these things is
focusing on the flow of value through
your system so if you're focused on the
flow of value through the system you
need to be focused on the value if
you're focused on the work breakdown you
tend not to be focused on value you tend
to be focused on delivering more stuff
so that's that's the
tendency but what's the relationship uh
uh that makes it difficult in
hierarchies so I've created a demo here
to show what the problem is uh so in
this example I'm just going to use Azure
devops that's my tool of choice that's
my preference um but this could be any
tool including just a mural uh uh with
backlog items so here I've got three uh
features features One features two
features three and the ENT inent of this
tool is that features work um at a
different level from from backlog items
uh
and they inform but do not control the
next level down right but the reality is
that they do control the next level down
cuz most people use this kind of I've
got quite a lot of things in there use
this kind of view to kind of see what's
going on so you're you're you're looking
at features breaking down into back
backlog items here and perhaps those
backlog items uh break down into
tasks task one save that oh I need to
close it now I made two don't save that
one uh so now I've got this hierarchy
this work breakdown structure towards
this item and then the tendency is to
use this View and to put like little
progress bars and whatever you want on
this View and you end up with what looks
a little bit uh like a project status
report that's the tendency when you when
you use these types of views with huge
amounts of discipline on your team you
can certainly avoid this uh but I find
that that's not the case for for the
majority of encounters that I've had
with teams that are doing this the other
thing that makes it very difficult is
that if I want to um make one item more
important than another item
because I'm looking at this view I
actually tend to only make things
important or not important inside of the
scope of the feature because I can still
drag and drop inside of here and order
that hierarchy same as if you were using
just mural and stickies right it has to
be under that feature but if I want to
make this item more important uh uh less
important than this item here I want to
drag it below this item and suddenly if
I drop this I now changed the parent
child relationship from feature one to
feature 2 and this is a feature one
element not a feature 2 element and that
doesn't make any sense so I need to go
put that back so when we manage our work
and we're trying to actively manage
what's going on here it it tends to make
it a little bit more difficult
to visualize to engage with with the
work what we really want is we want to
turn we want people to turn off the
parents and manage the backlog as a
backlog not as a hierarchy so they're
dragging and dropping things within here
they're ordering this list um and
creating a view that makes sense just
for them so the main problems with a
backlog uh hierarchy are the what first
one is the tendency
towards ending up with a work breakdown
structure um the other tenden is to not
order your backlog because it changes
that parent child relationship and its
effort to switch between the different
different views it's even more so on on
stickies on a whiteboard right because
you you have that fixed view you can't
pivot that display that you like you can
in tools and the last uh element that is
difficult is parent child relationships
are one parent many children within the
context of almost all all tooling it's a
tree structure um and that inhibits our
ability to have an item that goes on our
backlog that has many parents a many to
many relationship right um I might have
a thing that I put in my backlog that
enables five different features and then
that becomes quite an important thing to
work on because it enables these five
different features or is the first
foundation for these five different
features and it's very difficult to
represent that when we have that
breakdown structure from epic to feature
or high level item to Next Level item
uh to backlog
item so how can we think differently so
that we don't have this problem um what
we want to be able to do when we're
thinking about our PCT backlog is we
want to think about it as a flat list it
always should be a flat list and each
item has additional context that
additional context should be able to be
visualized in various ways depending on
the tooling that you're that you're
using whether you're using a a Hub uh
gitlab Azure devops or jira the tooling
will allow you to create some of those
visualizations those pivots on the data
without actually having a hierarchy
parent child relationships that's the
primary way to do that so I'm going to
show you how to do this in Azure devops
I have an example set up here I'm just
going to use the same uh team and I have
a bunch of things in uh my back hook
here if you ignore that effort uh column
there I will we'll just remove it
because it's inconsequential for what
we're talking about
here so one of the things uh that we're
we're interested in in this uh list this
is going to be a flat list um that we're
going to order but there might be
additional things that we want to take
care of so if you remember um we had a
bunch of things that had uh features
assigned to them so what I can uh do is
I can turn on the parents again
and what I'm going to do is I'm going to
get rid of those those those parent
relationships and I'm just going to do
uh tag ad and I'm going to cheat and I'm
just going to call it feature
one use feature one and I'm going to
call this one feature two I'm going to
ignore feature
three tag
ad
now tags need to be a little bit more
deliberate you can control both the
ability for people to create tags uh
that's
pre-moderation or you can use a post
moderation technique there is a plugin
on the store you can see it's got
28,000 uh installs across TFS and asure
devops um this allows you to actively
post moderate those tags so activities
like merging tags filtering tags uh uh
managing things you can do to manage uh
manage those tasks this work po across
TFS and as your devops I'm sure there is
the same story in other platforms as
well whether you're using GitHub gitlab
or
jira so now I have a feature assigned to
each work item I can easily open a work
item I can see that it's to do with a
particular feature or capability um I
could even link to that uh capability as
a a link to a Wiki page so I could link
to an existing item here and just pick a
hyperlink and go to a Wiki page some
kind of documentation on what this is uh
but what I ultimately want to be doing
is managing this flat list of work items
so that I can say that any item is more
important than any other item whether
it's feature one feature two I can
intermingle all of those things between
feature one and feature two to best
represent the business order and
business priority of my product backlog
so this is not um implying that this is
the order that we're going to select
items in this doesn't mean that this the
team is going to say well we think we
can do five item in the next 14 days
these or 10 items these 10 items are
ready that that's that's not how that's
supposed to happen uh what a team would
do is on each Cadence where it's
marketing where it's either replenishing
the ready Q in kamban or they're uh
doing their Sprint planning they're
going to make a a a
decision on how much work are we going
to take in from the from the priority
list versus um how much other work do we
have perhaps there's some uh long
running engineering work that's going on
that has to happen behind the scenes
that the customer do doesn't really care
about in the short term but in the long
term it's going to provide them with a a
huge amount of value so those items are
going to be brought into the Sprint are
going to be prioritized um in that same
way as these other uh business items you
may even add them to your product
backlog I don't have any of them in here
although it it does seem like that cuz
there things like review application
architecture but that's for the um
product that is referencing um and then
when I'm looking at this list I might
want to filter and understand what's
going on with with certain items so what
I can do is I can hit this filter uh
button here uh and one way to filter
would be to use the tags that we created
so I can say uh here's uh feature one uh
here's all I didn't do the feature one
very well did I um here's all the
feature 2 items and feature one uh
here's just the feature 2 items I can
also look at for example all of the risk
RIS Guardian items so if I pick risk
Guardian which is one of the projects
that is represented in here so I'm using
tags to not only represent the the the
features that we might be working on and
delivering uh some of those features
might go
across um applications that we're
building um but we're also able to
filter this by the application that
we're building so I can very clearly see
that these are the items that are part
of feature 2 that are part of this
application um but these three items
down here are not part of feature 2 uh
for that for that application uh so I'm
able to very easily change my filter and
say risk guardian and feature 2 and I
can effectively Matrix and filter what
I'm looking at to see what I might want
to take on into the the next Sprint uh
so in Azure devops uh I might even do
some little bit of plan
and there's my future Sprints for this
team um and I'm just going to do some
arbitrary uh uh uh forward forward
forecasting I'm not using a tool here uh
uh to do probabilistic forecasting but
I'm just taking a guess which is very
much a bad way to do it uh but you can
see on this list the actual order of
these items on the backlog and I'm not
able to reorder those items because
because I don't have that full uh uh uh
list of items cuz we're filtering right
it disables that ability to order but I
can still go in here and move to a
certain position um within this uh list
so I can say move to it's 25 I want to
move it to about eight move to eight and
then we can go fine tune that later uh
but here you're seeing there's one item
that's really important um for risk
Guardian here uh at four and then these
things are a little bit further down the
chain but we're going to create a Sprint
plan around risk Guardian because it's
been deemed fairly important for the
business um and feature two is more
important uh than things that are not
featured to but risk Guardian also
important so I'm creating this filter uh
to see what it is we're going to take we
can take about 20 things into the Sprint
uh but we only really want to take maybe
five things um for our uh Sprint goal
which is going to be around feature two
and risk Ian we're going to create a
story around that so what I might do is
take a little look across these items
and say well this this item's great that
we're going to need to do that that's
going to come in and then we've got yeah
that's not as interesting that feature
one but it should really be part of this
even though feature 2 is currently more
important than feature one uh and this
one and this one so that's three need a
fourth one this one's not as useful yet
but this is much more useful so we're
going to take that one and now I can
drag these into the next Sprint there we
go they've all been assigned to that
Sprint you can see that in there um and
that's that's our plan we could have
done this in Sprint planning we could
have done this in refinement and then
we're going to review it in Sprint
planning like we're going to take about
20 things into this Sprint but here's
the five that we think are to do with
the next goal we might get more
information at the review but we can we
can we can adapt this this is not
setting Stone this is just a a best
guess at this moment in time what we
think would be a good idea here for
Sprint one as we get nearer to Sprint
one
starting so there I've been able to do
that with filtering so if I remove that
filter you'll see those Sprint one items
there are not next to each other in the
product backlog because we're using the
order of the product backlog to inform
but not control the contents of our
backlog with a focus on value and we
made the decision about what items we're
going to bring into the Sprint based on
multiple um vectors of information one
was the the the the projects right so
here I've got risk Guardian Insight
Ledger uh Unity Erp there are various
various maybe we're integrating into
other systems right um we've got various
projects that are going on that are
managed by other people we're delivering
um the value and we've got a bunch of
features
which are a different way of grouping
the contents not based on project um and
we actually have there's another Vector
in here that we didn't really talk about
um which is the stage of uh um each of
those uh pieces of work so what's what's
the main topic of those pieces of work
uh that is independent of feature and
independent of project uh going on
within the bounds of our product that
we're delivering here which looks like
an integration tool so hopefully this
was a useful view of um how we can move
away from a hierarchical work breakdown
structure towards something that is more
flexible that is more usable and more
effective if you are struggling to move
away from a Project based work breakdown
structure for visualizing your backlog
we can help you we have Consulting
coaching and Mentor programs that can
help Kickstart your company's ability to
manage your work actively and focus on
the value that your business needs get
in touch
below