one of the great things for immersive
learning for
practitioners is that it combats
cognitive bias we tend to think we know
more than we do about a particular topic
you wouldn't believe the number of
people that participate in training uh
agile training that have been doing
agile and scrum for a very long time and
they haven't read the agile Manifesto
and they haven't read the scrum guide
the Dunning Krueger effect they think
they know more uh than they do so the
power in immersive learning is we
continuously Whittle away um they can't
escape the idea that we know less than
we discover by doing um and in order to
be doing more we need that Focus