our team's delivering working software
to at least some subset of real users
every iteration including the first and
Gathering
feedback if you're not doing that you're
probably not very
agile the purpose of agile is to close
those feedback loops and get tight
interaction with our customer everything
that we do before we actually get our
product in front of our customer is an
assumption and we need to validate those
assumptions by getting work in front of
real users as quickly as possible so
that we can ensure that as much as
possible we're going in the right
direction and not the wrong direction
maximize the amount of work not done
maximize the value that you get to your
stakeholders