so I first encountered devops as a as a
developer at Marl Lynch but I experience
the frustration that created the need
for
devops um in many jobs beforehand um I
started my career uh back in the early
ughs 2001 um and I was working for what
was then called New Media agencies which
are just web development companies these
days building
websites and we did all the things you
shouldn't be doing we deployed from our
local machine we edited in production um
we did all of those crazy nasty things
because at the at the time continuous
integration wasn't really a thing oh it
was round right at that time in 2001 I
think continuous integration had been
around for about nine years but most
most people hadn't really heard of it
most people weren't really doing it
around then uh you'll your experience
will absolutely vary there'll be lots of
people that that that were doing it um
and I experienced the frustration of
mistakes of deployments that failed of
overwriting things you shouldn't be
overwriting all of those kind of things
and when we when I moved to Mar Lynch uh
which is a big uh Investment Banking
Company the r tools were different right
you you didn't have access to production
um once it's production you only had
access to spe specific environments you
had to have specific deployment packages
you couldn't make changes to certain
types of systems like SQL Server you had
to give them uh a patch to be able to
apply
and when you're in those restrictions
and you try and do the same thing that
you were doing before cuz when I arrived
at the part of Maryland that I was
working at they didn't have any
automation they didn't have any have any
of these things you experience even
worse frustration because you give
somebody um who has doesn't care one jot
about your product uh some DBA in I
don't know where they were I know that
Marl Lynch had five and a half thousand
dbas in the organization who you would
give scripts to and they would go run it
against the databases and nobody else
was allowed to to go near the databases
um but it meant that that you would give
them it it would take them a half day to
get to it and they would tell you that
the script didn't work and then you
would have to go tweak the script and
give it to them tweak the script and
give it to them and it would just be a
nightmare and it would take ages to get
anything deployed so what what what we
started doing was thinking about how we
could do automation how we could create
a more slick process where at the very
least we were able to get into
production with with less hiccups there
wasn't a lot of devops going on back
then um it was called application life
cycle management and application life
cycle management was both good ways of
doing things and bad ways of doing
things but just under that guise of
we're going to be actively managing
these
applications um it's the term that then
morphed into devops a little bit later
on once once devops was coined so what
what what we did was we introduced tools
we introduced ways of doing things we
introduced automation to our story and I
started using at the time team
Foundation server um as part of that
integration automation uh everything
linked together traceability story for
application life cycle management we
made it a little bit more
professional um but while that was my
kind of baptism into that very different
environment where there's a lot of
controls we still didn't didn't do it
very well and it really wasn't until I
started working more heavily in the team
Foundation server
community and I became a Microsoft
MVP that I started engaging with other
people who were in that category and
really working towards making things
more effective that we started talking
about about how we could do the
automation how we could enable getting
from code all the way to production
without having people in the way uh uh
messing things up or other stories in
the way um getting in you know other
bias in the way getting in in the way of
the the thing you're trying to deploy um
and that was really my my introduction
into into proper proper it's probably
not the right better devops was as a
Microsoft um application life cycle
management MVP uh working with
other Alm MVPs within that category to
really really focus on on that story and
I found that I was I seem to have an
affinity for that an affinity for
engaging with uh development teams and
helping them get better um at that
continuous delivery continuous
integration tools tools are not
all of devops tools support devops but
they're definitely a common route into
towards devops cuz most I I I really
think of um devops as the other side of
the agile coin um
I.E agile was something that was created
but some people who were definitely
Engineers you think of the signatur
theago manifesto but they were also
much higher level Engineers they were
they were managers and they were uh
working on big products and projects so
they weren't just a software engineer
building products it was a much bigger
thing and they really um thought of came
up with with this idea of agile from the
that
perspective and some things seem to be a
little bit missing that were only
implied in the agile Manifesto but
weren't actually explicitly this is this
is the thing you need to worry about and
that for me this is how I feel about it
I think that's why devops uh was born
that's why application life cycle
management became devops is because we
really wanted folks from the engineering
perspective were trying to get to the
same thing that the folks from the agile
Manifesto perspective were trying to get
to as well um and that engineering Focus
means that that there's a lot more
Reliance engagement and support on on
tools on processes on systems cuz that's
how um core engineering folks kind of
think um and that that story kind of
culminated in me uh um co- co-authoring
a book for rocks called one of the big
red books um engineering books called
professional application life cycle
manag management with visual studio
20133 and that kind of solidified my my
progress towards um supporting that that
that that story and kind of I don't
remember when it came about it might
have been around that time it might have
been a little bit later um but a great
uh devops person called Donovan Brown um
who did eventually work for Microsoft um
came up with a definition of devops that
I think um makes the most makes the most
sense it's a little bit tools focused
but not as well um and I I quite like it
it's devops is the union of people
processes and products to enable
continuous delivery of value to our end
users so when you think about where
devops came from application life cycle
management the engineering side of
delivering products and that move
towards realizing and this was a big
realization for me as well with is that
um people uh sorry let me rephrase that
tools don't solve problems people do
right and people with folks like myself
with an engineering Focus very much
focus on the tools and the code and the
engineering and we sometimes forget that
the people are in the way not in the way
the people are part of the story as well
right and um we need to bring the people
and the processes and the products
together to create our system that
allows us to to to build effectively
build uh uh products and continuously
deliver products to to our end users so
there are kind of three primary
challenges in that story of of of of
devops um which is what I experienced as
I moved through them myself and I think
the the best way to experience them is
to move through them yourself right um
we we learn by doing um and the first
one is that that um culture and
collaboration shift if you think of the
agile Manifesto people and interactions
are more valuable than processes and
tools and that's absolutely true even on
the on the devop side but devops to a
much greater degree acknowledges that um
processes and tools support the people
in doing the things that that that that
we need to do um I keep I keep thinking
of the the um the night night Capital
group right that story about the the the
in I think they were an investment firm
um listed on the New York Stock Exchange
$450 million cash in the bank uh to
support their business um and they had
they had have failed deployment because
they were manually deploying they had
poor quality code they had a a poor
quality deployment with just one person
and something went wrong that they
couldn't figure out um and they started
hemorrhaging money the moment they did
their deployment and ended up they
managed by the end of the day they
managed to figure out what the problem
was with their deployment and and fixed
production but by then it was too late
they' drained their Capital reserves
they didn't have any cash flow anymore
and they had to file for for bankruptcy
um and the reason we know so much about
why they failed is because the
bankruptcy filing has to list why
they're going into bankruptcy and it
detailed the problems that they' they'd
figured out they ran into right um
they'd been reusing code that they
thought wasn't used for anything they'd
uh not been focusing on their
architectures and and building up
software quality and they had one person
doing the deployment with no backup or
support to validate what it was that
they were doing and the person
accidentally deployed to seven out of
the eight servers that they were
deploying to that's roughly the story um
so that that cultural
shift on the people side of getting
people on board with this idea that
while tools and processes don't solve
your problems they're there to serve the
people's needs um and enable them to
to make things that are really
complicated and difficult like deploying
software can often be really complicated
and different I I build and maintain a
product still and I think there's 20
steps in building the product and maybe
five or six steps in deploying the
product and they all have to be done
correctly in order for the output to
work I I don't want to have to walk
through that list every time Not only
would it be time consuming but I'm
likely to miss stuff I'm likely to have
my eyes go from step two to step four
instead of 1 2 3 right that happens all
the time I did training years ago for
for a bunch of testers um and I had made
the assumption that if anybody in the
world was able to follow a set of steps
that they' created you know to to to
validate that uh thing happens the the
correct way it it would be people who
were trained as testers but as it
happens that was not true we had Labs
that they were doing in this training
against a devops um and they would
constantly go wow this isn't working I
can't this doesn't work this is broken
your lab's wrong when in fact they
missed a step right so it's it's even
professionals whose job it is to follow
those steps when you're running things
manually also miss those steps it's just
the way the human brain works it's the
way things happen we're not going to be
able to fix it by focusing on the people
but we can build automation to help
support that cultural shift but people
have to accept that the the the people
that are part of your organization have
to accept that that automation is the
key that Automation in defining those
processes is the key to supporting that
story lots of organizations still
prevent us from being able to deploy
directly to production using automation
right from what we ideally want to do is
go from developer checks a line of code
into Source control right it ends up in
in our Deployable Branch whatever that
is uh we wanted to go from there all the
way to production and rolled out to
everybody without any human intervention
because that's our production line right
the the the the the the key shift here
is from development to delivery right
that's been you think about the way the
way car companies build cars they've
they've and Toyota kind of pioneered
this Toyota pioneered the ability to
deliver cars they're taking something
that they've designed and created and
that they works and delivering lots of
it into production that's their
production line right and we can apply
those those ideas and and and
mentalities to our our devops production
line which is from we've created the
thing and we validated that it works all
the way through and we can actually do
the validation as part of that right but
all the way through to to to get again
in the hands of real users that's that
not only that culture shift but also the
the the tool chain integration and
automation that needs to happen in order
for for that to work um and once you've
got that tool chain and Automation in
place right where we're able to do this
thing we then need to figure out how to
do it better how do we optimize that
production line to make it more
effective the the the the story I always
think about is um the the Azure devops
team right when they were the TFS team
and they were moving towards uh
continuous delivery from their waterfall
uh mindset um the the the the head of
that group Brian Harry at the time
decided to run a little test right so
they' they'd uh they were creating a
version of their product and they had
shipped their product all the way to to
production so it had gone through the
gauntlet of lawyers and validation and
uh um um signing and all of the the the
the gobbin that has to happen in between
so that it took them like I don't know
10 weeks 20 weeks whatever it was to be
able to to to get their product to a
state where it would pass the entire
Gauntlet that it had to go through and
then they had a Deployable version so he
called it a null build there's no
changes to the code base we're just
doing the same thing again and how long
does it take to go through the process
so you know upfront every one of those
checks so they had a concerted effort to
look at their tool chain right to look
at how they did uh the build and process
and what of these checks could they
automate into the process so that they
can then just give the artifacts and
they sign them off or even if we have
those artifacts and we pass these checks
will you automate that sign off right
will you as the person who has to sign
off over here just say I'm happy if if
you followed this process I'm happy it
all worked all I was doing before was
checking that you'd followed the process
manually if you can automate that I'm
good to go and work through that story
inside of the organization of convincing
all of those different people and the
build started to chunk down to a much
smaller capability and I think they got
it down that way to 48 Hours was their
their their automated Pipeline and then
they started thinking about the advanced
stuff right if your biggest problem is
going from 8 weeks to 48 Hours focus on
that story right getting all the
approvals getting all the engage bring
it down right now you're at this 48
Hours what's the next biggest thing we
need to do deal with that's part of that
cultural shift right not only have we
got the tool chain involved but we've
got that cultural shift of what's the
biggest problem what's the most length
of time that our process is taking and
how can we how can we make it shorter
and engage in that story so um then you
start thinking about more advanced stuff
like our Advanced Automation and
orchestration right the next thing that
particular team focused on was why does
it take 48 hours to run our tests well
we need the whole system up we need to
feed it with test data and then we're
orchestrating across the entire system
uh to do those tests is there a
different way perhaps we can convert all
those long running tests that need data
loaded and all maybe we can convert as
many of them to unit tests as possible
so they worked for another four years
getting rid of flipping that pyramid
right from having most of their tests
being the long running Auto Automation
and a few unit tests flipping that
pyramid until in fact after four years
all of their tests were unit tests and
they got that 48 Hours down to three and
a half minutes right so that's three and
a half minutes for a developer to
validate um that the product that they
just made changes to still works the way
it's intended to work that's that's a
total GameChanger for organizations
think about if you make a change and you
don't know for 48 hours whether it was
the right change or not or it worked or
not do you work on other stuff and
perhaps introduce more breaking changes
or do you stop and wait for that result
and then continue on that delay is a
huge amount of waste in the system again
Le lean product delivery right you're
thinking about how you do that and then
once you do get there and you you're
you're confident you can get things into
production what about monitoring logging
and observability right are you able to
see what's going on in production are
you able to head off and find and Trace
issues before um they become customer
problems are you able to um go and find
out what happened when something goes
wrong do you have the transparency that
you need in your product that's a huge
part of that tool chain and automation
that it takes many many um months or
years of effort to get your product to a
state where you even have time to focus
on that stuff so monitoring and logging
is is is really important that's
Telemetry right how much Telemetry do
you get out of your system I I I I only
know the stats from about five years ago
but about five years ago Visual Studio
the big Visual Studio product visual
studio uh I guess it would be 2018
something like that 2017 whatever
version it was um was sending 7 and 12
terabytes of telemetry to Microsoft
every day right so that's Telemetry on
what features A's developers are using
how long the things that we're using
take how long it take to load what
buttons we click all of those things so
that they can build a better
product because then you start thinking
about well if we've got our Advanced
orchestration we've optimized our
pipeline we've also optimized we can see
what's going on because we've got
Telemetry and logging and we can
observe in almost real time what's
happening in the system then we can
start talking about optimizing um for
scalability and reliability right these
are all part of that devop story and
then there's the third thing so we had
cultural shift and collaboration um we
had toolchain integration and Automation
and the third thing is continuous
learning and skill Dev velopment none of
that stuff I just talked about comes
along overnight and none of that stuff
everybody already knows in your
organization and even if you start
hiring in people that have devop skills
eh what do they really know what do they
really understand we need to build these
skills inside of our organization don't
think you can buy devops and install it
right you can't just bring in a
Consulting organization tell them to
install devops in your organization and
expect that to be the outcome the people
in your organization have to have gone
through the Journey and had the Battle
Scars to understand why they do things
differently and they're then incumbent
in your organization in your
organization's culture and they're able
as new people come in
to reduce the number of scars that the
new people need inside of your
organization in order to get on the same
track does that make sense it's kind of
like um why why we train recruits right
going into going into military
organizations you train them so that
they don't make the mistakes that people
made in the past things that we already
understand aren't going to work out well
that's why we train them so that having
that incumbent knowledge in our
organization and then having people come
in and train and become part of that
organization and that culture in our
organization is really important to that
to that to that story so that that's
kind of where I where I I guess um
that's where I got got to over I guess
um six or seven years I guess maybe six
or seven years so from
2006 to
2013 um 2013's around when I did the the
application life cycle management
book um that that was that was my story
um to that to that point but
then when as you as you
learn as you learn new stuff sometimes
we do things because we're told to do
things and we don't know why we're doing
things and in order for True learning to
happen we have to understand the theory
that's actually why train training
Theory training is so important
animportant inside of organizations
right because in order for the people in
your organization to have the Knowledge
and Skills to be able to make the best
decision in circumstances they've never
encountered before because we're doing
complex cognitive work we need to
understand the theory of why those
things are true so things like Little's
law and the theory of constraints and um
those are things that are part of that
the lean story that if we understand
those underlying Theory and Concepts we
can start doing stuff and learning right
we we feed that learning Loop through
our Theory and it solidifies our
understanding because the theory is is
the thing that helps tailor our way
towards knowledge and understanding um
so the thing in devops if you've not
heard of it something called the three
ways of devops these are kind of the
core tenants I guess they're probably
not universally agreed but these are the
core tenants in in the way I think about
it or of um of devops this is that
perspective shift to what's the theory
that we generate the body of theory we
generate that we then build all this
other stuff on top of because we've seen
it working right in organizations so
then what are the commonalities what are
the theories that we can um
understand that will then work in
everywhere else as well because
everywhere else is different so the
theories are the bit that connects it
all together so the first the three ways
of devops are are systems thinking
amplifying feedback loops um and culture
of continual learning and
experimentation um so systems thinking
uh the first one is really really
important that we can't think about
systems in
isolation so if you think about your
software as the system and that's what
I'm working with what about the people
that are doing things around your system
what about the automations that are in
place that build and deploy your system
the system is your entire organization
and everything that impacts on your
system so we have to look at all of
those things we have to take the
blinkers off and raise that impact
because if we
don't look at systems thinking as a
wider View as part of of devops and
agile as well right and agile as well
but we're not thinking about systems and
we think about just one small part we
might make optimizations for the part
that don't in fact result in a better
outcome for the entire system so we end
up uh making incorrect choices that
maybe inhibit uh the rest of the
system I'm not sure that I'm not
explaining that well let me think about
how I can explain that better better um
there are definitely things that I've
done where I've made a change to the way
I do things on the small scale that
means that the bigger scale of things is
harder to do so an example of not
thinking of the big picture in the IT
world is where um
organizations have a centralized
security department and the security
department in order to optimize their
world of
security they decide that everybody has
to use for example a virtual a virtual
machine right so in order to maximize
our ability to be secure and this this
makes per this a perfectly logical uh
consequence we want to 100% secure all
of our stuff okay nobody's allowed to do
work remotely in order to interact with
any of our systems you have to be on our
Network on our Hardware therefore we're
going to prevent anybody from doing
anything else or you could do what
Microsoft does for example um when
you're working with Microsoft you can
buy your own physical Hardware join your
own physical Hardware to their domain
they then take control of that hardware
and validate that it has all of the
security requirements that they need
they can remote wipe it and suddenly
you're able to work with any local
machine on their systems and be able to
interact um with a local machine right
you've got full low latency uh uh access
to everything moving stuff around that
kind of thing that is more effective
that's a let's take security with a
wider picture of everybody needs to be
able to do the job that the business
requires rather than focusing on
security as a blinkered view of just
that thing that's an example of systems
thinking it's widening that view and
looking at the wider scope of things the
second one is amplifying feedback loops
we need to be able to not only have
feedback loops but how do we maximize
the value in those feedback loops how do
we increase our ability to do stuff with
those feedback loops um so a great
example is when you're using Telemetry
right do you have the right Telemetry
not just do we have Telemetry from our
product seeing how people are using it
but do we have the right Telemetry with
the right timings of the right things
and how do we enable ourselves to get
the right data to then make different
choices on the way we do uh build
deliver our applications to customers
and what what we actually focus on those
feedback loops are hugely important in
in scrum we have loads of feedback loops
implementing that empirical process
control
system and then the third thing is that
cultural that culture of continual
experimentation and
learning that that how do we
enable people to not get blamed for
mistakes right we want to take
accountability for our actions that
we're going to be doing as much of the
right thing as possible but in order
to push the boundaries in order to
experiment not all experiments are
successful and that's normal it's normal
that not everything goes well so how do
we create an environment within which
we're able to not just punish people for
things going wrong but explore what was
the root cause of things going wrong and
how do we change the way our system
works in or in order to to
enable less of those things that go
wrong to happen and how do we change the
way we do things in order to minimize
our recovery time and maximize our
learning from the from the outcomes
these are uh uh the most important
things in application life cycle
management which became devops and that
story of the other side of the coin from
agile agil coming from the business
perspective devops coming from the
engineering perspective both focused on
trying to solve that same
problem at naked agility we love devops
um devops is how we engage with our
customers it's how we enable them to be
more effective it's how we get people
working together combination of devops
and agile practices which quite often
are the same practices um and it enables
us to help teams because there are there
are well-known metrics that we can use
in the devop space if you look at the
Dora report you'll find a bunch of
metrics um that you can use to get an
understanding of where are we as an
organization are we focused on the right
things are we looking at holistic
systems or are we you know H looking at
isolated things are we amplifying the
feedback do we can can people even
amplify their feedback loops or is
everything restricted and locked down
enclosed and there's no experimentation
no learning no ability to change
anything no ability to to do anything
with those feedback loops which case
people will stop using them so those are
the things which enable organizations to
not only understand where they are right
now organizations and teams to
understand where they are right now but
what's the next most important thing
they could be working on or what's the
next thing on their backlog of
increasing their capability to
successfully and continuously deliver
products of the highest possible value
what's the next thing they should be
focused on to to to enable that to
happen much much quicker if you're
trying to integrate devops into your
team or organization then naked agility
can help you focus on the three ways and
enable you to get the value that you and
your customers deserve get in touch
below