[Music]
do that
okay
um i guess uh welcome to this is the
is this the fifth
fourth fifth
fifth
uh um live workshop that i've been
doing uh this one is introduction
to the sprint review
so we're going to dive a little bit into
how the sprint review works
and maybe
why it's not working for us because in
some cases i'm sure it's it's it's not
working
um and how to do it a little bit better
um hopefully
this will be a good interactive
experience and i'm going to try my best
um to do better with the timing because
last week's uh not last week's two weeks
ago the
um kanban session
um that was the main feedback was
martin's timings up
so
um i'm gonna gonna try and do better at
that
peter is a veteran of some of my my my
sessions so he knows that my timing
quite often sucks so um
that's just the way it is sometimes
when when you
the participants have lots of awesome
information to impart sometimes it's
more interesting to listen to what
people have to say
uh so we have eight people
in person just now um i'm sure a few
people will turn up um as we go
um but i have as usual a little
icebreaker for us with some questions
about
the
um
let me just unlock them for you
unlock
um with some questions
about
the
sprint review
and i'd like you to
drag have a read of the the different
questions
um and drag either a tick or a cross
uh onto
um
on to the hexagon on whether you agree
with that statement or not
i did these ones a while ago so i i
don't actually remember how many trues
and how many falsies i've got so we'll
need to
we'll need to take a look
oh
has anybody got things dropping behind
nope awesome
just making sure because that's
sometimes a a mural
mural problem a tool problem
uh one perfect assistant for you
[Music]
i'll put another four minutes on the
timer for us to to go through this and
then at the end of
um this exercise i'm going to lock the
meeting
um
[Music]
we had
lots of disruption in the first session
with people kind of hopping in and out
of the meeting during the session so
um we lock it it does mean if you do
drop out accidentally
um because of internet or whatever
you'll not be able to get back in and i
apologize for that
um if you were uh
if you're still waiting to participate
you can
click the links and get into the
meeting before it closes
it interferes with my ability to quit
breakout rooms when people are joining
and leaving and joining and leaving
and then of ends up in a breakout room
on his own when it's supposed to be a
pair and he's like what the heck's going
on
yeah
i normally end up alone somewhere
it's a time when i actually can do some
work that's
even
where's f
okay well let's not use that button how
do you do
i've got a new keyboard
function lock that's what i want
f11 there we
go um
okay
we have well there's some that are not
ambiguous at all
number five
this is the only event where
stakeholders are regularly invited to
participate
everybody's on the same page for that
one for sure
let me grab a big tick i agree with
everybody
on that one
uh during the sprint review the product
owner may share budgetary
and likely release dates
i'm going to put another big tick oh
i'll grab the big take because then it's
already the right size there we go i'm
going to put another big take on that
one
we we
we want to we'd like to use the sprint
review as one of the primary
communication
mechanisms where we've got everybody
together
right so it's open it's transparent the
stakeholders are there the team is there
and perhaps leadership is there and the
product owner's there and we can
communicate things in an open and
transparent manner
and it allows us to maybe
have or not have or deal with
some of those things that come up when
somebody else thinks their stuff is more
important than everybody else's stuff
maybe they can openly and transparently
say so and why
and then find out they're wrong because
everybody else has other ideas right
that's kind of kind of the value in that
uh in this event
stakeholders and scra the scrum team
collaborate on next things
that could be done to optimize value
that's another green hick there
and we want to
what's next
right something might have changed so we
need to figure that
out uh then we get number three i'm not
doing them in any particular order i
guess new microlighter might have made
more sense but that's not the way i
started number three during the sprint
review the product owner may present a
forecast of progress towards the product
goals
right
um product goals are
pretty important
in scrum they help us focus the product
backlog
and gives gives us
ah what's the best way to describe a
product goal
so
we're going to have some kind of vision
or strategic goal for our product
and then
that might be
too nebulous too far out
for the people doing the work to
actually connect
to that idea
so a product goal is an intermediary
strategic goal
that is
far enough out that it's a bunch of
sprints but close enough that we as
people doing the work can actually see
how the work we're doing contributes
towards
that thing because sometimes the vision
is you know some solve some esoteric
customer problem and it's difficult to
see how we get there because that's two
years away um so how do we get something
a little bit closer to connect to
uh number one
the purpose of the sprint review is to
assess if the product increment should
be released to market
i would say yes it is
if your stakeholders are sitting there
saying we can get value from what is
what you have done so far
why would you leave it sitting on a
shelf
why wouldn't you ship it to customers
now you might not ship it to customers
if the cost to ship to customers is too
high
right
but then i would want to have a
conversation about why is the cost to
ship to customers so high
how can we fix that problem
shouldn't each increment go to the
you
it it should be released but regardless
it shouldn't be
it shouldn't be part of the
review to assess if it can be shipped
ah so i think it's saying if it should
be shipped
so if we have a potentially releasable
increment at the end of the sprint we
get together at the sprint review and
one of the outcomes might be push the
red button to actually release it it
actually goes to production
um scrum the scrum guide doesn't
require or enforce in any way that you
do ship to production at the end of
every sprint
and it just requires that you have a
potentially shippable increment a usable
increment
um
i would add to the scrum guide and say
yes you should beat shipping to
production at the end of every sprint
and if you can't ship to production i'd
want to figure out why and how do we fix
those things
that statement just had two negatives
and didn't catch both of them the assess
and should because i thought assess
if yeah i missed the should instead of
yep that's probably my bad english of i
know of norwegian so he obviously has
better english than the rest of us for
sure no i'm just the two negatives
caught me okay yeah
that that's my experience of being in
norway as i say stuff and people are
like yeah that's wrong
we don't speak english in scotland do we
peter
no no no i just uh yeah i'm just saying
the two negatives in that statement
caught me off guard yeah what did i just
i missed this should the ss and should
release to production okay
uh
what we got left number two
by the way that's the reason why i'm the
red dot
okay that's okay you did not you were
not required to own up to that
um station two this is a four hour time
box event for a one month sprint
that that is what the scrum guide says
up you have up to four hours
for a sprint review
right and it's usually
it's proportionally less for shorter
sprints so if you're doing a two-week
sprint you kind of have up to two hours
i would suggest
that if you're not having enough
conversations to fill that time
that for me would indicate
a smell
i'm not going to say it's wrong
right if you do a 15 minute sprint
review and everything is awesome you're
building the right thing your
stakeholders are happy they understand
what's going on your team knows where
you're going um and you can do that in
15 minutes
oh awesome
right
but in general i would see it as a smell
if you're not able to fill that time or
at least fill a good proportion of that
time it would mean to me that we're
maybe not getting to the crux of the
conversation we're not communicating
enough maybe we're not getting enough
feedback
from our stakeholders we're not engaging
with our stakeholders
um for them to provide feedback because
i don't know if you've noticed
right but if you have a a meeting
whether it's teams or zoom or any
platform
and you ask a question and there's 20
people there
you'll generally have tumbleweeds
you won't have anybody saying anything
if you do have people saying something
it will be the loud people who always
talk or the hippo
right you heard that expression that the
highest
hippo highest paid
individual in the room that's the hippo
right so either either people don't feel
like they can talk they don't feel like
it's a forum
within which they can
voice their opinions or they don't
really feel invited they feel like it's
a platitude
right
so there's a couple of techniques you
can use in there what one is
um
i i can't remember the the
the name of the technique
but it's you make sure you get an
affirmative or a negative
from everybody in the room everybody has
to say either yes or no and we take them
not saying anything as they totally
disagree with what we say so are you
happy with this product i want to hear a
yes from everybody that can be a
technique you can use to get to get to
that person that's going to say well no
this is this is a problem
right but maybe they didn't want to say
anything and to encourage them to talk
the other way is do breakout rooms do
smaller exercises leverage those
liberating structures i'll talk about
some of the options uh that i have seen
work
um i would also say that everything i
say is what i've seen work
in
the contexts within which i've been
working um so peter may have things that
work for him but don't work for me of
may have things that work for him
and don't work for me and it's culture
specific as well
the brits can be fairly loud and
obnoxious in meetings the norwegians
could be fairly reserved and
not boisterous at all
right so you need to take that into
account who is attending your meeting
and what is their culture even within
different companies
uh and then the last one number four i
don't know why i ordered them in that
weird way but there we go uh sprint
review has the highest number of
participate participants
making it an expensive event
okay so
this time
all of these statements
are in fact true
and the sprint review is usually your
most expensive event
right you've got two hours
you've got the scrum team so the product
owner
the developers and the scrum master
and a whole bunch of stakeholders
business people people who care about
your product
the most people
at any time are in that event therefore
is
by definition is the most expensive
event you have
so you want it to be valuable
right if you're wasting people's time
you'll find that participation will
decrease
over time because people will stop
coming back
if you don't show people anything they
care about
they're not going to come back next time
right even if you don't show them
anything they care about if they're not
engaged and don't see anything they care
about they're definitely not coming back
so we need to figure out how do we
encourage people to participate um in in
that event
that
does that sound reasonable for
my answers reasonable anyone to disagree
with anything
oh i got a little heart pop up there
that's pretty good
using the tool
using the tools
um
you need to do that
okay so well let's look at
what a sprint review might look like
okay so i've got
a couple of pieces that i want to to to
talk about here and then i've got
um
some little exercises around it
so the
the first
piece to think about
is
what
what's the purpose
of the sprint review in scrum
peter
i know i'm putting you on the spot but
what what do you think the purpose of
the review is
feedback
right it's it's
part of our empirical process control
system which scrum is trying to
implement
and empiricism
just means feedback it means
look at what happened and figure out
what to do differently next to make what
happened better the next time around
like that those empirical
feedback loops inspect and adapt all
different ways of saying the same thing
so
the sprint reviews outcome
should be
an understanding of
what we are doing next
and in scrum we store that information
in a artifact to provide transparency
called the product backlog
right that's where we're transparently
reflecting
what are we going to go do next what's
the next most important thing to do
what's coming up after that
right that's where we're reflecting that
so we need to walk out of the sprint
review
with an updated
product back clock
uh yeah i can put uh
off could you put the link for the mural
in the in the chat just copy it from
where you're talking
and you have one more question in the
james jet as well
i
haven't had that says can you like
what happens so carlos is asking what
happens when the product owner is absent
in the sprint review could you share
your opinion on that please that is a
very good question i am going to share
it with a little story i worked with uh
with an organization in
uh
horton
in uh which is about i don't know it's
about two hours south of oslo
i think it is two hours southern one
hour two hours would train one hour yeah
i always went on the train so it was two
hours
um
and and
that i had i worked with this team
and they were they were very
i'm actually gonna i'm gonna say
depressed
right they were not a happy team
um they had a very negative outlook on
the work they were doing and what they
were doing and i was trying to figure
out what the problem was
right so i go to the spread the the
events and see what's going on and at
the sprint review i just asked them
i didn't see anybody new so i was like
who's the product owner
oh oh that's that's that's thor right
he's he's not here
like
is
this is usually here
i don't know he doesn't normally come to
the sprint reviews
how how would you feel as a team
if your product owner thought so little
of the work that you were doing
that they couldn't even be bothered to
come and see what it was you did and how
well it was done
how would that make you feel
probably make you feel like nobody
values your work
[Music]
right
what are the what are the three
uh things that we need
to feel
like
we're
we can work well as from at drive dan
pink's book drive
let me remember what the three things
were
it was autonomy
mastery
and purpose
with the three intrinsic motivations
once you get money off the table when
we're not worried about putting a roof
over our head autonomy mastery and
purpose we want to feel like we're in
control of the work we do
right so scrum facilitates that with our
self-organizing teams selecting the work
at sprint planning
we want to feel like we're good at our
job right that we're learning more
things
mastery of our profession
right and that manifests both in
professional scrum
right we're doing that part well but
also engineering excellence if you're a
software team
you know are we doing
devops practices are we getting value
from our product are we continually
shipping it to production are we always
increasing quality are we learning from
each other that's that
mastery and then purpose
are we building stuff that matters
do we feel like
the stuff we build matters to other
people because otherwise why do i get
out of bed in the morning
if what i do doesn't matter
okay well i won't do it then and we'll
have the same outcome
so how do you create that purpose
for people and the product owner turning
up to the sprint review is probably one
of the first steps
right if you can't get the product owner
in you probably can't get the
stakeholders in either
and isn't he supposed to get them in at
least on the
that's one of these jobs as well to get
them together
to showcase what's happening and
what part part of the problem i found
for this team was that the product owner
also wasn't doing
the product backlog
therefore
the team was building stuff that the
product owner didn't care about because
the product owner didn't care what they
were working on enough to go update the
product backlog and tell them what to
work on
right so it was one of those vicious
cycles of spiraling down to
mediocrity
and the question is what was he actually
doing to
have the title product owner
sounds like he was not doing
wasn't doing anything
so so
but this is where we get to that
difference between
do i have the job title of product owner
or am i fulfilling the accountabilities
of being a product owner and i don't
really care about the job title part you
can be called a delivery manager you can
be called
a product manager you can be called
a project manager right i don't care
what your job title is
uh but somebody needs to take the
accountabilities
of the product owner um which is making
sure that there's a clear transparent
product backlog that reflects
transparency of the future that um
everybody on the team and the
stakeholders
understand
what those things are and then actively
managing that going forward into the
future so
if those things aren't happening that's
where i would look who's supposed to be
doing that
um so another question in the chat there
how do you get outcomes from the user
uh could you recommend some tips now i'm
not sure i understand outcomes
uh from from from the user so maybe
need to explain a little bit better but
i think i might answer that question as
we go through okay how do we get
feedback from the user maybe um
or maybe it could also be that you're
asking how do we know what the outcome's
supposed to be
rather than just being given solutions
which quite often users try and give us
solutions
so i'm not sure what you mean there
carlos
andre is asking an interesting question
as well
but can the scrum master be asked to
back up the product owner in their
absence right
and i would ask the question
if a product owner is doing their job
right they are taking those
accountabilities
then
they should be
knowing what's happening in the
marketplace
what's happening inside of the business
uh they have relationships and manage
relationships with stakeholders whether
difficult stakeholders negative
stakeholders they still need to manage
those relationships
and and they take all of that
information of what the team wants to do
what the technical realities of the
product is
what the
business needs are what the commercial
realities are and they funnel all of
that information into here's what we're
going to do next
i'm not sure
that i have often seen scrum masters
that have the knowledge and skills to do
that
right so it's it's like in a different
set of
experiences
uh
i'm not saying it can't happen
right but i would probably prefer
a business analyst
to be back up for the po because they're
going to have a better understanding of
what the business needs
than the scrum master might have
or maybe the scrum master is your
business analyst in which case maybe
yes right there's no real rule around
that
um
ah so carlos is asking how do we measure
the outcomes um let me kind of let me
put a pin in that and you ask that in a
in
in a little bit okay
um because i think we might get to that
um so what what do you think we need
going into a sprint review
what's what's
i i mentioned a couple of things as part
of this funnel
right one of the things that the product
owner
needs to bring into that story in order
to be able to review discover and
rearrange the product backlog
um to reflect transparency in the future
what should we show what should we have
on here
you have the sprint goal from the last
sprint so that's what you should be
measuring yourself
different against
because maybe we're measuring our yep we
are likely measuring ourselves against
did we achieve
the thing that we committed to
yeah
what what else is uh important in this
product strategy giving us the direction
where we want to go so we can align
flex strategy
yeah absolutely what what's our overall
strategy i would suggest that might be
uh
a combination of the product vision
and maybe the current
product goal
right
but maybe there's more information there
so i'm happy to put all of those things
on the
on the list there's probably useful
information
what what what else
remember you your product owner
is spending the money
they're deciding what we're gonna go
work on
so
what what do we need to discuss in order
to try and
be as
right as possible
at this point in time
in what we're building next
so the value of the product backlog
items
yeah
the value contained within the product
back clock
what about
we we just did this two weeks ago let's
say we're doing two week sprints
right we just we're doing two week
sprints
two weeks ago
um what's changed in the last two weeks
you've discovered more
ace or later wants you to inspect the
outcome
in the chat
yeah so that the the i'm
what is the outcome what's the result of
all of our work
the increment
yeah we need to inspect the increment
the product has changed
in the last two weeks
maybe that means some of the stuff
that's on our backlog we don't need
maybe that means that there's other
stuff we do need because of whatever we
built
right but there's also
changes in the business
right what's happened
in the business in the last two weeks
is their needs and desires exactly the
same as they were two weeks ago
isn't that part of just
having the backlog always
ordered according to what's required
or what's the changing and tide in the
business
so the this is the moment where we we
have all of those stakeholders
as well as the team together
so you mean more reordering the backlog
based on what has changed not because
if there's a change for it because
otherwise i would expect that to be
always present in order backlog so maybe
there's a change that the product owner
knows about but maybe there's a change
that they don't
yeah
what's happened in the business
right and then perhaps
market changes if you're building a
commercial product what's what have
competitors been doing
right maybe that's going to impact what
our how our priorities have changed
right what do you think happened in the
sprint first sprint review
at the microsoft teams teams
when uh lockdown happened
right we
we need the world's changed we need to
throw out this backlog and what do we
need now what's the most important thing
we can do to help solve
our users problems now which might
completely different from two weeks ago
right i would argue that is a massive
change that you don't want to wait for
the sprint reviews
are just for
i i would definitely agree probably
it requires a special session and
something bigger happen yeah
i used a massive example which
definitely i would agree or would
probably have some special things
happening um but what's happening in the
market what competitors are releasing
maybe they've released a feature that
means that users are starting to
gravitate towards your competitors
rather than your product how do you get
ahead of that
headed off and do that
so we're going to take all of that
information
presented in some way and bring it into
everybody's consciousness their frontal
lobe so we can noodle on it and have
discussions about it
so
we don't just need stakeholders but we
need the right stakeholders for the
conversations that we need to have so
your right of the product owner probably
needs to have some understanding of what
do i want to discuss walking into the
sprint review so i can invite some of
the right stakeholders
right some stakeholders are going to
come every sprint
because you're building stuff they care
about so they want to provide you with
feedback
so stakeholders is kind of a catch-all
word that they use in scrum which just
means anybody who cares about the
outcomes
that the team's working on
right so they could be users
could be business people could be
purchasers could be could be anybody
oh no unlock all
so i have a little flow
ah
uh carlos is asking
who who should present the sprint review
that's a good question and i'm going to
going to be answering that almost almost
right now
because what i have here
let me
that was going to be my next thing i'm
going to unlock this and just move it
out the way because i want to i want to
use it
so the first thing
that we probably want to do
during a sprint review is level set
everybody this was i think it was anna
came right out and said
um
you know what what's this product
strategy
is the product strategy the same as it
was two weeks ago maybe it is but maybe
we just need to reaffirm it maybe the
people that are there don't remember it
so let's reaffirm what's the current
vision and goal of the product
right and maybe we just show that
right but who who who who owns that
vision product goal strategy
product owner owns that so who's best
placed
to have that conversation
right honor
product toner is
like the
i don't know
you could use analogy of a ring master
of the the the event
right
um they're the hosts
who's
for them they own the product backlog
and the purpose of the event is to
update the product backlog therefore
it's in their best interest that it's
successful
um syed's asking who is allowed to be at
scrum meetings
anybody who you think has got input
valuable input should be there
so the product owner the scrum master
and the developers are always there
and then
there's the stakeholders which is
can be anybody it can be senior
leadership it can be actual users of
your product
it can be anybody
i worked with a company in the uk
uh and they ended up having to
they had one of those
um like all hands meeting rooms
in their company headquarters and they
would fill that for a spring review
they'd be hard pushed to fit the hundred
people that turned up
to see their sprint reviews
right but it took them months of
what do you really want
and once you start building things that
people want
they'll want to come and provide you
feedback
right they don't want to provide you
feedback on stuff they don't care about
so maybe share the goal
and then
does everybody remember what the sprint
goal was last sprint
perhaps not so we need to share that as
well and again that would be
the product owner sharing that
right
and then maybe in some way we want to
demonstrate the working software
who's best place to demonstrate the
working software
with the team wouldn't it
they're the ones who just built it
they should be able to explain to the
stakeholders what it is they've done and
why it matters to the stakeholders
we're building value after all not
features
right nobody really cares about user
stories and features they care about
value
what do i get from what you've just
added tell some stories
right that's the way i i i i story
telling is the best way to do that um so
there's a number of techniques that i've
seen work really well
in demonstrating the software um
depending on how many if you've just got
one team
right doing a doing a presentation maybe
they just present here's what we changed
right if you've got 10 teams
that might take too much time
so uh maybe you need something that
looks more like uh have you seen in
those american movies when the the the
the the kids have their science fair at
the school
and you've got a bunch of stations each
presenting a different thing
and people go to the things they care
about that's the science fair model and
that can be implemented virtually as
well with breakout rooms and there's
various techniques for that um but doing
that might be good uh doing some kind of
shift and share if you've got a lot of
stakeholders
shift and share is when you send people
out to breakout rooms and each breakout
room is a particular feature or part of
the product that one of the teams has
been working on and then you have the
attendees move to the next room the next
room the next room
uh in order to to facilitate that i've
done that one in teams
um
and it it works in zoom as well
but
how many teams should a sprint review
have shouldn't it be per team kind or
rent review per product
so if you have 10 teams working on one
product you show one
unified working increment to the
stakeholders
because you've only got one product so
we're doing a review of the increment
and we have one increment
we don't 10 teams working on the same
product don't create 10 different
increments
because then that's not integrated
together
therefore wouldn't meet a definition of
done
and that sounds good
so what what a lot of teams do or what a
lot of product management does
is um they they create some kind of
alignment in their product to minimize
the number of people that are
part of each of these stories right
so if you look at the way and the
example i always use examples from the
azure devops team because
um i i i've been working with them for a
long time uh but they all over the part
of the eight years of their transition
towards agility was they shifted their
product
from one big ball of string
right
to
almost like verticals
of here's a and it's now called as your
boards
right the graphical representation of
the work that you're doing
so there's one product owner for one
product
and then that product owner maybe has
two or three teams working for them
and those two or three teams are
contributing to that single unified
product so you have one backlog
one product owner
one
maybe one sprint planning or are like a
pre-planning and one sprint review
yeah but are you would you do one sprint
review for all five products in that
if i had
if i had five products different
products i would maybe have
five different
reviews yes
yeah but your the usher devops is now
becoming a then a
mixed sample or mixed example because
now they're five different product
five different products which
each of them
so at the small scale
right there is only one right answer
one product
one product backlog
one product owner
right
but once you scale up to larger
interconnected systems
maybe some of those systems are their
own products that can be shaped on their
own but i would suggest if it ships
together
it needs to be reviewed together
right so if you have a product where
you're breaking it up by component
rather than by vertical value streams
then you probably nee you probably
forced into the larger review where
you've got one bigger product and now
when you do have a much larger review
something the azure devops team did do
um was
prior to their sprint
review every team would create a video
to present the demo of what it was they
created and send that out to everybody
so
it's been my experience for the big for
big projects or big programs to do one
one
um demo for the whole project product
have you want to describe it um and at
one level you could say well i was
looking after data migration did i
really care that much about the user
experience at the other end of the
the data flow but it was still useful to
hear someone say
what we want to see next sprint is we
want to see the um
events
so then that would actually inform me
why people were then chasing me to
migrate events from the database
through the entire value chain so even
though i normally didn't care it
actually provided me and my team with
some useful some some useful feedback um
they
we can't load this data
whatever x y and zed data so we're not
going to display in the ux for another
couple of weeks so that would that
inform the guys other end of the flow
well let's not plan any work around
trying to get that data in
because the migration team aren't going
to get it to us for a few sprints so
it's
it is it is useful for everyone to hear
at least five or ten minutes what
everyone else is trying to achieve
yeah the the other teams are also
stakeholders to your
input or output maybe some of those
teams are providing output that is your
input
right and maybe you're providing output
that is their input they they're blocked
from delivering some features until
you've got something
there for them
right so it's that whole context
that is important in the demonstration
and so
i do agree of that there are scale
issues and you have to figure out what
practices work
uh the nexus framework which is
scrum.org scaling framework and
encourages having a single sprint
review but it does
talk about it being for up to nine to
ten teams
working together if you get more than
that you probably want to spread it into
i think they have a i can't remember
what the phrase is but it's nexus of
nexus
right you might have multiple nexi uh uh
uh that roll up to a single product
it's just more complicated and the
example that i think sits well with with
what you're talking about over as i i
think about the office team right
the office team sharepoint is not really
that dependent upon
words but word exists also as a separate
app but also inside of sharepoint so
maybe there are is a lot of crossover
um but they've got nine nine hundred
people
ish working on that product
um so
how might they organize that to be
to get the information to the people
that need it the feedback from the
people that need to provide that
feedback
um it's figuring out what works at scale
there are no hard rules at scale there's
so many different options there
yeah i'm just seeing some you said it
was up to four hours yeah i know it's
just a number but up to four hours for a
one month sprint and you should be able
to fill it but then if you are done
three teams
are you at 12 hours then
no it's still
it's still one sprint
so what what i've seen work and actually
what one of the teams that
peter was working with
um
they they
had a tight a time box inside the sprint
maybe each day i think there was six
teams and maybe each team gets seven
minutes to show their stuff or maybe it
was only five minutes to show their
stuff
uh i i so you're definitely bringing it
down
a little bit but what
i found valuable
was once they got into our cadence of
having those discussions about how do we
fit all six teams inside of this sprint
review
they started talking about telling a
story
rather than just showing here's i added
this feature to the product
okay but why did we add that feature how
does that fit into the story of what
these six teams are trying to build
and that started to then add more
context and so that it was even more
targeted feedback on
well we've built this part of the story
maybe we need to focus on this part of
the story next because then we can have
a holistic view of what's going on
it's generally to illicit conversations
the more conversations you have
hopefully uh
the the better the outcomes
uh but that was demonstrating
yes doesn't say if you if you are time
boxed
then you can always say at the end now
we covered off a b and c if you want
more information you know where to find
us
yeah so if someone is particularly
interested in
i don't know you know some example then
you should always have that as an open
invitation
did you find that that happened a lot
uh
yeah but we're all on the same floor
in one big building so it wasn't
difficult people would actually would
actually come and get you immediately
afterwards if you'd said something that
their areas pricked up on they wouldn't
they wouldn't dive deep into it then and
there because they can be very expensive
but they will come and see you
afterwards and say you would say you
weren't going to shift this
this information we actually only want a
tiny amount could you actually
prioritize that that's the sort of thing
that people would say uh after that
event
you know maybe even three or four scrum
masters get together and try and work
out exactly what we could deliver in
terms of you know to the overall to
overall product if someone wanted to
specific for some very you know high
value reason
yep
so that that that gets to that
collecting feedback
how are we going to collect feedback
from people especially when we're in the
virtual space because most of us are
operating almost 100
in that virtual world and it's even more
difficult
to get feedback from people you can't
just look at the person who you know has
some feedback or
see it as easily on their face if they
don't have their cameras on
um so the the the two
types of exercises that i've done with
teams
is one two four alls
right so have them build lists one two
four alls is about building lists and
it's one minute on their own creating a
list two minute in pairs forming it in
fours and they merge those lists and
then bring it back to the whole room so
what are the ideas for what's next
um there's also another exercise which
is made up of three parts
that i've used called a what so what now
what
right and that's quite an effective way
uh um
to to figure out what's next so i've got
both of those added to the to the to the
mural as suggestions to go research and
look at
and see if it will
do it both of them are part of
liberating structures uh so you can go
to liberating structures website uh and
see that there
um but uh what so what now what i've had
some really good experiences with it not
just um in sprint reviews but in other
other
areas as well it's quite useful
technique
oh so collecting feedback
um and it's again it's the the team and
the product owner who are kind of
hosting hosting that
and then
maybe we need to review the business
changes
right maybe this is where uh uh not only
do we have the the product owner and the
team providing input but we've now got
to bring the stakeholders in as well
oh well they're providing from
collecting feedback but
um they're they're talking
they are bringing you're saying to the
stakeholders what's changed in your part
of the business that you think matters
to what we're building
has do is what you need
changed
right because if you build stuff that
people don't need
they're not going to provide you with
feedback they're not going to care about
what you're creating what do those
people need
right and what do they need next what's
the most valuable thing uh we can do for
them and now what so what now what can
definitely work in that space as well um
and maybe those two activities you might
roll into one
collecting feedback and business changes
and having those discussions
um but i just wanted to be clear that we
need to make sure we cover both of those
topics
and then we need to actually review and
update the product backlog
so i i would
potentially crack open the product back
clog
show
everybody what's at the top of the
product backlog and are these still
things we need
right some of them might be technical
needs because the team needs to do them
in order for other things to happen but
we can have those conversations
i don't want a stakeholder
going home fuming why am i not getting
the thing i want i thought it was more
important than this other thing but
actually this other thing is a
prerequisite of the thing they want if
they don't understand that they're going
to be pissed
right because they're not getting their
thing
i normally publish they draft
um
sprint backlog for the next sprint
and maybe even do it prior to the
meeting so it's actually circulated in
advance uh that way people can turn up
with a pre-prepared opinion
that that is definitely a good way to to
prepare people if you have that
information have a have a have a draft
of the the
the goal what do you think what does
your product owner think the goal is
going to be for the next sprint
what are the things that they think in
collaboration with the team are going to
be part of that story because they
should have had those conversations
during refinement
right
oh yes so carlos the one two for all is
you you have one minute for people to
write stuff down on their own
two minutes in pairs
and then you join two of the pairs
together and they get four minutes uh in
in effectively two pairs
and then bring it back to the whole room
and it's a way to get even the most
introverted people part of the
conversation and contributing to the to
the story definitely gets people out of
their their their shell you can find it
on the liberating structures website um
but i run that i use that judiciously in
the in the live virtual classroom space
for sure it's a really good way to to
break that up and
stop people feeling like meetings and
events suck because it's just you know
broadcast
it's collaborating on what to do next
um
[Music]
and then the last thing i've got is
perhaps
reviewing timelines and budgets
for the next release
right we're spending the customers money
we're spending the businesses money they
kind of want to know
how
how are we spending it and i would
rather do that in an open and
transparent public space
with all of the stakeholders that care
about that stuff
then the product owner having
10 private conversations with a group of
people having to justify themselves 10
different times maybe in 10 different
ways
right don't let your product owner be
brow beat
bro beaten i think is the expression by
the stakeholders because they get them
alone in a room
right have these discussions open and
transparent
let's let the stakeholders brow beat
each other
rather than the product owner that's the
way i look at it
and at the end of the event we've
updated the product backlog
we physically updated it
we've made changes to it we've changed
the order we've added new things we've
deleted things
to me
that sounds like quite a lot to happen
in two
hours sounds like i might struggle for
time
right so maybe we can't cover everything
every sprint review but what's the
important things to cover
especially if you've got big teams off
right
so in in
and that science fair model works really
well where people just see the ones they
care about
uh it was a question
yeah
so somebody's asking what what happens
if i don't get everything done
for a piece of value
and i i would say that piece of value is
not done
and if you show
stakeholders something that is half
finished or even 90 finished
they're they're not not going to be
happy
and if you try and claim that it's
finished like show them something as if
it's finished
it's not really
morally or ethically
sound
i we're basically saying we finished
this
don't tell them we haven't finished
those four things that need to be done
and we'll do them tomorrow because they
might get forgotten or the
the world might have changed tomorrow
and we need to do something different
right and that thing never gets done
don't get caught lying to your
stakeholders
open and transparent is kind of the key
there
uh so i wanna uh i'm gonna skip this uh
little exercise i have at the bottom i
just kind of threw it on because i
didn't know how long this uh the sprint
review one would take but
um
that's really the the the the whole
sprint review that's it that's the whole
thing
now you may have additional things i
know that um when i worked with some
teams that peter was working with and
they also had like an architectural
review
that happened at the end
of the sprint review like we're going to
tack this on because there are people at
the customer that care about our
technical decisions that we made
right that they are invested in it
because we're going to build a product
and then we're going to hand it to them
and they've got to support it so they're
like we want to know how you built that
thing so that we can better support it
cool
just don't do that at the start of the
sprint review when the rest of the
stakeholders who are business focused
don't care about that stuff do it at the
end that's okay but again do it open and
transparent try not have another
meeting right because if you push it off
to another meeting there's other time
that's taken away from your team
[Music]
uh carlos is just asking about the the
the budget um the money that we're
spending
right every sprint costs money
we're we're using people's time so we're
costing money so so
what are we going to
to
work on over the next few sprints do we
have budget for
two sprints five sprints ten sprints
and do we need to go looking for
additional budget
um
yeah and for me that all sits within the
scope of the product owner and the
product owner is
accountable for value delivery uh
they're getting money from the business
and then spending it in some way
um
so it depends on your context right if
you're more in the professional services
context some of those things might be
blurred a little bit
um on who owns what and maybe you've got
some kind of account manager as well
right if you're building software i'm
thinking from an accountabilities rather
than a job titles perspective and you
might have somebody that is an account
manager who has to do the invoicing at
the end of every sprint because you're
invoicing an external customer
that has to talk up the time and make
sure that you're in budget and
you know what are our projections
because you've got internal reporting
you have to do for your professional
services organization
um that might be called a project
manager
right it's entirely possible um they
might also have accountabilities
outside of that account management um
they might be uh they might be the
product owner they might be a scrum
master or they might be a
developer on a team
um
my preference is to actually provide a
dashboard that they want everyone and
anyone can look at that says you know
this this is
um you know how many features we've got
to get through you know this is this is
our current burn up rate
you know and this is our current
predicted end date
for the current product backlog because
that way it engenders the debate i mean
if you're not going to finish on time
then that i'd start the debate early
about what's not going to get done or
extending out the timelines because what
you don't want to do is get you know one
sprint to go and go we've got six
minutes more work to do because then
everyone looks like a full
yeah we can be we can be opening you
know at the end of sprint one
right
based on our progress this sprint this
is what
the rest of our time looks like
don't we we we've only got one sprint's
worth of data so it may
change drastically as we get better at
delivering in this product as we build
up more of the infrastructure and get
faster at delivering features
but we can start having those
conversations
yeah and al always bring real data
i have have have data to look at on
what's going what's going on with the
product how we're delivering um
what our throughput is our
i use cycle time scatter plots and those
kind of things with teams
um definitely definitely a good idea
i mean i wouldn't i wouldn't do a deep
dive at the sprint review but i would
probably just have a graph
and you know a couple of a couple of
bullet points that says happy days guys
we're all ahead of schedule or
um
you know that's some great feedback in
the last two or three sprint reviews but
our backlog has now grown considerably
yeah we will not get through all of this
and that i wouldn't you know go into the
details but at least make everyone aware
that that's what your current broad
branch position is
yep
i agree
but you also need to have a different
discussion whether or not you're a
project or a product
right if you're a product organization
normally you just iterate
and push forward
versus if you're a project where you
have a finite date then those kind of
things are more important
so it's also yeah context-wise whether
or not you're
in my opinion at least
even with product based organizations
you know
unless you're in a absolutely unique
position you're always going to have
competitors you're going to have some
business drivers that will be setting
dates even if you know after you've got
to that particular release the next
release is three months or where
whatever thing happens to be
you still care you still care about
money you still care about time you
still care about
yeah but it's more you're
you might be reporting on two different
things whether or not you're this is
part of this release or next release
versus
an amount of
money right
yeah if yeah if you've got if you've got
a constant number of
um
constant team size
then yeah you thought you wanted the
debate is about when are you going to
release a feature
where if you're more of a software house
then it's more going to be about when
are you going to get it getting at the
end of this
product project to deliver a product
typically to your customer
i
i yeah i i agree i'm just going to
answer a question that that side had in
the chat which i think is very
interesting so he's asking can you tell
me about the types of reports that a
scrum master
should deliver to management
um and i i don't believe a scrub master
is accountable for any reports
to management the scrum master
accountabilities are are are
generally to the team
essentially to the product owner and
accountable for the effectiveness of the
team to management
um
so the the the
the flow of value
right in scrum who is accountable for
the for the
delivery of value
[Music]
so the the person who should be
um writing delivering managing
maintaining owning
any reports
around
budget and timelines uh around
flow of value and speed of delivery um
should be the product owner they're
they're the ones who own that
i'm not saying that they don't get help
right or that they don't delegate that
to somebody else that's entirely
possible um product owners can have
minions too
uh but
um it's definitely not an accountability
of
within the countabilities of the scrum
master
right it's within the accountabilities
of the product owner
and but i know that often ends up in the
accountabilities of the scrum master
because the scrum master is treated like
an agile project project manager right
rather than
a scrum master and maybe that's to do
with multiple accountabilities
right
um so i'm not saying that's wrong
i'm just saying uh
you need to watch out for that because
it can cause negative behavior
we have we have about 19 uh minutes left
and i'd really like to
um
[Music]
do the next exercise but i'm going to
have to be a bit of a bit of a time nazi
here
um
because uh
this this this
this one i think uh will be fun
so what i'd like to do
it's a little exercise it's called the
tritz all right so i'm going to ask you
a a a negative question so let me summon
everybody on the mural because we're
going to use the the the the mural here
um so what i'd like you to do
and there's how many how many how many
folks do we have
let's see how many oh there's ten of us
that's ten of us okay
uh i'd like you to
uh silently and on your own
generate a list of things that you could
do to destroy the sprint review
what would make it
not have the outcomes that we've been
talking about
right what could you do what have you
seen done
your organizations or other
organizations
what's something that you're
like the one i mentioned product owner
not turning up
right that's probably a big no-no
i'm gonna i'm gonna put that one on the
list
uh
so let me i'm just gonna
if i can figure out how to do it
just silently and on your own if you
want to type in uh something like
notepad if you do one item on each line
when you paste it into mural it will
become a bunch of post-its which is
quite
[Music]
handy ah
so if you oh well this i was going to
say if you're if you're on linkedin and
you don't have any sound
then go to youtube it always works i'm
thinking of dropping
the
no
you're on mute off so we can't
[Music]
i opened facebook after notes didn't
mean that a little while ago and it
seems that there is one
sound noise
oh well that's
so last time you had echo and now you
have nothing so
okay well
i i i it looks like it's pumping out
sound but if there's no sound i'm sorry
guys
um
i'm
the important people are the people that
turned up
so
i didn't want to break your flow on it
totally cool
and i can probably get to say i'm doing
a teams recording as well so i can
probably get the sound off that and
do some kind of magic
so i'm going to open a a a breakout room
and put you in pairs
so if anybody leaves i'll be very
unhappy because some well other somebody
else will be unhappy as well because
there will be an empty room
um
so i'm going to create five rooms
i will be going into a room as well oh
well that's not gonna work somebody left
just last minute
um
so let me fix that
oh okay no that works
i am good
so um what i'd like you to do
is in pairs i want you to compare the
lists you just made of of these things
that could destroy your sprint review
and merge them together into one list
and then i'll join two pairs together
that will be a group of six as well um
and merge those lists again
okay
so then we end up with one list d-duped
deduped
at the end when we bring it all back
together
uh what i was going to say actually
um
i'm going to add an extra one which is
internal politics
resize them all so that we can we can
read them a little bit better
i don't know if that helped or hindered
but
bit small box now
no
product owner not turning up not getting
feedback
people not engaging
oh as there's two not providing feedback
so i'm gonna delete one
rushing
not allowing enough time i i i see quite
often
teams putting 15 minutes for a sprint
review on their calendar
right that's not enough time to do half
of the things that we're talking about
in here if your sprint planning's 15
minutes and your retrospective is 15
minutes i'm i'm a little bit worried
about
um why we're not getting
uh
enough value
for that uh criticism
celebrating
of how people are doing it so at least
in my case we've noticed we had big big
sprint reviews of
60 people seven teams
so you could see people that were giving
time to focus on the high level but they
were going into so much detail that no
matter how much time you would give them
it still would be rushed because they
would just pack more details into it
yeah so um
having
having a plan up front
before going into sprint planning
um
knowing what you want your the teams to
talk about
uh what i mean the this is a uh uh
a presentation on the of the work that
was done in the state of
the product to the stakeholders
um so i would want to be actively
working with the product owner before i
walk into the sprint review and spending
a little bit of time what are we going
to talk about how are we going to
approach it what are we going to demo
what are we not going to demo because
the stakeholders just don't care
right we might have had to build stuff
to support other stuff that the
stakeholders don't care about
right there's no point in presenting
that at the sprint review
so how do we get down to
these are the values
the value that we provided to
stakeholders so that we can then iterate
on the next piece of value and and i
think that
focus on value is sometimes lost
any other um
highlights
uh maybe i want to uh ask about
something in here i mean like it's in my
mind it's uh
like plus and minus
persons because uh about the criticism
uh
what do you think about it like
uh is
the criticism is uh kind of feedback
through
or
is it just negative
so the there's constructive feedback
yeah that is
negative about what it is we did
and then those um
was that carlos or andre andre that was
asking the question
andre andre um
andre that that that question sucks and
i don't like the way you said it
okay
that's not that's not constructive
feedback
right
right yeah
so so
it's if you think of the scrum values
we want to be
openness
right and courage
to say that things are wrong
but respectful i don't know we see it
and it's it's not respectful to have
some hippo in the room saying to the
team that that that you suck and
everything you did sucks
and
your products suck you know that that's
not to create a positive response in
anybody
so so part of the
the role of the scrum master
is helping
everybody interacting with the scrum
team understand what interactions are
helpful and what aren't
as well
so maybe the if that that that person
who's like that is is going to be
participating maybe the scrum master
needs to go maybe coach them and help
them understand
how do we create
positive
interactions not negative interactions
and you can be critical posit in a
positive way
right and it's about the way we speak to
people the language we use it it it is
really important
and it's culturally specific as well
right
so what what works in
when i'm when i'm when i'm teaching
classes what works in saudi arabia it
doesn't work in the uk it doesn't work
in norway right uh the way people
hear things is different the way people
um react is different so you need to
bring some of that into it and when you
do have a multicultural team think about
those things
um it's specifically important for the
scrub master but the whole team needs to
be involved in being as effective as
possible
i would add to it that even even if the
criticism is constructive but all you do
on every sprint review is just focus on
the negative it really damages the
team's morale
um
in the past we had quite an experienced
c-level management and we always had
this very vague
um
yeah feedback like oh yeah we don't like
it but they didn't know why they didn't
know the direction where we should move
forward with that
and what happened in the end it's like
we would release let's say
seven different things that bring value
to the customer
um it was in timely matter my manner it
was everything was correct but they were
ignored because everybody focused on
this eighth thing that was not
fully up to the standards
and once you once you hear it every two
weeks or every four weeks
that everything you do is wrong and all
the wins are being ignored or like not
being
acknowledged in the room
then yeah it changes the whole dynamic
in the team as well so i would say like
the first point of routing in our
company was to share the stakeholders
okay it's perfectly fine if you don't
like something
but a as you mentioned constructively so
tell us you know what you want us to do
with it
and second do acknowledge all the wins
as well to to build up the the teams
yep
i i i would probably
[Music]
i would probably want to break the
stakeholders up into smaller groups
and to talk about those things because
quite often i i and i found this a weird
thing
the introverts
right don't want to speak when there's a
large group of people
but the extroverts are quite happy being
loud and obnoxious when there's a large
group of people but they're not as happy
to to be like that when it's a small
group of people
because i i think
i think
and this is just martin thinks
i think psychologically
if you're an extrovert and there's a
large group of people you feel like you
can say anything because you're
anonymous because it's a large group of
people and it doesn't matter
right but when it's a smaller group of
people it feels more intimate
well you're more likely to be challenged
though i would suggest it's smaller
you're also more likely to be challenged
than a small group of people and yeah
yeah so you're talking complete rubbish
there martin by the way
okay thank you for that
it's a nice small group i think that in
a very positive and constructive way
obviously
um so so so
uh breaking people breakout rooms are i
think are really important in all of
the exercises that we do but having
structure around what you want people to
do
um we we just did the oh and carlos
that's the one two for all
um that's the exercise we just did to
generate a list of things
um and and
i use this in meetings i use this
when i'm uh you know somebody asks in
the in the room oh you know what should
we do next
right and that that's a very vague
question but if you ask what could we do
next and you write get people to do the
one two four all right sound stuff on
your own you'll generate a list of
things like here's what's important next
um and then maybe get people to vote on
it right what's the the most important
thing because you may not have thought
of something that somebody else thought
of but it's actually more important than
the things that you thought of
do some kind of voting and then you know
okay maybe maybe this is the thing that
we need to focus on now
um and
it's um really important to to
get that collaborative environment right
and it can be difficult because when
you've got big groups of people um it
can be it can be very difficult to do
that what what one of the the six teams
uh one that i was working with with
peter before and there was what 70 80
people
in the in the sprint review
i think it was something like that
well
with that with that team the
the sort of business users gave positive
feedback
it was it was
you know it was the technical people and
you know as we all know from experience
you know no solution architect has ever
been wrong on any subject whatsoever
and therefore anybody else has come to a
different way of doing it
is clearly an absolute imbecile and
should be fired
uh if not taken outside and hung
and
where business users are more inclined
to say well i don't understand the
technology don't really care about that
but what i want to talk about is value
and
the the the developers want to deliver
value
and so that's that's an applicable
conversation
it's well i think your i think your
application is too chatty or why are you
using that database or
you know why aren't you using that yeah
that's that's the people that developers
will die in a ditch
over over that stuff
having it yeah
absolutely
um
and and i think we we need to maintain
that focus on value
right what what are we delivering that
people care about
because nobody gives a crap about what
technology the database was in apart
from a few pedantic people like peter
say
right it doesn't it doesn't help it
doesn't help the users to know that
well like you could you could argue that
it's critical for um
cost of ownership
i
i don't i don't disagree with that right
anyway
my point is you need to have a
reasonable and advocal debate about
about that based on
well i think that x is a crap database
because it won't do why and you think
it's a brilliant case there's something
else what's the business value that x or
y
brings to bear that's that's where the
debate should be not your opinion versus
my opinion clearly i'm correct
but we can quickly move on now
you are correct peter that that's how
you get those potential people to be
quiet you just agree with them
um
i'm just messing with you peter
i'll be with you
i know
so you can tell peter and i have been in
quite a lot of meetings together
so
um
i i these are the these are the things
to watch out for
um
and even if it's small like like uh in
magda's
uh version if it even if it's just a
little bit negative all the time
that can build up to that death of a
thousand cuts for a team
um and end up in that spiral of
negativity
um trying to
bring it down to
what's the smallest thing we can deliver
if we feel like we're never meeting our
sprint goals we're probably taking on
too much work
right or we've got the wrong sprint
goals fix those things
create a virtuous cycle supporting the
team
and what it is they're trying to do
and hopefully we'll build more awesome
stuff and less sucky stuff that's uh
what we'd like to see
there any
any any questions at this point
otherwise i'm gonna wrap because i am
six minutes over
i know
luckily when i do these things at the
end of the day most people don't care
that i go a little bit over but
alves waiting for slaughter
my dog cares
your dog here right
somewhere else doing doing something
nefarious i'm sure
you're eating into walkie's time
sitting there looking at you with the
lead in its mouth
not quite but anyway yes
um well if anybody does have any any
questions
you if you've not seen it already
because you're here obviously i'm
running a weird community thing i moved
away from microsoft teams as a community
because it sucks as a community
and i'm an over into it it's called
mighty networks and it seems to be
um
a lot easier to interact with i think is
probably
uh the phrase i would use
um so you're welcome to ask any
questions there ping me there or on
linkedin or
youtube or wherever you feel like okay
yes
i want to
ask one more question
i'm curious about the
no working software or no demo sometimes
the screen may fail
so what's the diamond what's the dynamic
in there
like uh are we still
need to
uh help the event the street if you are
skip it or
have a conversation or
what
can we gonna do about this
yeah so if if if you end up in the
position where
you get to the end of the sprint
and we don't have anything to show
right i'm obviously not going to show
stuff
but two weeks has still passed
right time has still passed still we
still need to figure out what's the next
most important thing and it might be the
same as the thing we didn't yet deliver
right but having a conversation about
why why were we unable to
to to deliver is it because the
requirements weren't clear is it because
the
some customer or stakeholder didn't
provide data that they were meant to
provide in a timely fashion
um there could be
a various things that we might want to
deal with within the context of the
stakeholders
and but we also need to be a little bit
courageous
as a team
to say you know we tried really hard
this sprint
and it wasn't good enough
um we weren't able to achieve
a working version of the product that
adds more value
here's why
here's what we're going to try and do to
fix it and we're just about to go into
our retrospective to deal with a little
bit more of that
um i definitely think it's still worth
it
right
i
i wouldn't be afraid to say everything
went wrong
i would want
the people you're saying everything went
wrong to to be respectful that we all
did the best we could given our
knowledge at the time and our skills and
abilities right and hopefully we learn
something during the sprint
what did we learn
we learned you can't do it that way or
that technology doesn't actually work
the way it's advertised to work
or
uh um
you know
uh i don't know peter's not a good
developer or whatever it was we learned
uh
during that sprint that resulted in in
our being unsuccessful is a learning
opportunity as well
they're much better off hearing that
news directly from the team in the
standard time scale and then fine you
might say it's not going to be a
two-hour review you might actually
advertise it out it's been a one-hour
review and give people back an hour of
their life now you might find that
they're actually
very supportive of you and that's hope
that's the way that it goes and you know
we'll have it's gonna impact us etc so
it might actually be a valuable uh
experience because the team's actually
gonna feel the love from the from the
stakeholders so i would i'd always do it
and
peter i i would if i was a scrum master
and in that position i i would maybe
um get in touch with all of the
stakeholders before they arrived and say
look i don't want you to be surprised by
this we had an incredibly
bad sprint um i i it would be really
helpful if you could be uh supportive of
the team and still collaborative in what
we're going to do next to make things
better
um i i would maybe maybe
knowing your stakeholders right
uh that might be something you want to
do or it might be something you're not
right but do you want but should the
there's two aspects or two comments
is appealed with no stakeholders but you
said the scrum master should contact
pure the product owner should do that
for sure yes
you'll just mention about the retro
because that's the most important part
but
should you in that case kind of perhaps
do the retro before just to so that you
you have some actionable light you said
okay so this is what we're going to
change and now we're going into the
retro to figure out what we're going to
change right
so so
yes
right if the sprint was that much of a
disaster hopefully we found out before
the last day of the sprint
and we can start to have those
conversations with the team because
that's a particular thing that's
disaster mode
right the retrospective is on a regular
cadence
so that we don't forget to inspect and
adapt on our process
and but it doesn't mean you can't have a
retrospective at other times because
something happened
absolutely thank you for that of both of
those
uh i meant i meant product owner when i
said scrub
scrub master there um and i also uh
definitely
don't wait for the retrospective if
something needs to be dealt with
ah
somebody just put something in the chat
yeah saying it's okay when you do it in
the same day yeah it could be and maybe
you just roll maybe your review in
retrospective you're including the
stakeholders a little bit in some of
your retrospective um and you can use
that time that peter was going to give
back to to maybe get the stakeholders
involved in how do we solve that problem
um that could be right
when you're in these circumstances scrum
is designed to deal with the common
cause
when there are exceptions exceptional
cause um
deal with it in the best way that you
think is going to end up with good
results that's what i
tend to look at
okay
well um i
i'm going to have to go on that so
friendly that i hadn't noticed um the
the
live stream had no audio
um so i'm gonna try and do a
post-production
fix on that using the team's audio um
so well we'll see that's part of the fun
isn't it
um
i had to rebuild i had to reset my
machine my my laptop does the streaming
and i had to reset my laptop last week
and i guess something's not right but
it's weird because it when i switch to a
different uh scene
it plays the music fine
it's just not getting the audio from
teams even though the little bars going
up so i'll need to figure out how to how
to do that
i've only had i had another techie in
the house that could help out with that
you need the producer
well so
sure
uh and and yeah that's definitely
something that would be useful
so uh the session in two weeks is uh one
that i have never done before i'm gonna
have to build it between now and then
and it's introduction to agile
leadership um because that seemed to be
what a lot of people were asking for and
but i think the one after that based on
some of the things that have been asked
here as well as uh on on on the inter
interwebs it will probably be around
data
um how do we measure
measure the team measure progress
measure
so not just the the kanban measures but
like okrs and
those kind of things how do we how do we
measure progress and i'll probably go
into evidence-based management stuff
okay
cool so uh thank you very much for
all of your uh all of your time
and i'm going to go and figure out why
there was no audio
on one scene
and i hope that was useful
thank you
thank you bye
thanks
thank you martin
you're very well welcome uh carlos and
andre
ananna
erica
stephanie thank you for coming
[Music]
so
do
[Music]
[Applause]
so
[Music]
you