if you want to
ensure that your your your products I I
actually don't like the phrase stay
within budget I know everybody uses it
but I I don't think that way anymore
when I'm investing in things I think
about it as I I have a I have a pull of
money and I'm going to move that pool of
money around where it's going to provide
the most value right so I need to be
looking at I need to I need data right I
need to understand what's going on so
for example I talk a lot about
hypothesis driven engineering practices
if we're building brand new products or
even adding capabilities to existing
products I want to have a hypothesis
driven story and that means that we're
going to have a you know it starts with
an idea what do we what do we think we
would like to add to our product and
this could be applied to a thing on your
backlog this could be applied to the
whole product or it could be applied to
a portfolio of products right but what
do you think you're trying to do right
and then you would do some kind of
analysis of that and figure out well
what's the outcome I'm trying to achieve
right this is what I want at the outcome
this is the thing that I'm going to do
that I think will help us move towards
this outcome what's the smallest
experiment that I can run and then I
would look at how am I going going to
measure whether I've made progress
towards towards that goal and I'm going
to regular reg regularly regularly
regularly assess based on my progress
towards that on whether I continue to
invest in this thing or I don't and this
can be at the small scale or it can be
at the the the grandio scale any scale
you like so a a good example is the
Azure devops team at Microsoft
wanted they were they were interested at
one point in trying to answer a
particular question right so the the the
the head of the product Microsoft called
it the product unit manager I think
that's their like the technical
technical term has has overall budgetary
control right so they have they have all
the money they know that that means
people right so they have I have exactly
600 people it's not but exactly 600
people and I need to allocate those
people to the
ideas that make sense in order to
maximize my return on investment and
keep my stakeholders happy keep my
customers happy keep keep build products
and have an eye to the Future on on
ideation and what is it that's coming
coming next so they're they're
allocating people's time is the the
biggest expense right
so they they had this this idea was
brought to them that we'd like to help
this is this this is the idea we'd like
to help
customers discover and deal with their
technical
debt right all they're building software
that helps build software so we're all
building software and we have technical
debt so we it would be great if we could
understand what technical debt we have
and then have things we can do to help
us things that help us minimize that
technical debt so that that's that's
that's it's a grandiose idea it's a big
idea that goes across the entire product
Suite you know I'm going to allocate a
bunch of time so the idea is that I as
the product owner the Uber product owner
there's lots of people in charge of
different parts of the product but Uber
product owner product unit manager
decide we're going to we're going to try
this thing I'd like to see some
experiments within the context of this
story and
you guys figure out you folks figure out
what it is you're going to do so his his
his lieutenants who run the different
parts of the product come up with ideas
on how and collaborate together what are
we going to do what are the ideas we
think we can have they nle on it and
they come up with some ideas and they
bring that say this is this is what
we're thinking this is what we want to
try okay cool let's try this one this
looks pretty good and they try it and
this could involve a 100 people spending
some amount of time
within a within a within a a quarter
within a year within a within a fixed
time scale to try and create some
features within this context right so so
when we're spending time on this
experiment that's that's money's not
being spent on other things that we know
are valuable we're
speculating on something that we think
might be valuable in the future right
that we might be able to do something
with so they spent a bunch of time on it
I think they spent about six months four
to six months on it if I'm remembering
rightly and they come
back and they're like we we we don't
understand how to solve this
problem the things that they'd created
they'd managed to create some things
they'd got them in front of real
customers like myself I'm their customer
got them in front of real
customers and they just didn't resonate
they just didn't provide value they
tried a whole bunch of different ideas
there was five or six different teams
different groups involved in it they all
had different ideas they all
collaborated together to create some of
these ideas and nothing resonated with
the
customers so at some point the product
unit manager is like right let's let's
let's let's not invest any more money in
this because we we we're not we've not
got an idea that's good enough to to
move the needle or solve this problem
you could
say that that amount of money maybe they
invested 10 million in this capability
was wasted money you could say it was
wasted money but you could also say that
there was a lot of learning involved
they learned not to go tackle that
problem they learned to save their money
and spend it on something else so in the
traditional World they would have spent
years on that capability to find out
that it was a bad idea right think of
the windows V Windows XP no not Windows
XP Windows 8 tobacco sorry my brain died
there the Windows 8 tobacco where
Microsoft spent six years they have 4
and a half thousand software Engineers
working on Windows they have 15,000
other people that's involved in that
story so you're talking nearly 20,000
people working for six years imagine the
cost in your budget for for
20,000 people working for six years on a
product and the end outcome did not meet
the expectations of the customer did not
meet the the the brand value right and
in fact detracted from the brand value
detracted from the customer experience
and you had a lot of unhappy customers
that went to other products like apple
right um that was a big jump ship moment
that people moved to to to other
platforms and
this fundament mentally was the Catalyst
for Microsoft looking at themselves and
kind of going yeah we're doing this
wrong this long cycle long budgetary
fiveyear plan right and and not getting
things very quickly in front of
customers very quickly testing and
validating whether we're doing the right
thing that's what we need to be doing
and we need to be doing it on every
product everywhere in the business at
every scale possible from the lowest
teams working on products
hypothesis-driven engineering practices
the the the the the board making
decisions about which H H products and
capabilities to fund and which products
and capabilities to not hypothesis
driven engineering practices you need to
be doing it at every level of your
business