creating an effective caman strategy is
hard in this world of hybrid work we
need to share our visualizations using
digital tools one such tool is as your
devops here I'll discuss how you can use
as your devops to visualize your work as
part of a camand
[Music]
strategy hi I'm Martin hinwood owner and
principal consultant at naked agility
I'm a professional scrum trainer with
scrum.org a professional pamban trainer
with Pro caman and I've been a Microsoft
MVP in GitHub and aure devops for 15
[Music]
years before we start it's essential to
understand why we need to use something
like Azure boards in order to manage our
work since the pandemic many teams have
moved away from physical offices and
even when we're in a physical office
we're not all there at the same time
this means that there's no physical wall
or meeting room that teams can use that
they can present all of their work
visually um where they can all see it
digital tools for saving and presenting
that work have really become more
critical than
ever now there is way more to a cband
strategy than just a tool a cand
strategy works best when applied to a
stable system one where we're all
following the same rules however most of
us don't work in environments like that
each participant in the system typically
makes choices based on their own
internal system one that they don't
necessarily share with the rest of the
team well why don't we share it I think
it's a result of not realizing how
important it is that we do share it we
don't realize how much
impact those seemingly small choices
make
like which item to pull or not and why
have on the entire system we've created
a lot of local
optimizations for for our overall system
that may have a negative impact on that
larger
system so what do we do about it well I
I recommend that you sit down with all
of the participants that are going to be
working on the work that goes through
your system um and have them work out
what rules they want to use are come to
an agreement on the choices that they're
going to make it doesn't need to be
perfect you'll have ample opportunity to
change and adapt those rules as you
discover the impact that it has in the
work but we need a place to get
started and really you you don't have to
do all of that before you start with
caman you can get started and then work
through those those those problems with
a rougher workflow um like just guess
whatever it is you work on just now more
uh uh details you can add later to start
stabilizing that system and and make it
more effective but but let's leave that
for
now for now we're going to look at how
we can create a camand board for a
typical software team and then how we
can Implement that in asure
devops I'm going to show you how to
manage at the cards on the board how to
customize the cards so that you can see
what's going on and also how to
customize uh The Columns and perhaps
swim Lanes if you have the need for that
um and then be able to see and visualize
what's going on on your board and filter
that board for the things you might need
so let's take a look um at what's going
on in your devops so I have an
environment um here this is just my
environment I have a a lovely org over
here on the left that's my uh learning
environment and I have a few projects
that I've preset up uh with things that
we can look at so let's look at a
finished uh uh environment first or at
least the first stage like we've set up
um our boards to be able to see what's
going on I'm going to click on demo
environment so on the left hand side
you'll see boards and you'll see two
things that are important you'll see uh
under boards you'll have boards and
backlog um those are the two main things
that I would expect both cban and scrum
teams um to use when they're kind of
managing their work so I'm going to
click on boards
first and here you'll see I have a preet
up uh board for this team so in this
view uh you can see that I've got a
number of different columns going on
here uh but the important thing to
realize is that the states of the work
items the underlying work item States
have have not been changed here when
we've customized The Columns this means
that multiple teams working inside of
the same aure devops project can have a
different set of columns while
maintaining the same States let's take a
look at some of the work item States and
how it applies to cand depending on the
process that you've
selected uh so here you can um see an
overlay with two things going on so I'll
horiz onally uh you can see the states
for the particular process that you
might have selected so if your process
for your work is based on the agile
process on the scrum process or the cmmi
process it'll have these different um
States uh that you see here so I prefer
the scrum process uh cuz I believe it's
the most generic although I do make some
changes to it uh so here's the scrum
process here we go from new to approved
to committed to done in the adual
process process which is the other most
common one uh people go from new uh to
active active to resolved resolved to
closed uh but the vertical columns here
where you have proposed in progress and
resolved and completed give you an
indication of how those states are going
to be treated by Azure devops under the
covers Azure devops has a whole bunch of
agile planning tools that have been
applied to the to the system that been
created um and the fundamental BAS basis
upon which they work is that uh you have
a proposed state so that's things that
we're not working on yet um so when
things get added to the system you'll
see that the lead time timer starts um
but the cycle time timer doesn't so
inside of azure devops they specify
cycle time as from when the developers
start the work to when it's finished and
lead time to when it's added to the
system to when it's finished you can
absolutely argue the validity of that um
I would maybe prepare prefer a more
configurable option but this is how it's
configured currently inside of aure
devops so if Uh something's in the
proposed state the lead time timer
started with the cycle times timers not
so in the agile template you only have
one state which is new which is in
proposed um and then you have active and
resolved which are in progress States
and then you have one completed State
called closed um and that's where both
the timers stop okay so when it crosses
this line it gets marked as uh um active
or
resolved sorry when it crosses this line
the cycle time gets uh timer gets
started so in in this case one of the
reasons I prefer the scrum uh process
here is that by default although you can
absolutely add it to the adile agile
template um by default it has two states
in proposed we you got new it's been
added to the system it might have been
added by some random person in your
organization so you don't necessarily
want to have started the work and I
usually use approved or some kind of
second state to indicate that the person
who um manages that backlog who is or
this could be the team
themselves the the team has agreed that
they're probably going to do it
right so that's where it's approved
we're going to going to work on it
that's why I would kind of like lead
time to start there but that's you can't
have
everything uh and then in progress I
actually prefer just one state um I
usually change it from commited to
something else like forecasted or just
in progress right new approved in
progress done
um but I prefer one state so that the
developers get the choice to split into
however many columns that they want um
having an active and forced resolved
State um can limit the way you can
configure the board but also you can
work it into the way you do things for
sure and then everything has a has a
default closed state so that's the the
the kind of flow of work from Azure
devops internals
perspective uh but we can configure that
however we like on the board so you can
kind of see here I'm going to try and uh
show you what this it looks like so on
this board you'll notice that I have uh
inventory I have backlog and I have
Discovery and when you look at the work
items they are new in all of those
columns okay so that they've not yet
this is the scrum template not the scrum
templ the agile template so you'll
notice that the the the the items
haven't been moved to a different state
and then in development we have
active and then in validation we have
resolved and in done we have closed okay
so this means
that when work crosses this line
here that's when the timer starts uh on
the uh lead time but it has to to cross
this line here in this particular
process to start the timer for cycle
time and all the timers stop at uh this
line here okay
um so that allows us to do a b Implement
a bunch of controls that we can use to
kind of see what's going on and manage
our work so this particular team has set
up we've got our inventory this is stuff
that's been added to the backlog that we
may or may not do yet so that's like the
The Back warehouse in our shop um and
then we've got a backlog which is the
stuff that we're going to try and sell
we're going to do has been moved to the
front and it's moved into that column so
inventory is just a big list of stuff um
and then when we decide we're going to
going to do something we've agreed to do
it um whatever those reasons are it ends
up in the backlog um and things in the
backlog are then options to be pulled
into Discovery so you could call this
options right uh
um so I'm going to pull things the
team's going to pull things from here
into into Discovery so they can put it
anywhere they like in Discovery so let
me drag and drop that in there once it's
in Discovery that column will change to
Discovery but you'll note that the state
has not changed I'll show you how that
works in a moment so once that that is
in this doing column Discovery doing
that's when we're going the team's going
to do all of that Discovery or
refinement work that they need to do to
figure out what this thing is before
they actually start it right before they
actually start executing on creating
this and things may drop out of this
space right because we might do some
analysis on this and figure out that
it's not something we want to do it's
either too costly um or or whatever
reason um here we've got generating
invoice reports that has been blocked
perhaps it's been blocked because we're
waiting for new information we we've got
a request out to somebody else but it
currently is blocked
but we've split this column into doing
and done so the doing column and the
weight State column we've done the work
and it's waiting for the next column to
pull it in when it crosses this line
here from Discovery to development
that's when this item is going to change
state so if I bring this across you'll
notice it's h currently set to new and
now it's going to be marked as active
cuz we've crossed that line um for the
for the internals of of of azure devops
from one state to another state even
though we've get multiple columns I'll
show how that's configured
soon so we've got that that development
uh column now so this is the the team's
going to work on it uh we're going to
work on it and at some point we're going
to mark it as done so it's now moved to
the next column um so again we've not
changed the state it's still active so
if you're creating reports across
multiple teams inside of the same
project you can still report on those
States you don't need to worry about the
columns right there's ways you can do
that too but um you don't need to worry
about the
columns so now um it's development done
it's waiting for whoever does validation
to pick it up uh this could be um last
minute checks by the the the developers
who want to um check that everything is
all the all the eyes are dotted in the
teas are crossed before they say
officially say it's done they're going
to check the work against the definition
of done against anything else they
believe they need to do
um whatever it is they need to do in
that that particular stage and then that
item when it moves across this line here
is going to move from active to resolved
um and you'll notice I've hit the whip
limit gone beyond it but just for demo
purposes I'm okay with that um and then
they're going to validate that it's in
the resolve state We believe We as the
team believe the work has been done um
we're marking it as resolved we're going
to come back around do a sanity check on
that um and then move it into closed to
say it's been finished um and there you
go we had a piece of work flow from left
to right through our system um hopefully
as effective as
possible now this team um is generally
hopefully uh when they're working um on
their their checks when they're viewing
this board is going to walk the board
from right right to left uh ensuring
that they've populated the board that
they've got it all uh set up they can do
those things here um and you can see
I've got the blocked visualization there
uh uh highlighted to see see what's
going
on so how might you configure uh uh
configure this there's a number of
things that you're you're going to want
to configure uh to be able to set this
up uh so I'm going to show you how to
set up and manage The Columns and Lanes
if you do want Lanes um so if I click
configure board settings over here on
the top right um you'll see that uh in
here um I have a configuration for uh
Fields where I have bug and user story
so if I click on user story uh you'll
see that um it's showing What fields are
available for user story so I've added
iteration path I think I didn't un buug
so I can easily just add iteration path
on here and it will show up on the bug
items as well so if I save that you'll
see that bug item change to include the
iteration State as well there's
iteration path there coming
in um so I can add additional Fields if
I have custom fields or something I want
to show on there it's definitely worth
considering that the more Fields you add
the bigger the cards going to be the
less you're going to be able to show on
the screen so just consider that um and
have only the most important information
surfaced here
uh you can add style rules style rules
enable you to change the look and feel
of the work items so um you might add if
I do a a test rule whatever it's called
and then I can change either the color
of the card or the color of the title of
the card uh so if I change the
background color of the card let's say
I'm going to change it to a kind of
light blue um only if the changed date
let's do change date
is greater than let's say today minus
one okay so if I save that if I've got
my uh there we go so these items that
I've moved today um are going to show up
uh today or yesterday today minus one
are going to show up as these things
have moved everything else has been
static and hasn't moved so I can uh
prove that just by bringing this one
across Ross and you'll notice it changes
color immediately because it's been
changed recently so you can use that to
highlight things that have H moved
recently or
not um I can also not only can I do uh
um styles on the cards you can have
multiple Styles if you want um again a
kaleidoscope of color um removes the
importance of color right so uh try and
be careful with that um and here you can
see I've got a a tag uh blocked tag tag
um that highlights a particular color so
in this case block tag highlighting red
um you can add other tags as well
depending on what it is you want to want
to look at
too um on these cards you can have
annotations so if the sub item of this
is tasks uh or things uh linked to to to
GitHub or tests you can have them
actually show up on the cards and you
can click on it and it will drop down uh
I don't have any of those set up just
now just for that that VI uh but then we
get to customizing the The Columns
themselves on the board so if I click on
columns you'll see that I have a the the
same columns that I had um set up before
the first one inventory has to be in the
new and the last one done has to be in
that closed cuz those are the start and
end States for the work items right so
that you must have at least one uh start
State and at least one end state
everything else in the middle uh you can
configure so for example I added backlog
um but kept it in new and I set the whip
limit to 15 so you can see that's 11 out
of 15 is in the backlog at the moment
and I can also choose to split the
column between it doing and done um and
then there's a I I don't really like the
name of this this is the the definition
of workflow uh field so let's say in
order for things to move move from
backlog into Discovery um there might
there's some things that need to be true
so I could create some
markdown uh uh that says
um
uh inventory to
backlog I'm going to do that inventory
to backlog um rule one right rule two
and then on the next one I'm actually
just going to copy that so that I can be
quick and call that
uh backlog to Discovery and what are the
rules that are going to be applied and
if I save that now you'll see at the top
the backlog has a little uh
um IE if you hover over it it will show
you that markdown information there so
you can add some of your definition to
workflow you can add links in here as
well so I guess it might link out to
your wiki page um or wherever you've got
additional information for these uh uh
for these rules for your definition of
workflow you could even store the whole
thing out there and just and just link
it so you can go and click those
items so that's that's uh quite useful
in the columns um as you go through you
can see discovery which is a split
column here doing and done all I need
you to do is take the box again you've
got whip limit you've got what what
state it's in this one is new
development is where we switch to active
again it's split and validation is set
to resolved and done is set closed so
those are really those those column
configurations it's not as um there's
not as many configurations as I I I I
might like in the long run uh but it
does give me that ability to to have
those visual boards and have work flow
from left to right across those boards
in a way that allows me to create those
those those visualizations that I'm
looking for uh you can add swim Lanes so
if you had um
different classes of service uh for work
flowing across this board then you could
create uh different lanes for this it's
not something I normally would do uh but
let's call this uh
uh expedite and we're going to make it
neon red cuz expedite is really
important but the default
is not going to be expedite if I create
that H you'll see I'll have this
expedite Lane going across the top and I
could pull a piece of work in uh and
move it along and it just counts to the
usual uh uh whip that I don't think
there's a whip you can add for the
expedite Lane is there a where can
I maybe I can set some
rules
um for things that have to be in the
exped D Lane versus in the default Lane
which can't have
rules I don't know need to explore what
criteria does there um it's not
something that I've actually used so
there we go you can see I've been able
to configure the board I've been able to
uh set up an expedite Lane I've been
able to set up my columns um and I've
now got a configured uh um caman board
uh there are some additional things that
you might want to want to do for example
if I switched to
backlog um I've added um some additional
columns here to the backlog so as well
as having State I've also added board
column uh and board column done um so
you can see a little bit more about
what's going on on the other board so if
you're the product owner or you're the
team lead or whatever people the whole
team right looking at the order of the
backlog um you're able to manage it uh
from there pretty
[Music]
effectively if you're struggling to
understand your systems or how work
flows through these systems the naked
utility can help or help you find
somebody who can help you we specialize
in helping companies that build software
get better at building software and
being able to analyze the flow of work
through your existing system is critical
to figuring out what to
improve don't wait get help as as soon
as possible to minimize that waste get
in touch
[Music]
below