so a product by product backlog
um is really very misunderstood product
backlog is just a list of things that we
would like the product to do that it
doesn't do yet that's it uh it can be
super short here's one thing that I
would like the product to do that it
doesn't do yet that's a product backlog
uh here's 20 things that I'd like the
product to do that might be a product
backlog uh here's something that's not a
product backlog here's 5 000 things I'd
like the product to do that is
absolutely not a product backlog that's
just a Dumping Ground that's a dump
right
um one of the key things that makes a
product backlog a product backlog is
that everybody stakeholders product
owner and team members understand
everything that's in there and if they
don't it's not a product backlog