the current state of um scrum Masters in
the industry at the moment is pretty
pretty terrible um there is a massive
massive systemic lack of
competence um in the in in the scrum
Master role in the scrum Master
accountability across organizations and
I think much of this comes from
the Boom that we've had the cash cow
that we've had in the agile world where
um the the this the demand for scrum
Masters to help teams which really
wasn't I guess realized as much before
the early naughties um has far
outstripped Supply right so so we want
to have somebody with some kind of uh
competence within this context on every
team um in every group um in every
Department of every every company right
so whether you're called a scrum master
or an agile coach or whatever um it's
all the same the same skill set and
because there's been a massive uh um
demand but very small Supply the price
has gone up and because the price has
gone up all the the the folks who aren't
even in it aren't even in that world of
the context of that team are looking at
these very lucrative jobs over here in
this other space and the grass is
greener over there so let's let's go
over there and we have lots and lots and
lots and lots of people over the last 15
years 15 almost 20 years um that have
moved in to this space to be a scrum
master or agile coach um who largely
have no skills whatsoever within the
context of the team uh maybe they've
done a a two-day scrum Master Class um
which FYI does not make you a scrum
master um just
like I don't know passing your driving
test doesn't make you a Formula 1 driver
right it just means that you you're
hopefully not a danger to everybody on
the road hopefully doesn't mean that
that that's not true um and you've got a
lifelong learning and experience right
you can't just jump in a Formula One car
you can't just jump in any racing car on
any track for uh uh without some level
of skills training knowledge expertise
you can get a track day right but um um
expect there to be limitations on what
it is you can do be be because it it's
takes experience and time to build that
experience and
understanding
of the
detail of the world within which you're
coaching and helping teams right um so
if I was coaching and I I for example
here's a great example of um a lack of
competence I did a bunch of training not
coaching but training um for police
officers in Ghana um they were going to
be using um scrum as an organizational
change mechanism like not to do their
work we were teaching them scrum so that
they could use scrum to change the as a
change mechanism in their
organization so I I have I have
competence and can understand
organizations and organizational
structure through experience right and
understand
how I understand
scrum and how you can use scrum to
incrementally and iteratively change
your organization and deal with those uh
that complexity right you have a backlog
backlog of organizational changes and
what Cadence are you iterating on them
all those kind of things
and but I have absolutely zero
understanding of police work beyond what
I see on TV
right I have I have no experience or
skills I can't say to a police
officer this is how you should do your
job and it will make you more
effective I can't do that and I wouldn't
do that I would not do that um we had
some when I was teaching the the
training I had the the head of
Cid in in in one of the classes we did a
bunch of classes ah head of CID and CID
is if you're in the US it would be the
chief of detectives maybe I don't know
the head of detectives Lieutenant for
detectives uh Cid in the UK and the
British Empire world is the the the the
investigative Divi Division I don't even
know what it stands for ID I don't know
anyway um so he was the head of c and he
started asking me a bunch of questions
about how he could apply
the things we were talking about to
police
work and I had to say look I have no
knowledge or understanding of what it is
you do beyond the
movies and I can
imagine that you don't know how long
it's going to take to solve a case right
you have to do a bunch of work you know
there are some things you always have to
do and there'll be something different
in every case every everything that you
do but you know perhaps what the
definition of done what the list of
things at the end is that you need to
have um and it's it's great if you can
figure out how to leverage some of these
practices to be able to help with that
but I can't help you with that right
because that's not my background and
expertise but what we're seeing and have
seen over the last 15 20 years is loads
of people coming into um it right my
back ground is it that's where uh this
this this this this stuff kind of
spawned from most recently right the ad
your Manifesto for for software
development and um they they they have
no background in software no background
in uh um any sort of it and they've
perhaps done a two-day scrum Master
course or perhaps done a coaching class
right so they've learned to coach uh
professional coaching
experience and that's just not good
enough to be able to fulfill the
accountability of the scrum Master right
the scrum master has um an
accountability to help the team be as
effective as possible and they do that
through three areas right they have
three um kind of sets of
accountabilities as it were one is the
accountability to the team itself so
what can they do to help the team be
effective in order to help a team be
effective you need to
understand the
context within which the team are
working whatever that context is for me
it's software engineering right if
you're going to be helping a team of
software Engineers become more effective
you have to understand
the the the practices the principles of
that work so that you can help them so
in in the software engineering World um
there are we have we have modern
engineering practices we have devops um
um we have things like release planning
and scaling and uh all of those those
those things to do with to do with the
actual engineering practices but you
also have stuff you might gain through
experience in other areas like how to do
organizational change right that's not
something that maybe you need it
specific skills for or conflict
management right that's something that
you might learn in your professional
coaching um but that doesn't remove the
need to have that understanding of what
the team is working on what it is
they're doing um so for a scrum Master
within that context i w within the
context of a software team right there
would be other things on my list if it
was for for for a different type of work
but for a software team I I would expect
them to understand devops devops
principles devops practices um
understand what it takes to fulfill them
what it looks like when they're being
successful um to understand um modern
engineering practices
right what if if the team's work is
building
software you need to understand how to
build software in order to help the team
be effective at building software
because they might not know I've worked
with lots of lots of teams all over the
world as a as a devops consultant as an
agile
consultant
that have huge gaps in their
understanding of of huge huge massive
gaps in what it is they do the the one
of one of the biggest ones um that I
usually use as as an example right
biggest Gap um was using using Source
control and not and understanding
branching but not understanding merging
not understanding that there are tools
within your Source control system that
allow you to merge code in a mostly
automated fashion right if there's no
conflict in changes and then dealing
with conflicts and I worked with a team
it was 30 Engineers um in an
organization they've been building
software for for many years um those
lead Engineers there was people
who been building software for many many
years and they had no idea that there
were tools inside of the source control
system that allowed you to merge code
and they were doing it manually with
Beyond Compare right they were just
comparing files and copying across the
bits that they want wanted hugely error
prone huge number of bugs introduced by
that kind of kind of mechanism because
they they weren't using those
tools if I didn't know that those tools
existed if I didn't understand the
workflow of source control right
regardless of whether you've actually
used Source control or not although I
think if you're going to be working with
software teams you have to understand
how Source control works you have to
understand how automated builds work you
have to understand how uh um um work
items um the work that you're doing can
be linked to the code so that you can
get more effective understanding of
what's being changed and how it's being
changed and how you're testing it um and
that doesn't require you to have been a
software engineer right if you've been a
tester or you've been an analyst on a
team and you've done those things for
many years you're going to understand
those things and if you don't understand
those things you need to learn those
things right in order to be a an
effective scrum Master for a software
engineering team but that's just one of
the things that one of the three things
that a a scrum Master is accountable for
they're also accountable for services to
the product owner not just to the team
but specifically to the product owner so
what does the product owner do the
product owner maximizes the value
delivered by the work from the
team so the one of the scrum Masters
jobs roles accountabilities things they
have to do is they have to be able to
enable and help that product owner
become more effective because that
product owner might not understand the
the things that they have to do they
might not understand the the processes
and practices that are available to them
they might have outdated knowledge they
might come from a
traditional uh um background where we're
not doing fast iterations and while most
of the practices can still be used they
need to be modified to allow it to work
in the iterative and incremental um
world right of continuous delivery and
continuous uh learning so how do you
help them if you don't understand what
they
do how how how how do you know that they
don't understand um hypothesis driven
engineering practices if if if you don't
understand hypothesis driven engineering
practices how do
you know that they should be able to
look at the Telemetry from the product
and understand and use it to help inform
the decisions that they're making how
how do you know that they need to be
building relationships with people
inside of the business and how they
build relationship ship with people
understand the dynamic of those
relationships unless you do you can't
help them do that you can't help them do
something that they don't know or don't
understand how to do already and in my
experience many at least in my
experience right because remember um my
caveat with everything is I get called
by people who need help so in
general product owners don't have the
background knowledge understanding or
experience to know um how to maximize
the value delivered in the product right
there are absolutely product managers uh
and product owners out there who do
understand that absolutely um but they
don't need to call me to come and help
them right they don't come to my product
owner classes they don't come to my uh
uh uh product management Mentor programs
right because they already know that
stuff so they can do it but if you want
to help those people who don't
understand you need to understand that
thing to be able to to to help teach
them coach them and Mentor them right um
and we're not even done yet because
there's a there's a third thing and the
third thing is the
organizational um I guess uh uh Lisa
Atkins calls it uh organizational
transformational Mastery I usually call
it organizational evolutionary Mastery
because I feel like Evolution doesn't
have an end whereas transformation might
have an end right it's a continuous
thing how how do you help the
organization change how do you um if you
don't understand organizational
topologies if you don't understand how
organizations function and go together
if you don't understand the the options
that are
available that have been known to be
effective within that space for things
to try and see whether it works within
this particular organization if you
don't have that standing how do you know
that something needs to change how do
you know that things can be different um
so you've got that
accountability to the organization for
helping them be effective and when you
bring all of that together you end up
with an individual that that's quite
significantly skilled with lots of
experience right they probably have a
Gray beard because they've been around
for a while um or gray hair right
they're they're they're
um he or she has been um in the trenches
with the team they've H worked as a team
member that's when I'm thinking about a
scrum master I'm thinking about somebody
who's worked as a team member for many
years gained a bunch of experience um
helped their team so they've started
helping their team their team has ret
ized that they're helping I they look to
them as a leader in that space of
Effectiveness um and then that grows
over time right so so not just the team
looking to them the product owner looks
at them the other people in the
organization start looking to them as
somebody who can help them uh um be more
effective deliver more value um change
the way we do things because have this
understanding of how all of the they
have they have a core understanding of
the theory the the the philosophies and
the principles to be able to apply them
within multiple various contexts but you
you get that through um learning you get
that through um experience not just
experience of doing it and trying it but
experience of of of of learning and
figuring it out and then seeing whether
it works and and closing those feedback
loops and having that Triple Loop
learning and changing your worldview and
how you can do things and this is just
not that it it doesn't seem to be that
common right um so there's a massive
deficit at the moment in the level of
competence and if you're you're you're
interested in in how big that deficit is
um there's
some a little is it anecdotal no it's
just not particular scientific but
there's some data from an organization
called scrum match uh who uh review
scrum Master skills I mean as part of
their story is is is is a little bit of
a recruitment story but they review
scrum Master skills um it's not just
people who are looking for jobs right
but it's it's it's to get a you get a
badge I I'm this level of scrum Master
uh so some people look at it as a bad
badging um and what they found was that
61% of the people that they engaged with
reviewed who were scrum Masters
already perhaps had been a scrum Master
for 10 years or more so there were
people in that list that were 10 years
or more um 61% of them are uh shouldn't
be SC masters 61% of them I think it was
38 I'm going to be a little bit off in
the percentages but only by fractions um
it was about 30 38% I think um had never
read the scrum guide and in that has
never read the scrum guide there were
scrum Masters who had been inrolled for
10 years or more never read the scrum
guide um there were uh uh uh the rest of
that
61% where I've read the scrum guide but
I kind of I you know I don't really
understand scrum that well I understand
scrum and I I can rudiment apply it to
to to
organizations none of those things are
good enough to be a scrum Master none of
those things are good enough to help a
product team be more effective so it's
absolutely no
surprise that as we enter a period of
fiscal uncertainty a global fiscal
uncertainty that
organizations are looking to reduce
their costs and they're looking at the
capability of the people that they
currently have as scrum Masters and
they're saying this isn't good enough
these people are not
competent and if you're not competent
you're incompetent the majority of scrum
Masters in row
today are incompetent they should not be
in that position they should not be
doing that wrong and the only only way
um organizations have to demonstrate
their lack of satisfaction with that is
to start getting rid of scrub Masters
and agile coaches and that's the
position we're in right now we're seeing
a a massive industry correction uh a
competence bubble has popped or an
incompetence bubble has popped um and
there are loads of good scrum Masters
that have been caught up in in in the
nasty right as organizations are
divesting themselves but almost all of
these organizations are still hiring
scrum Masters they're just being more
Discerning and I think we're moving from
an era of wild west agile towards more
of an era of competent agile