if we want to
improve the quality of our product and
reduce risk part of our automation story
is going to be cicd pipelines it's it's
worth
noting that
most most
teams don't use cicd for
cicd they use it for an automated
build okay
I see very
few
teams applying engineering excellence
and doing CI CD as it's intended to be
done just to clarify a little bit
continuous
integration
is coupled with Mainline
branching it's not integrated if it's
not in the mainline in with the rest of
your code so if you've got a CI a
continuous integration on a separate
Branch right that's not actually a CI
that's just a continuous build on your
separate branch which is great
definitely have that but we want
continuous integration we want to be
continuously pulling things into the one
true version so we have fewer and fewer
integration problems we have fewer and
fewer other problems coming off that
because we're having to support multiple
versions of our product if you've get
test live in branches you're just
fundamentally doing it wrong you might
have an older product I I
definitely don't judge the decisions
that led to that in the past right you
might have made that choice 20 years ago
in your product but you shouldn't be
making that choice today Dev test live
with
branches nobody no product anywhere
should be making that choice today we
should be doing continuous integration
and continuous delivery continuous
integration is where you have Mainline
branching and things are continuously
integrating into that Mainline Branch
right everything all the work of all the
engineers that are working on your
product are continuously integrated
every day uh Google is notorious for
this one they have one source control
repository for the whole company every
product everywhere in the company is on
that one main line okay so
that that's a little bit extreme that's
a mono repo that's a little bit extreme
uh but at least for a product you want
to have that Mainline branching model
where you're continuously integrating
every day you should not I would object
to a branch that's around for longer
than a day I'd strenuous strenuously
object to a branches around for more
than a couple of days right yeah yeah
I'm not saying that they wouldn't happen
it's possible but I'm strally object
where people work right people are
adding new things adding new cap ility
don't shouldn't exist for very long so
it it it that's CI continuous
integration continuous delivery is when
it hits the main
line it's going to
production that that's that's continuous
delivery is not I'm continuously
delivering to my test environment it's
I'm continuously delivering to
production to real
users now you might use a ring based
deployment model where you're protecting
and and limiting the blast radius of any
problems behind an audience perhaps it
could be audience-based rings that
enable you to to have your high-risk
customers in a later ring so you find
the problems first with lower risk
customers or or or yeah lower risk
customers but continuous delivery the
delivery part in continuous delivery is
production should be real users really
using your product
so if you're doing continuous delivery
you should be seeing every commit to to
the main repo or a particular Branch
right let's call it a branch could be
called main could be called Master could
be called HK whatever it's going to be
called is is ends up in production and
that's where people continuously
integrate so you CI into that and then
you CD from there to production and most
teams and most organizations don't seem
to do that they say they're doing cic
but they're just using the terminology
and the tools that are part of it to do
something else which is just an
automated build which is also fine right
you got to have the right technology for
the right thing I recommend cicd I
recommend continuous integration
Mainline branching and continuous
delivery into production for example on
products that I use that I build I might
not use true CD I think I'm almost
almost there I'm not quite there I think
my it's little bit too much risk for me
but because of my ability to test right
but
continuous I continuously integrate to
Main and no it ships to production I
have CD on on main ships to production
is a preview so the smaller number of
users so controlling the blast radius
and then when I feel like preview has
enough Telemetry to tell me that it's
good that it's not I don't have a larger
number of Errors I don't have people not
be able to do the stuff that they
they're supposed to be able to do in the
tool when I have enough data then I push
the button and it it rolls out to the
next ring which is everybody so I
effectively have a two- ring system pre
or CD system preview which is a smaller
subset of people that opt in to be using
the preview version and then everybody
else and I'll sometimes somebody asks
for a new thing I'll get it into preview
and I'll tell them it's in preview and
they can try it there and kick the tires
right so I'll bring new stuff that's
never been tried into preview people
will come and kick the tires and then it
will only go to to the rest of the world
once it's been successful and that's
generally how um Windows works that's
generally how Microsoft teams Works
Office 365 um all of most of most of
Microsoft products are now on a ring
based audience-based deployment model
and that seems to be the most effective
for services that you deliver to your
customers um I think websites are a
little bit different for like commercial
websites but again these are all things
that we can talk about and figure out
what the most effective model is CD
might not be the most effective model
for you CI might not be the most
effective model we might just want some
automated
builds having the
expertise to understand your product
understand its architecture understand
what the business is trying to achieve
with the product will help create that
indication of how naked agility can
support you in creating cic CD or just
some automation to enable you to be as
effective as possible and increase your
release frequency and reduce your cost
of deployment