well that's a great question what are
hierarchies of competence
versus hierarchies of control and why
does it matter
well the hmm let's define each one so a
hierarchy of control
is where everybody's
told what to do usually obviously in a
hierarchy right because it's hierarchies
of control but you've you've got um the
traditional organizational structure
the pyramid right you've got the small
number of people at the top that are the
thinkers right the deciders
and then you get the majority of people
at the bottom who are the doers
and steering
flows down right
so in order for uh uh
um something to be decided
right there needs to be some kind of
trigger that a decision needs made and
sometimes that's just going to come from
the top because the person at the top
has an idea and everybody shall follow
it right everybody shall do it
um but sometimes it's a market trigger
right and when it's a market trigger
this is hierarchies of control in a
market trigger you've got the the the
markets are actually at the bottom the
people talking directly to the markets
are not the people at the top they're
the people at the bottom they're talking
to the shareholders right which is a
different sort of Market but who are
talking to your to your actual Market of
your customers
so there's some kind of trigger and it
has to be important enough that this
person who has no Authority whatsoever
and maybe doesn't give a crap right
because they're just doing what they're
told it has to be painful enough for
this person that they filter that up
to the next level right and then it
needs to be painful enough for that
person above I.E there's enough people
below giving that feedback that they're
like oh I need to escalate this and then
it escalates and it escalates and
escalation is is the word to watch out
for right so we're managing by
escalation
you've got this item this problem is
escalated up the chain until it gets to
somebody who for want of a better
expression this is how my dad phrased it
you get to somebody who it's beneath
them to deal with your problem right and
they just say to somebody below them
just fix it I don't care right just fix
it or they just make a decision and it
doesn't matter whether it's the right or
wrong decision nobody cares they just
make one right because at that level
they're not connected to the environment
and so I worked at Merrill Lynch for a
few years and before it was bought over
by Bank of America so Bank of America
Merrill Lynch now but
um there were there were 16 people
between me and the CEO
how long do you think it would take in
that pyramidal structure for that
trigger to get all the way to the top a
decision to be made and then that to
filter all the way down and remember it
has to be the same message that filters
down to the bottom which is never the
case because you know politics happens
in here as well
so that's that's a that's hierarchies of
control you're you're maximizing the
amount of time it takes for a a signal a
message to get to the person who needs
to act action it and then and then for
the change come on we'll be back down
and and that was great when
we were in the industrial revolution
right where these these practices came
from where in fact the the Mantra is
slow and steady wins the race right
would be would be the watchword of the
day because the customers aren't
changing their mind all the time the
customers aren't exposed to a hundred
different companies doing the same thing
and then picking that you're making the
product that they are buying end of
story right perhaps really really really
rich people could afford to import a
product from somewhere else in the world
um but otherwise it's all all kind of
more local
um um industry right you you if you want
a ship and you're a shipping company you
go to your local Shipyard in Glasgow if
you're in Glasgow or perhaps Southampton
but you're not gonna buy a ship from a
shipyard in China right that doesn't
make any sense whatsoever you would even
know that Shipyard existed right no
marketing no Communications at that
level so so so that's hierarchies of
control work great then but today with
the speed of Market change right because
there are no static markets anymore you
need this decision process to be much
much quicker
so hierarchies of competence
are about kind of I guess kind of
flipping on its head while still having
a little bit of hierarchy because kinda
uh there I I believe that there's
definitely a human need for for for
hierarchy right
um any time you see a group of people
who are challenged to complete some task
whether it's here's a pile of ropes and
stuff across that river right they're
going to you're going to have
leaders that emerge
based on their understanding or ability
within that particular context right so
if you gave the same group of people
another task it might be a different
leader that emerges
based on the context that they're in
that would be a hierarchy created based
on competence I choose to succeed
succeed secede succeed some of my
control over what it is we're doing to
you so that we can all collaborate
together to get to the outcome that we
desire and I'm Deli I am choosing to
secede that control to you because I
believe you are the most competent
person to do it and you'll see in larger
groups of people there might be multiple
different competing ideas for how to
solve the problem and perhaps you'll end
up with two groups of people with two
leaders that are both trying to solve in
different ways and then you see which is
the better outcome or the quicker
outcome more of the more optimal outcome
right
um and and that's just a natural thing
that we do so the fundamental difference
between hierarchies of control is
in hierarchies of control you as an
individual
um don't choose to follow you are
enforced to follow a specific person
even if you think they're the most
incompetent idiot in the world
um and in that model you actually
there's an expression that you hear a
lot which is promoted to their level of
incompetence you heard that expression
that's that's just fits perfectly with
that model because somebody is seen to
be good at doing a job and then they
promote them to the next level up and
maybe the next level up is All About
Management and has nothing to do with
actually doing the same job and now
they're not good at it but you never
demote people you only promote people
so then they never get promoted again so
they've been promoted to their level of
incompetence one level down they're
awesome this level up they suck right
and so you end up with these massive
management structures and organizations
because you've promoted this person to
the level of incompetence and oh crap
they're not actually doing their job so
we need to find somebody else so we
promote this other person I know they're
actually good at it so out of how many
people at that level
how many people are actually useful
that's that hierarchies of control
create some of those structures
so in hierarchies of competence you have
no
enforced structure in that manner
um a good example might be Netflix I
think holocracy they they they they use
some of those ideas where they have a
board which is kind of the enforced
hierarchy part they have a board who
sets strategic Direction but everybody
in the company's job is it everybody in
the company's job is to figure out what
can they do
to best fulfill that overall strategy
right so that could be I'm gonna go join
this team over here because I like what
they're doing or I've got a cool idea so
I'm going to what's it called when you
attract people to your position
um you know you're going to be the
leader and attract follow attract
followers that's the one I tried
followers and move in a certain
direction
um and that's all ad hoc and dynamic in
that world so you can almost go well
that's that's all the way over here and
maybe your company's not ready for that
we're all the way over here in this
top-down terroristic waterfall model
you gotta figure out what's the first
thing we can do to help move a little
bit more in that direction to leverage
the people that we have and get closer
to the market and have a faster shorter
feedback loop faster turnaround time
between market triggers and actual
things happening in our organization
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility