legacy systems are a security nightmare
You know it I know it Outdated security
protocols compliance failures waiting to
happen systems nobody wants to touch
because well who knows what will happen
when they break The reality is these
systems were built in a different time
under different assumptions They were
never designed for the level of threat
we face today And yet businesses depend
on them Which means modernization isn't
optional It's inevitable But here's the
thing Modernizing blindly is just a risk
A bad move can introduce security holes
you never had before So how do you
modernize
safely at Naked Agility we don't just
talk about digital transformation We
help organizations understand their
systems of work so they can make better
decisions about security compliance and
maintainability This means looking at
how teams plan build and deploy software
It means integrating security first
practices not as an afterthought but as
a fundamental part of the way work
happens Because security isn't a
checkbox It's a continuous discipline
built into how teams collaborate how
decisions are made and how systems
evolve over time So if your legacy
systems are keeping you up at night
let's talk Because modernizing shouldn't
be about keeping up It should be about
getting ahead