so
effective product
ownership focuses on product management
there's a kind of
misconception that we're in some way
replacing product management with
product ownership or that they're
different things right um they're
absolutely not they're exactly the same
thing uh so this this is
where product ownership
within the context of scrum right
because I I definitely want to
disambiguate between um when I'm talking
about the product owner I'm talking
about the product owner as defined
within the context of scrum and the
scrum guides not the job title or role
that your organization has created and
added other baggage that is nothing to
do with those things right so you might
have a product owner within your
organization and it says in the job
description also responsible for writing
reports for management also responsible
for managing the product the pro the
project right or other stuff that is not
what what what I'm talking
about the product
owner is an accountability within the
context of scrum that's it it defines
that the product owner
needs to be somebody that
exists that the organization
respects and that is
accountable for the maximization of
value delivered from the work of the
scrum
team that's the product
owner the product owner their job
title is not product
owner that's a that's a madeup
organizational misunderstanding of
moving towards scrum right there's no
such thing as a you shouldn't have job
titles in your organization that are
product own or score Master right that
should exist
um you're in product management right if
we take product management as a as a big
rapper of all of the things that need to
be done in order to manage a
product
we're shifting
the focus of that from a longterm maybe
we do a two-yearly delivery cycle right
towards a very short delivery
cycle and if we're doing scrum if we're
doing scrum there's some
accountabilities that scrum brings for
those people that are doing product
management
um
so one could
say that the product
owner is an aspect of existing product
management that probably should always
have been there in the first place but
maybe wasn't necessarily
Quantified enough to make it a viable
thing and
[Music]
in the past organizations have been able
to skate
by without having that
Clear Vision goal and value Focus
organizations were able to to to to
skate by perhaps they had um um deep
coffers built up from some product that
didn't have any competitors that they
they they made and now we have lots of
money so it actually you know we don't
need to maximize we just need to get by
um or for other reasons right but as we
move to towards that shorter iterative
cycle it becomes more important to focus
on value and less important to focus on
more
stuff right we're not maximizing
productivity we're not maximizing the
number of items we deliver per time
frame um
because oh we can't okay we kind of are
but we're not trying to deliver more
stuff we're trying to deliver more
valuable stuff and in order to deliver
more valuable stuff rather than just
more stuff we need to understand what
value is and in order to understand what
value is need to understand what
direction the organization's going and
that's the foundation of product
management and product ownership is an
accountability in
scrum I think I think I've said this
before scrums like a
mirror right the mirror just reflects
what you're doing
and says why why can't you do this thing
that we think you should
need so the accountability of the
product owner being maximizing the value
of the work done by the scrum team why
can't you do that what's inhibiting your
ability to do that that's why the
product owner accountability exists it's
not a job title it's not a job role it's
an
accountability that
forces product management to reflect
on why they can't manage the
product in this new context right CU
because we're we're we're moving from
those long-term deliveries towards
shorter and shorter deliveries for all
products across all Industries and part
of the reason for that is we want to
take advantage of opportunities in the
market and we want to deal with
surprises that come from the market
right our environment or our
business um and in order to take
advantage of them we need to take
advantage of them more quickly than a
competitor can come along and take
advantage of them or a new business can
start up and take advantage of them
otherwise we're too late to the party so
in order to do that we need to move
faster what is the amount of time that
your business
needs to go around that cycle of
re-evaluating what we're doing that's
the cycle you need to be on how quickly
does your Market change most of us don't
exist in static markets right we exist
in volatile markets that are always
changing the the niches that our
organization has grown to fit um growing
contract on a regular basis if they're
growing and Contracting on a regular
basis and you're in one Niche um you're
going to feel that pain on a on on that
on that cycle right that's something
that sometimes my business suffers from
where you've you've got that cycle of of
of uh organizations having
um having having their flesh with cash
so they're looking to to train people
and increase skills so our training
business goes up um and then you have an
economic downturn um and our training
business drops right that's that's the
ebb and flow of any one business so how
do you mitigate that well you need to be
as a product owner product manager you
need to be thinking about how do we open
out new markets so all of the es and
flows of those those different markets
operate on different Cycles so that we
have maintain our ability to operate as
a business without loss um by divesting
our our interests into lots of different
areas um and product management at a big
organizational level is thinking about
how do we get into new markets how do we
get those new stories in and the product
owner just said product owner
accountability is just to maximize the
value of the work done by the team so if
we're going to have a bunch of team we
should maximize the value of the work
that they're actually doing and in doing
that maximizing the value return on
investment that we get from the work
that we do we should be able to adapt to
those changing needs in the market do
the product management thing uh and
that's product management includes
portfolio that's part of it right scrum
is part of it because it's managing the
work done by the scrum team right that's
part of that story creating little um
social technology uh that allows you to
manage that but it's within that wider
context so the idea is that um we have a
holistic approach to product management
of
which the product owner is just an
accountability a part of that story we
need to create a a shared understanding
with vision goals and value for the
direction that we're going so that all
of these self-organizing teams can work
together towards that common goal right
that's how we achieve that common common
goal um and we're using shorter
iterations particularly scrum in this
context if we're talking about the
product owner um for frequent product
validation through inspection and
adaption right scrum is founded on
empiricism we need to have regular tests
to validate our hypothesis that a
feature is going to advance value and
that is why saying that product
ownership um how does product ownership
build on the foundation of agile product
management is is kind of like the the
reverse of the story it's actually how
does product ownership enable product
management to maximize the value that
we're trying to create