naked agility is available for DevOps
and agile training and consultant
contact us for a free consultation
I'm Russell Miller I'm a professional
scrum grinder with scrum org I live in
Atlanta Georgia USA
have a couple of under under my belt
I've talked the professional scrum
master course the professional scrum
product don't of course live virtual and
this was my first opportunity to deliver
the professional agile leadership
essentials course via a live virtual
training method of delivery
very powerful course it was very
successful in my limited experience but
although that depends upon them the Venn
diagram of you know trainer and
circumstances and in class and so we had
a good experience
I've taught it several times maybe not
eight times yet it's one of my favorite
courses that the scrum dot org offers
the world
it's good after an event we do it during
training but also good after an event to
look back at the things that went well
to try to amplify that for future class
experiences and for things that didn't
go as well to make to inspect those and
make an adaptation you sound great
well I would have heard me anyway cuz
but you I was coming through it so yes I
was saying that in the professional I do
leadership classes really it's targeted
at those folks who are in a position on
edge scrum teams but that aren't maybe
directly on the scrum team and we taught
it with a combination of Microsoft team
as the communication channel is called
mural as are all that it's like
wakeboarding it is what boring tool
that's right we have a virtual canvas
that class participants and instructors
can apply images to in text and tables
and video a lot of rich rich
communication may be richer than simply
audio that's for sure
yeah and I I like the tool it had some
the pros I think you've mentioned this
that it it's like being it's as like
being in a classroom like he's on a wall
and drawing things I think you could get
but the downside for me is it was a
little bit laggy I wasn't performing so
well but I think time
I had zero no not like tiny but zero
problem was like why I think that might
be my setup I need it or changed the way
organizing it I've God I'm using a my
purpose a main machine think I've just
got it in
great machine I love that and have one
myself yeah I do like it as well
although I never detached the monitor
but I find it to be pretty pretty useful
and generally its performance but I've
just been having issues I'm running and
running
oh yes video open broadcast system
studio and I'm feeding my binging sheep
so I've got my OBS feeding into
Microsoft team so that I can show slides
or my desktop or something behind I
can't
which has been useful gives me some good
capabilities but it does take extra
resources on them yes this this new way
of working I think many of us are
discovering that the tools whether that
be webcams or whether that be laptops
would that be monitors or where that be
headsets that we were suitable for the
occasional or even multi day per week
telecommuting don't suit us quite as
well for 100% remote work
it was an opportunity to to reunite the
world doesn't know that years ago even
before I was actually several years
before I was a PST that I actually
enlisted your help with a team that I
was on and you came and gave both me and
some others in my organization some
training and made a positive difference
and so it was it wasn't me paying you
back this was me an opportunity to get
to participate in a training from the
other side of the table with you so it
was a both a great experience but also a
bit of a treat for me Martin
I think Windows 8 had been on the market
for about 15 minutes when you came to
oh that makes it true actually
well you haven't you haven't heard but
that that class and the the outcomes
that our team were able to help bring
bring to bear or bring bring to lie to
bring happen we're actually very
significant and I think that your help
was not was instrumental
kentley
it was good because each of the teams
could get some individual attention
which is not always possible even with
alive so this is a bit of an advantage
because in a live class unless the class
is very very large I'm teaching those by
myself
and so having having a second person is
an advantage for those participants I
believe that that's it's actually more
more often available maybe more often is
probably a threat word but it's it's
Mazie it's more possible because I
certainly wouldn't have probably
traveled to Scotland this week to be
with you
the the virtual training while there are
some challenges that we're going to
articulate here in just a moment there
are some some significant advantages and
one of which is that you can participate
as a student in a training that you
might not have been able to participate
in not that it would be too far to
travel but the travel time to join is is
infinitesimal it's right the distance
between your you were I guess your sofa
and wherever you want to participate in
the classroom thanks for covering there
hopefully my white Mike was working
other people otherwise we want to turn
up so I can see and it breaks and so one
that one of the things that I think I
think it would have been difficult to
facilitate the class without a little
bit I think I my my I guess my I find it
really easy to switch between the rooms
that was something that it's very easy
easier once the meeting is started in a
room you can I can get there very quick
in the thing that maybe concerns me
about running class um without help or
even running a class with more than two
teams even if those trainers it's how do
you know when another team no yes and I
can think of all sorts of ways to
facilitate that for the students like
they can just yeah most directly even so
they can send us is right I said
or they can put a message on in channel
we were using what is just difficult to
know each people yes
something I've thought of doing which
might be beneficial is for this class I
did our technology check with folks why
got the the students to set up a meeting
with a 30-minute meeting with me I think
I said actually said it at fifteen
minutes just to get together check the
tail works and we have the student but
one of the students it was 45 minutes
making sure that they all do work
getting things set up we how we would
run in the class to they were
comfortable and I think I was thinking
over the next week I'll probably make
some functional videos but I can ask
students to watch first rather than
having so many one-on-one fashions do
those thing that's it that's actually a
great idea because I have been reluctant
to take my students time in advance
because I'm trying to realize that
people have other things to do so I
asking to attend a 16 hour class plus an
extra hour before I've been reluctant to
do that and I actually had it had not
occurred to me to make a pre-recorded
video so that's a brilliant idea
yeah just here's how I'm going to run
the class but anyway for the majority of
the students I think the majority of the
students had used teams before yes
therefore they didn't need any help and
in fact the number of this
but into the team um the week before
when I said to top and ID'd everybody
they were in how to loot road and send
me a message or I'd even got wet them
that was Jim oh but I know that there
can be authentic Asian issues with email
address that's been enabled yourself the
kind if if they're using their corporate
identity their ability to do that is
with it their enterprise if their own up
there logging in with a little bit
difficult I do have one customer that
can't do that they're they're not much
the other it's all of reality and but I
always add all my students about teams
channel or my students can operate of
the course we're posting then they take
a class with me I have a script that
adds them permission where for the
classes
that's a it's a powerful advantage if I
may say Martin to the trainings that you
offer is the ability not only to have
the in-person well live training and
advice but also to connect even after
the fact through teams and gain
additional value after the courses of
them yeah even the folders that have the
training material like the really it
soft PDF of us like that afterwards I
actually keep that updated as the
courseware come out from the dark in
team that and give you students they
will get access to you access
I can
look at things again that works Oh
technologies that we watch I think not
much it's worth noting however that
students were using their laptop
integrated cameras or their separate
webcams and even that presents it's an
advantage we can see you see each other
the disadvantage is that it can be
distracting if a student or instructor
changes camera angle then it's in person
if you put your head down or look to the
side it's sort of a natural thing it's
not distracting but if someone switches
their camera off or switches to a
different camera or to the integrated
camera on their laptop it can be Sully
distracting candidly yeah well I'm and
it looks like I'm not paying yeah I do
think that culturally this is an opinion
culturally we're going to get over that
sooner rather than later and an example
that reminds me of the smart watches
right once upon a time if I did this you
would think I was ready to stop talking
with you but because we get messages on
our wrists now it's it's no longer oh
you don't want to hear what I say it's
oh you've got a text from your wife or
you've got a reminder that you have a
meeting in an hour and so uh eventually
you're going to realize that just
because I'm not looking directly at the
camera and doesn't mean I'm not with you
yeah that's right yeah because we have
we have we make the assumption that
you're doing email or you're doing
something else entirely
right they don't cite it sometimes as an
instructor right whatever is coming up
next well that can be difficult when
you're also Europe who time engaged with
students
but then you know you need to set
something up or the next thing yes I'm
doing my next by virtual classes
whoo-hoo yes Apps Foundation's
professional scrum foundations classes
so that's kind of like and I describe it
as it's the one or one from class where
we just focus on the scrum guide we
don't focus on Asian like yes am let's
focus on this from part but in order to
create an environment where um I guess
where students can feel like they're
doing scrum without being inhibited by
their organizational impediments do
sprints on a product in class yes but
they actually there's no Lego
it's actually building software in the
class and I'm the thing that always is a
light bulb for me or at least firfer for
my classes when students realize at the
end and two hours working on the project
and they've created a website and
they've integrated five different
actually five different websites either
by the end hours of the product very
proud like what could you do in two
weeks
yes I think that many students are if
there aren't used to building things to
a done State there aren't if they're not
already accustomed to that for some it's
very hard to envision then it's even
possible yeah and I actually I this has
only happened once the one team one
class and I've taught a lot of PS apps
but I had one team at the end of the
Sprint
it's the first sprint you're the one
that's normally a car crash just give me
a URL and they had already created the
Dorothea created source control but the
website under source control
well added features to that website and
created a continuous delivery DevOps
pipeline live they were in production in
the first 30 that was well they they
spoiled you for the rest of your PSO
exactly because well I like to use them
as an example because if if a team of
five people regardless of what their
knowledge level was at the star
obviously they pick technology the
understood they'd already built DevOps
pipelines in the past they don't worked
with the tools and technology if in 30
minutes a team of five people in build
product and if it's a production what
seven
well and for those who attend who who
aren't currently working on a layer or
even higher in the organization for them
to see what is possible I find that
often it opens eyes to well if this is
actually possible then why aren't we
doing that what other organizational
impediments are exist that prevent these
people who are capable of doing such
great work from from delivering that
value to our customers more frequent
exactly and I think the PSF is a good
I'll ping in internally an organisation
so these are private classes I'll be
running high oh I don't think I've ever
run a public this doesn't make sense for
me good it's generally you have a lot of
people in the class that are all from
the same all of that dirty laundry for
me it's a lot of fun oh I'm filling the
dirty laundry out of the drawer isn't
saying like look at the nasty this is
that's maybe I'm a bit of a masochist in
that way I like to cause trouble I think
you just like to expose the
opportunities and and so that the the
organisation can can then adapt that's
actually where a company from Ikeda
Jilla tea I read getting naked the art
of consulting a little bit called start
with why I'm those two together resulted
in what what I'm what I'm doing now when
I asked a Vox consultant to start start
my own
I didn't know the backstory for your
business thing but I did wonder if it
came from Lindsay oneis but nobody
nobody ever forgets the name of a
company I was embarrassed bookmarking it
well I do I do have I have two funny
stories with that well one's not a funny
story I have one customer the m and
access my website or receiving from me
the the the maybe I work with their
sends me was from her Gmail and get it
firewall but I do have a customer it was
actually my first customer when I moved
back to the UK and we it was a PS f4 now
you won't get this reference I don't
know about how to translate it into you
bass but it was in a town called aiming
ham which is next to a town called a
grid and Grimsby as a perfect name it is
where all the chemical factories ER and
I was working with a shipping company
but it was M one of those everybody was
in fluorescent vests in the whole
company and small office that was almost
like a bunch of Port Evans stuck
together I was working with a small team
that had come in from all the different
ports around Northern Europe where where
they were based they come and eat
together it's class and and I had a
sense of relief my first engagement in
the UK because I heard more swearing
that two-day class the night aired in
three years living in s rating because
people in the UAE and I think in most of
most of Europe aren't afraid of those
words I
books and bass are you'll like it's an
HR violation engine them whereas in the
UK it's often if you're aggressive
towards people or em opening towards
people then that's an HR violation but
just hurts on text of I stubbed my toe
or whatever those things are