number one have a definition of done
that would be great right know the
amount of work you need to do in order
to get to done that's part of the
purpose of the definition of done how do
you know how does every member of your
team know when they're thinking about
how much work they can take on in a
Sprint what they actually need to do to
get there right that's your your your
definition of done helps enable
that
so also the second thing is probably uh
stop taking on too much work that's
always a good one um most teams will
take on um the amount of work that they
feel will fit in a Sprint and that's
wrong right you shouldn't take on the
amount of work that should fit in a
Sprint you need to think first about how
much time you need to reserve for other
things okay so there are a number of
other things you need to reserve time
for in the Sprint one is uh how much
time do you have to spend paying back
technical debt that's one uh perhaps
you've got some some refactors or re
architectures to do there's work around
that uh perhaps there's been some
production issues and you want to go
figure out and rework some of the way
you've done things in order to make
those production issues less likely
there's a bunch of work perhaps there's
just some bugs you need to go fix
there's things that that customers have
asked for or feedback uh that are small
things you'd never have a whole Sprint
just on those things but you've got a
bunch of bunch of stuff there um and
then you need to think about um how
much work do you think is left in order
to fulfill your Sprint backlog this is
your net new work uh that goes to
towards your your Sprint goal uh that
you're going to do the Sprint so this is
the high complexity work usually fixing
above can be really simple or it can be
really hard right you don't you don't
know but all of net new functionality is
generally really complex and very
unknown so you need to have enough space
to take on a piece of work that might
expand to fill that space right and
there's one thing which is the third
thing that I've not talked about and
that's ref refinement how much time do
you need to think about refinement that
needs reserved cuz the third thing
refinement you need to understand the
future to some degree right a lot of
folks talk about oh we're doing agile we
don't need to do planning anymore that's
crap you need to do more planning and
more often and one of those things that
we do we call refinement which is any
work that you do as a team that is
looking at the product backlog not
adding capability to your increment
right so if you're looking out into the
future and you're saying uh what are the
things that are coming up in the backlog
are they the right size maybe we need to
break them down um do they have
dependencies that we need to plan for
right if you get into Sprint planning
and you realize that you need a firewall
change uh that has a 6 week lead time
you're already screwed right that's not
happening this Sprint even though that's
when it needs to happen because we've
got this firewall change whereas if
we're looking out 6 weeks into the
future in our product backlog and
anticipating trying to anticipate as
best we can you're never going to be
perfect but as best you can what's
coming up that we need to deal with
those dependencies those different
activities that we need to request stuff
or do stuff you know could be servers
could be environments could be all sort
sorts of things uh that could get in the
way what do you need to know now you can
mitigate a lot of that by your scrum
Masters should be thinking about well
why do we have to look out 6 weeks for
firewall changes well it's because this
team over here takes six weeks to action
a firewall change perhaps that's
something you want to go fix so you
don't have to look out so far on your
product back clug and you can bring that
range in right because you want how far
out you look should be minimal but
sufficient right you got that goldilock
zone of how far do we need to look out
and you want it to be as short as
possible so any other activities you can
do to make that shorter so those are the
three things uh that a team who
struggling to get work completing the
Sprint Sprint need to think about you
need to think about doing good
refinement if you understand things a
little bit more you'd be surprised how
much more easily they fit in a Sprint
you need to not plan the whole Sprint
just plan the
bit that that that you believe you can
do and take into account those other
activities that you need to do every
Sprint don't fill the whole thing that's
mental um and the other one was having a
definition of done so that you
understand the amount of work that is
required to complete each thing thanks
for watching the video If you enjoyed it
please like follow And subscribe I
always reply to comments and if you want
to have a chat about this or anything
else agile scrum or devops then please
book a coffee with me through naked
agility