oh that's a great question
so the question is how does scrum
help leadership teams pick the most
valuable work to focus on
and the answer is it doesn't
scrum has absolutely nothing in it
to help leaders pick the most valuable
thing to work on that is their job
not scrum's job to figure out
right if you're if you're in business
and you're running an organization
you're the one that needs to understand
where and what to invest in based on
your interpretation of the market demand
scrum can't do that for you
kanban can't do that for you
safe can't do that for you Marisa ssadm
was never able to do that for you
the leaders need to make that decision
they need to understand their business
understand their customers understand
this strategic Direction having a
strategic direction that they want to go
in and figure out what are the things
that we need not Solutions right but
what are the outcomes we're trying to
achieve what's the next outcome we want
to achieve and then scrum will help you
create
teams of Highly professional people who
can organize around delivering that
using scrum