I think the common mistake made by my by
rookie agile Consultants
is the belief that just following the
rules of whatever process or or
practices you've picked is going to
solve any problems and it's it's not
uh scrum is a great tool but it is just
a tool people need to want to do it the
team needs to want to do it they need to
pick it not the agile consultant so
picking
processes for the team is probably the
biggest rookie mistake
um but also focusing on
the rules
of the game rather than the under rather
than the underlying reasons for playing
in the first place
right why why are we wanting to move
towards a greater degree of agility why
do we want scrum well it's so we can get
closer to the customers and make better
business decisions right so that we can
iterate quicker on the wrong ideas and
do more of the right thing and less of
the wrong thing empiricism right
um so I think their biggest mistake is
not focusing on those underlying
principles that support the ideas so
that the people involved understand what
decisions they need to make in order to
support and benefit from the process
rather than just telling people what to
do you're gonna do scrum
okay well you end up with a lot of
friction and push back and uh people not
liking what's going on and if everybody
in the team's not on boards you're not
going to be successful