foreign
how much of an impact can a great ideal
consultant have
I I think they can have a huge huge
impact because they're
they're not an agile consultant tends
not to be interested in hanging around
that that's the difference I feel
between Consulting and coaching like a
coach is going to be there all the time
but a consultant
can't be there all the time usually one
because they're more expensive right so
the company doesn't want them hanging
around for too long but really the
consultant is doing that deliberately
right if the company wants you around
full time you're not expensive enough
um because you you want to be coming in
helping them with very specific problems
they're the ones that are going to be
fixing
the problem they're the ones that are
going to be doing the work you're giving
them things to try or perhaps
um what what one of the
one of the things that I've done quite a
lot with organizations is
um I guess I call it the state of agile
report right and what is the current
state of the way things work inside of
the organization from the perspective of
agile and what are the things like what
are the top three things that the
organization should focus on improving
and so I'm not necessarily there to
solve any of those problems right I
maybe come in for a week or two weeks
I'm going to interview 20 or 30 people
in the organization at all different
levels ask them questions about how they
work how they figure things out
um and you get a lot of answers that are
contradictory in that story right
because you get the people actually
doing the work saying yeah we don't
really write unit tests and we don't
really have automated builds but then
you speak to leadership and they're like
yeah we've got continuous delivery and
we've got uh uh all these unit tests
coming out of our ears and maybe we've
got too many unit tests and and there's
a fundamental disconnect there because
leadership and organizations will often
say
I I I I've heard in my uh uh on my
leadership Grapevine that we should be
doing unit tests and then
the teams feel Under Pressure to do unit
tests so they'll just tell them that
they've done unit tests because maybe
the product that they're working on is
absolutely impossible to do unit tests
but it's not possible to have that
conversation with leadership because
there's not an open and transparent
relationship going on there in the
organization
so being able to find and identify those
problems figure out uh um um what it is
that oh and these are big things that
need to change not little things they're
not subtle things like coaches come in
and fixed subtle things and and work on
the bigger things over a longer period
of time
but
that often takes too long
because you're gonna put that out there
it takes too long what you want to be
able to do is go into an organization
see a switch on the wall that at the
bottom it says not continuous delivery
at the top it says continuous delivery
and you want to figure out how do I flip
that switch
how do I just turn that on how do I just
fix this problem and quite often you're
not always going to be right and I
always when I go into organizations I'm
always explaining that right I'm saying
I'm going to give you things to try they
might not work for you they maybe have
worked in other places but things to try
and they try them and either it works
for them or it doesn't right and then
they can come back and say well we tried
this and it didn't work but it worked a
little bit right so what else can we do
to figure this out and that's that
Consulting moment
um that I think coaches do as well right
but this is just taking that piece off
and saying let's just do this piece
because I feel that
organizations and leaders in
organizations
um people and organizations need to own
that problem themselves they're the one
that's their organization they're in the
crap that they're in they need to deal
with figuring out how to get out because
if you get somebody in who's given
accountability for changing that problem
but isn't really part of the company or
doesn't really understand the company it
can be very difficult for them to affect
change and that's why it takes longer
because then they have to build all of
those relationships before they can
change
but quite often when you come in as a
consultant
you're not worried about being fired
right that's the first thing because
you've got another gig next week and
you're not coming back
you might not be coming back at all so
you can just be absolutely brutally
honest in your reporting and say this is
what's going on your organization this
is why it's broken this is things you're
going you're going to need to fix I
recommend you go find a coach and help
you fix this thing but then they know
that's what they need to fix they have
it in the front of their mind and
they're potentially think they can see
that switch in the wall and like if we
could just flip that switch and they're
figuring out more things to do that
and and I think that's that's why I
think that great Consultants
can be more valuable
than great coaches
because their focus is on Flipping that
switch
as quickly as possible
um
and flipping things quickly like ripping
the Band-Aid off right you've got you
you don't want to peel it slowly because
that's going to hurt more
you want to just rip it off do something
different and deal with the Fallout of
that bigger change and I'm going to say
well it depends right that's why you
need a great consultant because the
great consultant is going to be able to
go yeah you want to slow change that one
and you want to Fast Change this one
right because if you slow change that
one it's going to be a problem and if
you fast change this one it's going to
be a problem and that that's
things that people feel are unique to
their organization
but they're really not I
one of the things that I always find
really interesting
is every single Consulting customer I've
ever worked with
has said we have these magical unique
problems and we need your help with them
and I go in and their problems are not
magical and they're not unique they're
the same problems that everybody else is
having there's little fine Nuance of
difference right but the big problem is
the big problem that everybody's having
and part of that comes from a a
tailorism to volatism right so from a
traditional uh hierarchical
um Industrial Revolution thinking
um focused on things changing to
um a democratized self-organization uh
distributed thinking focused on people
right so those are the one of the two
big
bridges that needs that that needs to
happen in organizations and but there's
lots of other things that are small that
they can do within those structures that
will enable them to do better
right but you've still got those big
problems that are the same everywhere
because everybody's trying to do this
this
decentralized self-organizing teams
but they're in a hierarchy with steering
and Leadership and control from the top
and they're they're just but they're
mutually exclusive right you can get a
little bit of this inside of this but
you can't
get all the way over here where people
want to be where they see the biggest
benefit in
um what they're getting so I feel that's
the value of a consultant is being able
to to come in and quickly identify and
point at things and that need to change
and a lot of these things are really
obvious when you come in from the
outside but they're not obvious at all
when you're inside of that story
um and having somebody come in and do it
I'll point out also quite often I come
in and the sponsor for me coming in says
here's the things we'd like you to tell
leadership right because they already
know what the problem is just nobody's
listening to them and they need somebody
else to come in and say yes this is
indeed a problem that you've been told a
whole bunch of times
um and I'm only going to do that if
those things are actually true right if
I'm gonna look and see but
um it's really valuable to have somebody
with knowledge an experience coming from
the outside that's maybe recognized
inside of the organization
in that traditional hierarchy to to help
make that start making those changes
across to the other side of the
other side of the wall