naked agility is available for DevOps
and agile training and consultant
contact us for a free consultation
hello my name is Martin Thank You wit
I'm a professional scrum trainer with
scrum da dark and also Microsoft MVP in
your DevOps and I had I've been doing
some live videos over the past couple of
weeks I noticed that many people are and
I've been inspecting adapting on the
things that other folks are doing and I
think um this is going to become a
regular session I haven't settled on the
timing yet but I'd like to be able to
answer a bunch of questions that folks
ask there's been an interesting couple
of weeks and in that regard and I've had
a few people on Jim a few days ago and
Daniel Vacanti
last week to have a little chat um I've
since upgraded some of my technology
with Daniel we had some audio issues so
I now have a monitor in my ear and I got
a new new microphone so I think these
things will help a little bit the thing
that I wanted to UM chat a little bit
about today is I got our question from
somebody they asked on LinkedIn not
everybody wants to ask publicly so I've
added a link down here that you can go
to and ask me a question if you don't
want to ask it publicly you can always
ask it publicly as well I think one of
my things are not working check you can
always ask it publicly and seems to be
online it's just pretending it's not
okay
yep I think I've got a problem with that
one let me just delete it and we had it
um not that one that's the one I want
one of my streaming services was not
connecting properly I think these things
happen they're sent to try us so as I
get set up with these things I'm going
to figure it out so that's me adding it
back in again
it says sending data but it hasn't
popped up and said it's online yet so we
will see I guess I'm going to have to go
figure that out afterwards never mind
so I'm going to be doing a few of these
I wanted to make sure that everybody was
able to ask questions even if they
didn't feel that they would be able to
see they didn't want to know some
everybody to know who they were that
kind of thing so I set that up that was
one of my colleagues who does some
officers suggested that and I think that
makes a lot of sense so the question
that that I got and that I thought was a
little bit interesting and was what are
folks going to do with their teams now
they're they're not effectively a
distributed team what are they going to
do with their boards how are they going
to manage that information so I want to
talk about em three different platforms
that I've used
they all have their pros and cons they
all have their specific areas of
interest and I think there's a little
bit of progression there I don't talk
about that but I also want to
speak a little bit about um what it says
in the scrum guide around co-located
teams it doesn't it doesn't really
mention co-located teams it says it's
better if people are able to work
together same as it does in the agile
manifesto and people work best if
they're in the same same location like
having a team room having our stuff on
the walls and having everybody together
but the realities of the current
situation mean that that's not always
going to be possible and while it does
mention those things in both the scrum
guide and I do manifesto it doesn't say
that they're mandated it's okay to have
a distributed team there's nothing wrong
with that you're going to maybe lose
some communication effectiveness but
that's the cost of doing it that way
that's just the way it is there's
nothing that says you can't do that so I
want to make you feel like or I want you
to have the expectation that you can
still be doing scrum you can still be
doing Kanban you can still be doing your
agile practices even when you're not in
the same room that's okay that's no
mandate for that the mandate for
colocation or not the mandate for
colocation the recommendation of
colocation and is really around
maximizing those communication channels
and we can do that maximization even
when we're not face to face so there are
tools we can use to store our backlogs
priorities and boards on the internet so
everybody can get access to them and in
a way that it's not just sitting in an
excel sheet that everybody's editing
because that does not do well for for
multiple and edits and so what I want to
do is show you these three tools that
I've looked at I've used all of these
tools in anger
they have their pros and cons some of
them are easier than others
the first that I wanted to show was
github so if I go to github.com github
does have the ability to have issues I
have our project here in github
repository and github the onus is on the
repository and then everything else
hangs off that repository so I can go in
and I can I can do issues which are
pretty straightforward they're not great
for agile management it's just our list
of issues and but any of these issues
and can be added to a project
so here I've added this issue to a
particular project and it's been added
to the to-do column so I'll get to do in
progress and done and I can click the
little cog and I can add it to as many
different projects as I want and it will
basically create an item on that project
that is related to this item here
they're not I think under the covers
they're probably separate items but from
our perspective they're kind of the same
thing but it will show us some cross
data between them so if I go over into
projects and I can create as many sub
projects to this repository remember
repository is the main item and then
projects are inside of that and where
and I've not done a whole whole lot with
this but I can add additional columns
and I can edit the column I can edit the
name I can add things I can copy a link
directly to that column and I can drag
things around inside of that world so
there's an item that I added directly to
the board and here's that item that is
linked that is when I click it it's
going to open the data from the other
item rather
rather than having another thing going
on there this is a good tool if you are
running an open source project as many
are this is one of my open source
projects and it has its limitations the
all of the the data is stored in the US
if you are an enterprise company or any
European or non-us entity that has to
have private data then I would not
recommend storing it in github privately
at the moment if it's a public project
like it's our open source doesn't matter
I have all of my stuff in github as well
but it was a private project you might
want to and store it somewhere where you
can control the sovereignty of the data
and that's that's a big deal for many
European organizations but there is also
private repos if you're a US company and
github as well and you get some of those
features there so it's a pretty
straightforward tool lots people already
understand how to use github they like
the features of github and they can add
that capabilities there the second tool
that I went to look at is actually a
little bit of a step back from from
development and that's plat tasks office
comm and Microsoft planner is a small
tool built into the office 365 suite and
there is an app that works on your
mobile phone that allows you to create
boards and move items between those
boards so at the moment they just call
them buckets so if I do in progress done
to create the same idea as we had in
github and then I just add a task
I can add a task on there and then I can
drag it between the boards I can add
additional information if I want like
attachments and priorities and start
dates and end dates and all of those
kind of things and whether it's started
in progress or completed so regardless
of the the columns a little bit weird
maybe but I can also add a little tag so
I can make this one green I don't know
what that did did that do anything
do I have to click it or is that just
changing the label is a receive button
okay I don't know how that part of that
works but I'm sure you can figure it out
I saw a simple board it has really good
mobile access which github has good
mobile access just for issues and wiki's
and source code it doesn't have good
mobile access for the planner
they are projects yet that's okay I'm
sure I'm sure they'll get around to it
at some point but this can be a useful
tool and this can you can have tasks on
here that link into your outlook tasks
you can have stuff you just add to the
board you can create charts and
schedules and plan around this with
notes this is this is a good medium
solution especially if you're
interacting or doing non-engineering
work and you can add your your plan to
your calendar so you can see all of the
things you're supposed to be working on
and you can add as many people as you
want into the project you can see here
I've got a bunch of guests in there
there's only two people in my as your
active directory that are like members
of the item directory everybody else's
are is a guest this is part of my one of
my projects the other one that I want to
talk about is actually might want my
favorite one to use and and that's
Devdas your comm Azure DevOps is tool
that is not always free
so github
are free for public projects office
tasks the office comm Microsoft planner
is free for or free as the bad word is
included in your your office 365
subscription so we'll just I'll be there
which is okay but there is also the
tools in Azure DevOps to look at as well
so if I sign in to Azure DevOps it's
going to sign in to one of my
organizations so my nkd agility my
company's organization and here I have
all of my projects listed so in Azure
DevOps
project is at the top and then you can
create multiple you can have one or more
repos inside of your project so if you
just have a small product that you're
working on you can have project and repo
just being the same thing you one-to-one
relationship which is actually what I've
got here or you can create multiple
repos inside of our project and by
adding repos to that that like we just
like you add projects to get up so if I
go into my azure DevOps
process tools you can see that I have
some wiki it's very a little bit like
github in that regard it doesn't have
all the same features there's a little
bit of disparity between them but I have
at boards and on boards I have straight
work items this is the work item
tracking systems this is just a list of
the work items so I can see my active
work items I can see work items I follow
I've recently updated and I can add new
work items of various types so it's not
just issues or just tasks like in the
other two tools that I showed you have
various different things I'm using a
process
here called the scrum process so I have
put a backlog item which rolls up to
feature resource up to epoch it has bugs
it has test cases it has tasks that's a
bunch of different things but I have
this these entries so this would be an
individual work item this one is a
backlog item and this backlog item has a
bunch of data associated with it just
like in the other tools so description
discussion and various things I've got a
follow link but I also have additional
things I can link to it and so I can
link to development items so here
there's a pull request and this is a
merged PR so that's a commit and a pull
request associated with it ok I also
link to existing other types of work
items so either related parent-child I
can actually link it to a github issue
by pasting in the github URL I can
relate all of these things together
which is kind of kind of nice I kind of
like that this is this is my tool of
choice for these kind of things and so
then if I go back into here and I go
into boards on boards I'm going to have
my cab on board so the default camera on
board and has the same States as the
work items so my work items here my
product backlog items and bugs go from
new to approved to forecast it to done
that's the the minimum you can have on
the board is what you've got set up in
the in the process but then each
individual team that's working in here
and this tool in particular supports
having multiple boards and multiple
teams inside the same project so I could
have and I do have customers that have
70 or 80 teams in a single project so
single source code 70 to 80 teams
working on one product they each have
their own boards backlog sprints but
they have some
commonality and they can share things
between the hidden link between each
other's stuff as well social
dependencies and that kind of thing so
here I'm just looking at a board so this
items in forecast state and I can drag
it around and you'll see that the state
changes from new to approve the forecast
it and once they get on to all the way
to the end to done they should be locked
off and finished that's the idea so I
can view it as a board a Kanban board I
can control this and I can do I'd have
some features telling me to control it
the first is what fields do I want to
show on each item that's pretty basic
and then some color coding rules I can
set up so I can set it up that things
glow if they've been changed recently or
if they've been tagged by a certain tag
that's that's always you can do that and
set up annotations for items that are in
github tasks or tests you saw that I
could link from that work item to other
things if it's tasks github issues or
tests they're actually going to show up
on this dashboard if you take that that
box and tests have a special some extra
features this is for manual testing not
for automated testing so this is when
you're transitioning into being an agile
team and you still have a lot of manual
tests and you want to bring them on
board and that's all supported in here I
don't expect a Joule teams to use a lot
of this and then you can set up and
control the columns so remember I said
that the minimum set of columns are the
columns from your work item so what what
set as the states but I could take
approved and I could break it into two
I'm just seeing if I can move that up I
can although I managed to click and do
that so if I want to break approved up
into two
columns and I can insert to the right so
this one I'm going to call it and
[Music]
refinement and then once we agree
refinement is complete this one is going
to be Oh Teddy ready
okay so refinement you can see the state
mappings as the state that is on the
work items and is the approved state
will be in refinement and the ready
state sorry the refinement column will
have items from the approved state and
the ready column will also have items
from the approved state and the system
will default them to one of the columns
because we just split a column where
there might be items in it and then you
can move things between it and that
allows us to each team even within the
same project and can set up their own
set of columns so you can say here's the
standard that our organization is going
to follow and which is new approved
forecast done that's our standard
everybody working on the one product has
to have the work items floor that so we
can understand what's going on we can
see a holistic view of everything in our
product everything in our work that's
going on but then each team can go and
set up and configure their boards
however they like in order to facilitate
them owning that managing that following
their own individual processes because
every team's work might be a little bit
different they work on different things
they have different types of work that
are going on inside that project that's
okay they can they can do that how they
like and you can set up additional
swimlanes
so by default there's only one
horizontal swimlane but you could set up
a swim lane for a particular stream of
work and I in the same understanding as
Daniel Vacanti in having different
classes of work
or classes of service is probably a bad
idea it's going to interrupt your
ability to flow on your other work and
you're better just improving your
overall flow so I would just leave it as
default but if a team did want to
experiment with an expedite except I
can't spell there we go and expedite
lane then they can do that as well and
then you can choose how cards are
ordered so do you drag them in between
if you have only a few things you might
want to have a set up this way if you
have hundreds of things on your backlog
because you're not that agile a team yet
you know you've got 300 things in your
sprint that can be a little bit much you
can set it so the order doesn't change
when you're dragging them around because
that can be a little bit difficult and
you can also display or hide two
different levels of backlog so many
teams especially scrum teams working
with either just scrum or scrum and
Kanban are going to look just at backlog
items they don't really care about
anything else but if you've got much
bigger teams where you have more than
two teams working on one product you
might want to enable features and epics
as needed and then you can set up the
workdays and whether my bugs are treated
as backlog items or not that's why I
made a few changes there so I'm going to
save and close that and you'll see the
changes in the UI it's gonna refresh and
you'll see that I now have expedite
lanes so if I create a new product
backlog item
I'm just gonna call it test because I'm
lazy I can drag that in to expedite and
then I can have I I might I and my team
might have agreed different rules for
expedite than for the default Lane and I
can have things flow through the system
like that so that that works pretty well
on boards just setting up and managing
Kanban boards it has whip limits it
doesn't force you to adhere to them this
tool doesn't really force you to do a
lot and it kind of leaves it open for
you to figure that out which is kind of
the way I like it that's how an agile
team should function because each team
should be able to choose to do things
differently if they want to break their
web them it's that's okay well they can
monitor their data and see how that goes
so I can do some analysis on here so
this is I don't have iteration set up so
it's not going to show velocity but it
would show a cumulative flow I have one
average work-in-progress because I don't
have a lot of work flowing across and
this team hasn't been worked on in a
little while so you can set up some
analysis these ones are the defaults and
then there's a feature timeline so you
might have some kind of dates or
expectations that you have to meet maybe
there's a big event coming up that you
want to work towards or maybe have some
features and they are available for and
in order to do that oh I get new
features in progress in the timeline so
it's not going to show me the features
but I can create I have a feature
timeline that shows that I can create an
epoch roadmap which I also don't have
any epics so it's probably yeah I don't
have any epics assigned so it's probably
not going to show that either that's ok
I'll go back to boards so this is my
backlog items board and all of those
things well at least a board and
analytics and are available at the
backlog level and if I went in and
enabled to do logs
if I enabled features and epics I could
also change to features and I would have
our board which you'll see it has only
the default columns for features which
is new in progress done that's the
default and I can break that out if I
want that level but analytics is based
on the features and then feature
timeline is always features an epic word
map is always epics because the
expectation is features are something
the way a lot of decisions has been made
in this product is around as the way a
lot of teams inside of Microsoft work
because it's a Microsoft tool and
Microsoft use it extensively internally
so backlog items are just backlog items
features are looked at as something that
you're going to deliver and so while you
might deploy a backlog item out to
production it's not a tangible finished
thing that you might want to see a
timeline of when are those things going
to be finished what's currently in
progress at the moment for that feature
so if you think about it the development
team and the product owner at the
implementation level cared a lot about
the backlog items at the feature level
you're looking at holistic units of of
things that go together backlog items
obviously are broken down into smaller
items and then epics are things that
appear on your road back maybe a longer
lived it's gonna take many many Sprint's
to get them get them get them finished
many releases to get them finished
that's the way that looks so that's at
boards in here it also has backlogs
backlogs are super handy and I find to
be very underused with teams so in here
I just have a list of the items that on
my backlog and I can drag and drop them
to order them I can also go and stick
them in sprints and I can configure and
control the sprints and set them up so
that will let me set up my backlogs and
again it has analytics and access the
feature type line and the epic roadmap
there's they're the same so what can
view that as a board or I came for so if
I go to Oh wrong button views a board it
takes me back here views a backlog it
flips to that other view so backlog is
the view board is also a view and it's
the same data it's the same data so I
can use this across multiple teams the
boards even have auto updating so if
you're looking at it on multiple screens
it will automatically update as you go
through which is kinda nice so I've
already talked about those features but
now I'm in a backlog view I'm not sure
that's gonna configure the team settings
so it's just gonna have that yep and so
the current sprint plus whatever other
ones you have currently figured
configured are going to be listed in
there there's lots of different ways to
set up and configure Sprint's I have a
number of blog posts on how to do that
for one team and how to do that for
hundreds of teams working on one product
and and also how to do lots of different
products inside of the one project as
well which many organizations do for
various reasons and so I have a lot of
blog posts on those topics you can go
look at those you can also if you are a
scrum team and not just a Kanban team or
you're a scrum and Kanban team or a
Kanban with a little bit of scrum team
or just a Kanban team or just a scrum
team all of these features work well you
would just ignore that sprints tap
because you wouldn't need it but if you
are using that you'll see you can have
your PBIS that have brought into the
sprint pin to the left and you can have
break that down into tasks that then
flow across the board I recommend
working as a team using the Kanban guide
for scrum teams I think it's really
important to have good metric
cross-cutting metrics that you can rely
on and user stories story points and
velocity it does not give you that it
might give you that for one team early
on in their maturity level but if you
want to mature scrum team they need to
start
looking at the Kanban guide for scrum
teams and bringing in some of those more
advanced metrics to look at but in here
and I've got my task board I can see
that's so that's my scrum board you
might call it but it's just a list of
tasks relating to the things on your
backlog and I can look at the breakdown
of my backlog so let's see and might a
sport and I break this item into task 1
task do there we go
and I can go to the backlog and I'll see
that this has been broken down so
they're actually related and if I open
that task do you'll see as a link up to
the pbi product backlog item that I have
there it's pretty straight for kind of
like you would expect it to have um so
there are some other tools there are
some teams out there that like to look
at their capacity and plan towards that
so this is not meant as a project
management tool it does not have the
features that you would expect in a
project management tool however if I'm a
team and I just want to get an idea of
what my capacity is for this sprint as
opposed to the previous sprint or I have
people who take on different sets of
tasks I can add some of those things in
I tend not to use those features in
capacity I just ignore that to be honest
I now tend to ignore the task board as
well but if I have an immature team I
might have to look at one of those
things I might need some of that data
and then hopefully as we scale up the
team as we scale up the project and the
people around we can start ditching some
of those things as well so I can view
this either from our backlog basis or I
should be able to change that - so it's
filtering and where is view options
there we go so instead of looking at it
from a backlog items on the left and
tasks I could flip to people on the left
and what tasks are saying to them
flowing across and I can also have work
details and planning so I can move
things to other Sprint's and do those
things all in the UI and I can create
queries if I just want to go find a
bunch of work items or I want to load
them out into Excel or for don't do it
but if you need to load them into MS
Project you could do that as well but
don't tell anybody you can just create a
query build a query in here for finding
work items in your system emailing them
around all of those kind of things
there's also a tool called plans which
is about how do you plan work for
multiple teams working together and it
allows you to create plans add teams and
their backlogs to the plan and see
what's going on across our much larger
team so if you had an access and you
were using the nexxus framework you
could set it up and it would also
support things like safe they would
support more non agile methods like say
for waterfall or other things you can
you can do that in here
and if you're following more agile
techniques so you're looking at DevOps
you're looking it at scrum you're
looking at time and you're looking at
any of the reducing cycle time figure it
out as you go along ideas then you will
be able to use some of these features in
that way as well again it's going to
have features that you're not gonna need
if you're in either category or features
you're not gonna like to use if you're
in either category but it's because
there are lots of teams doing lots of
different things um I've also added a
couple of plugins to this I have a tool
from Daniel Vacanti
actionable agile I just have the demo
and looks like my free trials expired
but this allows you to do some really
powerful analysis of the data and as a
tool from
Vacanti from his companies or Google
look up at actionable agile analytics I
also have dependency tracker in there
which one of the MVPs built I think I
don't know what this will load might not
be pretty because I haven't used it in a
while no there's no dependencies based
on my criteria but it's all tools to
play around with so those were the three
tools and that I've used reasonably
extensively I've also looked at and used
Trello on occasion and I've also looked
at other tools that are out there as
well but not in any great great depth
these are the tools that I've used in
anger with teams figuring out how things
go together how to organize that so I'm
gonna take a quick look and see if there
are any questions I think we're not
streaming on YouTube because it wasn't
working properly and but everything else
is maybe no it's maybe not I'm not going
to percent sure I would need to go if
there are any questions I can answer
them I can also take questions on this
URL that I will answer in the next
session I'm quite happy to take that in
the next session and if you come back to
our YouTube channel which is I don't
have it up there but it's nkd agility
net /tv you will get to our YouTube
channel where everything streams on
there except for this one because I
think it's not actually working so I
will have to look at that after this and
figure that out so if there are no
questions
then I will will have to figure out why
YouTube's not working nevermind
so hopefully um you got something useful
out of this I'm going to share Jul this
I'm not a hundred percent sure what that
schedules going to be yet but I'm going
to come up with a schedule for the
office hours where it's just you know
come and ask me some questions and I'm
also going to come up with schedule for
the webcast that I've been doing a live
webcast where I have some talk about
some stuff I do some presentations get
some people in to talk about things okay
well hopefully this was useful for some
folks and anybody who comes back later
please use the ask and see if we can't
find some other awesome questions to
answer okay thanks very much
naked agility is available for DevOps
and agile training and consultant
contact us for a free consultation