so the question
is how does the PSU course help teams
make more effective product development
decisions
and I think
the main
value take away from the PSU
is is this hypothesis driven driven
approach to software engineering right
to product development hypothesis
doesn't approach to product development
that that
in order to know that you want to add
something to the product you need to
have a reason for it to be there and
because Bob and accounting asked for it
is not necessarily a good reason to add
it to the product right it might be the
right thing for Bob but what about the
300 other people that use your product
is it the right thing for them and Bob
might be quite important but if Bob's
happy and he's important but 299 people
are unhappy with the feature you've
created then perhaps you're going to
have a very negative impression build up
slowly over time that overrides Bob and
then the customer stops using your
product right that's that that bounce so
having
um creating hypotheses right why are you
adding this feature to the product what
value is it going to bring to the
business and how are you going to
measure that you've been successful in
the changes that you make and then even
once you've got all of that figuring out
what's the smallest experiment we could
run to start validating that hypothesis
right so that's that's effectively what
you should build first you should be
running lots of little experiments for
these different little features and
capabilities that you might add to the
product in the future right you might
add the full thing to the product but we
need to run lots of little experiments
to figure out what are the things that
should go on to the main part of the
backlog that were actually
delivering right that's that delivery
channel to customers this is this
Discovery Channel this design channel
are we figuring out what it is we're
creating and the whole team works
together on that the whole team is part
of that team that helps uh uh facilitate
that and I think that that for me is the
big value proposition of the PSU but it
has a kind of additional side
proposition in that
um quite often the the the the the
design the design team like the
designers are separate from the
engineers and the designers go design
stuff and and kind of hand it over to
the engineers and then the engineers go
build it
and trying to figure out how do we bring
that together right I mean you can't you
can't expect everybody in your in your
scrum team
um to be a ux designer that doesn't make
any sense you've you've got to study
you're just like you can't expect
everybody on your team to be a coder
right you've got to study your Craft
um you've got to you got to become good
at your craft and then you're able to
provide value and make the right choices
and and help with the team so you're
always going to need those expert level
skills for these particular skills but
there are also lots of things that
everybody on the team needs to
understand about design
so that they don't what's the what's a
good expression they don't cut the feet
out from under the designers right
because the the every person on your
team is making lots of little micro
decisions every day that that that may
impact on architecture way things work
all kinds of things it's going to impact
in in the product and perhaps they've
spent a whole bunch of time going down
this route that then the designers come
out with a a new way of Designing that
then has a massive
cost and impact on the way the product
goes together and that that could have
been
maybe reduced by having these two groups
work closely together so that the team
better understood the long-term
strategic direction of what it is that
the designers are trying to do and that
they can incorporate some of those
things into their continuous decision
making right that way they make more of
the right decisions and less of the
wrong ones and and bringing those two
groups together so that for me is the
the second part to that story not just
bringing hypothesis driven Engineering
in which
should be there anyway right but also
how do we bring these two groups closer
together
um and how do you balance how much of
this work you do up front
um
and how you integrate it in to the
stream of value that you're actually
actually delivering on a continuous
basis so how do you bring this all
together into a unified strategy so you
can continue not only in the small scale
continually and repeatedly deliver value
to the customers right but also in the
hypothesis driven engineering
continuously run lots of little
experiments maybe five or six little
experiments a Sprint we're trying to see
the numbers change so that we can spend
more time in that area but that data
from that those hypotheses are then
feeding back into the story that the
designers working with the product owner
and the whole team are figuring out like
where are we actually going with the
product how are we shaping and changing
it and how do we incorporate those
long-term strategic initiatives into
this Sprint cycle where we have this
regular delivery Cadence so answering
all of those questions is for me the
main purpose of the professional scrum
with user experience class
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility