the question is
what
would be a great
ideal Consulting outcome for a customer
and that's that's a that's an
interesting question because I think
it's different for every customer right
but It ultimately comes down to
trying to think of the right words and
the right phrasing
it
it comes down to being able to
consistently deal with surprise
not sure that's the best way to describe
it right but
the reality of the world is that things
are changing and happening all the time
and businesses have
two types of surprises they can have
there's positive surprises negative
surprises
positive surprises they want to be able
to take advantage of negative surprises
they want to be able to like let's make
sure that doesn't mess with us
and
though they're they're because they're
surprises you don't know what they're
going to be you don't know when they're
gonna happen you have to have a system
that is able to roll with it
and most organizations are very very
rigid
so an ideal outcome for
an agile Consulting engagement is that
the organization has less
bureaucracy and more adaptability right
I mean that's that's ultimately what
organizations are trying to do
the the difficulty is that there's
there's two fundamental
mental constructs that are seem to be
seem to be mutually exclusive
and it's very hard to move from one to
the other and it's very easy to move
from the other to the one right this is
the bit that's difficult is that you you
have that that that tayloristic
type of organization which is top-down
command and control 18th century
Industrial Revolution thinking right
that's their that's their their model
that pyramid model
and then you've got
organizations over all the way over on
the other side which are fewer in number
who are completely decentralized
um node-based organizations where the
people making the decisions are the
people that are up close to the market
whereas in the the pyramid organizations
the people making the decisions are
furthest away from the market right the
CEO my one of my favorite quotes is from
Simon saidek yes absolutely simonsonic
so one of my favorite quotes is from
Simon siniak
um and and he talked about speaking to a
CEO
and saying to the to the CEO or the CEO
saying you know I know what my customers
want
and Simon says to him well you haven't
spoken to a customer than 15 years how
would you know what they wanted and that
that's the person that's furthest away
from the market is making all of the
decisions
whereas in the the
node-based organization that the CEO is
at the center providing services to the
organization there is there he's the
cost center right the CEO or he or she
the CEO is the cost center and the rest
of the organization is the value
creation and they're interacting
directly with the market invoicing
getting money from the customers so
ultimately the ultimate goal is to move
from that top-down terroristic
organization towards this node-based
people-orientated
it was Mary Follett so I guess follicism
Follow Tight I don't know organizations
I'm gonna thing over here but it's very
hard to move from tayloristic to
politistic
okay but really easy to fall back the
other way because all you need is for
Rigamortis to set in to move back to
that rigid top-down model because that's
what it is and one of the things that I
think a successful
agile consultant will do
is work with people in that organization
to help them have a more flexible
mindset
so from from top down
left to right at all levels you want
every single person in your organization
to be thinking about how do I remain
Nimble how do I remain adaptable how do
I Stave off
the rigor mortis right that is that is
bureaucracy
and that needs to be in in in every part
of the organization it's not uh
something that you can just hire
somebody in and they install in your
organization is every single individual
in your organization needs to be part of
that story so successful agile
Consulting looks like
um um
building understanding in the
organization
um building
um
tools that people in the organization
can use to remain Nimble otherwise
they'll fall back to the age-old tools
that everybody talks about
um and and not being there full time
right it's like it's almost like a
crutch when and somebody is there full
time it's a crutch for the organization
they need to learn to stand on their own
they need to learn to make their own
mistakes
um so that
I know that probably doesn't really
answer that question of what does it
look like
right but I think what it looks like is
different in every organization I I
could articulate what it looks like it
at Microsoft although they're only some
way along that transition towards that
that that that that that goal
every organization is completely
different and it's so different because
their Market is different their products
are different their people are different
and there's no one right way to to
answer that question