how do you know what additional
potential value you could be achieving
with your product but that you haven't
yet how how do you find those gaps
evidence-based management has a key
value area called unrealized value where
you would be expected to come up with
some metrics to help you understand that
Dynamic now evidencebased management
does have some example metrics in there
you might look at the experience or
satisfaction Gap in your product you
might look at market share um you might
look um at other metrics that you can
come up with for your product but you
need to understand what values left L on
your table CU that's where your product
backlog comes from