foreign
so the question is in a highly
competitive market how to scrum product
development help acquire and retain
customers
I think there's two parts to that one
part is it doesn't right
um the the the the
you it's the value question again right
this this there's kind of two parts to
the puzzle there's there's
um market value right and Market values
made up of current value I.E what's the
value that's in your product right now
so you might measure things like I don't
know
um you might measure customer
satisfaction employee satisfaction and
usage of the features in your product
hopefully you get hopefully you've got
lots of telemetry coming off your
product to know what buttons people are
clicking when and why and at what time
of the month so that you can gather that
data and make decisions right that's
current value
um but also looking at
um
unrealized value
right for those that recognize it I'm
talking about evidence-based management
here but unrealized value is looking
forward in the future and figuring out
what what value you don't have in your
product yet that you need to have in
your product
so you could be looking at satisfaction
gaps hopefully you're not just doing
competitor analysis right but sometimes
you might do a competitor analysis and
figure out
um what you need to have on your product
backlog those those
two things scrum can't help you with
right you you need you need to be able
to it's going to create an environment
hopefully within which you realize you
need to do that and that
um you need to collect that data and
figure it out but that's your your your
your Market your market value is your
job as the business right
um but then you've also got your your
um
organizational capability
right at the bottom of this this this
story in your organizational capability
is two things it's you're you're you're
organization's ability to innovate
and their time to Market
right those are those are two things
that
um people
inside of your business doing the work
do have full control over
the value discussion is a business
discussion right and scrum can't help
you with that business discussion except
to tell you that it needs to happen
right or or help make transparent that
it needs to happen on the other side of
that you've got your capability and
again it's
scrum just tells you that it needs to
happen right the minimum Cadence in
scrum is monthly
you're expected to have working usable
product at the end of every month
um if you don't have that we're you know
we might be doing okay but we're not
doing scrum
um if we are able to do that then maybe
there are things that need to change
maybe we need better engineering
practices maybe we need to pay back
technical debt maybe we need to look at
look at other things maybe we need to
look at how quickly we can get features
into production and and from the value
conversation that anything we come up
with is is is like um
a hypothesis it's perceived value until
we actually get it into production get
the data from our customers or interview
our customers and get that back into the
into the process
so you might be looking at time to learn
at the bottom there and both of those
categories ability to ability to to to
innovate right how much time do we spend
adding net new features rather than
adding
incremental features to or inter
incremental capability to existing stuff
net new features is where
it's it's it's where the value is right
or potential value is and you're gonna
have to add a whole bunch of net new
features to find that one piece of value
that that is actually valuable so in
order to do that we've got to get it
into production as quickly as possible
which is the
uh time to market right how quickly can
you get those features that you've
created into market so it's a big
balance here between figuring out what
you need to do for the future the
business needs to take care of that into
um it being existing value and also
figuring out what your your your your
your ability to innovate is and your
time to Market that that creates that
evidence-based management view of your
organization
um and scrum helps and
um implicitly I think is probably the
best way to describe it implicitly with
many of those things right it tells you
you need to have a product backlog
but it doesn't tell you what goes in
your product backlog or where it comes
from and or how you you maximize the
value of it right that's a business
decision
it tells you that you need to
continuously
deliver working usable product but it
doesn't tell you how you're going to do
that what tools you're going to use what
practices and techniques you need in
order to achieve that
so scrum is a tool for making
transparent
that maybe some of these things are
lacking
in your organization so in order
to bring that back to the the if you're
in highly competitive markets
scrum enables the transparency you need
as an organization to figure out that
you're not going fast enough and where
it is you need to fix is it that we're
delivering lots of the wrong features
right because we're monitoring our our
usage is it that we're delivering
features now that are too late for the
market maybe our our ability to to get
features into production is too slow is
it because uh the the the we're spending
too much time struggling with the
complexity of our existing product and
it's very hard to add new features so we
don't add many of them
right those are all
pieces of information that scrum makes
transparent that we can then use to
change but we as the business still need
to do that change scrum's just going to
tell us there's something wrong we still
need to do something about it