one of the main ways to wreck your
campign strategy is is not agreeing how
you're going to work as a team right
unless you've you've sat down with the
people you're going to work with and
decided on how are we going to approach
things we probably don't have agreement
right most people um unless you sit down
and agree are probably not on the same
page we don't have all of our nosies
pointed in the same direction right
we're
we I might pick things based on um their
Affinity to something I like you might
pick things based on their Affinity to
something you like and
suddenly we're what from the outside it
looks like we're randomly picking stuff
to work on right
um that that working agreement
is so often missing uh from
teams for some
reason lots of people think that you can
just throw 10 people together and
they'll magically figure out how to
navigate the complex nature of of
delivering high value complex products
and be able to just figure it
out and they also think that you can
just apply some
framework and if we all follow that
we'll also all be in in in agreement so
for example scrum right we have a a
caman strategy um we're going to do
we're going to do scrum as part of that
that's that's we're going to create a
bounded environment we're going to do
all those things and um scrum is going
to solve all of our problems that's our
working agreement no it's not it's not
your working agreement at all scrum is a
framework it's not not uh blowby blow
how to do stuff are you going to use
story points are you going to use
planning poker those are not part of
scrum they're optional things that you
might pick have you decided to do those
things if you're if you're not doing
scrum you might just have 10 people who
all want to work a slightly different
way working together towards some
outcome so I would say to you if I if I
took one of my lovely board games to my
board game group I'll will be there
tonight at playing if I took one and we
didn't we all we we got the pieces out I
don't know if you've seen these things
but they have like 300 pieces in the box
right um we got all the pieces out of
the
box uh I set it up the way I think it
looks like it should be set up so I'm
not going to look at the rules I'm just
going to make some stuff up and then
every member that's playing all all all
four of us uh make up our own rules for
how to play the game we don't read the
official rules we just do it our own
way are we working together are
we playing the same game right you can't
have a win you can't have success unless
you've agreed what the rules are for
Success right most of these games it's
the most points right but have you
agreed how you get points can I just
move a piece to here and say now I have
300 points
that's total disorder that's total
disarray and most teams that I see and
engage with operate in a state of total
disarray because they've not agreed what
their rules are they've not agreed what
game they're playing what success looks
like how they get H little successes
within the context of the bigger
successes that the organization's trying
to achieve so sit down with your team
and
agree The Way Forward don't tell you
need to agree because if you tell me how
to do the stuff that I do I'm going to
ignore you I need to be in agreement
with you you need to collaborate on
creating that definition of workflow we
need to collaborate on creating our
working agreement and it actually
doesn't matter whether you have a c I
don't care if you're doing if you're
doing caman if you're doing a caman
strategy caman method scrum doesn't
matter what it is if you've got a bunch
of people working together you need to
get together and agree how you're going
to work otherwise you have disarray
everybody's making it up as they go
along don't do that if you're struggling
to implement a cand strategy we can help
or find you someone who can click the
link below and get in touch today