they went from from 25 features to
production each year with the same
number of people to nearly nearly 150
features to production each year and
even taking four years to get there holy
moly I would rather have 800 features
than 25 features right and yes the
features are smaller but it's more
experiments right it's more chances to
get something right it's more ideas to
see if they connect with the customer so
in the old way is you you you have to
stick with and focus on something even
when it's not quite the most optimal
thing but if you're doing lots of little
experiments you can find oh this thing
resonates really much more than these
other things with the customer let's do
more on that until it stops resonating
and then we move on to something else
and move on to something else and we
build a better product with more
capabilities