when should an organization consider a
professional agile consultant that's
that's an uh
so the easy answer
is is is
when when they've just
most unimaginably failed to deliver or
failed to be successful and would have
unfailed to be successful in whatever
Endeavor they're trying to achieve
because I actually learned this from Ken
um at that moment when
an organization is reeling from that
failure
they are most open to change
they are most open to doing something
different we we need something different
we need to try something new
um as this backfired on occasion I do
know of a company that only uses scrum
and agile when a project is in Jeopardy
and then falls back to Waterfall so they
run all these projects waterfall and
then near the end of the project they
have to switch to scrum to actually
deliver it and then they switch back
again which is totally weird but that's
how they how they do things but that
that
that failure to deliver
creates that desire and need for change
so that's that's probably the best time
to bring in somebody to help
unfortunately
there's an unfortunately there as well
is that that quite often companies turn
to really large Consulting companies
who don't although they talk a good talk
don't necessarily actually understand
standard they don't really understand it
um you you companies are won over by uh
fast talking PowerPoint presentation
gurus that are able to to to talk a good
game but can actually deliver
and so that that's that's the risk at
that moment right because they're
they're desperate for for help
um and then they're they're they'll take
whatever whatever's on offer and there's
not always the right thing they're gonna
find the right agile which is why I
guess you said professional agile
consultant right you've got to get that
professional one in there
um
but I think that that that's probably
the the key time to get get them in but
really the other answer is anytime
any any time maybe maybe you're being
really successful and you wonder
could we be better
um sometimes having somebody come in
from the outside and look at what it is
that you're doing and something that
I've done a whole bunch with
organizations is kind of like a
I guess I would call it a state of agile
report or a state of devops report
where I come in and I interview a whole
bunch of people in the organization
generally solo but sometimes in teams
and just ask them how they're doing how
do they you know what's their Cadence
for delivery how often do you have
working products and asking all the way
up through through the organization and
into leadership as well and hopefully
you can get a hold of some customers too
right because they always have good uh
good stories to tell
and create
that that like what's the next big thing
that this organization should tackle and
I don't think that often comes from the
inside without a little bit of outside
injection of knowledge or a different
way of thinking or a different way of
looking at the problem because we're
when we're in the jar looking out right
it's difficult to kind of see what our
what our own problem is
um so yeah both both when you're when
you're totally hosed and uh when you're
not right so pretty much anytime
hmm
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility