agile product management differs
from product management that has been
done for many
years in actually very subtle ways so
you could say it doesn't differ at all
as well because all of the tools and
techniques that you would use in product
management um and you have been using in
product management for many years is the
same tools that you would use in agile
product management
but the way that you approach the
context of the tools and which tools
make more sense and which tools make
less sense is the bit where where it
differs because of we're we're we're
changing the underlying principles of
what it is we're trying to achieve so in
the traditional traditional
World we're probably going quite a long
time between actual
releases very much at least to get the
first release
um and then between releases were're
probably taking a long time I'm thinking
about um the Azure devops team at
Microsoft when it was team Foundation
server um and visual studio right that
era around the 2010 era um they were on
a two-year two-year cycle right so they
were um delivering a new version of the
product every two years halfway they
would do a service pack and then halfway
into to roughly about the same I guess
it was roughly about the same time they
would have a a beta of the next version
of the of of the product um and what
what really
happened was that when you're thinking
about product management you're thinking
about how do we make a product that
maximizes the value for our business
right that makes the most money that's
that's what we're talking about with
product management we have a product we
need to manage what we put into that
product what we take out of that product
how we uh ship that product how we
Market that product in order to maximize
the return of investment right that's
that's ultimately what we're talking
about and in in that um world of
releasing long releases right long time
between releases they found that they
really
struggled to um to maximize that value
for a number of reasons it just took too
long to advertise the value that they
thought their customer wanted
so the first one is you have to build
the whole thing right you have to
customer wants XYZ feature you have to
build XYZ feature because when you ship
XYZ feature you're not technically
you're not shipping again for two years
so if there's something wrong with X XYZ
feature or XYZ feature doesn't have some
capability right
um
then the customer customers going to be
frustrated and may go to another product
right may go to your competitor because
they do have have that feature
so that
idea of um shipping once every two years
actually
means that you can't take
feedback and get it in front of your
customers for four years
generally there may be circumstances
where you can change what you're working
on but then it becomes a big issue right
because you've planned all of this stuff
over two years and somebody makes a
change to what it is they want to
deliver what is the impact across all of
the things um that you're that you're
working on so that's why we have change
change requests right we make a
complicated convoluted change request
policy system in order to reduce the
change coming in because change coming
in is high cost because we have to
change all of the things that are going
on in order to accommodate that that
that change so um you've got this this
long cycle you've got that I I mentioned
that it was twice the iteration it's
twice the iteration length to
incorporate feedback from your customer
quite often um and the reason for that
is that you you get your product in
front of your customer
um at this point and then in two years
we're going to do another ship but we've
already had to plan what we're going to
put into that two years right so when we
get feedback on version one of our
product that's going to end up in
version three of our product if it's
small enough or important enough it
might end up in version two but we'll
have to kick something out that we were
going to deliver um so that's that's
that's risk right because we're not
delivering something that we think the
market needs
and we end up with that twice the
Cadence right twice our Cadence is the
amount of time it generally takes to get
features new features and feedback that
the that the market desires so what's
the cost of delay what's the cost to our
customer of not delivering a feature
that they need in order to service their
business and we're not going to deliver
it to them for up to four years probably
a little bit less but up to four years
that is a m massive impact on not only
your customer ability to to to innovate
and do things differently or or fulfill
their their needs um but on your team
and the people doing the work's ability
to see the value that they create being
used by the customers because the delay
is just too low they're not working on
that feature anymore by the time uh uh
the customer gets it so one of the
fundamental premises that we talk about
in ag product management the agile piece
versus the just product management piece
is that we're going to have much shorter
Cycles much radically shorter Cycles so
for example the Azure devops team went
almost overnight some false starts but
almost overnight uh from a two-year
delivery cycle um down to a 3-we
delivery cycle so delivering to
production every 3 weeks delivering to
real users out in the world every 3
weeks and that enabled them to get
closer to the customer right so even if
we still had that same at twice the
iteration length you're talking six
weeks to get something new in front of
your customer that they need or tell you
that they need and six weeks is much
shorter than two years four years right
up to four years so up to six weeks
instead of up to four years and that
fundamental change
means that a lot of the practices that
you might use in product management then
become a little bit of irrelevant right
so I'm think practices I'm thinking of
that become become irrelevant um would
be change requests right they they they
pretty much become irrelevant because
change requests were there to protect
the plan and protect the investment in
the plan but since our plan is now only
3 weeks um we don't need to protect it
so much because the risk of something
derailing that plan is much smaller
right because we and we can correct much
more often so we don't don't need that
change request
system um and we would look at portfolio
investment like how much time are we
investing in different features
different parts of the product or do we
want to move people and we can move
people in a 3-we Cadence um rather than
on a two-yearly Cadence but then we're
also because we're
um delivering more frequently we're able
to um then remove other things right
that are going to get in the way of
delivering more frequently can you can
you imagine having to do uat for your
entire product every three weeks right U
doesn't make sense user acceptance
testing doesn't make sense there's a
famous quote from Brian Harry uh um I I
love that presentation of his that he
did and he had a a picture of the the
slippers from the the red glittery
slippers um from Wizard of Oz and it was
like there's no place like production no
matter how much testing you do no matter
how much uh uh validation you do you're
always going to find production issues
and that's where uat came in right uat
was trying to protect production from
issues introduced by the engineering
teams
but if the engineering teams are
delivering new versions of the product
every 3 weeks where's the time to do
that uat so one of the things we need to
fix one of the agile practices we need
to bring in is much higher quality
product much higher quality code much
higher quality Engineering in order to
not have those issues in uat your uat
should be a cost center anyway it should
not be a Value Center if uat finds
something that shows a failure of
quality in the engineering system um U
should never ever find anything um so if
you build up quality to the point where
uat is a cost center not a Value Center
then the people that fund the uat that
desire the uat because they find stuff
that will start to erode that because
you're demonstrating the quality of your
product you're demonstrating that that
uat is unnecessary because it never
finds a problem um so that that you have
to apply that thinking to all of the
practices that we have in product
management do they make sense in agile
product management versus the way we
always used to do things right so can we
do it quickly is it getting in the way
of actually getting our product in front
of users because that's how we validate
that we've built something that's
valuable how do we um enable that
continuous delivery of high quality
usable product into the hands of our
users and what of our practices that we
use right now in product management make
sense in that space and which don't make
sense right and they maybe don't make
sense because they become irrelevant or
they don't make sense because they take
too long um and what are we going to
replace them with um in order to
effectively maximize the ROI of our
product in the market