so the question is what are the steps
that the team can follow If the product
owner is
incompetent um that's pretty strong
right incompetence is pretty strong but
I have met a ton of product owners that
would perhaps fit into that category or
the other adjacent category which is I
don't know what I'm supposed to do or my
organization doesn't allow me to do the
things I'm supposed to do
right so it's not it
manifests the same way the outcomes the
same and ineffective product owner um
but the reason could be incompetence or
I'm not allowed right within the bounds
of the org or I don't feel I'm allowed
um in both of those those
circumstances I would probably suggest
that there's some um onus on the scrum
Master to figure out how to how to deal
with that right it might not might not
be ideally the product owner is the
person with the money who can resolve
those problems but often they're not so
what can you as a scrum Master
do um with the support of the whole team
right perhaps with the support of the
whole team perhaps with the support of
the person who is the product owner to
engage with the business to engage with
the organization and the way the
organization is structured in order to
enable a greater degree of product owner
ship right that's that's part of the
scrum Master services to the product
owner um if if if you don't have a scrum
Master on your team just pick somebody
in your team who who has an interest in
dealing with some of those things and
they can be the scrum Master right you
they don't need any special skills um
they just need to be a bit battle
hardened in working within your
organization which if you've been
working there a while you probably are
and start going building those
relationships right who do you need to
speak to take out for dinner buy a beer
for in leadership in HR in the
organization to start building those
relationships for them to start seeing
your point build in those those back
channels um there's there's uh what was
that that that movie with the nuclear
explosion um uh in in the baseball game
uh clear and present danger no it was
the other one um anyway that movie which
you probably remember better than I do
uh uh the channels were how things got
done right between the Americans and the
Russians there was there was people uh
that
are low in the organization who are in
either organization who were able to
have conversations to trade information
to find out things that are going on
that that's one of the skills of a of a
scrum Master politic right it's politics
uh being able to practicing um um
politic getting into um the the
conversations that you need to get into
and in order to get into those
conversations you have to demonstrate an
understanding of the topic you have to
make small suggestions around the side
perhaps an email with one person who
then maybe invites you to some of those
conversations because you've
demonstrated uh your knowledge and your
capability um and then you know you
don't want to say anything unless you
actually can add value add value where
you can build up your knowledge and
experience in that space and and and
encourage change and that's how
everything gets done in organizations
right in especially when there are lots
of people that don't understand how to
do that so if you have a an ineffective
uh product owner um that's the best
route if you have an incompetent product
owner who really just shouldn't be in
that position at all they are not uh the
right person the the the old adage is
kind of true people are promoted to
their level of incompetence right um
people are good at their job so they get
promoted to the next level up um and
then in the next level up they're also
good at their job so they get promoted
to the next level up and they get to a
level where they're no longer good at
their job and that's where they stay um
when in reality organizations should
offer that capability to drop drop back
down right to to to you might have the
seniority but I I I'm I don't want to do
this job up here I want to do this job
here or this job even further down in
the organization I I really respect some
of the things I I meet people at at
Microsoft who've been a soft engineer a
a real coder um for for for 20 30 years
um inside of the organization and they
they take on more responsibility and
accountability by um mentoring other
people helping with other stuff but not
actually managing people um which often
is not a skill that lots of people have
right just like taking any any anybody
with skills with people and making them
a programmer is probably not a good idea
the converse is also also true um so
maybe that product owner is just not
meant to be in that position and there's
very little that you as a team can do um
there's certainly with the politic
around the side you could maybe let
people become
aware of the problem um but you need to
really skirt that moral and ethical area
of um should you be going behind this
person's back perhaps you go speak to
that product owner and say uh say say
say something in the first instance
although that might get you got to gauge
that situation yourself um but all the
team can do ultimately is be the best
team they
can um deliver working usable product be
that competence at that level and if
we're not building the right thing
that's not the team's fault that's the
product own fault and hopefully at some
point the organization sees that we're
continuously building awesome product
but it's the wrong product um and then
they see that light of it's the product
owner that's the problem not the team um
and perhaps the scrum Master can help
educate with that right not rather than
going behind the product owner's back
just explain to the business what a
product owner's job is what the team's
job is what their roles and
responsibilities are and hopefully
they'll be able to see what the problem
is thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked
agility