in
traditional
budgeting we take all we we spend a
bunch of time once per year and have
been a little bit factious but have a
whole bunch of people in our
organization fight over how much money
is going to be allocated to their
pot right and then that's that's their
pot for the
year they
know that if they don't spend it they
lose it right if you allocate a million
dollar to to a particular project and
they only use
500,000 next year you're going to be
thinking of giving them 500,000 and it's
going to be very hard for them to fight
for for for for a million even if that's
just the normal EB and flow of what it
is we're working
on and if something doesn't fit within
like we spend we spend such a long time
building the budget and balancing it
right like a like a like one I've seen
those the the the the budget that
countries have it's this massive massive
massive book we end up with not not
obviously as big as that because we
don't have as many things but a big book
of here's what the the budget is for the
year the problem
is that five minutes after we've
ratified the budget that we put our
stamp on it and said yep that's our
budget for the year the market
changes the the the state of the product
changes ideas change so if somebody
comes up with an
idea it's not in the budget for this
year right but the market opportunity is
in a couple of weeks we have enough time
to build it but we don't have any budget
right that's maybe small enough that we
can there's discretionary funding but
let's say it was 6 months worth of work
so it's massive effort massive Endeavor
but huge huge huge payoffs
then we'd probably do something right
but where's that balance in your
organization that that level that the
scale of the payoff versus the cost we
have the money we have to go
find where's that where's that biting
point and how much do we lose how much
value in the market do we lose because
lots of things just don't quite hit that
biting point because we're doing yearly
budgets so there's a bunch of things
around Beyond budgeting which is how do
we re How We Do budgets in order to be
more effective but effectively the
result that you want for your
organization is that you can fund the
things that make sense at the time they
make sense right so in the agile World
we're getting working product in front
of our customers as frequently as we can
right so depending on what it is you're
building that that time scale might
change I the manifesto says for from a
few weeks to a few months right scrum
talks about 30 days 30 days is the
maximum amount of time between uh uh um
getting things in front of your
customers and if you look at the the
detecting agile BS paper from the US
Department of Defense uh they talk about
every iteration in including the first
getting your product in front of real
customers so not not not to uat not to
just merely test users but to real
production users so you're going to
production every every iteration if
you're doing that if you're getting to
production every iteration then that's
your pivot point right it's not a yearly
Pivot Point figuring out what we're
going to do but it's a a a a much
smaller pivot point so instead of
allocating all the money at a single
yearly point we want to be EB and
flowing as you know this this project
reach reaches a dead end there's not
much more value to be had so we're not
going to we're not going to continue it
we're not going to do more Sprints we're
not going to do more iterations at the
moment we're going to move it into
maintenance mode which changes its cost
profile and for other things there's a
new initiative some folks have come up
with a great idea let's let's let's fund
that so you're effectively looking at
more of a of a venture capitalist or a
entrepreneur style budgeting model in
that you're not allocating all the
funding to projects upfront you're
allocating you have a pool of of of
Finance available like how much can we
spend you should know that on a regular
basis what's our what's our capability
and then we want to spend as little as
possible to get the maximum value and
that EB and flow needs to happen the
difficulty
in the traditional model is I I have a
had a customer
recently who are doing big things it's
manufacturing and they're making big
things big expensive things and they had
a a machine that was
faulty and the well okay it wasn't
faulty it was just getting old it was
starting to make mistakes it it it it
was creating less effective Parts than
the product
needed and they kept using it and the
person who ran the machine wrote the
business case for H getting a new
machine and started passing it up the
chain they did all the due diligence
they needed to do and it kept going up
in the organization because I think it
was a 10 it was a 10 or2 million spend
therefore it had to go Fairly high in
the organization to get approval and it
got to somebody who looked at it and
said that's not on my budget for this
year no and that that's not in its
budget for this year no cost the company
billions of dollars in recall calls to
recall the product and and and and
resolve the issues that that resulted
from this machine that could have been
replaced for $10 million and it cost
billions so that that's why we need to
that that's an example of why we need to
do something different the bit that you
don't see like that's an obvious one
right that's a catalyst for change
because oh my goodness me we just we
just had this huge cost why did we have
it because of this $10 million we didn't
spend well let's spend the 10
million but the bit you don't see is
your unrealized value if you think of in
evidence-based management at the top of
the curve in your in your market value
of your product you've
got unrealized value on one side and
value on the other so you've got value
that's in your product your your your
current increment and then you've got
unrealized value which should be
reflected in your backlog but there's
more unrealized value than is actually
in your backlog
right we want to be continually adapting
that unrealized value as the market
shifts as opportunities arise as things
change in the world and it's very
difficult to do that within the bounds
of a traditional yearly budget cycle so
we need to adapt our yearly budget cycle
into the context of we're not doing
yearly projects anymore we're building
products and a product has a budget and
they can allocate it however they like
and budgets for products tend to look
like n number of people right the most
usually usually the most expensive thing
especially when we're building software
is the people so this particular product
has the budget to support 100
people a year on it that's that's their
budget cycle and then with within that
budget cycle they're deciding how they
allocate it what features they allocate
to within that context that can be a
kind of halfway where your organization
might still be doing yearly budgets and
but you're able to adapt it to the
product cycle but there's more you can
do take a look at Beyond budget