how does my real world experience
translate into my training style well
I think they're neat for that you to a
little bit understand
my my my experience I guess
um I was a software engineer for 10
years I just got into software
engineering the year before.net came
along
so I was ASP for a year and then
straight into into.net and that's where
I I'd really been ever since I mean I I
I do other things but that's mainly
where I where I where my sweet spot is
right my my comfort zone
um and then I got recognized by
Microsoft as doing some interesting
things with Team Foundation server
right I was that was and I became a
Microsoft MVP
um in 2008
uh and then what really happened was
um you got when you become an MVP right
you kind of get access to a whole bunch
of internal stuff you get access to lots
of free tools and lots of things but the
big thing is you go to the MVP Summit
every year and the MVP Summit is three
and a half thousand uh uh MVPs from all
over the world all the different
countries all the different Technologies
all descend on Redmond in uh Washington
state in the US
um we basically take over the whole of
Redmond all of the hotels uh for uh for
a week and Microsoft puts on a whole
bunch of sessions and events and all
kinds of things
so you get you start to get these
personal connections with all sorts of
other people in the in the in the
organization uh but my experience was my
uh competence was TFS kind of TFS devops
Alm was that space and there was between
80 and 90 MVPs in that category and this
was a really tight-knit group because
devops was emerging at the time it was
definitely loads of people who were at
the top of their game right because
they're into all these different things
and Technologies and coming into that
world and writing a lot of content in
that world and really understanding what
it is that we're trying to do with
devops like I leveraged a lot of their
knowledge absorbing all of their ideas
allowed me to then uh I guess impress
some of the people there
um and I worked for a year remotely for
an Australian company with Adam Cogan
um and then I got hired by Steve Borg to
go live in Seattle
um as a devops consultant and I spent uh
three years I think it was Alm right
application life cycle Management pln
Consultant bit devops uh consultant for
three years in the US and I effectively
had a different customer every week or a
different customer every two weeks
across the us so I think I spent time in
about 15 different states
um I saw all the industries like there's
no specific industry that devops is
relevant for it's any company that has
software so we did Aerospace we did
military we did I think I didn't work on
that project but the nuclear power
plants
um Healthcare uh Finance I did a gig for
uh finance company that does the
finances for all of the stars in
Hollywood and so they have this huge
building and they only have one floor at
the top and the rest of the building's
empty it was really interesting
um but
that experience of seeing all these
different organizations seeing what
they're doing seeing how they're
treating and engaging people means that
I I almost I think I've never had a
circumstance where I don't have a story
for where there's somebody else that's
more dysfunctional than whatever the
person that's talking to me the story
that they have
so I I think I think that's a huge power
in the training world because you want
you want people that you're training to
realize that there's light at the end of
the tunnel
you want them to realize that they can
get to somewhere else and unfortunately
I think this is a very human thing
knowing that somebody else is worse
makes you feel better right and it makes
you go maybe I can be less worse right
maybe I can so then I'm listening more
and engaging more so I think those
stories help from that perspective and
but also bringing the stories of
um how people have solved particular
problems or even
things that haven't worked right oh I've
had a couple of customers that I've
tried that this way and it's just not
worked for them at all they just had to
to to ditch it and I think that is one
of the core characteristics of not just
uh uh um me as a PST but most of the
psts that I interact with are people
that have worked in Industry that have
worked with lots of customers that have
all of these stories and and there's
nothing more interesting than a whole
bunch of psts getting together
um to have a conversation about all
these crazy things that have been
happening in organizations because then
you can share those stories and bring
more things to the table when you're
training so I feel like that that
experience of being a software engineer
right that's one thing that that it
lends me credibility when I'm working
with people in teams that build software
right because I have been the person
building the software I understand how
that works and then the the seven years
as a devops consultant
um is that that little bit level above
all of the processes around how we build
software moving towards continuous
delivery
being able to categorically tell people
there is no software on this planet that
can't move towards continuous delivery
right there's no pulling the wool over
my eyes for uh uh capabilities in that
space
um and then moving into into training
and
agile Consulting
means that all of that stuff is the
foundation upon which I'm I'm building
the classes and the courseware and and
what I'm trying to do and what I'm
hoping people will learn and engage with
and and find out more about
um what they can do