automation is a huge part of
enabling the building of software to be
more effective more standardized
more efficient I don't like that word
but it it certainly fits
here the difficulty is that anytime
you've got a human doing something
you're go you're going to have mistakes
you're going to have mistakes you're
going to have steps missed you're go
things are going to go wrong two two two
kind of examples one's a commercial
example and one's just an interesting
one so one of the interesting ones do
that one first is that I used to teach a
bunch of testers how to use the Azure
devops test tools uh when there was a
separate apps was quite some time ago
and you would
think that the superpower of testers
would be that they could follow a test
script right they're going to spend a
bunch of work creating the test script
but then they're going to follow that
test script to run the test running a
manual test
and follow those steps right so there's
10 steps in the test they follow those
10 steps and it either passes or it
fails right well in this training we had
workshops we had labs and they had to
follow a set of steps on the lab
and I kept getting feedback from loads
of people in the room loads of instances
of the training I would get feedback all
the time that the labs were wrong that
the labs didn't work that that the they
were following the steps and the lab
doesn't work it doesn't do what it's
supposed to do and this was false they
just weren't following the steps they
were either missing something or
clicking the wrong button or not
whatever it was right
so those
testers whose job it is to I'm I'm I'm
being a little bit factious here whose
job it is to uh create and then run sets
of steps manually perhaps um to validate
whether something is built correctly or
manifestly unable to successfully and
consistently run through a set of St
steps and this is just part of Being
Human it's not a slight on them it's not
a tester thing it's a human thing the
commercial example is the KN cap capital
Group which you might have heard of or
maybe not but they went bankrupt because
somebody couldn't follow a set of steps
they had a they had a deployment of a
new version of their product there were
Stock Exchange Management trading
software so you can imagine when
something goes wrong the cost of
something goes wrong is pretty enormous
and with $400 million in the bank at the
beginning of the day a deployment
happened it went wrong because the the
the person running the deployment
deployed to eight out of the nine
servers and because not all the servers
had the latest version of the code some
weird stuff started happening it took
them till the end of the day to figure
out what the problem was which was steps
missed and by that time they had to
declare bankruptcy they were done right
um the cost of these types of mistakes
is enormous the that one is a a very
extreme example but the cost of somebody
who's running a set of steps and this
could be a tester it could be a coder it
could be uat right could be a user they
walk through a set of steps and then
they communicate back that it was wrong
it didn't
work that cost is in investigation from
the engineers in loss of focus on new
because they're not building new stuff
for you when they're having to go look
at this erroneous problem and what we
want instead is automation the solution
to both of these problems is automation
there is an expression I use that if it
can be automated it should should be
automated and if it can't be automated
it should be rearchitecturing
close the feedback look think about if
you were you were telling a story I'm
thinking codes kind of like telling a
story you're telling a story you're
working on part of this story and then
you get you submit it to your your your
your publisher and the publisher takes
six months to come back with feedback
and the feedback is this didn't work
that doesn't work can you change this
can you reformat this now you're much
further along in the story you're
working on a different part of it and
now you have to come back to this
previous part of the story and get into
the mindset of this part of the story
and try and ignore the things you
learned during the Future Part of the
story right the character development
has changed and you have to go back to
this old version of the character with
older style of of how that character
does
things and now this you need to do this
differently so now we're trying to make
a change back here in the
past when we have understanding from the
future that would impact how we would do
this but we can't let that impact what
we're doing it's huge cognitive load
right and that's that's in code it's
exactly the same exactly the same thing
happens when you have to do that so not
only do we want Automation in our
process to automate tests so that we
don't have as many false positives of of
test failing or false negatives H anyway
false negatives probably good and false
positives right but we also want to have
those tests run as quickly as possible
so that we get that feedback loop closed
as quickly as
possible preferably I'm talking about
minutes that's what I'm talking about
here is we want automation that runs in
minutes that tells us whether we've
preferably seconds right or milliseconds
but minutes at the most at the outside
um a great example of that is the Azure
devops team uh they used to have very
long automation to find out whether
they'd broken something it was 48 to 72
hours because they had to run on a bunch
of servers because they had long running
they had automated tests but they were
long running system tests those are the
wrong types of automation so not all
types of automation are the right type
of automation they were certainly better
than trying to do it man ually right but
those types of tests tend to be flaky
tend to have a lot of false positives
tend to be difficult so they embarked on
an Endeavor to invert that triangle of
tests right so if you think about you've
got you've got fast running unit tests
that your developers are creating that's
testing just the smallest unit of work
all the way down to Long running system
tests at the bottom and they had
38,000 long running system tests and a
very small number of of of unit tests at
the top so their pyramid was the wrong
way up right so what they did was they
spent a whole bunch of time money and
effort flipping that pyramid round and
working through moving all of those
tests to fast slick Automation and they
got from 24 to 48 hours to find out
whether something is wrong all the way
down to 3 and 1 half minutes to run the
their entire test infrastructure locally
um on the developer workstation so you
close those feedback loops you shorten
those Cycles manual is the longest cycle
anything manual whether it's deployments
whether it's testing anything manual is
is prone to mistakes so you get false
positives and negatives but it also
takes time it's timec consuming and it's
costly I oh I worked with an organ
organization years ago that's the only
organization I've ever encountered like
this so it is unusual it's an outlier
but they had twice as many testers as
coders their quality was so bad in their
software that they had to do I think it
was n and a half thous hours of manual
QA to validate whether any change the
developers had made would actually work
in the system so they had 600 testers
and 300 coders um in their teams and
that it was all manual tests and that is
just
unsustainable think of the cost of
having all of those people versus having
fast tight
secure easy to understand easy to Val
automation that could run and check your
software on a regular Cadence you will
build more
features you will build those features
with a higher level of quality so you'll
have happier customers and if you're
building more features you're having
happier customers you're doing more
experiments right because you're
building more features you're more
likely to open out new markets and
you're more likely to make a profit