so I just got asked if I had a basic
blog post for installing um TFS 2013 I
realized that I hadn't really done a
basic out of the box install and since
probably 2010 most of the time I've been
doing upgrades so on my Surface I'm
going to create a new virtual
machine and I already have a domain
controller running
now we need to set this um at a minimum
of 248 for memory I'm going to use
dynamic memory so I only use as much as
I need once the machine's running and
but TFS does a check for the amount of
memory in a machine and and if this
isn't set to 2048 will not be able to
install TFS so that's the minimum you
need but it can be actually like L based
on dynamic
memory
private let me select now I'm going to
use a Windows Server 2012
R2 there we
go so I'm going to start this machine
well I just going to connect to it and
then start
it now this is just going to do a a
basic vanilla install of
windows I will need to go and get a
key let me do that while we're
waiting
oh
awesome so I'm just going to use um
Windows Server
2012 R2 standard
and paste in my
key there we go so we don't want our
core installation TFS is not currently
supported on core um it mostly works
there's just a couple of things that
don't particular around build servers um
so I'm going to pick with a
guey now I obviously can't upgrade it's
a blank install so and I just do that
there we go that's going to copy the uh
files do the install uh reboot and that
will get
going so now that we have it
installed wait it's just took a minute
not time to go and get a coffee
so that's me logging in for the first
time yep and now I can get a proper
resolution
awesome if you're using Windows
8.1 and uh uh server uh 2012 R2 you get
this enhanced session mode that allows
you to not only copy paste uh but set
the resolution a little bit more nicely
and all kinds of stuff been
so if you've used server or server uh
any of the newer server
versions We fig a
minute you will
know that it just picks a random
computer name and you have to change it
so I don't really want that as the
computer
name so I'm going to change
that
btar and I'm going to have to reboot
that uh
first before I do anything
else give it a
sec
go so now we have a machine Co
btar let me just check settings and
everything think the network
is ah see I've just got it set as
private and One
processor change that over to
Wi-Fi but I will need private as well
okay so let me just
quickly
uh's shut this
down there we go change the
settings I'm going to get two processors
I'm going to
add a network
adapter private Network there we
go that should make it one run a little
bit
faster and uh to be able to connect
to private
Network awesome
okay I need to set up my private
Network and
these let me just do
okay so now I have that set up I should
be able to change my work
group to in. nm.com should
my domain
should find my
[Music]
domain
um we should be good I want to do the
install on a domain cuz that's more uh a
better example of what people would do
in the field uh most people don't
install TFS in a work group so um that's
what I'm going to
do just give that a minute to join
there we
go and we just need to do a quick
restart and then we can install TFS
perfect now all we need to do is install
TFS so let me insert my TFS
dis this is just the RTM of a team
Foundation
server so this is a completely blank
server we've just joined it to a domain
we don't have anything else installed on
it and you may want to install SQL
Server to get the full version of uh of
SQL server and TFS actually includes a
license for SQL Server standard and so
you can just install that and you don't
need an additional license as long as
it's only used for TF
but I'm just going to continue with
Express and TFS will install at SQL
Express as part of the the installation
once we got get to the configuration
part so and the first part of the TFS
installation just gets all the files on
disk registers all of the the the dlls
and does all of those um local piec that
you need to do but it's not going to um
install any of the third party tools
it's not going to configure anything yet
we're going to do that in a minute there
we go in just a few minutes it's
installed TFS I'm just going to do a
trial install just now let me activate
that there we
go and I get my standard installation
wizard now there's a number of options
here um the standard server and if you
want to use default instance of SQL
Server um but this will not work for uh
um SQL
Express and won't configure reporting
services and the reporting pieces for
you we have a advanced where you can
configure um all of the the SQL Server
databases SharePoint um SQL server and
ala Services Services all those pieces
very easily and I'm actually just going
to take a basic install so this is going
to install Express it's going to um
configure work atem tracking build
Services Source control all of those
things are going to be configured for us
and up and running at the end and but we
won't have um anything else we won't
have SharePoint integration we won't
have reporting Services integration and
and we can't do any kind of nonstandard
configurations with this mode so let me
just start
Wizard and the first thing it's going to
do is going to install
Express and it's going to go in away and
check my system and make sure
everything's running okay so this is
going to check for prerequisites it's
going to check to make sure that it can
install stuff there can always be
something extra that goes wrong but it
does a pretty good job of checking the
system requirements so you can see
everything's okay it's also going to
install uh IIs fancy name for I um and
make sure everything's good so if I
click configure it's going to go off and
do that it will take a few minutes
specifically for cons configuring IIs
installing um SQL Express will take a
little bit longer than everything else
um but it should only take a few
minutes awesome so we've got an
install it's complete and we can just go
to
hopefully I like we need to log
in a tap
[Music]
there we go connected to
TFS I currently have one collection with
no team
projects so I will need to set that up
but I don't have real to do on here so I
will do that later and there you go
installing configuring TFS very
straightforward um on a basic server
configuration