um that's a really good question what's
the most interesting outcome
because it can be interesting good and
it can be interesting bad right I I have
had the expedience
um we'll start with the interesting part
right or it depends how you look at it
it depends how you look at it it could
also be interesting Goods right
um but I had this experience with a
company in the United States that was a
very old-school type of company
uh put it this way the the the the the
the the cubes
uh if you're not familiar with the way
things work in the US you often have
these uh cubicles with partitions
temporary partitions around each desk
where you've got a finite amount of
space and that's yours and they're quite
high so you don't hear other people but
there's big big cubicle thing and the
cubicles had awk paneling
that's that's how how old school this
this organization was and how much how
much money was going around and one of
the problems with organizations with
huge amounts of cash flow and huge
amounts of cash to throw around is that
they're not that interested in change
right because change is risk and if we
have a huge Cash Cow that we're milking
then then why should we change and
potentially risk that that cash cow
um which is why Ken kench Weber talks
about the the time to go into an
organization and affect change is when
they've most egregiously failed to
deliver something right that's when
people are most open to change
but uh in this organization
um I did a whole bunch of of sessions uh
it was was kind of devops and agile it
was all homegrown it wasn't it was
probably prior to doing a lot of stuff
with a lot more stuff with scrumdorg
um but I managed to convince the 30
people in it leadership and management
that
um this agile and devops thing is a
great idea we need to move towards
continuous delivery we need to move
towards inspecting and adapting causing
the feedback loops Gathering data
figuring out what's going on so this
this
it was totally sold on this idea
um and then I I heard about the
like eight months later maybe a year
later
um I heard about that engagement and
they were all gone from that
organization they'd all been they'd all
effectively been fired because the
organization had decided not to go that
way anymore so as an organization we're
not going to do Agile we're not going to
do continuous delivery we're going to do
the same thing we've always done and
they kicked up a fuss right because
they're like well no that's not not good
we're gonna have these problems we're
gonna have huge amounts of technical
debt we're gonna have potential failures
going down the line and they were enough
of a problem that that they were gotten
rid of right so that's kind of
negative but I don't know if you think
about it it's probably those folks went
on to better jobs to more advantageous
organizations that are trying to do
things a little bit differently and
perhaps they had a better outcome for
for most of those folks so that was a
big negative one
um that's probably the most the most
negative one that that I've seen and
that was an unusual circumstance right
you don't see that sort of thing
happening that often
um but the other one uh the most
positive positive one
uh was training for one of my favorite
favorite organizations at the time which
is actually in Utah which is a crazy
place but it was in Utah and um it was
for a company called back country and
back country where our clothing kind of
clothing manufacturer clothing uh ski it
was where um you know where the the
Olympics were held at one time in in
Utah and you know basically from their
office you can see the the ski jump and
all the things that are around that and
they trained
um everybody in their company
so there was a really interesting
organization because there were less
than 100 people in the whole company and
48 of them were software engineers
so this is a clothing company why do
they have 48
of their company being nearly 50 of the
company being software Engineers
um and it was that they built and ran
their own procurement software
so their their software that they use to
get the stuff to to to to to to organize
the factories in in China that were
making making the apparel get all the
apparel across into the US and get it
distributed in the US they're different
warehouses and then you get to get it
sent out to individuals because they ran
their own points of sale as well they
had five or six different storefronts
that were all their brands and they also
had not only their clothes but other
competitors clothes on their own website
as well
that was all their own kit right they
built all the software the guy driving
around the warehouse with an iPad
attached to his uh a forklift telling
him which pallets to go get and pick up
and what trucks to put them on they
wrote the whole thing right
um so that's why they needed so many
software Engineers but it was hugely
effective for them
um so what we did was we did scrum
training we did the applying
professional scrum it was called
professional scrum foundations back in
the day it was actually my first ever uh
uh uh classes of that type that I that I
ran
um and there were very big classes there
was like 45 people per per class which
is which is pretty big I normally max
out at 25 now
and they trained everybody in the
company the CEO was in one of the
classes the CEO's secretary assistant
was in one of the classes the guy who
drives the forklift in the warehouse was
in one of the classes
and even things like the guy who drives
the forklift in the warehouse after the
first half day and went to his
management and said uh what what the
heck am I doing here obviously he drives
a forklift in the warehouse so I'm using
the polite version of the way he would
say it right what the heck am I doing
here this is of no value whatsoever
um can I just go back to to doing my
doing my work
and um you know his managers like oh
just just stick it out for today and if
you still have the same story at the end
of today then then you can you don't
have to go tomorrow right but but the
end of the first day he was the one uh
kind of standing up uh pointing at the
board with the team talking about the
different uh uh uh uh items on the
backlog and how they could add more
value
because he had an epiphany he had this
realization of the connection between
the feedback he can give
and the product that's then created
so he realized that he was uniquely
positioned to provide major influence to
the way the software worked for him to
better support the success of the
organization and it was this
I need to be involved in this I need to
be a part of this story and that was
that was just
fantastic uh thing to see and and hear a
little bit more to the story than than
that but I still get emails from people
in that organization and that's what
that would be 12 years later I still get
emails from people in the organization
saying it was a complete game changer
for the organization that experience and
I I can't take ownership of that right
they took ownership of that it was
can you imagine
everybody in the organization goes
through this training this training is
so important that the CEO says I'm going
to spend two full days sitting in a room
with all of these people and demonstrate
even if they know all the stuff already
I'm going to sit here and demonstrate to
everybody in the room how important this
is how important it is to our strategy
going forward
that for me is is leadership right
um and that that just that was the most
amazing
um class I've ever been a part of and
then going forward into the future uh
their CIO has called me in to do
additional training with them at
healthgrades which you can see some
videos on my YouTube from the folks at
healthgrades
um I've uh uh people have gone off to
work at Coca-Cola which I've done
training for
um yeah it's been that was a great
experience for for me for them and for
their organization
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility