your definition of done affects your
bottom line It's not just a checklist
It's not just technical standard Done is
strategic A strong definition of done
means faster time to value It means
lower risk It means real agility not
just faster sprints When teams
constantly deliver increments that are
live usable gathering telemetry and
validating outcomes you don't just move
faster you make smarter bets you adapt
quicker you grow stronger At Naked
Agility we help organizations connect
their definition of done directly to
business impact Because done isn't about
getting through the work It's about
making work matter Want to make Dun a
weapon for growth not just a process
let's talk