as you change the demands you're putting
on the product you're going to have to
change the architecture of the product
in order to support the new demands that
you're putting on it so investing in uh
the the the time and effort for the
teams to be able to work towards those
outcomes and we're not talking about
we're not going to deliver any new
features because we're trying to do this
we're talking about enabling them to do
a little piece at a time um the the the
the Azure devops team had uh some
architectural changes they needed to
make in their test infrastructure in
order to reduce their time to Market and
to completely clear off the old test
infrastructure took four years right
we're not talking about shorter time
frames we're talking about long-term
products that exist in the market