oh that's a that's a great question why
why is a scrum team better served by an
agile consultant rather than a
professional coach
um I think professional coaching within
the context of a specialist task
has its has its limits right it kind of
professional coaching is is great but it
makes the Assumption which in many
circumstances is the correct assumption
that the people that you're coaching
understand already understand how to
solve the problems that they need to
solve and and that's just not
fundamentally the case uh for almost all
organizations and teams that at least
that I work with
um once teams are up to speed and
heading in the right direction then we
might want to focus on more uh a more
cultural Focus but certainly early on
and certainly if teams aren't yet able
to continuously create usable working
working product in a regular Cadence
they need to know what they don't know
which means that uh an agile consultant
or an agile coach is spending more of
their time in a teaching or mentoring
stance where they're helping those teams
understand what they don't know or
perhaps
um
knowing to look where they don't know
right I mean that that that's the the
fundamental problem with
um having an agile coach that doesn't
have a deep technical understanding of
the the work that is underway and and I
I by technical understanding I don't
mean that they can they can go rock up
next to the developer and code and then
go sit next to the devops guy and point
out where he's doing his builds wrong
right that's not what I mean I mean a a
deep Technical and philosophical
understanding of the processes practice
these tools capabilities the the
direction the the what what are the
things that great teams do out in the
world that other teams don't that are to
do with their engineering practices
right if we're talking about a software
team you need to be able to understand
um what what what is what is devops what
are the components that make up devops
why is devops successful how do you
convince a team that they should be
doing some of those things how do you
have conversations with of themes about
continuous delivery if they're not doing
it and perhaps the teams say oh we can't
do that here right
um how do you have those conversations
allay those fears within the
organization to enable that for those
teams so that those teams are then able
to make that choice now they understand
that it's valuable they can't just make
the choice you need to help out with the
organization help convince people that
this is the right direction
um and that's even before you've tackled
any of those ideas around
um how how you know people's people
feeling happy being safe you you they
need to be able to to do their do their
job as well so I feel like for agile
consulting or even agile coaching
the vast majority of the work uh that
they that they do that they focus on is
around these technical things scrums are
while scrum itself is not technical it's
just a bit of knowledge that you learn
right all of the practices and Tools
around making it successful are deeply
technical
um are you able to sit with uh with a
group of product owners or or product
management and help them understand
uh impact mapping and how impact mapping
can help them and help coach them in
doing that technical task right which is
creating the impact map those are all
things that I would expect an agile
coach slash consultant to be able to do
now I've named some specific things
right like impact mapping you definitely
don't have to know them all right
because there's hundreds of thousands of
these things but you need to know you
need two things you need to know enough
to know where to look right that's
that's that's that's what the first part
if you've got enough experience and you
know where different tools and
techniques have helped in the past you
can then go read up on that tool and
technique and because you already
understand all of the foundational
Concepts and constructs you're able to
to bring that into your Lexicon your
capability a lot more quickly and then
engage with the team and help them or
our group of people and help them figure
out how to actually do that particular
particular thing and it can be a
learning opportunity for you as well
deep technical expertise in the
fundamental principles of agile and lean
and devops doesn't mean you know how to
do all of the things it means you have
the tools and skills to be able to learn
and communicate all of those things
regardless of the environment that
you're that you're that you're dropped
into right yeah
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility