so the question is what is my primary
role in a devops Consulting geek
and I think that's a difficult question
to answer without the context because I
find it depends very heavily on on where
the customer is what they're trying to
do what they hired you for and what
their problem is
but if maybe quantifying that that that
primary goal as to to provoke the
customer
into thinking about
how the
manage and deliver the work that they do
and how their this the system that they
have in place that delivers that work
and can be disrupted for their benefit
right
so devops is is about optimizing that
flow of value
from idea all the way through to to to
the to to the to the customers of that
product and then and then closing that
feedback loop right getting that
feedback back into the system
so what what is it that's getting in the
way of that find find the thing that's
taking the longest in that process and
go poke at it and pick at it and that
could be
um a technical Focus right a tool issue
the the all the builds are taking 24
hours to do all the testing well that's
too long right how do we go go fix that
or that could be a people problem uh
this this this uh approval needs to
happen but the person who does the
approval only does it once every uh two
weeks so if you if if you get the timing
wrong right you're just waiting for that
approval in order to be able to close
that feedback loop that's just waste
that's wasted time so how do you find
those things so I think that would be my
my focus
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility