one of the ghosts it's actually two of
the ghosts of agile past are the three
questions you might have heard of the
three questions in relation to the Daily
scrum what did I do yesterday what am I
doing today and What's blocking me or
you might be thinking of the
retrospective what went well what didn't
go well what do we need to to to change
right or um there's various Renditions
of the three questions CU three must be
a good number U but the reality is that
if you've got a scrum team and you do
the three questions once maybe a couple
of times either at your your daily or at
your Sprint review then that's probably
okay right there's nothing fundamentally
wrong with the three questions but what
is
dysfunctional what is that ghost of
agile past is when the three questions
become the purpose of the daily or the
purpose of the retrospective and you'll
see that on teams they'll come into the
daily scrum and they will um go into
autopilot it becomes a rote procedure
for them to follow that they each need
to answer the three questions and you'll
perhaps see the project manager sorry
scrum Master writing down the answers to
those three questions so they can go
update their project plan that is not
the purpose of the daily certainly not
the purpose uh of the Retro with the
other three questions you need to be
focused on the value that we're
delivering and is that value moving
towards the outcome that we're trying to
achieve we're trying to be successful at
delivering on the Sprint goal and
potentially other stuff in the Sprint um
and are we making progress towards that
are we are we blocked with that as a
group so what I tend to see as a more
eff way to move forward is for teams to
focus on the value in the Sprint we we
don't need to hear from everybody right
if Bob is working on the same task for
three days in a row it's boring to hear
from Bob and really adds no value there
might be a good reason why Bob is stuck
on that task for three Sprints in a row
right but that or three days in a row
but that doesn't mean that's how we want
to um uh surface that during the the the
the Sprint the daily scrum because most
people in the room don't really care
right it's not part of their uh uh uh uh
thought process but what you could do is
focus on the value that's being
delivered what is the next most
important piece of value that we need to
deliver how are we doing with it well uh
Bob and Brenda and Billy are all working
together on this item and Brenda
provides uh an update for the for the
team on how how we're doing on that
right as as a group how are we doing
that might be a better way to proceed
you've just one person spoken one piece
of value and three people are uh have
been working together on that particular
item or perhaps um focusing on the value
you might be thinking about which of
these items on the board have not
moved in a long time right what are we
forgetting in our daily that's something
to look at how old are these eyes
something getting too old on this board
uh you've maybe seen if you Google uh
banana peel uh uh uh daily um work item
aging with with banana peels you'll see
a board with stickies on it and bananas
actual real banana peels stuck to it um
and the more Brown the banana peel gets
the more fruit flies there are flying
around uh than the older that item has
been and let's deal with it before the
fruit flies come out now that's just an
arbitrary silly visual indication but
the reality is the longer things are
stuck in your
system the longer things are stuck there
the longer they're going to take right I
I mean I'm the the exponentially longer
they're going to take the longer they're
in there um and that's based on the data
right you can go collect that data look
at that data monitor the flow through
your system and you'll see that um very
much happening things that get stuck
tend to get stuck um and if you don't
have clear rules on uh as a team right
our team's way of working if you don't
have a clear consensus on what do we do
about those things uh quite often they
just get left and because they get left
you end up getting to the end of the
Sprint and there's things you haven't
done and things that haven't moved and
things that get left behind because
we're not focusing on maximizing the
value that we're delivering as a team
and that is a ghost of agile past the
three questions creating dysfunctional
Behavior where we're not focusing on
value
delivery if you are being haunted by
these go posts of agil past we can help
exercise them or help you find a
consultant coach or trainer that can
don't let these Phantoms undermine the
effectiveness of your value delivery and
the longer they linger the more they
will haunt your team's progress send me
an email to Martin nkd agility tocom and
we'll help you get to the bottom of it
if you want to have a discussion about
your unique needs or situation then
please book a call or visit us at naked
agility tocom uh we also have our
immersive and traditional public classes
on our website and we'd love to hear
from you