professional scrum Master immersive
learning experience is is is unique
because it
enables that um double Loop learning
that you get from being able to try
things in your
organization and then take take that
information collaborate with others like
like what happened during that
collaboration um bring it all together
with a group of people who are all
trying to do the same thing and then um
figure out what you can do differently
right how do I make this thing that I
was doing even just a little bit better
and I and I think there's there's two
there's a really big advantage in the
the PSM because as a public class
because you've got a bunch of people in
the class that are from other
organizations while you you might come
along and you might bring a friend from
your organization cuz that's always a
good way to to
um to get help when you're back in your
organization as well right having
somebody else who's been through the
same experience uh but also you get um
the different perspectives of the people
in the room um and that is absolutely
invaluable to enabling you as a scrum
Master to understand what what what is
realistic and what isn't right a lot of
folks come to um a PSM class especially
thinking as we're talking about the
stuff in the class thinking that that
just won't work here right that won't
work in my company it won't work in my
company because we do this other thing
not realizing and hopefully they do
throughout the class but not realizing
that that scrum is intended to be a
mirror that shows you what what's wrong
with your organization like why can't
you do that oh we want to do um
continuous feedback loops right we want
to at the end of every Sprint we want to
get some real users in front of the
software and we want to find out what
they think about it right we want to
validate our assumptions well why can't
we do that and I think the immersive
learning is especially focused on that
because it's over a much longer period a
time because you have those sections of
learning and then that assignment to go
and try something in your organization
and those assignments are kind of
crafted around those most difficult
ideas um most difficult things to do in
applications Mo in in applications in in
your company most
difficult contentious gnarly problems
that scrum Masters encounter um in their
organizations so that we can collaborate
and get help from each other right I as
the facilitator might have seen a bunch
of uh um experiences right in in
organizations where um those things have
worked out perfectly or I might have
seen other ones where things you want to
try um just fell flat right there's no
right answer to any of these questions
so how do we collaborate around it and
how do we maximize that collaboration
and I think uh the PS M immersive class
maximizes the learning and collaboration
that happens if you want to have a
discussion about how immersive classes
can revolutionize your training
experience then please book a call on
our website alternatively you can find
all of our public immersive classes
listed there as well and we would love
to hear from you