momentum is is movement right you're
you're moving in a particular direction
and you have enough
stuff moving in that direction that that
it's difficult to stop right that for me
is momentum like a ship uh when a ship
puts on the brakes and it takes 10 miles
to stop right so so momentum especially
in product delivery is does does
everybody who's working with you
understand the direction that you're
going so that they're going in that
direction and they're going to pull
other people along with them who don't
necessarily understand as well as some
people do so if you've got enough people
moving in that direction in order to
pull in the rest of the people and folks
that you need and this is true for I'm
building a product or I'm changing an
organization or