deployment frequency can serve as a as a
leading indicator of your company's
ability to
reduce the time to
Market I think there's a lot of metrics
in that space that you probably want to
look at because it's pretty it's pretty
it's pretty
difficult like you could deploy really
frequently to a test environment and
that has no bearing on your ability to
to deploy to production right you're
deploying stuff to a test environment is
breaking all the time so that metric on
its
own is is not going to it's not going to
just tell you that you're going to be
awesome right that's absolutely not true
there are a number of things that you
can look at but your ability to deploy
to an environment and the speed with
which you can deploy to an environment
and let's assume that that environment
is stable is stable so measure that as
well right the stability of that that
environment that that would be a a
reasonable indication if we had a stable
environment we're continuously
delivering to that we should be able to
get stuff into production right deliver
it to the market much more quickly very
quickly right but then you need to look
at what gets in the way I I I have
there's a little formula that I think it
works really well I've seen it work
organizations I know it's not my formula
it's it's I think it's a fairly logical
thing but look look at your entire uh
pipeline from ideation coming up with
ideas to go into your
product all the way through to getting
in front of your your customers and
closing the feedback loop right so
you're you're collecting data and
Telemetry on how that feature is used
being used how performant it is those
kind of things and then having it
feedbacks so that that whole Loop is
your time to learn right and that
is your your I'm not going to say it's
the only not your largest might it's the
largest one I'm going to talk about just
now your largest feedback loop right but
that has lots of little things that
happen in between so if you look at your
time to learn and figure out how long it
takes you can find the thing in that
time to learn that is taking the long
longest amount of time and go tackle
that go make it shorter go fix it and
then once you've fixed that thing right
you've collapsed it into something much
faster much sleeker look for what what's
the next the next Blocker in your in
your in getting your time to learn down
to a a manageable size but the question
then begs the question what is a
manageable size of of of time to learn
and as any quantity question as much as
you need and no
more making those
things faster than you need might have
an additional
cost so maybe focus on how quickly do
you need to be able to get things into
production how quickly do you need that
to maintain the existing customers how
do you fast do you need to be able to do
that to M to to get new customers right
because your your potentially your sales
team is going to be promising things to
customers and then you have to come back
around and and build them and because
they've been promised there's an
expectation don't have train your sales
team not to promise stuff but there
might be an expectation and if there's
an expectation of a feature then you
need to ship something within that
context as quickly as possible Right to
start building on that expectation
building trust otherwise you start
eroding trust because there's an
expectation that's not not fulfilled so
this is this is one of the quandaries of
the the delivery manager how fast we
need to go and there's definitely a
school of thought that faster is better
right even if your business doesn't need
or isn't demanding to be able to change
faster to be able to do things faster if
we're able if we in
Engineering in building the product are
able to shorten those feedback loops as
much as possible we can iterate on it we
can use that data we can get little
changes in front of real customers as
quickly as possible and then we can
monitor the Telemetry we can see how
we've impacted performance we can see
Live error messages coming through or or
or live Telemetry live performance live
eror messages and then be able to do
something about it and make little
little tweaks to get things right um and
I think that's the important thing when
when the outcomes that we're trying to
achieve are so complex right not
only how we achieve the outcome there's
a lot of
unknowns what the outcome's going to be
there's a lot of
unknowns and what we're going to
discover along the way there's a lot of
unknowns there's so many unknowns if we
get that loop as tight as possible we
can deal with surprises right when
something goes wrong we can deal with it
we can make a change we can ship it we
can make a change we can ship it that
didn't work we can make another change
and ship it right we can we can iterate
on that and when the business comes
along with an opportunity which they
invariably will right they're going to
come along and say this massive
opportunities come along and they're not
going to say it like that right they're
like oh my God I need this feature I
need it right now it need I need to ship
it tomorrow
right if you are shipping once every
Sprint shipping once every two or 3
weeks that's not an impossible task to
add something and ship it within a few
days but it's going to be fraught with
risk and danger right risk and danger
because if you're doing something that
you've not done before and you have to
get it out quicker than you're used to
doing it before there's lots of points
failure in that
story if you as a as an engineering team
if you're a delivery manager and you
have a team or a bunch of teams a
product or a bunch of products if
they're able to continuously ship to
production so they're doing continuous
delivery to to real
users
then this opportunity comes along we add
some capability it ships we add some
capability at ships we build on that
capability at ships we get that much
tighter iterative cycle and if that
feature is this big how much of this
feature is required in order for sales
of the business to advertise start
advertizing that that that feature start
leveraging that feature in the in the
market right maybe you only need a very
small amount maybe you can do a couple
of days of work and ship it and then
that feature is there and they can start
adverti marketing it getting value from
it and then you're building on that as
users start using it and you see how
they're using it you can focus on what
it is you you you need as you go so
so this confluence I think
of product
development and delivery of that product
is absolutely critical in order
for us to maximize the value that the
business gets that that the business
creates um and in order to do that we
have to have we there has to be extreme
trust not only between us and the
business but between us and the customer
and it's not the business and the
customer it's us and the customer
because the customer knows that the
business doesn't ship the product they
know that we ship the product right
engineering ships the product so when
it's not the right thing they're blaming
the business when it's poor quality
they're complaining to the business that
we suck right that's that's pretty much
what happens so if we can get rid of
that problem then the only problem is
what are we going to go build and if
we're in we're in a position engineering
is in a position to help provide all of
the data for the business to be able to
make a determination on on what it is
they build and what they don't and
that's our job that's pretty much our
job we need to help the business make
those decisions and give them as much
information as they need in order to
make those decisions effectively and
that means collecting Telemetry that
means being able to continuously ship to
production that means en enabling the
ability that when a opportunity for the
business arises that we are able to
deliver on that opportunity faster than
our competitors