foreign
2023 is predicted to be a very tough
year what do you think will be needed to
win and improve
in 2023
businesses need to be more astute
than they are now I I work with
organization after organization that
have
no idea what their cohesive corporate
strategy is they have no idea what level
of quality they really want in the
products that they create
um and they have no idea
of what is really needed in to
understand what it is we need to we need
to build and addressing those things
is going to make the difference between
being successful in 2023 and being
unsuccessful in 2023 the the organizer
there's quite often a fine line between
businesses being profitable and
businesses not being profitable and it
can be very small things that that make
that difference between profit
profitability and not and if you're
Building Products that are delivered in
a market where there is lots of choice
then you have to be more attractive than
your competitors to your customers
um and if you're slow at delivering what
customers are asking for if you're
um don't have all the features
that they're looking for in in that
particular Market if you're
um
losing
your skilled employees because they're
unhappy
right and taking their Knowledge and
Skills elsewhere perhaps to your
competitors
then you're not going to be successful
if if the market is hard right if
everybody's under hardship those that
are going to be successful are the ones
that are investing in people
and investing in their ways of working
if your ways of working are more
effective than your competitors you'll
be successful
um
I think that's
an
that's that's really what it is you need
you need to be more effective than your
competitors and
scrum and kanban are tools that you can
use to highlight through data right
visualization of data the current state
of what's going on in some of those
spaces so that you can look at it and
know what what you need to improve
so
the big things to to invest in product
ownership is hugely lacking in
organizations most organizations have
have no idea what a product backlog
should look like they've it's yeah it's
just
no idea what it what no idea how to
analyze their Market that their business
exists in
um and they need people in their
organization that can do that and those
folks aren't going to magically be able
to do it they need they need training
right they need to they need training
and they need practice
um and that's that's one of the reasons
that we offer an extra hour of
coaching right 60 Minutes of one-on-one
coaching for every student because I
know how so difficult it is you come and
take our product owner product owner
class and then three months later you've
got all these questions and no way to
get answers because your business won't
fund uh uh a one-hour coaching session
with the trainer you had three months
ago so we just include it in the process
and and and in fact if
man if people just wanted a chat I've
Got Away on my website to book 30
minutes book a coffee with Martin right
and just have a chat about product
ownership about how to get more out of
it how it's actually just product
management Right add your product
management and the product owner is the
same thing
um and how do you leverage those
capabilities that that scrum can enable
for your business or kanban as well can
enable for your business
um I
to get better
at delivering value
that's going to be the big difference
are we delivering value to our customers