I think that that Dogma really has no no
place in a Consulting engagement
um it actually has no no place anywhere
right Dogma has no place anymore
anywhere
um but there there is a place for being
pedantic
um when you're in training right because
you're trying to learn something here's
the way this thing is supposed to be but
when you're actually implementing inside
of organizations when you're actually
talking about talking to people and
engaging with them when they're trying
to do their jobs there's no place for
pedanticism
even a word either it's about being
pragmatic and empirically adapting our
processes to the changing demands of the
business that's it