really common mistake that agile
consultants make is just being cultures
and being a coach assumes that the
customer already knows and understands
what they need to do differently in
order to be successful and that is
definitely not always the case
um quite often if you're Consulting you
need to teach you might even need to
dictate right say do this differently
and try it differently you're definitely
going to be giving options right you're
definitely going to be suggesting
different ways to do things and helping
encourage those different ways and
organizations
um
the other way is going to make you more
money because you're going to be there
for longer but being a consultant is
about helping the customer not just
making money