most
organizations that I
encounter really suffer
from Miss deadlines and budget overruns
for their software projects it's
probably the most common issue uh that I
see happening happening in organizations
and it can be really unpredictable you
can you can think that you've got this
one in the bag but it just the bag melts
and it starts dropping out the bottom
all over the all over the street this is
something that is a fundamental
reality of the world of complexity right
that the the what we we know is less
than what we don't know therefore we
have a high degree of
unpredictability and the
things the the what we we use to
mitigate that is effectively technical
leadership and Engineering Excellence
right we we we need our
Engineers to be building products that
are of a high enough quality that we can
pivot as needed at any moment and we
need our leadership within our
organization who have a controlling
interest in in the product right the
delivery to have enough of an
understanding of the technical technical
realities not just of doing the work but
of ideation and and futurism right what
are the possibilities for for this
product to be able to enable better
decisions to be made within the context
of the
product this and this is this is super
hard because we like to think that
there's one right way to do something
there's a best practice that's a fallacy
we like to think that all of we've hired
these awesome Engineers they just know
how to solve the problem and that can
quite often be a fallacy as well
so we we need tools and capabilities
around that to help us be be more
effective
so the the principles and philosophies
behind agile and
scrum those ideas of iterative
development of continuous delivery
continuous feedback continuous testing
pretty much anything with continuous in
front of it in in in the modern modern
software engineering space are those
things that will enable us to be more
effective to make better decisions to
encourage technical leadership and to
encourage engineering excellence