how does the aps course
help people apply scrum effectively
well it kind of helps in a number of
ways
so because it's a practical class
they get experience during the class
understanding what is Scrum why it works
and how it would work for them right so
you've you the people that are
participating in the class by the end of
let's say the the
um the second half a
um have a have a firm grasp of scrum and
there's still two more Sprints after
that ones are uh
um how would you describe it like uh
dysfunctional dysfunctional people
attributes Discovery session
um and then the one after that's a kind
of scaling session if we if we get to
that don't always get to that
um but the
the last part of the class that we do
after we've done all of those those
things is we've kind of got got two two
main exercises one is a choice and the
other ones we I kind of always do
the choice one is is this a group of
people who have been doing scrum already
um and if they've been doing scrum
already then we do like a scrum tune-up
exercise
where they're effectively doing a
diffing exercise between the scrum they
just learned and the scrum they're doing
in their organization
so do a kind of diffing exercise kind of
what's different how they feel about
those changes get get that information
down we have a little uh exercise around
that the other option for that one is if
they've not been doing scrum uh then we
have a scrum startup exercise and in the
scrum startup exercise they're they're
you know who's going to be your product
owner who's going to be your scrum
master and where are you going to store
your backlog
how are you going to manage it just to
get them started and thinking about how
that's going to work in their
organization so those those two things
alone it's one or the other I don't do
both
um is is really good
but then the last one of the last
exercises that I do with groups is
creating uh organizational change
backlog
because the the people that know most
about how organizations need to be
different
in doing agile other people that are
actually doing the work that are
struggling within the bounds of the
processes that the organizations created
so by asking them to create that
organizational change backlog or add
things to the organizational change
backlog and they're thinking about all
the things that affect them
whereas when leadership adds things to
the organizational change backlog
they're probably thinking about things
that affect them right and they're
proxying the things that affect other
people what they think is going to be a
problem for other people
but when you get the people that have
just gone through this scrum class scrum
class and they realize what needs to be
different they start adding all sorts of
things to the class and sometimes
sometimes it's you know they'll add we
need more people trained in this so that
more people understand what it is we're
talking about that's always good for me
right
um but most of the time they're adding
things like well we've got this policy
in the organization this needs to change
or leadership's not engaged enough in
the story that we're trying to create
this needs to change
and it's very enlightening for
leadership if they're attending and I do
recommend that
um the time when I've seen the aps be
most effective
um I did a class for a number of classes
for a company in the US called back
country
there are clothing apparel uh ski type
place in Utah and we trained everybody
in the company from the CEO all the way
down to the to the guy who drives the
forklift in the warehouse was fantastic
and what was really interesting was the
guy that drives a forklift in the
warehouse at the end of the first half
day we did two full days for the class
but the end of the first half day he
went to his boss and said by the why the
hell am I here I don't want to be here
what is this crap you're having me learn
I don't see why it's valuable for me can
I just go back to driving my forklift in
the warehouse
uh but by the end of that day
he was the one standing at the board
engaging with the team uh asking them
questions or do we have this do we have
that how would this work because he
started to realize
how
the work that these Engineers were doing
that he didn't have any connection with
before he started to understand how the
work that they were doing
affected his world
because he's driving the forklift in the
warehouse he's got an iPad attached to
the to the forklift that's telling him
where all the stuff is in the warehouse
and What needs to go in the truck and
what order he needs to get things out
and pack it and all of those kind of
things and they're the ones that are
writing that software and he happened to
have people at his table because we just
self-select into teams that were
responsible for some of the things that
directly affected him
so he understood why it was important
that he'd be part of that process why he
needed to engage in that process and it
brought another dimension he's the
customer was in the class right inside
of this company but even the view that
the people in the room had of the CEOs
sitting there
and the CEOs participating in the class
and actually focusing for two full days
on the class because he saw how
important it was
um to that discussion and then when
you're having that discussion at the end
the organizational change backlog what
needs to change who's in the room that
can deal with it the CEO is sitting
right there and can here's the
organizational change backlog this is
yours now you need to do something with
it and that that that
whole thing really helps now that's
different in a public class right you're
not going to get uh everybody in a
company in the public class but you get
quite a lot of the things that I've
talked about there all the way to that
point there's maybe not the Epiphany
moment at the end when you're creating
the organizational change backlog and
for the organization as a whole
um but it's still still a great
experience