so the question is what what's what's
the most common mistake or mistakes in
spin planning and let's start with the
purpose right
um Sprints planning's purpose is to plan
the Sprint
sounds reductive right but this purpose
is to plan the Sprint
um what I would expect to see happen
there
is that we we we're going to going to
um walk into Sprint planning
with an ordered well understood product
backlog as input we're probably already
going to have an idea of what your
Sprint goal is going to be right because
you know what your product goal is going
to be you've probably just discussed it
at your uh review
with your stakeholders and what's next
right
um and the team probably already has an
understanding of all the other work that
they're going to have to bring into the
Sprint as well as working on the Sprint
goal
so then the purpose of the Sprint is to
decide what it is we're doing how much
we think we can do
um and what what does that what does
that look like
so the one of the big mistakes that
teams make is is is not having
an ordered understood product backlog
walking into Sprint planning it is the
fundamental mistake that almost every
team that I that I work with
runs into at some point and that's that
um they're taking on work because
they're told to take on work not because
they actually understand that work
if you're a good good
um indication of this is if your team is
sitting doing planning poker during
Sprint planning you're doing it wrong
you should not
be sitting doing planning poker like we
don't understand this thing what is it
that's too late that's far too late if
you're if you walk into Sprint planning
and you pull something off the product
backlog and you're looking at it and the
team has never seen it before they've
got no clue what this thing is and they
suddenly realize that you need a
firewall change and all ops take six
weeks to implement a firewall change
you're just screwed already right you
can't bring that into this Sprint you
need to know about that six weeks ago
that's what refinement's for
refinement is where you push off the
understanding of the work that any any
estimation you want to do although
estimation's not required by scrum right
sizing right or the sizing you're going
to do the understanding of what's in
your product backlog all comes before
Sprint planning and when you walk into
Sprint planning it's a case of planning
the Sprint not planning all the stuff
that you should have planned already
before you got there right so that's
that's one of the biggest uh mistakes
that I see teams making is not already
understanding stuff I'm going to caveat
and say somebody will say uh uh but what
if we just received feedback uh from the
stakeholders at Sprint review and
there's a bunch of unknown stuff that
comes into Sprint planning awesome we're
gonna have a long Sprint planning this
Sprint right that's that's where we
might see uh planning poker or other
estimation techniques or whatever you
need in order to gain understanding
because some surprise happened right
there was a surprise
and we need to deal with that surprise
if every Sprint is a surprise they're
not doing it right right you're
absolutely not doing it right you need
you need to minimize the chance of
surprise I there are some products out
there where they get more surprises than
than other products that's cool right
roll with it it's what works best for
you you're trying to maximize your
Effectiveness as a team so we maximize
the value that we deliver to the
customer and for that we need to
understand the work that we're doing we
need to understand as best we can the
work that is coming towards us
so that when we get into Sprint planning
we can have a conversation about what
we're working on this Sprint right
that's what we're working on this Sprint
is what comes into Sprint planning and
ends up in your Sprint backlog and
that's what you're going to do
but during every Sprint you are also
working on refinement
you're also refining things in the
product backlog you're also gaining more
understanding of things that you don't
know yet
so when you're planning your Sprint you
also that's the other thing that teams
don't take into account you also need to
carve out how much time do we need to
spend understanding the surprises and
the unknown in the future
so that the next Sprint isn't going to
be on yet another surprise and the
Sprint after that isn't going to be yet
another surprise okay
that's why
doing too much is another thing the the
taking on too much in the Sprint right
because if you take on too much in the
Sprint you're like oh well we don't have
time to do all this refinement
right
because we're doing all this stuff and
we've taken on too much and we're really
struggling and we're having to cut
corners and we're really and then we get
to the next Sprint planning and we're
like oh
we don't understand anything that's in
our product back clock okay we're
screwed again okay we're gonna do the
same thing again and it's uh it's like a
death cycle you also find that teams
that end up in that position often don't
meet their Sprint goal so now they're
unhappy that they've not bet their
Sprint goal because that's supposed to
be a thing right so you've got a team
that continuously and repeatedly is
unable to meet the things that they've
been asked to commit to every single
Sprint how happy do you think that team
is going to be
not happy at all right
do happy
successful teams make great products or
do sad unhappy teams make great products
I would suggest that sad unhappy teams
do not make great products so you don't
want sad unhappy teams so stop creating
them stop building a situation
right here where you have these sad
unhappy teams because they're unable to
continuously and repeatedly unable to
meet the expectations that they're
setting for themselves but other people
are setting for them as well stop doing
that [ __ ] that's really bad right that I
mean that that's that's Sprint planning
is supposed to set that that purpose
that
um set the purpose for the Sprint why
are we doing this Sprint what are we
going to do how are we going to do it
right and you've already failed if you
walk into the Sprint and you don't know
the answer to most of those things
already
right other than surprises right which
I'm fully accepting you could walk into
a Sprint and uh great example of that is
Imagine imagine you were working on the
Microsoft teams team
right building Microsoft teams and you
walk into your first Sprint planning
after Lockdown from covid and you're
told immediately that we've just gone
from I don't know uh 150 000
simultaneous users to 500
000 simultaneous users practically
overnight and that our systems are
starting to crumble right that's where
you throw out everything you thought you
already knew and you're gonna start
again and perhaps they spent 90 of that
Sprint refining what's next and only a
little bit working on the stuff they can
right Sprint planning is all about
figuring out what it is you need to do
next but don't leave it too late get
your refinement in there first
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility