agile is hard and it's designed for
complex environments so as you would
expect there are many behaviors that
I've found in organizations that are
suboptimal to say the least here are my
seven deadly sins of
agile hi I'm Martin hinwood owner and
principal consultant at naked agility
I'm a professional scrum trainer with
scrum.org a professional cand trainer
with Pro caman and I've been a Microsoft
MVP in GitHub and Azure devops for 15
years one of the seven deadly sins of
agile is lust is is loads of
organizations are um talking
about agile transformation
digital
transformation whatever
transformation they they want something
different because they've
realized that the markets have changed
right it's taken them a long time to
realize the markets have changed they
changed years ago right in fact 1930s
was when the market started to change
1970s they were totally changed and it's
taken until now for a lot of companies
to actually realize oh [ __ ] stuff's
changed what's going on right why why
isn't our old processes and systems uh
uh working so now they're looking around
for something new they've got that I was
going to say seveny year itch right but
it's the 70-year itch um and they're
looking around for new processes and
practices that they can use and they see
this agile thing doing really well and
they want it right they want they want
it desperately and they don't really
want to do the work for
it they just W to buy it I think there
must be a usism for that but I think
I'll stay away from it um they just want
to they just want to buy this thing they
don't want to actually spend the effort
and the time and the energy to figure
out what it means for them and their
business they just want somebody else to
come in and install it they just want to
pay somebody to come in and do it for
them right that's what they want to do
and that's why you see a lot of
organizations bringing in and you know
the big four Consulting companies you
see McKenzie and Accenture and Boston
Consulting Group coming in um giving
giving giving advice but the problem is
they're giving advice based on all of
these other big organizational
Transformations there is no precedent
within your organization for agile you
can't just look at what somebody else is
doing and lust after it and bring it
into your organization you need to build
your own unique way of doing things over
time and actually do the work to get
there and that's uh why you can't just
lust after this agile thing you need to
do the work to bring it into your
organization one of the seven uh deadly
sins of agile is gluttony and I see this
a lot um in teams where
their their their backlogs and their
products become
bloed um bloed and full of basically
just full of crap that needs to go right
so one one uh common um entry is is is
the product backlog if you if you go
into a a team you're working with a team
and you go to look at their product
backlog and there's let's say there's
six or seven people working on this team
and they have 5,000 things in their
product backlog they're doing it wrong
right there that's that's greedy they'
they've eaten all those backlog items
they're sitting in their belly and they
can't walk around they can't move
they're not going to be nimble right
they're not going to be agile because
it's it's almost impossible to
understand like what is our value what
value is in our product backlog diving
into that thing is just just not a good
idea right you you've get too much stuff
in your product backlog
another another way gluttony manifests
is during Sprint planning right shoving
more stuff into the Sprint backlog uh
than the team can possibly deliver in a
single Sprint and that continually
results in the team having to vomit uh
uh backlog items into the next Sprint
right if you think of it that way
perhaps teams will stop doing it um
taking on too much and then it spews
into the next Sprint and if it's if it's
one or two things that move into the
next Sprint and maybe not every Sprint
is probably okay right you're not going
to be successful in everything you do
but if you're constantly
got tons of things from a Sprint flowing
into the next Sprint flowing into the
next Sprint perhaps there's need to
consider um are we taking on too much
work um are we doing too much are we
taking on too much work work um so
that's that's the second second form of
of gney uh that I see in teams and the
third form is uh leaving stuff that
nobody uses in your
product right uh the Standish group uh
in Boston used to create the chaos
report every year and they analyzed
about 70,000 projects worldwide and they
found that only only 35% of the features
uh that we build are used by our
customers 65% I think the phrase was Ed
little if ever 65% use little if ever so
so hopefully we can stop building them
in the first place right that would be
great let's stop building them in the
first place but if we have built
them why are you keeping them in your
product why are you continuing to spend
maintenance hours support right how long
does your build take um how long your
build take if you remov 65% of the code
that's in your product right because
you've got rid of those features your
build would be faster your teams will be
able to work faster there's a less
complicated uh body of content you'll
just get better and faster at doing
doing doing things so the way to to to
ah man loads of teams just need a
gastric bypass for that right um how how
do you how do you restrict the the the
amount of um stuff that's in a in a
product that's really hard because it's
it's that's that's much harder than
backlog or Sprint backlog right um is to
figure out what percentage of the
features of your product are actually
used and the the worst is continuing to
invest in features that are of no use
right features that aren't used by your
customer cuz I guarantee you loads of
teams do that uh years years ago um I
worked with a a a a bank in
Boston and um they were absolutely
adamant that this 65% was crap and they
knew their customers way way better than
anybody else um and there's no way they
were they were wasting 65% it was a lot
less that's what they said so we we we
we said to them what's what's your
Flagship product that you build what's
the product that you think you know your
customers best and are building all the
awesome features like this one this
one's the best so we got in amongst the
code we added application insights app
insights is a an Azure uh uh feature
that can be plugged into any application
anywhere which basically collects data
so it supports all the programming
languages all the setups and you can out
of the box it does a bunch of stuff but
then if you add this is a feature right
and you can say if some how many times
do users click that button of our body
of users how many of them have clicked
that button you can get all of that data
and we analyzed their their their their
product uh end to end so we collected
data for 3 months um and then we went
back to them and said here's the 7 and a
half% of features that your customers
use all the rest was waste right um over
90% of the money they invested in their
product was waste and what was really
interesting was that more than 80% of
the items in their back clog at the
moment we're going towards additional
capabilities for features that weren't
used by their
customers right so
no don't don't don't eat the whole thing
right you've got to figure out how do I
pick and choose what I'm going to eat
don't eat the whole feature at once
right you don't know if you like haggus
yet so don't order a whole plate full um
get like a like a starter that's got a
little bit of haggus and try that first
and then obviously when you realize you
do like it um and your customers like it
then you can make more right but don't
don't over uh uh OV eat um on your
product backlog don't overeat in your
Sprint backlog and don't overeat in the
features in your
product so one of the civil and deadly
sins of agile is greed and this usually
manifest t s in um in
organizations by an overwhelming focus
on resource
utilization let's let's get rid of the
fact that we're calling everybody
resources as if they're cogs in a
machine rather than actual people right
but that focus on resource utilization
was a fantastic idea when we were
running
machines and machines could churn out
things on a regular Cadence and we were
able to the more your machine is running
the more value you're getting in return
for the the cost of the machine and the
cost to run it right um that's how you
would what where that re resource
utilization idea comes from but when you
start looking at people and how people
do work people need a a thinking time
people need uh um do things different
ways right if if we can automate stuff
that we do the same all the time but if
we're going to do something different
all the time which in my world
background as a software engineer
everything we coded was something new
otherwise we would have used an existing
framework right um so anytime you're
writing code you're doing something new
anytime you're building a product that
doesn't exist yet you're doing something
new that's never been done before right
so when you're doing those even if it's
been done before by somebody else it's
not been done before by you um and when
you're doing that uh you need to um give
people the space to be able to do things
well to be able to think about things to
be able to learn things to be able to
try things and that means that people
aren't always 100% focused on the work
that they're doing they they're they're
doing other things while thinking about
that work uh some examples Maybe um have
you ever uh been working on something
and got
stuck and the only way for you to get un
no matter how much time you spent on
this thing you were stuck right you're
100% utilized cuz you're working on this
thing
but you're not making any progress
you're not delivering any value but if
you just go uh go out for a walk right
or you sit with your wife and you
explain the problem to your I do this
all the time I explain some problem to
my wife and she doesn't necessarily
understand the problem that I've got
right I'm talking about code and
architectures and things and halfway
through explaining it I figured out what
my problem was right cuz I knew I just
didn't have a
moment to look to the side I don't know
if that makes sense like like an out of
body out of idea experience out body
experience and look at that thing from
the
outside um so that that resource
utilization is a fallacy uh when you're
talking about people um there's no such
thing as resource utilization you want
to be looking at flow efficiency and
value delivery how much value Are you
delivering to your customer and I
actually I don't care if my team members
are sitting around on their butts for
90% of the time as long as we're
delivering the value to the customer
right the value to the customer is the
important thing is the customer happy
are we getting an adequate return on
investment for our product those are the
ideas uh that make sense um I worked
with somebody years ago who ran a little
experiment with some teams um that he
worked with in a in a company in the US
and he uh decided to or got convinced
leadership that per Sprint he would
remove an
hour from each Sprint
so you can imagine you've got a 40 hour
week per week per Sprint you've got a 40
hour week the next Sprint he's going to
do a 39h hour week with the team and the
Sprint after that he's going to do a 38
hour week with the team and the Sprint
after that he going to do a 37-hour week
with the team and I've got a question
for you at what point do you believe
that value delivery
suffered if the focus is on value
delivery delivering features now that
doesn't mean that for the other two
hours people aren't the the the the
hours that you remove people aren't
actually working right if you think
about it scrum team somebody who's
focused on solving problems um works
100% of the time right when I'm when I'm
having a shower in the morning or when
I'm I actually do a lot of my best ideas
at the gym I go to the gym I'm working
out the gym and I go oh that's a great
idea and I go on my phone and I message
it to myself right and then the next
idea Pops in how to solve problems and
figure these out is not something that
you get from 100% utilization it's you
need thinking time uh so can you guess
where he got to he got to 16 hours per
week before um uh a value delivery
started to suffer because all the rest
of the time is thinking time that the
team needed
thinking in the noodling time um
so very much Stop Being
Greedy stop trying to get people to
maximize their utilization and instead
focus on maximizing the flow of value
delivery to your
[Applause]
customers one of the seven deadly sins
of agile it's sloth
and this manifests in a number of number
of different ways with with teams with
organizations uh with leadership all
over the place um one of the most common
um elements is just not bothering our
bothering our ARS actually doing the
things um that that that we say we're
going to do right we say we're doing
agile but we don't deliver working
product at the end of the Sprint we say
we're doing agile um but we have long
convoluted deployment processes which
are not in control of the developers we
say we're doing agile um but we don't
have an ordered backlog right all of
these things
are places where we say we're doing
something but really we're just kind of
lazy and line through our teeth in order
to not have to do the work perhaps it's
because somebody in leadership in the
organization ation has decided that thou
shalt do Agile and your product is not
particularly suited to that model
because it was built in a in a
traditional maybe it's got Mainframe and
all kinds of crazy stuff in there maybe
there are other reasons why it's not
viable within the the the confines the
structure of of of your organization the
system that you're in um but I would
much rather teams and people were honest
and
transparent with their companies and
their organizations
about what they they can and cannot do
what isn't is not agile um I really like
there's a great article
um called uh detecting agile BS uh from
the US Department of the pents and if
you search for it you will find
uh a great little workflow on it it's my
one of my favorite uh uh things that I
use in organiz organizations so here are
uh six sloths uh things that
organizations kind of say they do um or
pretend that they're agile but they
don't actually do these things uh and
this I think these are great uh so first
one is our teams delivering working
software to real users every iteration
including the first and Gathering
feedback that's like that's like the
first thing that's almost agile in a
nutshell are we coming up with ideas
getting those ideas in front of
customers and getting that feedback if
you're not doing that sloth right you're
you're you're you're not able to get
things done uh the second one and
because this is Department of Defense
right uh is there a product Charter
laying down the mission strategic goals
and do all members of the team
understand how they contribute right
that's absolutely key if how can we
expect people within the context of our
of our product of our teams of our
organization to make good decisions
about what it is uh that they need to do
if they they they they don't have all
the information they need right we're
we're hiring smart clever people and
then we're not empowering
them to do the things that they need to
do right we're not we're just not
empowering them um and that that's
that's part of we need to communicate
with them and if you don't communicate
with them sloth if you don't actually do
those things you're you're you're being
lazy right just do it uh third one is
feedback uh from users turned into
concrete work items um on Sprint
timeline shorter than one month right so
are you getting uh things in front of
your customers at least once per month
um and
those that that that shouldn't be that
hard right it shouldn't be that hard to
engage uh with your with your with your
customers get parts of your product in
front of your customers and then get
them to tell you what they think of it
right Gathering feedback from from from
those users that shouldn't be that hard
and if you're not doing it sloth cuz
it's not that hard you're just being
lazy uh one I I already mentioned a
little bit uh is the full ecosystem of
your project agile IE agile programming
teams followed by linear bureaucratic
deployments is a failure right why do
you have linear bureaucratic deployments
after your adual team have done the work
yeah we might be able to make working
product in two weeks but how long does
it take before that increment that two
weeks worth of work actually gets in
front of real users so that you can
close those feedback loops break down
those
assumptions validate what it is that
you're creating that it is actually
value um and if that's too
long that's it's not agile if you look
at the agile Manifesto you you it
says ideally a shorter time frame but
only a few months uh between having an
idea and getting it into into production
um that should be uh the case and then
the the the fifth one our teams
empowered to change their requirements
based on feedback the the people doing
the work should be able to change and
adapt the requirements that they're
creating in the system the things that
they're building we want to build more
of the right things and less of the
wrong things we want to maximize the
amount of work not done all of those
things require the people doing the work
to be able to delete add or change
things from the backlog as needed based
on those interactions that we've already
talked about with the customer and if
you're not doing that sloth right why
are you not doing that why is somebody
not addressing the problems of why you
can't do that if your organization is
saying we want to do Agile year and we
want to get all the benefits oh but you
you can't change your requirements you
have to do everything that here's the
300 things we need you to do that's
fundamentally not agile welcome changing
requirements even late in development
these are just fundamental uh uh
principles of agility and then the last
one on the Department of Defense you
know not well known for being an agile
organization but um the last one on
their list is are teams empowered to
change their process based on what they
learn so not only changing the work that
they're doing but changing the way that
they're doing the work and why aren't
your teams empowered to do that well
because people more senior can't be
bothered with that they just want to buy
agile from some vendor install it and
then everybody just does it that way
that's that's not fundamentally how
agile works
agile is about the emergent practices
The Continuous change emergence and
adaption of our processes practices and
tools in order to be able to maximize
the value delivered to the customer the
stakeholder which maybe the business
themselves right and without those
abilities we can't do that I I I feel
like these six things absolutely impit
omey that's not a
word are sloth right if you're not able
to do all of these things you're not
really that interested in moving towards
agility you're really not that
interested in doing those things it's
it's lazy it's inept get off your ass
and fix
it one of the seven deadly sins of agile
is wrath wrath occurs in many different
forms uh in teams working in
organizations um most often it's the
inability for us to do things wrong it's
the inability for um an organization to
accept that we're not going to do things
right every time Um this can kind of
manifest in um a example from Recently
um we need to work with an organization
we need to create uh some some some
procedures and practices around um doing
a deployment need to create procedures
and practices um and the team that I've
been working with wants to create here's
here's what we think is going to work
let's try that and then as we figure out
more we can iterate on this policy and
procedure and get it to be what we need
it to be in order to be able to to be
successfully in production and then we
can reuse that as we go for for future
applications right future things that
we're doing uh but the the the other
side uh didn't want to do that they
wanted to uh you you create your final
draft we'll take that we'll run it
around the 100 people that need to go
see it and we'll create a spreadsheet
with all of the things wrong with it and
here's the things wrong with it that you
have to go fix before we can approve it
right that approval process is is Wrath
right it's you can't be wrong therefore
the end result needs approved before you
can do it because if it's approved it's
now no longer your accountability so
we're not going to blame you right so
it's a blame culture uh uh uh uh
technique it's going to run up the chain
get approved and then whoever's approved
it at the top it'll be beneath them to
solve the problem anyway so if something
goes wrong oh it's not the people down
here's fault because it was approved
go up who approved it oh the CEO
approved it well okay then well it was
wrong whatever right so there's no
there's no accountability it's a lack of
accountability results in Wrath uh uh
going on in in the
organization and I think this this
manifests in lots of different ways I
think that's the core thing but it
manifests in lots of different ways uh
one of them uh that I've seen happen
with a team uh was um I had it was
during a a Sprint review uh the team was
demonstrating their product and features
to the
stakeholders and um one of the
stakeholders asked the team why did you
build it that way right in a kind of it
was in a kind of accusatory tone like
why did you build it that way right like
kind of kind of like that and what I
would expect to happen would be that the
product owner would take accountability
for the value value delivered
accountability for the value delivered
in the team and they would get out in
front of that and say well these are the
decisions that we made we can always go
back and change them um blah blah blah
blah blah that's taking accountability
but no that's not what they did um wrath
they passed the buck and the product
owner turned to the team and said no why
did you build it that way right and
that's that's not taking accountability
and I think wrath is a is a big reason I
don't want it to be my fault it needs to
be somebody else's fault otherwise
something will land on me I'll get
covered in the poop uh uh from the from
the mistake that happens um and I think
that lack of mistakes is a huge huge
part of that story so don't let your
organizational culture of
Wrath create this environment where
nobody will take
accountability one of the seven deadly
sin
of agile is
envy and for me I think
Envy in agile looks like um just copying
other people's stuff right that's one of
the the the ways it
manifests that um we we we believe we
maybe believe that if somebody else is
getting success with something then of
course we will get success with
something and the difficulty is that
that's not necessarily true at all um
and it I'm going to rephrase that it
might be it might be it might be
possible on the small scale right so
you're you're you're working with a with
a team um one of your colleagues and
another scrum master or another product
owner is using a practice that they're
like oh this is great we do this and
this and we have this value stream and
we're able to to to get good good stuff
from that and you're like okay I'd like
to try that
right that's that's not really what I
consider Envy that's just trying
stuff Envy would be um looking at a
great example of Envy Spotify
model Spotify model is a fantastic
example of Envy there is no such thing
as the Spotify model there is no such
thing uh so there was a
presentation uh and paper uh that a
couple of folks that were were leaders
in at Spotify did at a conference uh so
I think they did a couple of conferences
talking
about what Spotify was
doing what their Journey was and where
they currently were on their
Journey right that was they're they're
they're telling an example of how they
did things and everybody went ooh the
Spotify model
let's let's do that and they absorb that
into their you know I I want this uh uh
um this capability and they go try and
bring it into the organization but what
folks don't realize is 6 weeks later
Spotify were doing it differently they
weren't doing what was defined in the
Spotify Model A year later they got rid
of the idea of of tribes and uh uh
guilds and whatever else they were doing
because it it didn't it didn't work for
them right they tried something and it
didn't work for them and that that Envy
of oh they're doing this awesome thing
so we need to be doing that awesome
thing I think it results in a lot of it
results in a lot of fomo if you've heard
that expression fear of missing out I
think that's kind of part of of Envy
other people are getting stuff and you
want the same
stuff and that's where where at many
levels organizations fail so they fail
at the the the the process level right
because you you look at um a a a Spotify
model or you look at safe or you look at
any of those big uh uh uh uh models and
say I I want that I want to install that
in my organization and then you pay lots
of money to get it installed and then
wonder why you know you're not getting
the benefit uh there's the the
application level um I talked about this
recently on a on a podcast um that the
installing an application that enshrines
somebody else's business processes into
your organization is not necessarily
going to be successful for you right so
the example I used before was um sap
right sap is a a massive application
tool very common in our industry but if
you if you adopt a sap tool right sap
comes with a bunch of different
capabilities so let's say it's let's say
it's invoice processing let's say it's
invoice processing right sap has a
workflow for invoice processing that
comes out of the box it has certain ways
that it does things and you're giving up
the way your organization does things in
order to adopt the way sap does things
does that kind of make sense that like
there are some things that you can adapt
in sap but only Within the bounds of
what the developers that created it
allow which means that when you see some
of your
competitors um perhaps installing sap
and building their whole procurement
processes in sap you think oh we need to
do that if they're doing that we need to
do that or if our competitors are adding
these features to our product we need to
add those features to our product and
that that's that's that's following
that's Envy right that's following not
building your own path uh Simon syc does
a great video uh that is on this topic
and he talks about the the the the why
you know start with why and he talks
about going to two uh conferences one's
a Microsoft conference under Balmer uh
and one's a Apple conference and at the
Microsoft conference everybody wanted to
know what their competitors were doing
what are their competitors doing what
are their competitors saying uh uh what
are they what are they launching what
features do they have at the Apple
conference they didn't give a crap about
what the competitors were doing they're
like this is the way we're going we're
doing this cuz it fits within our belief
model generos generosity Comfort
confidence contentedness friendliness
goodwi
kindness benevolence friendship those
are the the Opposites of of of envy and
I think think that that if you can put
aside what everybody else is doing and
focus on what do you need to do and what
do your customers need um you'll have a
lot better time both in the process
space in the in the tool space and in
your organizational structure
space one of the seven deadly sins of
agile is
pride now you do want to take pride in
your work we all want to do good things
we want to believe that the things that
we create are
valued but I think the pride that's the
sin part is blind Pride you're taking
pride in something without actually
measuring its outcome right we talk
about this all the time for for for
product owners don't just build stuff
willy-nilly you need to collect the data
the Telemetry the analysis you have to
do hypothesis you have to create the
hypothesis I think this thing if I build
it is going to add
value you create it and you don't just
assume that it's going to make the value
that you think it is that's Pride
talking you need to analyze the data and
figure out if that actually did provide
the value You're Expecting and you need
to stop investing in something that
isn't providing the return that you're
EXP expecting it to do another good
example of that uh is is uh Satia
writing down the cost of Windows phone
right writing off Nokia for for 8
billion sometimes you have to swallow
your pride and not sink more money into
something that's not going to provide a
return and you just have to stop um I
used to work at a at a bank um in the UK
in uh near Edinburgh and they created
they had this massive piece of software
that basically all it did was create
forms for customers to fill out but it
was the most
convoluted unusable
unwieldly um I don't know I I'm trying
to think of more words to describe this
Ridiculousness of this this software um
it
was didn't provide the features that
they actually
needed but they'd spent 2 million on
building it so they must use it we must
continue to use it that's that sunk cost
fallacy right which I think is very
closely related to Pride while we've
invested this much money it must be
awesome so we must use it um and those
are assumptions yeah I think pride pride
is how come we we assume stuff we assume
lots of things
the product owner assuming that the
features the ideas that they have are
good ones right the market doesn't
always agree um developers building
things in a
way that entertains
them rather than that actually focuses
on the value delivered to the business
um I've been guilty of that many times
of working on features because they were
fun not because they provided any value
to the the customer um done that a ton
um so you need to be really uh uh
careful that you don't become too
prideful make assumptions about the
products and capabilities that you're
building the code that you're writing
the the the the stories that you tell in
such a way that it clouds your view of
what's really going on right because
then all you're looking at is Vanity
metrics you're you're missing out on
what's really going on so don't be so
prideful that you miss out on what's
really going
[Music]
on