uh what are the top two things that a
product owner needs to bear in mind when
adopting the entrepreneur stance
I kind of think of the the entrepreneur
stance as as like the Visionary looking
forward to the future
um and that's where a lot of the stuff
that ends up on your product backlog is
going to be this is just one part of
being a product owner
and I think the the two most important
things to focus on and one is connecting
the team to uh the value that you're
creating does everybody on the team
understand
the connection between the work they're
doing every day and what it is we're
trying to achieve do they understand
that connection so that that would be a
lot around uh Vision communicating it
product goal communicating it Sprint
goals right making that connection
between the work that's happening every
day I think that's probably one of the
most important things and the most
common lacking things
um the other one is where the value
comes from uh one of the things that I
find when I engage with product owners
the first thing I ask them is is how do
you decide what's valuable and what
isn't and quite off often the answer is
I make it up as I go along right which
which
uh while not necessarily 100 wrong a lot
of people have very good
um guts skills at reading the the
reading the market reading the
information that they have
um but really we want to be taking a
more evidence-based approach
so from a product owner's perspective
are you making decisions
based on
information
do you even have the information that
you can get there's going to be lots of
hidden stuff right we're still taking
bets we're still taking risks
um but
do you have enough information to make
more of the right decisions and less of
the wrong decisions uh so for that I
usually look towards Evan's base
management right making sure that I
understand my my current value I have in
the system like uh our product that's
our current value puts features already
in there and our unrealized value what
are the stuff that we need to have in
our system that we haven't built yet so
kind of looking forward into the future
but I also really considering our our
our other more organizational capability
focused metrics where I'm gathering data
from
um both our our ability to innovate
right how much time do we spend on net
new things versus existing things it's
that's the same reason that
um uh we all get upset that Netflix is
canceling our you know favorite show
right because they do a season and the
numbers are good but they're not amazing
and if they're not amazing they know
that the second season is going to be
less amazing than the first season
because it just always is
so they would rather invest that same
money they would invest in doing a
second season of existing show into
doing a first season of a brand new show
that might be more likely to get a
higher return on investment for that for
that first show right we get all upset
because they cancel our favorite show
with their favorite characters right but
in reality they're making commercial
decisions based on the data and the
analytics that they're collecting from
who's watching all the shows and how
they're doing it you need to do that as
a product owner right that's the product
owner making those decisions based on
the data so you've got your your ability
to innovate and then you've also got
your your time to market right how
quickly can you go from
same for Netflix as well right how
quickly can you go from an idea to
getting that thing in front of real
users who are then able to give you
feedback right how quickly can you get
stuff in front of them and I think
that's that's if you think in the in the
in the in the movie TV show space that's
why we're seeing so many limited series
now
um and that's because
we are unhappy with that false sense of
we're getting more later
right we're getting a second season and
we're hoping for a second season and
then we don't get it whereas if they
Market it to us as it's a limited series
we're only making one
if it's if something happens we might
make that but we're only making one then
we don't have that sense of loss as
users and that's product ownership right
they're managing our expectations
they're looking at where the next piece
of value is coming from how can we get
different users increase our market
share into our product uh and and really
understanding value and how it impacts
on that and the decisions that you make
get the data in there as well that was
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility