many companies make the mistake of
security as an afterthought doing
security validation and Security checks
at the end of the
process this is
not a
small company problem it's not a big
company problem it's an all company
problem and some of the largest tech
companies have resolved this with
something you'll probably hear about in
in Dora in the Dora report which is
shift left shifting left shifting
everything as left as you can as close
to the developers as close to the
engineers as possible is how you resolve
these issues because what has been
happening is that we will do many years
of work on a product could be months
could be years could be weeks we do a
whole bunch of work on a product and
then we ship it to pen testing or
somebody who's going to do some security
validation for your for your product
even if it's yourselves doing it but you
just do it at the end and you find a
whole bunch of problems and some of
those problems are going to
be
systemic to to how you've built your
product in the first place right we we
we we oh right in order to fix that
we're going to have to rearchitecturing
if we're late in the game we're ready to
ship everybody's asking us when when's
it going live so we need to get out we
need to blue blue Peter the heck out of
that and we get out our super glue our
sticky tape and we go figure out how do
we paper over the cracks in our product
to prevent the hackers getting in and
the problem is that hackers are super
good at peeling away the edges of those
things to get underneath um and prevent
those get access to your system and take
it over um I
I've been involved with um some
exercises that the Azure devops team did
where they hired a team of professional
hackers this is red blue exercises hire
a team of professional hackers brought
them in and their job they're the red
team their job is to hike the system and
the blue team's job is to a detect them
and B do something about them right
either prevent them getting in or push
them out or all of those things and the
red team always wins that's the thing
you have to realize is eventually the
red team is always going to win they're
going to find a flaw they're going to
find ways to peel up that that tape and
the only way for you to prevent those
things is to not have vulnerable code in
the first place not have vulnerable
architectures in the first place and the
only way to do that is to ref Factor the
heck out of your system to make those
things go away and then stop those
things from happening in the first place
so for example the Azure devops team
they do these red blue exercises and
then the red team's job is to go around
all of the teams in the organization and
show them how the red team was able to
use their code to get access to the
system and how they could have coded it
differently or architect it differently
or changed the way they do something in
order to prevent hackers getting in that
that's security by Design that's
security from the start that security
baked into the problem this is true for
a lot of different facets of software
engineering is that it's every team
member's problem right what the business
wants is every team member's problem how
much it's going to cost is every team
member's problem the customer's worries
are every team member problem and
security is every team member's problem
so building Security in rather than
testing it in building quality in rather
than testing it in is about shifting
left getting as many of those skills
that you need for your context um into
the hands of the developers that are
doing the work and there are a bunch of
tools out there that can help with that
there sonar sonar Cube and sonar Cloud
which enable your developers to analyze
their code and find and perhaps
hopefully deal with vulnerabilities um
there are known vulnerabilities that
happen in the code you can also use
GitHub which is part of they have a an
advanced security protection system uh
which you can use in GitHub or as part
of aure devops and to again analyze the
code find problems poke at it it's why
when if you're a developer and you try
and upload um some code that has a pat
token or other thing that looks like a
security token or a password into the
system you will be prevented from
checking in that code from committing
that code from the repo from doing a
push to production by GitHub and as your
devops because the advanced threat
protection is detecting that and
preventing it from getting into the
system in the first place shifting as
far left as we possibly can to validate
that those things are not going to cause
those vulnerabilities a really common
vulnerability is is developers on dev
machines putting passwords in text files
right on dev machines there's all sorts
of vectors uh that hackers can use my
advice are capability to help you is
within the context of Shifting left and
enabling your teams to have the
knowledge and skills they need to be
able to prevent and remove as many of
these issues as possible before they
become an