[Music]
And I think we're live. Are we John? We
are indeed. Well, welcome everybody. I
hope there is somebody out there. If you
are out there, drop us a a message in
the public chat and just let us know
you're there. Um, today we're going to
be having a conversation, a discussion
about the open guide to Kambban. a truly
and I do mean this most sincerely
although I sound like a movie actor now
but I do mean this truly when I say this
has been a deeply collaborative effort
amongst a great number of people who
describe themselves as flow
practitioners or people who care about
the the concepts around flow and the
constructs around flow. I'm sorry
they're not all here today but different
uh commitments mean they can't all be
online at the same time. They're they're
out earning a living. Um, but I think
this is going to be a nice conversation
and I'm going to give an opportunity for
my fellow colleagues who are on the call
to to say hello and just to to let you
know what their thoughts are and then
we'll get into a bit of a discussion
about the guide that is now live folks.
It is now live cambanguides.org.
Unless I'm wrong, you'll see a banner
going across the screen now. So, it is
live. It's a similar familiar interface
you'll find thanks to our friend Martin
um who's done some mastery in the last
48 hours to get that up and um and it's
available to download currently in in UK
and US formatted documents A4 and letter
size in English and I'm sure as the
community rallies around different
translations will start to emerge so
they're more followable in your local
language around the nuances of some of
the link linguistics we've had to to
play with to get a guide that we could
reach consensus in the majority of the
Kambban and FLO communities. Um I'm
going to stop talking now guys and let
you say something. So I could just say
just a few words. I want to thank a lot
of people who don't want to be named and
there's a number of people who are happy
to be named and so Jim Benson
um famous for the lean coffee and
personal canban and also does a lot of
work in Obe
Andy Carmichael uh formerly from KBAN
University still very much stalworth in
the uh in the Kanban community Jose
Cassal who's been in Kban University and
Proanban and and the flight levels
community, Magdalena Furlit in scrum.org
uh from Poland, Michael Forny who's here
with us as well on the on on this uh
live stream and of course Martin
Hinchelwood uh who is a wonderful
reviewer but also enabled us as well to
have uh open discussions. So on the
website that we'll look at later on uh
you can actually uh contribute to the
discussion and uh Martin was basically
the architect of that. We'll talk more
about that uh later. Um in addition, we
basically had Christian Neverdal as
well. He's a PKT, a Proanban and uh
someone who does this stuff all the
time. So he doesn't just train, he's
consulting all the time, just like a lot
of the reviewers here. Nad Talai as well
from Camban University, also from the
safe community. Steve Tendon from the uh
Tameflow community uh author of many
books and of course here our wonderful
Nigel Tuttler here on the screen as
well. So really looking forward uh to
sharing uh this document with you Martin
I'm going to hand this over to you next
if you want to say a few words.
Sure. I think um one of the things that
I apart from doing reviewing the
document which I was all very uh honored
to do um I wanted to help leverage my
technical skills. I think I'm the
technical one in the in in the group
from a from a software perspective. Um
to help enable a greater community
around the document. Um, so we're we're
leveraging GitHub. Many of you might not
be familiar with GitHub. It's not as
hard as it sounds. Um, but it does give
us a bunch of capabilities that that
that are great. One is that all of the
the the document is in markdown, in
text, in source control. So if you want
to fork the repo is probably something
that you will you will figure out how to
do. uh but copy it, make changes, and
send us uh requests for changes. That's
super easy to do. Um even better than
that, it comes with a pretty leveraged
discussion forum capability built in. Um
so we can we can have discussions, we
can debate over different topics and um
as other other guides have done maybe
that results in meetings and live
discussions as well when you need to
hash things out um and then somebody can
make the changes and and submit them and
it's not all on the people who were part
of the original group. anybody can go
and fork that create uh uh changes um
specifically for new languages. Uh so
one of the things that we're able to
support is that the whole site is multi-
language not just the guide itself. So
one of the the common barriers is how do
you find your language on a site that's
predominantly in English if you don't
speak English right? So the whole site
is is translatable. Um, and we also
maintained all of the existing content
um, from the previous uh, uh, Kamban
guide uh, documentation. So, they're all
all available on the site, including the
the translations from previous versions
are in there already as as PDFs at the
moment. Um, but if folks want to come
along and turn them into markdown, we
can we can have the whole site in French
with all of the history of uh the
cambangan guide as well as the new open
cam guide. Um, and I think that that
openness is really important. Um, it's
kind of akin to open source. It's not
really open source because it's it's a
document. It's creative commons. It's
more in that context. Um, but the more
community engagement we can have, the
the the better the better I think the
document will be as well.
Uh, thank you Martin. Uh, Michael, could
you say a few words as well, please?
Yeah. Um I find passionately the fact
that um not being a native speaker
myself uh I I understand that a lot of
community might struggle as Martin
mentioned but what we've seen right in
the when we were reviewing the documents
and sharing we received an
overwhelmingly number of requests of
translations. So I think that that's a
very good symptom that the spirit of
this initiative it's already out there.
So people want to part participate, want
to help or want to be helped finally in
their own native language. So the fact
that this is from the community to the
community I think it's really really
powerful and we encourage everyone uh in
in in attending the session today also
to speak with others that couldn't
spread the word and and finally get uh a
common ground to stop fighting about
stuff and start understanding each
other. You know I'd like to say
something on that. I think that's a key
key point this stop fighting with each
other as yeah we all enjoy the echo
chamber on LinkedIn and other sites to
to you know duke it out and have a bit
of fun and give an opinion and stuff but
the fact that you know the fact you
could bring me I could sat I said this
earlier when we were chatting before we
went live and saying that you know I
could have sat on the sidelines and keep
throwing rocks and calling BS on things
that I had problems with in previous
cambes and camb discussions.
because of my Toyota roots and because
of my training in the sort of TPS world.
Um uh or I could get involved and I
could give an opinion and have a
conversation and have a discussion. And
the fact that the theory of constraints
folks and some of the Camban University
folks and other people who see the world
differently to Nigel and Nigel only sees
the world Nigel sees it. It's not that
I'm right or it's not that I'm wrong. us
to have a v a lens of perception is a
huge achievement that we all managed to
get together and we found language and
there was some there's some nuancing and
people will look at the guide and say
yeah but you could say this like that
you could say it like that but think
about this is a huge amount of people
that have come together almost all the
the the key proponents and actually have
said we can find words we can live with
and when I did my old Lego series play
stuff years ago we make like shared
models, you know, shared mental model
type thing. And it was, you don't have
to agree with everything, but can you
live with it? And that's where I found
myself. There's some great words in
there about Toyota and about lean
thinking and some of the things I'm
passionate about that everybody can live
with because they don't disagree. And we
found words that expressed it. And it's
the same for me when I look at some of
the measures and metrics that are sort
of the same thing with different names.
But that's okay because if it's familiar
to you, use it. It means the same thing
and you're getting the same result and
the same outcome and that's okay. And I
think that and you know John and I have
had a lot of spats over the years,
public as well as private, a lot more in
private than in public. And this I've
expressed opinions, you know, that eight
out of 10 cat owners might express. Old
English joke there. Um and but we
managed to sit down and say there are
things that we can discuss and agree on
because it's important for the general
community and the practice. We're
practitioners and and contributors.
There's people out there just are users
of the system and they just want
something they can use with utility to
solve their challenges and help them in
their what are often very complicated
and sometimes complex environments. and
we need to stop fighting and proving
we're the biggest guy in the room or the
biggest mouth in the room. And we've
we've done that. And I think that's a
huge achievement. And I thank John for
doing that, which you know, I'm biting
my tongue hard here now. I thank John
for doing that. But and I think the fact
that so many people have come together
from so many different, you know,
factions if you like or so many
different uh views on the world of flow
and created something that's very
practical, got great utility. The
language is relatively easy to follow
and when translations come we'll get
even easier and we made an appendix of
stuff that everybody wanted to talk
about which you can use if it's useful
to you and say I'm familiar with that
and I'll go use that because that's
valuable to me. It's not a you must do
all of this stuff. And I think overall
that's a huge achievement for us all to
come together and do that.
Indeed. Yeah. It was it was a pleasure
really to build bridges, wasn't it,
between these communities and and um we
tried to use language that feels a bit
awkward but also more straightforward at
the same time. For example, people talk
about work in progress or work in
process depending on your community. And
uh we had a comment a few days ago,
well, isn't that work that started
that's not finished? people kind of
understand that a bit more, you know, uh
there's different language about how
things take, you know, is it flow time,
is it lead time, is it cycle time, and
all sorts of arguments about that. And
so, well, it's elapse time from started
to finished. Everybody understands that.
So, when's your started point and when's
your finish point? And of course, you
could have more than one starter point
and more than one finish point. And uh
there's a lot of good stuff in in Canban
Guide. We we built on that. And but also
what we did as well was we tried to
achieve more coherence as well. Uh and
um yeah I'd love to hear more about that
Nigel from you like in terms of like
some of the things that would have
bothered you before about Kambang guide
and maybe I wouldn't say they'd be
resolved but like as in you're feeling a
bit more comfortable maybe about what we
have in this document now. Look, you
know, you mentioned started, finished,
which is a really important thing
because people add things into a
backlog, an intake, a queue, whatever,
wherever you receive your requests for
doing work from, whatever you call that.
Um, and the thing is this, once it's
received, once it's known to you, it's
work in progress. Work in process. So,
progress and process for most people is
synonymous nowadays. the the
manufacturing world tend to talk about
process and and I talk about progress.
It's just so just to take that as it is.
But the starting and finish concept is
because one of the big bug bears for me
is that and Little's law talks about
this and other other clever people out
there that once the work enters the
queue enters the line for Americans that
don't like don't get the word queue but
once you enter
sorry I live in Texas folks once you
once work is actually in the queue to be
done it's in process it's now work in
the system and you count it from that
point and as work transitions from step
to step, stage to stage, I don't know,
column to column, whatever you whatever
language works for you, there is a cue
at each step and and you know, even on
back in the Toyota days, you know, said
Kambban is a compromise and the the
effort here is to remove cambans because
camban is a signaling card. It's a
signal for work or for inventory or even
for transportation. But the more of them
you have, the more inefficient your
process is. So the idea is to reduce the
number of process steps so things flow
more quickly. Ideally to do, doing and
done, you know, to coin a phrase, but
there is more than one doing column. And
if there's more than one doing column
because of the linear nature of your
process, then there is more than one
waiting state, more than one queueing
state. And it's important to measure all
of those if you want to find where the
constraints are in the system and to
deal with those. So I think that that
for me was a huge uh clarification in
this work and I think you know that's
one of the big things that stands out
for me. I have a whole list here but I
want to yield to some of my colleagues
who may tell me the things that stand
out for them.
Yeah. So uh Michael what's uh what's
done what stood out for you actually?
you were one of the reviewers of this
document and what did you notice
actually the first time you saw it for
example and maybe what you think about
it now I I think that something that
wasn't stressed enough uh before was
value measuring actual value delivered
there was uh probably I got it wrong
myself but it was too much about the the
process of optimizing the flow and not
enough focus on the value delivered
thanks to these optimization
So when we talk about and it's more on
the why we do this right the how is very
important but the why and and the
feedback loop that we can trigger is
essential because otherwise we will be
as as we say in my country very good in
driving a sport car right uh on the wall
right and we need to drive it safely. So
the the value uh the clarification of
the of the metrics about value the fact
that we're there to bring value to to
our uh customer I think that that that's
that's an additional part that also
could break some of those
misunderstandings for those who say oh
you know I don't like KBAN because it's
not focused enough on value. I think it
always been but it was not so evident
and clear to everyone else. So in the
appendix where uh on top of the um let's
call it traditional or standard metrics
there's more focus on these additional
metrics that can be useful or not
depends. So your your context will tell
you if that makes sense in your context
and maybe could be an invitation. Oh
have you ever thought about it maybe you
should consider them right? Um and
another point you know very very
contagious if you want is uh previously
you cannot even mention lead time right
as if it was a bad word and my
understanding was oh you know nobody
gets a common agreement or what we mean
by that so instead of deep diving and
try to investigate what we should mean
about I'll just we don't just mention it
it's not a metric but the end to end is
is is essential right So the the the
level of detail I think that we are
providing to the to the readers to
choose uh the best definition that suits
with them with their situation where
they want to achieve it. It's giving
this guide in my opinion uh more an
holistic view.
I I would agree Michael. I think it's
given it huge value and you know I was
just scanning down as you were talking
and because of that appendix which has a
lot of conventions and additional
measurements in there that as you say
people can use in their context whatever
works for them. Um but the the the whole
definition we we found ways to make
things that people argue about simple to
understand and one of them for me
favorite one was stable system because
we talk about system stability and we
can all argue about what is a stable
system what is a cause of instability
and how to measure that and this then
trust me I got loads of opinions on that
but as we said in the guide put simply a
system that can consistently meet the
demand placed upon it I mean to me
That's a stable system. I mean in Toyota
people would agree with that and most
other people would agree if we're
meeting the demand and the systems
function it's stable. Can it be
improved? Probably 100%. But it is
stable in in a and so things like that
really really help me to support this.
And of course as John's showing on
screen now track time is in there and I
pushed for that and and you guys all
said this was okay and the language was
consensed. I'm not going to beat beat
this in this uh webinar, but the the
fact that that was there so people who
are familiar with that or people who are
unfamiliar with it can go look probably
I want to learn a bit more about this
but it gives them an opportunity now to
do other independent research and be
introduced to terms that might be useful
or people who know them and choose not
to use them that's okay too because it
may not fit their definition of workflow
and I think that's a key thing John I
might invite you to to mention that talk
about the definition of workflow. Yeah.
Because I think and like the definition
of value and the definition of workflow.
I think they're two really important
concepts irrespective of the rest of the
content that everybody really needs in a
working environment. John,
yeah, I can certainly talk about that.
So, um let me just uh share the the
section. So uh very much in keeping with
uh Kamban guide uh we just uh we
thinking in this guide we talk about um
not just coherence with what was
happening before with Toyota and so on
but also everybody talks about you know
outcomes and all that kind of stuff and
of course a lot of people would say well
the quicker you deliver uh outputs the
quicker you get outcomes and there's
truth in that and actually there's a a
kind of a thinking error in assuming
that it's all about outcomes but because
if you if you're too slow with those
outcomes, you're dead, right? So, so
this guide is trying to get that balance
right about how do you how do you
optimize your flow and how do you get
that balance right between efficiency,
effectiveness, and predictability and
and so in your definition of workflow
when it's visualized, that's essentially
your your canban board. And you could
have more than one definition workflow
on your board as well, which is fine.
You might have multi-level systems or
you might even have different item types
that have different workflows. And so
that's okay. You can visualize that if
you want to. And so we're saying, well,
you know, what are the units that go
across the board? If you're in a
software world, you might be using news
stories or something like that or bugs
or tech debt things like things like
that. Uh if you're in a marketing world,
you might have different types of
campaign going on and so on. And then
depending on the item type, you'll have
a started point and a finish point. So,
when does the clock start and when does
the clock finish? And for some teams,
it's like when I took the work in. For
for other teams, it's not when I took
the work in, it's when I actually
started doing the work. And I don't
personally like that because that's not
very customer oriented because maybe um
maybe you've been thinking that you were
only working on for three days. Yeah.
But we told the customer two months ago
we started, they think it's already
started. So, you could have different
clocks running, you know, doing
different elapse time clocks, start to
finish and so on. And so, we tried to
use different language. Yes, we
appreciate a lot of people are using
work in process, work in progress and so
on, but essentially we're talking about
work that's started but not finished.
Started according to your started point
and finished according to your finish
point and that can be wherever you want
it to be basically. Uh you need to say
how work in progress is controlled and
we were very nuanced about this subject
actually. Uh we had lots of debates
about this because in essence if you
think about it when you're using work in
progress limits uh essentially you're
just trying to contain the deluge of
work coming in to the to the system and
are there other ways where we can really
genuinely create pull you know where
when people ask for stuff we we actually
do the work and when people actually
start work when they've actually got the
capacity to start it I often see people
saying oh I'm going to start that today
boss and they put into in progress but
they can't start it because they're
they're working on something else. So
like bring it in when you're ready, you
know, when you've actually got capacity
to work on. So little things like that.
We talk about that. We talk about
different ways that you can control whip
as well. Uh also we give some examples
as well about some policies. I love the
little bit we brought in kind of going
back to where this all came from. You
know, why would you let bad work go
downstream or as as Nigel would said
into the next process. You know, why
would you why would you do that? But uh
we're being explicit about that. It's
not just about uh optimizing the flow,
but also can we uh I'm not saying get it
right first time or anything like that.
I'm not saying that at all, but can we
do a good professional job? So we we
we're feeling confident it's not going
to come come straight back on us.
And we still think that you should have
a service level expectation. It can be
based on the history of your system. It
can be based on a selection of the
history. It can also be based on a guess
if you don't have enough data. And it's
it's based on your you know your
previous history. So like if you do have
history you you would know how much the
previous work took but we can't really
say that what happened in the past is
going to happen in the future. So some
health warnings around that as well.
Okay. And then of course you need to
visualize that as well. So this this is
probably the most important part of the
guide I would say. It's like this is
kind of like you know what you uh you
don't really have a workflow unless
you've got these properties and we we
have some recommendations on metrics and
measures as well and and there's courses
and practices that we want you to follow
just like in Kambban guide. We want you
to control the amount of work in the
system. We want you to ensure that you
don't let work rot on the board. Uh a
rot you should have a rotting in
progress limit you know of uh of zero.
Nothing should be rotting on the board.
and and you need to kind of resolve
impediments as well that cause block
work to to move on you. So you need to
actively manage the work uh make sure
work doesn't get and then of course you
need to improve the flow as well. You
need to uh not just improve the workflow
improve flow the flow of value and so uh
we define value in this as well. We
define stakehold define lots of things
but remember lots of canban system
members
they can only do so much. So people who
demonstrate leadership we call leaders
not necessarily managers it could be
leaders and teams as well. Um but we
like to see managers if they exist uh
doing what Nigel will call Genchi
Kambutsu go to the source collect the
facts to you know get the right
information so you can make some good
decisions and do it so often that the
truth actually emerges. Don't do like a
what I call a royal tour visiting once a
year and everybody's putting on their
makeup and they're you know I'm brushing
my hair unusually and all that kind of
stuff. uh you know trying to make sure
that it's real that actually people find
out what's going on. So I don't want to
break your flow there pun intended but I
think this is a very important section
for leaders or people who are in senior
executive or management roles and may
call themselves leaders to think about
because this is their active
participation.
This is where they get involved in their
phrase, they lean in to go figure out
how to improve the system because a lot
of us in senior roles will complain that
the system isn't functioning optimally,
whatever that means, and it isn't
delivering the outcomes and outputs we
want. But they do very little about
really getting involved to understand
how we do what we do, how the work
actually gets done. Which brings me to
the other points that I'm I'm really
pleased about in this is that first of
all we declare that Kambban is a
strategy for optimizing the flow of
value through a system and we say it is
a signaling system to call for work or
inventory which is the basic concepts or
constructs behind the way Toyota used
this but it's it's we want to optimize
the flow of value so that we're making a
clear statement on that and and in the
appendix in the con in the conventions
you'll see that The definition of kamban
from Japanese means signboard or
billboard and is a visual cue that
triggers one to select i.e. start or
move a work item. Nothing should be
produced or move without a camban
signal. Now it's not the Toyota folks
will tell me yeah but there's a few
nuances missing there. But the idea is
this is to show that this is
obstensively a visualization
approach. It's a way to signal and also
to see. You can see the work and if you
make your boards effective you can see
how the work flows through a system good
bad or indifferent and leaders who
choose to come and look at that will
actually be able to see where the
challenges are the constraints are all
the opportunities for improvement are so
at its heart that's what it is we're
signaling how work gets done we're
focused on the flow of value and I think
these are just the key aspects that most
most of us who are in this flow sort of
centric industry are trying to achieve
most of the time. So I'm really really
happy with a lot of the the work that's
been put into this.
Thank you very much uh Nigel and I'd
like to have a chat with Martin actually
about a question that popped in if
that's okay. Um so it was a it was a
scrum question um go and maybe Martin
you can have a go as well. So uh I would
like to add a perspective from scrum and
canban when I pull an item into the
sprint uh during sprint planning to
forecast I'll be working during the
sprint I consider not started items as
items not pulled into the system on
whip. Now it depends. So we mentioned
earlier that you can have more than one
starter point and more than one finish
point, right? So if you're using scrum,
you'll probably have a started point for
like you brought it into your sprint
backlog maybe and your finish point
might be well you meet your met your
definition of done and heaven forbid you
don't I hope you when your definition of
done is releasable but if it wasn't
there was something else going on in a
downstream process you might have
another finish point for when we really
actually released it and got feedback
and so on but actually the I think
people miss a trick when they use scrum
and canban when they just use canban for
the the sprint backlog piece you can
really be looking upstream and
downstream is the kind of way I kind of
like to describe it. Martin, I'd love to
get your perspective on this. What What
are your thoughts on it? I I think it's
quite a common um issue to run into,
especially as a lot of the tools that
provide metrics around this don't really
they're not really adequate. My my
background is Azure DevOps. I'm a
Microsoft MVP of Azure DevOps and and it
doesn't do this part very well out of
the box. all the data is there but
getting it out is a little bit a little
bit difficult. You're into PowerBI
realms or third party tools there. you
you want to cons
I'm Nigel talked about this earlier that
is as as soon as soon as it hits your
backlog at all it's started work right
so you want to have the timer start
there
but you also want to consider the wait
time that it's sitting in your sprint
backlog waiting to come into that sprint
itself but you also want to consider
that
you might not do
Right. Uh the your sprint backlog is a
list of opportunity.
I'm going to phrase it that way just for
just for fun. You're it's not no
guarantee that something you put in your
sprint backlog is actually going to get
delivered at all. So there's perhaps
there's perhaps a started finished
moment for for a particular team where
they're looking at we want to understand
the stuff that actually goes through our
system versus things that that wait
there but Nigel will pull me up for you
can't ignore that wait time. Right. So
I've been I've been channeling Nigel a
lot recently and things I've been
waiting for. Yeah. Martin's even built
even built a Nigel bot I believe. But I
don't know why you would do such a
thing. I have I have a chat GTP Nigel
bot that allows me to ask it questions.
It's a really good point and this is
where the design of your workflow
i.e. your board, your visualization
becomes important because is this
prioritized work we're expected to work
on in the near term and if it is it's
started it's in the queue we start the
time because you got item age as one of
the the measures in uh in the in the
camban approaches so it's aging somebody
said do this and and it's in an order to
be done well you haven't started
activity on it but it is waiting to be
done it's in the system so little's law
that it means it's it's being measured
from from a throughput perspective. But
so we need a way to distinguish this
from all this other stuff. Now in the
old days and days of Y, I used to have I
still have a column on my board behind
me says ice box. It's stuff I had an
idea about that I'm not actively working
on. It's not really in a queue. It's not
been processed or prioritized, but I
don't want to forget I thought about it.
So I put it in this cold storage so I
can go look at it occasionally. Go, am I
going to move? Am I going to prioritize
that? Is that going to become a thing?
So I think it becomes the decision of
the people in the system to and that's
what it says in the guide anyway to
determine how best to handle that and
how best to measure the work. The
problem with it with an ever growing
backlog and a backlog is never ending.
It's always growing. it's you know
people can add to it as scrum will tell
you is that when you know it just start
you get to a point where you just got
this infinite queue of work and thing
and if you look at the kingman equation
and again theoretical mathematics and
stuff and I'm no expert genuinely on
that but it says you know the the if you
start if you start to add things to the
queue and you start to overutilize the
people which is another thing we deal
with in the guide about whip limits and
what they're actually meant to do is
meant to prevent overburden. Um, so not
meant to max out your capacity because
if you max out your capacity, the queue
eventually becomes infinite. So new
things coming into the queue will just
never see the light of day or will take
eons to see the light of day. So people
who are pract people who start to
practice these things need to look a bit
about queuing theory. Think about the
designs of the boards. Think about where
how things are categorized
and then measure the things that make
sense in your context. Yeah. I I I just
wanted to add to that that that um
the way the the system is also a lens
that you look at the work through,
right? So that the the there's there's
the system from the perspective of
potentially this group of people doing
the work that might be your scrum team
and what they care about is when they
actually bring it into their sprint
backlog and they they're going to start
it. That's that's what they care about.
But then you've got product management
who are looking at the wider system
looking at well the customer asked for
it here and we're delivering it to them
to production all the way over oh I'm
not in the view all the way over here
and they care about that time but the
scrum team's time is only this small
piece of of that ideally you want to
broaden their story so that it's part of
the the better story but the you've got
the realities of where you are right so
so I I think it's I think it's a great
question and I don't think it's just a
camb for scrum teams thing. It's just a
camb thing. Um it's it's the holistic
flow thing and all the kambban guide for
scrum teams is really trying to do is
take these ideas around flow and give
you perspective on them within the
context of scrum.
And scrum itself has that narrower focus
in general, right? From a guide
perspective, it has that narrower focus
on just the scrum team, not the wider
organization, although we do often widen
it out. You know, there's a a question
from Tom. I'll put it on screen. Uh, and
Tom's a stalwart in this industry and a
big influencer to a lot of us in this
and this work indeed. How can we track
the quantity of a particular value like
usability or security? And we it's a
diff it's not an easy one to answer. Um
John will probably find something
relevant in there, but you've got to be
careful because you've got
quantification measures and and and and
quality measures. So a lot of the
approaches are used are quantitative
these probability forecasts and things
which are discussed in the guide without
using any particular naming. But the the
quantification is what most people are
doing. But we need qualitative metrics.
I was speaking to some doctors and
surgeons this week on a different
broadcast and it'll be out in some weeks
time about the fact that a lot of
measurements in the health care system
are quantification.
You know, number of patients seen a
number of this a number of that and
that's great but it talks nothing about
the quality the quality the qual the the
uh the value that's coming out of the
system. So we do need to start to look
at you know if something like usability
is a quality measure security you can go
both ways on that it's risk mitigation
it's risk avoidance so it's qualitative
but what about the quantitative side
there's different measures so I'm not
going to profer an answer because I'm
not the world's expert on this but again
depending on your context and what it
means to you in your definition of value
which we talk about in the guide
understanding what value means to you
and what value means to your
stakeholders, your consumers, your
clients, your customers, whoever they
are in your context because it will vary
the whole internal external sort of
discussion about who who's receiving the
value. You need to look at how you
define that and then find the
appropriate ways to measure that. The
guide gives you some suggestions. It's
not a a mandatory list of things you
must do. Nor is it a comprehensive list
of things that you can do. So this is
where people need to understand their
workflow, understand their context,
understand what makes sense in their
world, use the guide as it what it's
intended to be, a guide, not a recipe,
not a prescription.
Yeah, thank you very much, Nigel. Um, so
I'm a big fan of Tom's work and um,
I was telling the story about this only
yesterday when when Tom was consulting
up to about 10 years ago, I believe. Um,
he went into a CEO and he uh, he asked
the CEO like, "What's your most
important project?" And Michael, you
were there. You heard me talking about
this. And uh, and the CEO would say,
"Well, this is my most important
project, you see."
And so then um uh Tom asked uh the co
what's what's so important about that
project and and so the co wrote down
what was so important about it you see
and um
so Tom asked the CEO to uh to bring in
the uh chief whatever officers you know
marketing officer finance officer
officer all these officer officer people
and uh they came into the room it was
like we were in person and so on and uh
and I think it was Tom asked so what's
so important important about the this
project and could you write down please
what's so important about it and they
all wrote down something different they
they use words like better you know
weasel words you know you and I give a
give people a little prompt actually you
can use on any LLM you just say if
anybody tells you that you've got a
clear objective or a clear goal or a
clear requirement just uh write in your
favorite LLM
tell me the ambiguities in the following
text colon uh or sorry using Tom Gilb
style SQC specification quality control
and then you put in your text and it
will drive a lorry through your
requirements your or truck what you call
it in Texas truck a semi semi is a is a
is another word
so I'm a big fan of quantification for
that reason so you need to have a a will
to to try but we talk about both
quantitative and qualitative because
there are some things that are difficult
like for example cooperation is
difficult to when you have a relay race
who who's uh who gets the credit if you
win the race? Is it the person who
passed the baton or the person who
received it or it's like uh there's no
mathematical equation to tell you that.
So, but it doesn't stop us from trying
Tom. So, I hope that answers that one.
Got a few other questions as well. Uh
one of them is from Mike Levian just
going back to here. And so, uh the
campman guide 2025 was also released
recently. Yes, I was involved in that
myself. Would you see any contention
between the two guides? No, actually um
what we've done is we just built on it
really. Uh there are some things that
are a bit different maybe uh different
perspective because you've got different
voices and this is an open guide so for
lots of communities whereas uh maybe
there was a slightly narrower view in
Kanang guide but uh it's building on it.
In fact on the site open guide to kanban
you can actually see in the history
section you can see uh the uh the
previous versions of the current version
of canban guide a 2025 you can see the
translations as well for the previous
versions like uh uh December 2020 July
2020 and uh I have offered actually to
the translators if they want to put
their translations and some translators
saying yes they want to so uh we're
opening our arms to people in proamban
as well to uh to use the site as well
and uh contribute to this as well and
all communities actually. Uh so yeah the
next question is a bit more prickly I
think. Uh I'm curious if you to know if
you've had any feedback from Dan Vikanti
and Pratik Singh uh beyond simply citing
them in the guide. All I can say is I uh
communicated with Daniel on the 10th of
June what I was doing that I was going
to fork but it's not just me. It is a
collaboration. It is a a collaboration
amongst mult multiple people. So, and
you can do that. It's open source and
all that. So, hopefully we did a good
job with the the uh creative common
notice. And by the way, because this is
going to be an open document, it means
if there if you spot bugs in terms of
how we did things or what we said or no,
I don't agree with that formula, I don't
agree with that description, you can log
a bug. It's it's completely fine. It's
open source. It's uh a little
competition. How many bugs can you find
per page? Because we kept finding bugs
on it this morning. So, I'm sure you'll
find something. Uh so, this will be
updated more frequently as well. So
hopefully uh that helps. Mike, thank you
for the question. I I think I think it's
a a good thing to to point again at the
the link on the kangist.org goes to the
GitHub repo that backs it where
everything is and there's a discussion
forum on there to have conversations
about some of these ideas. Um and the
any issues that you have perhaps a
discussion is a good idea to start with,
right? Um, sometimes it's not the right
idea to just create a bug out of the
gate and say this is wrong because
perhaps, you know, perhaps it's I'm
channeling a little bit of Nigel here.
Per perhaps you're just wrong from your
perspective, right? And have some some
other eyes on on your idea. But once you
do come to a consensus, you can you can
make the change yourself and submit it
uh submit it to us and then we'll we'll
hopefully bring it in as as quickly as
we can as long as it's relevant,
pertinent, and there's probably another
word in there um that I'm looking for
that I'm not good at those words, but um
a good change, right? Yeah. Thank you
very much. And actually, it was a real
challenge, wasn't it? Uh putting this
together. I guess my job was kind of
curating all the wonderful ideas from
the different communities that are out
there and and often I say things myself
that when I go to write it down it's
like is that really true
and I often find things that I used to
say when you write a book you challenge
yourself when you write a guide it's oh
my god is it really really true you know
so you know John I would invite
people who know my work and my
background with Toyota and the t years I
was very lucky to be taught and trained
by them and also the conversations I
have around Toyota's production system
lean thinking and various discussions of
that there are a lot of people in that
community
who could now get involved if they
disagree with the way I've worded
something or the way I've tried to
channel my training over the years into
some of the the nuanced words they also
are invited to participate in this to
help us evolve how to use these
techniques that originated in Toyota
that were inspired others like David
Anderson and others to adopt some of
these ideas and bring them forward. And
if you think that some of the nuance
language could do with improving or
there's something that's missing or
something that's misworded, you now have
an opportunity to contribute. You have
now opportunity to go to the the
website, grab kambanogs do
kambanguides.org as it's on the screen
now. uh go and get into the discussion
and contribute an improvement, a fix, a
suggestion or have a bit of a a
conversation and a debate with the
people in there and that will help us to
improve it even further. My my focus
here my effort was to try and
explain the distinguish how we
distinguish Kambban in manufacturing
from Kambban in non-manufacturing
so-called knowledge work not just
software development which has been used
in of course a great deal and to nuance
that the difference between push and
pull systems that's in there what a whip
limit describes versus how Toyota pulls
things and how they self-regulate the
system and we'd like to see
self-regulating pull systems in there.
These are the things we'd like to see
emerge. The the guide doesn't say you do
it this way or that way. It gives you
some suggestions and guidance as in a
guide, but it does tell you that in your
context, it would be great if you could
do some of these things, but it leaves
that open for you to do that. So have
anybody in the community that are
considered lean focused practitioners,
Toyota focused practitioners, the people
who I looked up to as leadership and who
taught me over the years and others I
still collaborate with. If you want to
make it a little bit better, this is
your now opportunity to do so.
Thank you, Nigel. Um Michael, I'd love
to get your perspective as well. Um I
think you had a couple of topics that
you wanted to bring in. The floor is
yours. Yes. Especially for those who
might have been uh pushed back by uh the
the KBAN stuff. They did not understand
and maybe there was a lot of concepts
that were not explained in brick layers
theorem as they say in in England. I
think this guide helps to understand
more what we're talking about. Uh help
us to to break those barrier and those
misunderstanding. Oh, this is just for
manufacturing. No, it's not. Uh takes a
lot from that, right? It's it's a it's
an important uh DNA. But what struck me
probably from the first reading was that
was that part where is written you don't
need to start with everything but if you
don't want to start at least start from
here. So the starting point right a lot
of people struggle in getting things
perfect before even starting. Start
where you are. Start making a
difference, right? Start reducing by one
day your delivery time. It's already an
improvement and move on from there,
right? So the fact that this guide helps
you also to orient yourself in a world
that might seem um and that's my
personal opinion slightly from the
academia different difficult to
understand not for me uh or stuff like
that probably will bring more people to
give themselves a chance to read this to
understand it and scratch your head and
say you know what I can grab some of
this stuff and and use it to make my
team's life uh slightly less miserable,
right? I'm not saying making their life
perfect, but you know, when when when I
introduce flow in in with my teams uh
and I'm and I'm blessed to work with
humans uh not too much AI at the moment,
but they I think they need uh more
simplicity than complexity. They need
their life to be simplified. So these
concepts can resonate very well with
their day-to-day experience. So when
they see something, right, when they
visualize their work, especially in in
the scenarios where we're in, they're
not lucky enough to be in the same room,
right? So having a board that tells our
common story is essential. And if you
don't have a visual radiator that is
telling what is happening and is not
triggering the right conversation and
does not help you to monitor what's
happening, how can you expect people to
deliver value or to understand uh what
not to do to work right to maximize the
work not done intercept waste be before
it becomes waste. All the concept that
people that come from the lean and the
kban uh might might find second nature.
But for some people it's brand new. Oh
really? Right. The simple things that
make big changes. It's something that
not just in the academia, not just in
the training but in the actual activity
as consultants that we try to make
people's life much better.
uh you can really find uh I wouldn't say
solution but definitely tools and not
just one hummer uh for everything right
different tools for different scenarios
depending on where you are so I think
that's that's something that might
struck and I would encourage people to
give it a read and and and and find
something useful for them be a little
bit selfish if may say so right help
your people uh taking in what works for
Thank you so much uh Michael and um I I
saw another question came in as well
about security about you know uh what
you do about for me for for example
information security and risk right so
um one of the things that I love about
Tom's work is
it's almost like you're starting with
who you know we've all seen the video
starboard why the golden circle and all
that and there's some elements of truth
to that and there's some elements of
questionable But I still find that a
useful video nonetheless. You know, it
it excites people. But really, I think
for me it's about who like who are our
stakeholders and we define stakeholder.
It could be internal, external,
customers, end users, decision makers,
governance people, whatever, right? Uh
and we've got these stakeholders and
each of them has expectations and
they've got limits as well like uh one
of the stakeholders might actually be
the law actually might uh we we often
say, "Oh, it's the lawyers." Well, act
that's what Meta thought and then they
got a 10 billion euro fine from the
European Union, you know. So, the law is
the law is the law. So, like who are
your stakeholders? What do they expect?
What are their limits?
Which stakeholders are more valuable
than others? And people will often tell
you, oh, I want a secure system.
And you know what? Having a secure
system, I mean, even this website we
have today, making that 100% secure, do
you want to know what the cost for that
is? It's infinite.
infinite. So, do you have an infinite
budget? Because I don't. This is a
collaborative exercise, right? This is
on a shoestring. We're a bunch of people
who care about the community putting
things together. Very much with the
support of Martin here, getting us up
and running with the website and so on.
Really appreciate that. So, like in all
honesty, what would happen is people
say, "Oh, I don't want any hacks."
Really?
Uh, so no hacks ever?
Or or would you be okay with uh would
you tolerate uh maybe one hack every
five years or is it would you tolerate
one every six months actually or is it
more about we don't mind them getting in
but actually what did they get access to
and can we close it down quickly you
know things like that and so what I love
about Tom's planning language language
for short plain two world planning
language is you you quantify you say
what's the number of hacks for example
uh uh what's the meter well the number
of hacks reported on our internal
dashboard or what's spotted by our AI
system seeing people getting in. Okay,
so what would we tolerate? What's
tolerable? And then what's our goal?
What are we aiming for? Well, we'd
actually be okay if you only got hacked
once a year, you know, and if you
actually look people in the eyes, they
might be happy with that. And then uh
the you know, what's the stretch? Well,
we only get hacked maybe once every 10
years or something like that. So you can
quantify because if people assume that
we only get hacked once every five or 10
years uh then don't be surprised if your
budgets just explode because you've just
uh goldplated what's uh been asked for
when really we would have expected less.
So actually quantifying those is very
important. So just having the will to
have that conversation is really really
crucial I think. You know something,
John, that's where the, you know,
there's a huge debate about probability
forecasting, you know, and we won't dive
too deeply into it here, but the the
area of risk management is where things
like Monte Carlo simulation and
probability forecasting comes in. So, if
you are in an area where you're trying
to manage risk, uh, and I'm fortunate to
know people in risk, then that's an area
where that should be a greater focus.
And that's we're not going to give you
the solution in this guide. We're going
to give you a guide to be able to use
what we think is valuable. And I think
now you've just there was a question
from Casper actually. I think you just
put it on screen a minute ago. Um I
think actually it's that one there.
Awesome. And and it comes to that
because I was reading that while you
were talking and and you know, if I'm
interpreting this correctly, you know,
it's it's talking about the the
challenges, the friction, the
constraints, whatever words we want to
use in the system. and and whether we
you know we using scrum scrum or water
agile or waggile or whatever we call
these things in the old days dwords but
um the the reality of it is and this is
why I think what we've created
collectively is so valuable because if
you visualize how work gets done all
that stuff is transparent and as Russ
said earlier 100% transparency is
crucial we can see it all and then we
can start to ask questions and in the
guide we talk about you know helping
people to get the right answers more
rapidly. There's language in there
specifically um but essentially if you
can see the workflow you understand
every step of how you do the work this
stuff becomes visible and you start to
have the conversations to deal with it.
And there is language in the guide and
I'll I'll find that so we can pull it up
in a minute. But I just wanted to sort
of speak to this point because what
Casper is saying is what drives people
bonkers in the real world. But the
answer to this is to make the work
visible. Once you can see it, you can
have a conversation about how to deal
with it. And there is language in the
guide specifically about that. John,
I'll hand back to you. Yeah, thank you
so much, Nigel. Uh there's a question
from Ross actually. Um
so who do we see as the audience for
this? And uh maybe I'll go around the
room on this actually. Um I'll uh you
know I'll go to Martin first and to
Michael and to Nigel and I'll give my
own comments as well. But curious to
hear your answers folks because uh we're
all from different walks of life. So we
have different perspectives. That's the
whole uh fruit of the collaboration
really. There's different perspectives.
I'm very cur curious to hear your
answers. Martin, what's your perspective
on this? Yes. Unprepared response. I I
think that
um in in general for me the guide is a
tool for practitioners
to help them engage
with other other people. I I think it's
definitely a tool for everybody, right?
But I don't think it's discoverable for
everybody because how do you find it if
you don't know it's there, right? it it
and if you don't know that flow is your
problem and most people and most teams
don't know that flow is their problem.
They don't understand what flow is. They
don't understand there's a whole
mathematical thing around flow that's
not just making [__] up. It's actually
understanding mathematically how work
flows through your system. And I feel
like that this is a great guide for
practitioners
to use in reference
to to Some of it is a little bit of
lending credibility. Sometimes you need,
you know, you know, we've we've all
we've all been in this situ. I would I
guess many people in the chat as well
have all been in the situation where you
go into an organization to tell them
what they already know.
And that that you're bringing a little
bit of external credibility to that
story. And if you just have one person
talking about flow, if you just have one
person using those words, and that's why
it's so good that the guide is in
layman's terms is in plain planer planer
language than a lot of the reference
material out there. Um that that you can
point people to this guide. You can use
the language that we're using in this
guide to benefit the work that you're
doing with with your customers. And
I think that's for me is is is the core
audience for this is practitioners and
then they're they will use this in ways
with their their practitiones. I don't
know the
story.
Thank you Martin. Yeah, Michael, what's
your perspective? Yeah, to me um I I see
a very very um diff diverse uh audience
could be the newbies, right, that might
have read uh other guides and found hard
to understand because there's a lot of
unsaid or take taken for granted or even
expert practitioners that would like to
dive deep into something uh like you
know tact just just just to mention one
they might have heard it but I I never
find a very simple and straightforward
explanation of that and it's perfectly
fine if it doesn't fit with your system
but what it does and maybe you could
decide to apply it and propose it but
also as a conversation starter and
something I really liked it is that
whenever something is mentioned and is
referring to something outside may it be
uh systems thinking or other thing there
are references so it's a starting point
is allows you also to to build up a
scaffolding system where you can start
uh your your personal journey in in
expanding your knowledge or use it with
your team probably as a trainer can also
be a a good uh element to to uh to
sediment concept and and again as we
said simplify the the language. So in
short um the the the audience I think is
wider than might have been probably
before and this would also um make more
people comfortable to say you know what
I read this um I think might be
interested for you rather than oh you're
doing scrum now you should be doing
kanban that's why right maybe there's
these things that you can apply in in
your current scenario it doesn't mean
it's either or So yeah, probably the
audience is is more wider than probably
might have been intended for other
guides before.
Thank you so much, Michael. Nigel, very
interested to hear your perspective as
well. Sure. I like the word scaffolding
that uh he just used because in some of
my work on complexity and and stuff, we
talk about scaffolding being a temporary
structure we put in place to support
learning, to support whatever we're
trying to support. Some of it may stay
permanently because it becomes part of
the system or it others can be removed
away. So for certainly
uh anybody starting out trying to find
the way to manage work may find some
utility in what we've described when we
talk about I'm going to flash up a
couple of things and I posted some of
the camb it came up as you so it looks
like you're making these statements but
that's good. These are copy paste from
the guide. So if we read this, the
strategy of Kambban system is to enable
the the system members to ask the right
questions sooner as part of a continuous
improvement effort. And then later on we
talk about as you mentioned early
genbutsu
uh which is the Japanese phrase which is
go and see without assumptions
understand what's really happening where
the work is done and take action. And
there's some words on there. I won't
read it all out and people can read it
and grab it off the the video later. But
the whole point of this is so who is the
guide for? Well, it's clearly for people
that are starting out wanting to manage
workflow in some way. Be it software, be
it something else. It's clearly for
people who want to visualize that
workflow and understand where the
opportunities for improvement are.
Whether you call it kaizen or whatever
or constraint management, it's there for
you. But this says managers, leaders or
people who call yourself a leader or who
have characteristics of leadership who
control work in a managerial way, then
that's something that this guide
suggests that you get involved with. My
advice to people who start to use this
to help them in in their work using
camban type systems
is to make that section visible. It's
the improving flow section. Make that
section visible to your leadership
managers, people who tell you what to do
so that they see they have a role. And
if they read nothing else in the guide
other than the statements about what is
flow, what is value, demand management,
they read that paragraph
that will be valuable and will help us.
So I think that primarily yes people who
are using it and practicing it but
people who are managing the process the
system and the people who are practicing
it need to be shown it so they can see
where it's relevant for their role in
helping the system improve.
Thank you, Nigel. And uh I'm not going
to uh duplicate what's a lot of been
said. I agree with everything that's
been said by by by my colleagues here.
Uh my own kind of lens on life is
coherence.
And so we we can have uh canban system
members doing great things. Um and if
you think about it, what we have in this
guide is really a coping strategy for
all the craziness that goes around goes
around. If you have a team, all the
craziness that goes around, the
overwhelm of too many things being
started in the organization and and if
you think about it in scrum, the product
backlog is a coping strategy for all the
nonsense. You only bring in what you
want when you can bring it in. And
similar here with the open guide to
kamban as well. And there's lots of
strategies uh for for for dealing with
that. Um I think one of the things that
Nigel talked about is really close to my
heart as well which is uh how can we
make sure that there's more
understanding about what's really
happening in the system and some people
talk about you know it's okay to be on
the balcony as a manager and there's a
lot of merit in that you can see what's
going on but there's also a lot of merit
as well in just getting down on the
floor rolling up your sleeves and
putting on your Wellington boots
metaphorically and understanding what's
really happening because uh you'll often
find that you're asking the team's you
know saying I want more uh I want it now
and I want the quality up but actually
uh is that coherent and so this guide is
trying to uh do a couple of things is
trying to help people who are not in any
of the existing canban communities or
flow communities they're not even aware
of this they think canban is when you
don't want to do anything else you just
visualize crap on a wall forgive my
language so we're trying to say well
it's not that actually it's uh that
there's there are some minimums there's
not a lot that you have to do in this
guide if you're going to use canban but
uh we're trying to say actually this is
what we really mean and we're trying to
reach beyond so it's an open guide so
we're trying to reach beyond so that
we're using language that we think
everybody understand you don't have to
be a canban nerd we hope to understand
what's in the guide we've also got lots
of definitions and if you disagree with
anything of course you know you can
debate with us in the discussions and we
can we can do a follow-up and so on so
for me it's about coherence so what are
the camp system members dealing with
also if there are managers is what are
doing coherent as well with what's going
on in that exactly. It's not just a
board full of post-it notes uh and Jura
and so on. It's that's not really what
we're talking about. It's about having a
balanced system, a balance between
capacity and demand. And we've got lots
of suggestions on how we deal with that
as well. So yeah, I also want to bring
uh some attention as well to some of the
people that we'd like to acknowledge as
well uh because uh this is a fork of uh
KMAN guide May 2025 version which I was
involved in of course and there's many
people who uh were involved in all of
these uh different uh versions and
history and so on and they deserve
credit. A lot of them don't want to be
named and I understand why. Uh but there
are some people who were happy to be
named at the time. For example, the July
and December 2020 versions of Kambang
Guide. We had John John Paul Bailey, uh
Jose Cassal, Colleen Johnson, Todd
Miller, Eric Neabberg, Steve Porter,
Ryan Ripley, Dave West, uh Julia Wester,
Uvalure, and Deborah Zanki as well who
was involved in editing uh that
document. Uh we were driving poor
Deborah crazy, I remember. uh but it was
really cool working with Deborah and
very grateful for that. Then we have the
May 2025 version where there were some
additional reviewers including for for
example Mike Delena Furlit, Tom Gilb,
Colleen Johnson, Christian Neverdal,
Pratik Singh, Steve Tendon and Julia
Wester and uh we had more uh reviewers
than this but the people who were happy
to be named for the open guide to canban
were Jim Benson, Andy Carmichael, Jose
Cassal, Magdalena Furllet who said hello
to us earlier, Michael Forny who was
here, Martin Helwood who was here,
Christian never has at a Guns and Roses
concert and I really I think that's a
good decision much better than being
here and but he would love to have been
here today. Nadart Talai as well who's
been a mentor of mine actually he intro
he reintroduced me to Kanban believe it
or not in 2015 I kind of dismissed it a
bit 2010 2011 thought yeah whatever and
uh N brought me back to the to the
trough so to speak and Andy gave me a
lot of mentoring as well so very
grateful for their their uh putting me
on the right path. Steve Tendon, if
anybody remembers during the pandemic
all these live streams, everybody was
bored. I was doing loads of live streams
and I think we did uh 10 hours of video
with Steve Tendon and uh and Nigel who's
here as well, of course, and many other
people, many in many many influences,
people who probably don't want to be
named here at all. Very fed up that we
even named them. How dare you? What
we're saying here is look, people who
are acknowledged here do not necessarily
agree with what's written in this
document, and that's okay. We still owe
them um a massive debt of gratitude and
we're very very grateful to everybody
who was involved. It was a very very
intensive review the last few weeks that
I think it's been about three weeks that
we've been working on this roughly. You
know John I think it's an incredible
achievement to get Steve Tendon and
myself in the same document agreeing. So
I'm sure I'm just go on and it's open so
anybody can can come and disagree with
us and submit their suggestions discuss
collaborate with everybody else and and
figure out what's next. No, I agree
John. I think we're at that time. We are
indeed. Yeah. Just one comment on
Casper's things there. So he said
evolutionary. Yes, that's its bias. That
tends to be its natural stance. you that
doesn't stop you from doing big changes.
Um so if you're in a situation where you
have what I call layer cake teams you
know uh if you're an IT back backend
middleware front end dependency hell all
that maybe you realize after a while
maybe we need to restructure you know so
like we're saying you might need to do
that depends on your school of thought
and so on where you come from um there
could be other things as well maybe the
performance management systems need to
change maybe the finance systems need to
change because the way we're budgeting
and so on. So we're kind of hinting at
that as well in this document. So it's
actually not all small changes. So we
think actually uh we could use canban
for doing something much more as well.
So yeah, thank you every very much
everyone for joining in the discussion
today. Uh I think what I'd like to do
now is go around the table for the final
words and I'll start with Martin again.
Poor Martin is always getting stuck the
first time then we go to Michael and uh
and Nigel uh to maybe close us out
today. Thank you so much gentlemen.
Martin over to you. I I want I want to
to to reiterate just just based on a few
of the comments that um KBAN and scrum
are not at odds with each other. They
are complimentary practices. They work
together really well and you you may or
may not like scrum, right? That's
perfectly okay. Um, but they they
definitely um I don't have a single
scrum team I've ever worked with that I
don't also recommend looking at and
using flow metrics and flow uh uh
monitoring and understanding your flow.
And I think it's uh great that if you
want to translate the guide, if you want
to be involved in that process, not just
making changes to the guide, you you
might not have anything you want to
change you, but you want to contribute
in some way. Perhaps you could try help
translating the guide into another
language. Perhaps you could just
participate in conversation and
discussion. If you don't see the
conversation,
if you've thought of it, like writing a
blog post, right? If you've thought of
it, probably somebody else has got that
problem, too. So, ask that question. Um,
and collaborate on on figuring out what
works well.
Uh, thank you, Martin. Michael, over to
you, please. Yep. For me, I think is an
invitation uh to start a journey. That's
not the end of the journey. That's the
start of the journey. Even if uh you
think you're an expert, even if you
think you've discovered everything, uh
this gives you a fresh reread and you
can validate your thoughts or question
them, introduce a little bit of value,
array and maybe thinking out of the box
is just for software. is not is for
systems and and the people people go
back into right what I really love about
KBAN is that you ask people to make
those changes that can improve their own
life every day right make that change be
be vocal observe that's why transparent
100% so if you see something that
doesn't look right raise your hand and
let's change it together so the human
side to me I think is very very
important so the journey and the human
side. Thanks. Thank you so much,
Michael. Nigel, over to you, please. Um,
I've said so much on this uh broadcast,
but I think that this is an invitation
for people to participate. I think it's
an opportunity for them to to learn
things. I think it's an opportunity for
them to apply some of the thinking and
and ultimately to understand that all
we're trying to do with flow as it says
in the guide is is to foster a smooth
and balanced system to create value.
This will help you in that direction.
Thank you so much Nigel. Really
appreciate uh you coming on today and
thank you everyone uh for who
contributed uh to the document. Uh,
thank you for all your comments today,
Martin. Thank you so much for getting us
set up on the website. We were uh on the
website a lot today, weren't we, Martin?
And Martin's been doing lots of things
in the background. Absolute hero. Thank
you so much. You always ask me just in
time.
Yeah, sorry about that. We were still
finalizing the document this morning.
Okay. Yeah.
So, and uh Nigel, thank you so much for
uh for being willing to collaborate.
Yeah. Our conversations haven't always
been easy and uh yeah, big respect to
you for uh for finding a way to to work
with us on this and and to find a way to
help people actually and uh there's lots
of arguments going on on social media,
but we can get together sometimes. We
can agree on some things, can't we? We
can find a way to help people and really
appreciate the uh the coherence that you
brought as well from a Toyota
perspective and the the challenge that
you gave us as well during this whole
collaboration as well. Really appreciate
that. And uh Michael, your reviews all
the way through this as detailed as
ever. I really appreciate you. You
helped me as well with a a recent guide
as well. And uh this one, your feedback
has been phenomenal. I really enjoyed,
by the way, working with uh with Michael
on retro Lego serious play. Anytime I do
a PSM class for scrum.org in London in
person, Nigel uh not Nigel, sorry.
Michael turns up and because Nigel was
talking about Lego earlier, that's why
he had a Freudian slip. So, Michael uh
turns up and does his thing and it's
amazing and he helps my training to get
better and uh and uh he's helped me a
lot actually over the last couple of
years. So, I really really appreciate
and for everybody involved. The document
is there. It's for you to to look at. Uh
and uh we hope you enjoy it and uh and
if there's anything that you want us to
improve, please let us know. Uh it's
collaborative. Uh there'll be lots of
discussions. Sometimes there'll be a
little bit too much noise going on
because remember we're people who have a
day job as well and you know this isn't
uh being funded by some major corporate
or anything like that. This is like just
a few people getting together. We'll do
the best we can. Sometimes what we do is
we write long form articles to just try
to make sure that when we're having
debates about things that we're talking
about the same thing and we invite
people to calls as well. So when we feel
there's a little bit of friction going
on, we'd like to set up some Teams calls
or Zoom calls or whatever to whatever
platform you're using so that uh we can
kind of understand your perspective more
because sometimes it gets that gets
lost. Nuance gets lost a bit sometimes.
Yeah, Gary was there as well when he was
trained as well as one of Michael's
retro Lego serious play uh trainer. So
yeah, thank you everyone for joining.
So, thank you Nigel, thank you uh
Martin, thank you Michael, thank you
everybody for being here and we hope you
enjoy the document. We hope you find it
useful and if there's something you
don't like, join the discussion and uh
maybe join the discussion before you uh
go on social media. I had a recent
document. Oh, I am only halfway through
the document. I just like to say well
maybe you should finish reading the
document or or I haven't read the
document yet but this is what I think.
Um no yeah I got one of those the other
day as well.
So read the document please. This is
shorter. It's uh it's manageable. So you
know just go through it and uh we put a
lot of thought into it. So if there's
something wrong the best place to talk
about improving it is on the site.
There's a join the discussion section.
That's a much better place much more
constructive than you know getting
clicks and all that kind of stuff in
social media. And you can still get the
clicks by the way because what you've
probably noticed already is that there
are contributors already on the site.
And so people who contribute
get recognition. So they're you uh you
contribute something you're also a
contributor to the stockman. So uh you
know that's a healthy way to maybe help
the community. Uh there's there's too
much arguing. Let's let's try and help
people fix problems and let's try to win
not win arguments. So thanks everyone
and uh yeah we'll leave you there and
thank you so much for your time and
looking forward to hearing what you
think. Thank you so much everyone.
Thanks.