I think I think one of my favorite
favorite sayings
um I don't know I don't know where I
heard it to be honest I think I've heard
it a few times from a few different
places
um but it's the that don't put down to
malevolence
what you can put down doing confidence
right
most of the time when you're working as
a as an agile coach in organizations or
a scrum master or a product owner or a
developer and people are
doing things in a way that negatively
affects your ability to do your job
right most of the time they're not doing
it because they're dicks right they're
not doing it with their dicks they're
doing it because they're measured
there's a there's there's a reason that
they're being measured in a way that
results in them making decisions that
have a negative outcome right or uh so
so somewhere in the organization there's
some level of incompetence that that
this decision has not been changed right
this measurement have not been changed
the old adage that hopefully nobody
still has in their organization is that
developers being measured by the number
of lines of code they write right we all
know that's a dumb thing to do because
especially if you're a developer because
what you do is you start copying and
pasting out Shakespeare into the
comments and then you end up with these
uh lots of lots of uh lots of light
lines of code you've written and in fact
um I've seen I've seen organizations do
the opposite as well
um the fewer lines of code
that you write right which is meant to
be somebody thought it would be a good
idea
because you want to optimize your code
as much as possible
but what you end up doing is you get a
bunch of people that go well it's not
raining but today then and I'll get my
bonus right so you have to you have to
people's people's behaviors
are directly related to the way you
measure
right
you you you think
it's the culture
right that that creates that so people
focus on changing the culture in an
organization but it's not the culture
the culture is just as the shadow on the
wall
of the measures for people reflecting
through people's activities and that's
the shadow in the wall right
so you can't you can't actually change
that you can't change culture you can't
affect culture change the way people are
measured
change the system
right and this if you change the system
the light will shift and the shadow will
change
so it's always a system problem it's
never actually the people are in the
middle
and they're just doing what the systems
telling them to do or the system's
encouraging them to do or or you know
like um
you know how sometimes you feel like
doing something is an uphill battle that
at every turn you're you're you're
sabotaged by somebody in your you know
you're trying I'm trying to ship this
product to production and you just get
sabotaged at every like oh we're gonna
be oh crap Here Comes compliance or you
know what whatever it is you're
sabotaged at every turn that's because
it's it's an uphill battle right
the system has created an uphill battle
because they don't want you to do that
you need to tip it the other way make it
easier
here's a perfect analogy for that
um why why do we have change requests
yes that's the way why do we have change
requests in in organizing you've got a
project you try to deliver your back
project and the customer comes along and
says our business has changed we need to
change what we're working on and we're
like well
here's the 5 000 page change request
form and the contract negotiation team
that come along with it to to help you
navigate this this problem and the
reason we do that is we don't want to
change anything because if we've got a
traditional project mindset you want to
plan out the project at the start you
want to minimize the variance in the
project and just deliver it right that's
that's we need to make 5000 widgets
you've placed an order for 5000 widgets
we're gonna make 5000 widgets and if you
come along later and say you only want
400 widgets that's tough we've already
committed to making 5000 you've signed
the contract right
that works great for factories right
because it protects both parties but it
totally sucks for building stuff that
doesn't exist yet
so this this this
malevolence that we sometimes feel
that is directed at us to inhibit our
ability to do stuff inhibit our ability
to get stuff done is is not male
elements at all it's it's the
incompetence of the system the system
has created this level of incompetence
in the people that results in that
shadow in the wall that we can't change
change the system always work on the
systems
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility