one of the seven signs of the agile
apocalypse is silence silence manifests
in many ways uh but it often manifests
as people not willing to speak up when
they see something wrong they're not
willing to speak up when they see uh uh
teams or people doing things that aren't
part of what we're trying to do they
don't speak up when uh decisions are
made that negatively impact the Val
delivery to the customer they don't
speak up when we lie to the customer by
saying that we can do something before
we've done it these are all things that
manifest as silence and silence is one
of the uh seven signs of the AG
apocalypse thanks for watching the video
If you enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked
agility