the thing that will completely sink your
Consulting engagement before it gets
started is the contract
um if your contract uh States
um exactly what needs to be delivered
when
um on what Cadence and how much it's
going to cost uh you're already screwed
right that that that's not the reality
of the unpredictable nature of building
products that don't exist yet
um and if you sign up to those contracts
you're you're you're just gonna have a
bad time
um make sure that you think about
how you don't want anything in your
contract that specifies exactly what
you're going to deliver and when you
want to be talking about the outcome
what is it you're trying to achieve and
what value are you going to deliver to
the customer
everything else is irrelevant