one of the things to teach a product
owner Apprentice is
negotiation negotiation is something
that as a product owner really as any
team member but especially as a product
owner you're going to be using
constantly um you're going to have to
negotiate with the developers on your
team you're going to have to negotiate
with your stakeholders you're going to
have to negotiate with leadership in
your organization if you as a product
owner want to be able to
influence the things in your
organization that affect your ability to
deliver value even if you don't control
them you need to understand how to
negotiate and engage with the people who
can so negotiation is really important
so as a product owner Apprentice there's
a great book um I'm trying to remember
the author uh but the title is never
split the difference a never split the
difference is about negotiation it's
written by the FBI's head hostage
negotiator for the last 20 years and he
talks about it as whether you're
negotiating bedtime for your kids or
negotiating hostage release is the same
tools and techniques that you use um he
has a a masterclass on
masterclass.com um and what you need to
consider as a product owner and if
you're helping out an apprentice product
owner they need to understand the
ramifications of the decisions that
they're making and how to engage in
communication that gets them to an
effective result right so just because a
a a stakeholder wants something even if
they're the CEO doesn't mean it's a good
idea to build it it just doesn't mean
it's a good idea to do it
but you might not be able to just say no
to that
person what are the tools and techniques
that you build as an individual to help
you make help you
enable that other person to withdraw the
request is the way I think about it
right you don't want to say no you want
them to say no um if so you might not
start with uh saying no you might start
with asking them questions about what it
is they expect to achieve from that
thing and when they don't know the
answers that could be a good indication
that it's not well thought through
perhaps you sit with them and do a lean
business canvas what information do they
need for example the CEO if you're an
apprentice product owner you're not
going to be able to say no to the CEO
what do they need to
understand themselves so that they say
no that that's what you need to enable
as a product owner you need to enable
their understanding so that they realize
that that's not the outcome that they're
trying to achieve and if you're you're
you want them to say yes to something if
you're the product owner asking for more
money or asking for new features or
asking for a different name for your
product or more budget whatever those
things are you don't want to start by
just asking a question that has a yes or
no response will you give me the money
for this no right you want to figure out
how do you get to yes and it's not
always a straight line that's what
negotiation is all about so this these
are fantastic
skills that you need to learn and we do
cover some of them in the professional
scrum product owner class uh we don't
dive that deeply right I mean we've got
a two-day class you can't really dive
too deep ly into some of these topics
but what we do cover is what is what are
the things that you need to understand
and where can you find the additional
information that you need to to engage
in longer term learning about this this
this topic or these stories and if
you're taking our immersive classes
right they have a lot more H assignments
to go and do in your organization so you
would be able to come back we can talk
about how you
engage with people in your organization
and how you improve those techniques
over time that's the value of
negotiation and as a product owner
Apprentice or as somebody who's getting
started as a product owner or even
you've been a product owner for a while
and you're struggling to engage with
people and
get that influence that you need to
maximize value those are the techniques
that you probably want to focus on
negotiation
techniques if you find it hard to learn
negotiation skills my team at naked
agility can help you find a product
ownership course or coach who can help
you or we can find somebody who can
don't let these sorts of issues
undermine your ability to deliver value
and get a help with them as soon as you
can use the links in the description to
get in touch