in
organizations leadership plays a pivotal
role in uh driving cultural and
organizational change um that enables
you to support the frequent and reliable
deployments across multiple teams and
there are a number of key things that
leadership probably wants to focus on or
at least try to see if it can have an
impact on these things one is setting
Clear Vision and goals um if you look at
Dan Pink's book drive around autonomy
Mastery and purpose purpose is a huge
part of that and setting Clear Vision
and
goals enables people to have purpose
they can see how the work that they're
doing every day um benefits the overall
organization worked to achieve those
goals so making making those connections
leaders can also invest in Automation
and
tooling if you want to do continuous
delivery to production it's going to
require a a number of things to happen
within your organization one of those
things is that you need to support that
ability to deliver faster right so if
you've got on Prem servers where on Prem
environments where if the developers ask
for a new environment it takes six weeks
for the operations team to to go buy the
hardware build that out deliver that
deliver that in some way then you're not
going to be able to move to continuous
delivery it's not possible right that's
a six week Blocker in the middle of that
six weeks constraint so um investing in
learning around these Technologies
Automation and tooling to be able to
support that to be able to sport teams
moving more quickly um automated
deployments automated building out of
environments automated everything right
then that that's one piece the other
piece is that the applications that you
currently have that you may have a
long-term strategy for right they're
going to be around for a long time may
not be architected in a way because
maybe they've been around for a long
time already may not be arch architected
in a way that's suitable for for
continuous Sol to to production that's
just reality right as you change the
demands you're putting on the product
you're going to have to change the
architecture of the product in order to
support the new demands that you're
putting on it so investing in the the
the time and effort for the teams to be
able to work towards those outcomes and
we're not talking about we're not going
to deliver any new features because
we're trying to do this we're talking
about enabling them to do a little piece
at a time um the the the the azured
devops team had uh some architectural
changes they needed to make in their
test infrastructure in order to reduce
their time to Market and to completely
clear off the old test infrastructure
took four years right we're not talking
about shorter time frame we're talking
about long-term products that exist in
the market as your devops the the
product that is as your devops was
originally released in the market in
2006 uh we're now in 202 five so it's 19
years that product has been in the
market been making them money been a
flagship product within that context and
visual studio has been a product for for
for for longer right these are long-term
products and they need long-term
thinking about investment in
architecture investment in refactoring
investment in Automation and in change
right because your needs your demands as
the business on engineering
the demands of the customer on
engineering are going to change over
time and you need to change your product
and invest in changing your product to
support that so that really comes back
to to this idea of continuous learning
and Improvement not just on in on your
plate as Leaders but also on the
engineering team's plate are are you
putting your engineers under so much
time pressure that their biggest problem
is getting stuff out the door or
do they have time to to talk about and
discuss how what they need to learn how
they need to change the product um the
refactors that they have to do or when
they start talking about those things is
the immediate answer no we don't have
time to do that because we've got to Shi
some features that's a losing
proposition absolutely a losing
proposition it's not a short-term losing
proposition but it's a long-term losing
proposition there there is no way to win
uh
cutting short-term
quality cutting quality for short-term
wins rather than long-term wins
so those things together as Leaders
along with I there's loads of things you
could do you you could you could you
could break down silos in the
organization so if you have coding uh
hierarchy and test
hierarchy anytime you've got a a a test
manager and a Dev manager and then you
get team members that are reporting to
multiple people because they've got the
team that they're on and perhaps a
product manager that they're dealing
with and then they've got their Dev
manager as a line manager and other
people in the team have their test
manager as a line manager that's a mess
right that that's that's complicated
that's people being pulled in different
directions that's teams having more
difficulty more friction in working
together towards a common goal than in
not working together towards a common
goal right because there's more uh
things pulling them in different
directions so breaking down silos um and
ultimately leading by example people are
going to look to their leaders to see
how are we expected to behave within the
context of this organization and our
leaders need to present that example
that we can use to to to
to build that culture of collaboration
and Trust within our organization