so in addition to
our mentoring and Consulting programs we
also provide
training um the purpose of training is
to teach those
underlying um Theory and
principles with practices actionable
practices that people can use and that's
kind of why I do scrum.org based
training because
their philosophy around training is
about understanding the core Theory and
principles like here's the first
principles of what it is we're trying to
achieve um then building on top of that
here's the thing right so you're you're
you're learning the thing and then what
are the additional um processes and
practices complimentary processes and
practices that can use on top of that um
to do to do more to be to to to to get
the value out of it that people are
expecting to get and I one of the main
reasons I I I liked scrum.org was
because of that story because of the the
community of trainers the people that
that it gave me access to to discuss and
collaborate on how do we understand
these things how do we communicate these
things how do we enable them to to be as
effective as possible within uh uh
organizations um but the two-day
training format that was pre pandemic
was really good for the trainer right
because you fly in somewhere you do two
days training and then you fly out um
but not so good for the customer because
if you've got a bunch of people who are
struggling to deliver value right in
your organization and you spend two days
teaching them scrum where's the rest of
that story right if if if they're still
under pressure after that two-day class
then how how are they actually able to
do to do anything to action any of those
things and time goes by and then they've
forgotten most of what it is that
they've they've learned that's why I
think they say only 10% of of things you
learn in that format are actually stick
right so you put 20 people through the
class they all remember a different 10%
of the course cuz it's what matters to
them or impacts them they maybe
Implement 2% of that so you get a 2% net
gain um of Knowledge from that two-day
class but if we um change that format up
this is why we've moved um towards the
the the immersive learning format um and
incorporating it in a that story as well
into a bigger bigger Mentor program is
that um
even even if even if that 2% was all
that was
true you're then
2% compounded over multiple sessions
right so rather than having two full
days uh let's say we did eight half days
right so we've got eight half days over
a longer period of time and even if we
still got that 2% actionable change we
get 2% and then compound it with another
2% and then compound it with another 2%
because there's a gap in between and
there's an assignment for people to go
do inside the organization but I believe
that that format is a heck of a lot more
than remembering just a 10% because
we're only learning a couple of hours
worth of stuff we're not learning 16
hours worth of stuff and then you have
to try and remember a percentage of that
16 hours we're
remembering from that two hours worth of
stuff that we've we we've researched and
talked about and collaborated on to
understand that teaching part and then
they have to go and try and apply
something in that context within their
organization and yes everybody's going
to learn still going to learn something
different people are all going to retain
different things but even if it was
again just learning the 10% it's 10% of
two hours plus 10% of two hours plus 10%
of two hours so the end percentage for
the same learning content is is much
more powerful much more effective like s
orders of magnitude uh uh more effective
for
organizations and because they get the
assignment to go try and do things
within their
organization um during that time they've
also provided actionable value for the
organization so think of it like that
iterative process in scrum where we we
do a Sprint and then we deliver usable
working product we've got a a learning
exercise then at the end of that
learning exercise they go deliver usable
working product within the organization
they just need to figure out what is the
use you know we give them an assignment
but it's it can be quite vague right we
give them lots of different ways to
resolve that assignment um they pick
something they try it in the
organization they've made a change that
change either was successful or it
wasn't it was either able to be
implemented or it hit a roadblock and
then we come when we come back around
we're able to um
debrief that activity that they did so
they then get feedback and engagement
closing that feedback loop right on how
you know what did you manage to change
how effective was it in your
organization what roadblocks do you hit
how do you get past those roadblocks
what have other people tried and even
especially when you you put a big group
through that within your
organization you you even get
cross-pollination and cross learning
because one person or one group within
the bigger group says we weren't able to
do that because this doesn't work in our
organization and the other groups like
well actually we were a we were able to
speak to this person and this person and
get this to happen so we were able to do
this which got us halfway there and that
cross-pollination and learning is hugely
important to that to that story and and
it works great across organizations as
well when you have multiple
organizations participating so that
that's moving towards that immersive
format so we kind of started in the
two-day format we then moved into the
four half day format then into the 8we
immersive format and now moving into the
the the kind of more Mentor program uh
maybe over over well from from eight to
50 weeks right of of that program um
with sessions and workshops and
different things going on I think
um this is the game Cher for
organizations because we're not just
giving you the information we're
collaborating and working with you to
help you implement it over a longer
period of time