that's a great question so the question
is how does a scrum team estimate uh
what can be delivered in a single Sprint
and the ultimate answer is maybe the
don't
um the scrum guide does not have the
word estimate or estimation appear
anywhere within its contents
it uses the word size
the team should be able to understand
the size of things on their product
backlog and which is not quite the same
as estimate
um estimation is a is a great tool there
are various estimation tools and
techniques that teams can use
I generally use those tools and
techniques to help teams understand the
things on the put it back look better
because I find it's much more valuable
much more important to have the
developers and the product owner and the
stakeholders understand things than it
does to say it's going to do this amount
of time right because ultimately if we
say it's going to take this amount of
time we're talking at our butt there's
there's no way for us to know how long a
creative piece of work is going to take
it's just not possible think to yourself
I I I'd like you to to write a book on
the topic of uh leadership in the United
Kingdom political leadership in the
United Kingdom them how long would it
take you to write that I want you to
tell me off off the top of your head how
long will it take you to write that you
don't know you can't answer that
question you could probably take a rough
guess but you might be orders of
magnitude under or orders of magnitude
over because you don't know whether
you're going to get writer's block you
don't know whether you're gonna not be
able to find a critical piece of
information that your brain thinks you
need you don't you don't know any of
those things you can't predict those
things so the the the the the surprises
that happen when you're Building
Products
things you don't know and give you a
very high level of variance so the idea
that you can estimate things you don't
know how to do yet
um is is just ridiculous it's very
different from the story of
um if I asked uh electrician to estimate
how much it will cost to rewire my house
that's something that they probably can
estimate because they've done houses
like mine before right they've they've
my house is not that much different from
anybody else's house the way you wire is
not different from anybody else's house
when you're building a product that
doesn't exist yet
the tools and techniques and practices
and ideas and architectures and ways of
doing things don't exist yet you have to
come up with those and that's where
those surprises come in
um so how can a team estimate what can
be delivered in a Sprint I think they
take a guess like everybody else does
that's why you're you're your Sprint
goal should never be the whole Sprint it
should only be part of the Sprint
because you might be you might be wrong
you might think this will take two of
the 10 days that you have in your
two-week Sprint and actually it takes
five okay well we've we've we've built
that in by having a Sprint goal that's
much more targeted and we are going to
drop some of the other stuff that we
brought into the Sprint that we thought
we we would be able to do but maybe we
can't the Sprint
so the answer ultimately is you don't
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility