every shortcut adds to your technical
debt Every time you skip quality
standards every time you fudge what done
means you're not saving time You're
creating future rework A weak definition
of done means your increment isn't truly
usable It means production risks hidden
failures and uncertainty It means you
can't trust what you've built At Naked
Agility we help teams create a strong
enforcable definition of done ensuring
every increment is shippable usable and
backed by real evidence Not just built
but delivering real insights Not just
working but meeting organizational and
strategic goals Weak delivery isn't
about missing features It's about
missing outcomes missing feedback and
missing trust Ready to stop paying the
hidden costs of weak delivery