[Music]
[Applause]
hi my name is Martin Hinshelwood I'm the
owner at Naked agility and I'm a
professional scrum trainer and Microsoft
MVP I'm running a professional agile
leadership essentials twenty-seventh
till the 30th of July over four half
days from 9:00 a.m. till 12:30 at CES T
which is 8:00 a.m. till 11:30 British
summer time professional agile
leadership essentials is a hands-on
workshop that uses a combination of
instruction and hands-on exercises to
help managers and other leaders who work
directly with agile teams understand how
best to support guide and coach their
teams to improve their agile
capabilities so join us on the 27th and
30th of July for four half days 9:00
a.m. until 12:30 c EST
[Music]
you