there's a number of migration services
that we we offer um they're kind of
related as two sets of of tools there's
there's Martin as your devops migration
tools which is uh on GitHub and
available for people to use but we help
people use it we do it for customers um
when they don't want to learn it
themselves so that's the um more
targeted migration tool so I want to
move I want to stuff I want to merge
stuff
um so that's that's that's the actual
moving individual work items around
that's what I want to do then then
that's our one of our services the other
one is a kind of managed import into
Azure devops uh Microsoft have a tool
called the Azure devops data migration
tool and that data migration tool takes
the whole thing