the third most powerful practice in
caman is improving your
workflow it's all well and good to have
your visualization so you can see
everything that's going on it's all well
and good to actively manage The Works
through the
system but if your system's broken or
your system could be
improved and you don't do
anything that's not not going to Bod
well for the future right so improving
the workflow making changes to the
system in order to maximize the flow of
value through the system can help us
prevent things like blockages and uh uh
things backing up in the system things
getting old in the system once you've
identified why those things are
happening you need to actually do
something you need to actually change
the system in order to make those things
more
effective so many so many so many teams
will just sit there and they'll
understand that there's a problem with
the system and they'll just say well we
can't do anything about it that's that's
Bob Bob Bob is is is getting in the way
and Bob is not doing something he's
supposed to do in a regular Cadence um I
wor worked with a team uh in the US and
what we we had the caman board on the
wall right and we couldn't change this
part of the system okay because it was
it was our caman but we had a
dependency right that might be something
you actively manage away uh we had a
dependency on on somebody else and it
was basically an approval state right so
stuff would go through our system and
then at this point it had to be approved
and then it would continue through our
system and the person who did the
approvals didn't want to look at the
board every day didn't want to approve
stuff every day so he did weekly
approvals he would every I can't
remember what day it was let's say it's
Monday every Monday he opens up the
board uh Monday morning he opens up the
board and approves the things that need
approved but what if we finish something
Monday
afternoon that sits there for seven days
before it gets approved so what started
doing our our board was this we were
quite it was quite lucky our board was
on the wall in the main area of our our
our business right in the corridor where
everybody was going past like everybody
the CEO CFO everybody would go past this
board and what we did was in that column
just at the bottom of that column we
started adding Post-its in there that
listed Financial numbers we kind of came
up with a calculation this was part of
our actively managing how much does it
cost for things to be sitting waiting to
be approved and we started putting that
cost in there and those numbers would go
up uh towards the end of the the week
and then they would go to zero on Monday
and then they would start building up
again and go to zero and start building
up again and we had a little graph
showing showing that that flow of that
bad flow of work through the system and
at some point that person whose job it
was to approve walked past that board
and kind of had a double take and kind
of went what what are these what are
these
numbers and we just explained that's the
cost of these items sitting there and
waiting that's our weight time cost so
we thought we would put it on the board
because this is where one of our bigger
costs is and what happened that person
changed their behavior almost
immediately and started
checking every morning for anything that
was blocked or needed approved in fact I
think at one point they were checking
every morning and every end of day so
that everything was just blowing through
the system and that was the single
biggest uh cost benefit that that team
had in a six six Monon period was
reducing that cost of delay of things
sitting there and not being approved
when they were in fact valid they were
in fact approvable IE they would be
approved uh um and it just waiting so
changing your workflow or creating a
situation within which that workflow is
changed is one of the three most
important principles of a caman strategy
that the things you have to have in
caman if you're struggling to implement
a camman strategy
we can help or we can find somebody who
can click the link below and get in
touch