so I get a lot of questions about the
difference between traditional
management versus evidence-based
management um I'm not I'm not sure the
term traditional applies uh it's
interesting I I um had a book on
evidence-based management practices um
that I gave to my father about 10 years
ago when he was asking me what the heck
is it that you do and um I gave him this
this uh
book radical
management and he read the book and he
said oh that's what I've been doing for
the last 40 years in my company that's
the type of things trying to change the
organization and um um move people in a
particular direction and do all those
things so uh
maybe that's why traditional like if
people have been doing it 40 years ago
80 years ago then
it's the common management the the the
normal way people approach things
evidence-based management is
hard right if we're talking about the
differences between uh traditional
classic the way most people do things
common cause right um evidence-based
management is hard evidencebased
management is uh we have to collect data
we have to read the data and we have to
make informed
decisions how
uh uh uh most management decisions are
made are one of two
ways make it up I'm just going to decide
I'm the manager I'm the boss I will
decide and I make a decision right or I
ask somebody more senior to me to make
the decision right so escalation based
uh uh uh decision making and both are
bad both are bad we we we shouldn't be
making um decisions on multi-million
dollar Things based on or even smaller
than that right but based on just making
it up um we want to be asking why are we
doing this thing what do we hope the
outcome's going to be and how are we
going to measure it right we want
evidence to know that's why when we're
in court we don't make decisions based
on how we feel today right we collect a
bunch of evidence um we present that
evidence to a a group of people and a
group of people Analyze That evidence in
including you know not evidence Parts as
well how they feel about it how they
think about
it and they put it together into
something that is a coherent a coherent
decision um and that's what we would
like to see in in in management today
um most
[Music]
managers um
trying do evidence based decision
making unfortunately the evidence that
they choose to
accept um is generally whatever the
easiest data it is to collect um most of
that resolve revolves around s do
metrics right original estimate actuals
how far off course are way um people
talk about scope creep well you said you
were going to do this and it's changed
to this therefore the scope has changed
or
um oh what geez it's that that
traditional look at data
[Music]
um is
very what's a good way to describe it
vanity metrics that's the expression
I've not used in a while vanity metrics
are are the biggest part of this I I
want to create
metrics um for me as a manager I want to
have metrics that make me look
good I want to keep my job I want to um
perhaps get promoted um so I want to
create metrics that make me look good
that's that would be nice so uh that's
the ones I'm going to focus on that's
the ones I'm going to judge my um people
people that report to me by is the
metrics that I think make me look good
and unfortunately metrics that make you
look good right
suboptimal metric we're we're looking at
one part of the puzzle me right my me as
a manager I'm looking at one part of the
puzzle and I'm trying to make a decision
on how I measure Things based on one
part of the
puzzle but is my decision going to be
good for the whole thing for the whole
organization for the whole uh product or
organization team whatever it is um at
whatever level you're playing at is is
that going to be the right metric that's
going to help progress the the the the
outcomes the impacts the the goals that
we're trying to have as an organization
the vision um or is it just making me
look good and that's a suboptimal a
suboptimal metric we're not looking at
the whole system just part of the system
um and that's really common I see that
with story points and velocity right
ridiculous uh metrics to look at outside
of the context of internal to the team
um sry points and velocity can be useful
inside of a team actually I would maybe
disagree with my own statement there but
they might be useful within that context
but outside of the team no use
whatsoever any manager that makes a
decision based on velocity um any
product owner that makes a decision
based on velocity um you know sum of
story points per Sprint or some of tasks
whatever it is um it's just mental
that's vanity metrics that's we're
trying to make the Met massage the
metrics to make ourselves look good and
that's really the big difference between
traditional management and evidencebased
management evidence-based management is
about the evidence we're going to
collect the evidence we're going to try
and validate that evidence right is it
good evidence or is it bad evidence um
and then we're going to try and make
decisions based on on it rather than
just making stuff up