so the question is how do you decide
whether you pivot or stay the course and
this is something that quite often will
need to make a decision at either at the
Sprint review or pretty pretty close
pretty close after it where the product
owner
um decides whether we're going to Pivot
and change direction based on what we
learned
um cancel the whole thing
or or or we need to we need to stay the
course and I think
um it I mean it's going to depend on an
awful lot of factors there's loads of
things that the product owner is going
to have to take into account
um what the what the business wants the
direction the business is going uh what
the stakeholders want if they're
separate groups
um what the customers want and what
direction is going and what the team
wants as well and what the state of the
current state of the product so all of
that information kind of comes into this
funnel and then you have to make that
decision and sometimes the right
decision is to is to walk away
so sometimes that's going to be the
right decision
and it actually you you wanna you wanna
be really careful and avoid the the sunk
cost fallacy
right where if you've invested so much
money in something
um that you you you feel like you can't
let it go and you have to keep moving it
Forward
um I worked at a a bank here in the UK
called intelligent Finance
um and they were anything but by the way
it was an oxymoron but they had this
this XML based uh form generation system
and they invested so much money in it
that they had to use it and they kept
using it going forward even though it
was demonstratively and arguably the
wrong uh implementation that there are
better ways to solve the problem
um that that when it was solved at the
time right that was the right way and I
think that's an example of staying the
course when you shouldn't stay the
course
right that should just be let's figure
out how to solve this problem a
different way that's that's more more
effective
another great example probably one of my
favorites is is is Nokia right Microsoft
bought Nokia
um and Satya had to make a choice right
do we do we stay the course do we keep
moving forward
or um do we pivot right maybe we do
something a little bit different or do
we have to just abandon it
um and his choice uh based on all the
information he had at the time was to to
abandon it which was probably the right
choice to make but that was what uh
eight nine billion dollar write-off
of of investment Microsoft had just
bought it
um And he as soon as he came in as CEO
he actually there's there's if you've
read his book
um he he arrived at Microsoft just too
late to stop the deal
um he didn't want the deal to go through
at all and it was too late for it to
stop so it was immediately upon the
purchase
um he's like we're gonna have to we're
gonna have to write this down we're
gonna have to write it off
um and the implications are huge right
because that has implications are at
that level that has implications on
share price it has implications on other
companies on vendors on
um all of the companies that have built
up uh uh things that they were building
on top or delivering in combination with
um Windows phone and yeah they had to
they just had to kill it
so as a product owner
you're accountable right in that case
Satya was the product owner product
owner for Microsoft the CEO
um hopefully your decisions won't be as
big or as scary as that but they can be
as big and scary within the context of
what it is that that you're doing and
you
it's your call right
um and you need to make that call with
incomplete information if you wait long
enough that you've gotten all the
information you need it might be too
late
so sometimes you have to make that call
place that bet or fold
um when when based on the information
you have based on your gut you've got
the data available and then add your gut
feel to it what do you think is going to
happen and work for probabilities
um so don't keep investing in something
that you don't believe is going anywhere
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility