technical Excellence is one of the most
important Concepts When You're Building
Products uh scrum talks about this in
that um you're you should always have a
usable working product at the end of
every iteration um agile talks about
this um the idea is that in order to
mitigate risk we need to create usable
working product so in
the the the the more linear model right
where we know lots of stuff up front
let's say we were going to build three
300 houses on a on a construction site
um we know a lot up front we know
exactly what designs of the houses we're
going to have we've probably had to get
planning permission right so these
things a lot of that is locked in um for
what it is we're going to do so we know
how much materials how much wood how
much plaster we know when we're going to
do certain things on s or mostly when
right there's some variant but not a lot
of variants so when there's low variance
we mitigate Risk by doing more planning
right we we we we we plan up front we
create a bunch of documents around that
planning um we um create here's a list
of risks that might happen um if this
risk happens here's the mitigating
action we're going to have here's the
percentage likelihood that that risk is
going to happen um and we'll maintain
that data over time right so um we
create this whole body of material and
planning and dates and things around
that story and that's great when
variance is low um and that allows us to
mitigate the risk right because if
you're going to spend I don't know uh 20
million uh building
this area of houses um then then need to
plan for that but even even then you're
going to take a little bit of an agile
approach right you're not going to build
all the houses at once and then sell
them all at once you're going to build a
few houses and sell them and a few
houses and sell them because you're
testing the market and you're seeing and
you might then even need to apply for
different planning permission to change
your mind so there's still a lot of
variance in that story I do get that for
those that um are in that industry but
in general right old school you're
you're you're kind of making that those
decisions up
front but when we have high variants
which as I just noted can happen in the
building industry as well but when we
have high variants we um can't mitigate
Risk by writing everything down and
creating a story for every single thing
that might maybe happen because every
single thing that might maybe happen is
going to change every day right think of
the
the I like to I like to think of the the
the the Multiverse right you've got all
those decision points that happen and
every time you make a decision and go
down A New Path a whole different set of
decision points and problem points and
issue points occur so every time you
made one of those decisions every time
you made one of those little changes you
would need to rebuild all of that body
of asset and it's just not reasonable to
do that it puts too much of a um
overhead on uh uh people time everything
and you end up
with that story of the plan not being
able to the plan itself not being able
to keep up with the reality of the world
therefore we then make bad decisions
because we can't really see what's going
on and so we're not mitigating risk at
all
but in that high variance world we
mitigate Risk by creating a usable
working product on a regular Cadence
right that's how we mitigate the risk we
deliver something we create that thing
that the customer is looking for and we
offer it to them for inspection so they
can look at it and see yeah yeah yeah
you're doing the right thing or oh what
I don't understand why you made those
decisions great that's a great
conversation right so in order to be
able to have a usable working product at
the end of every iteration and I I do
want to point out this this is not a
pipe dream this is not a ideal World
thing um I I I want you to all go look
up um the
DI uh the US Department of Defense di
article on detecting agile [ __ ] um
it was an article that a paper that was
sent out to every procurement officer in
the the the I think it was the Air Force
um to let them know what they need to
look for
when they're working with vendors right
when they're buying stuff from
vendors so that they can make better
purchasing decisions this vendor is
telling me telling me that they're agile
how do I know that they're agile I'm a
Layman I don't understand necessarily
understand agile I don't necessarily
understand that new world how do I
ensure that I'm buying the right thing
and this article lays out a whole bunch
of questions um that enable that person
to at least start getting some insight
and one of the key questions um and this
is like the first one for for for
leadership was um are H uh versions do
you have a working version of your
product every iteration including the
first that gets into the hands of real
users real users not uat not fake users
not test environments real
users every iteration including the
first
so if you're doing two we iterations um
then at the end of the first two weeks
you should have a usable working
product that's how we mitigate risk in
the agile and scrum space that's how we
ensure that um when people give us money
we're actually delivering something that
will be valuable for them right um and
that's really hard hard if our our our
software our product the quality of our
product is terrible that's that's really
hard can you can you imagine trying even
if you were building houses right uh and
um you're you're there's there's broken
broken joists there's things not
attached properly there's leaky pipes
there's flooding we've not built the
house properly and we're trying to hand
that house over to the customer and have
the customer come in and look at it and
the customer's like well this is this is
Terri what I'm not going to buy
this that that's where engineering
Excellence comes in that's where
technical Excellence comes in um we want
to build things that actually work we
want to deliver less stuff up front
right in the in the fictional you know
that old phrase um
20% so is it 80% of the work takes 20%
of the time and the last 20% takes 80%
of the time
that is because our quality was bad
that's because we didn't have technical
excellence in what it was that we were
doing so we got that 80% of the
functionality we've done it looks like
it works but actually behind the scenes
it's a total mess spaghetti absolute
garbage and the customer comes along and
tries to use it and they're like oh we
need to fix this we need to fix that and
you end up hatching right you're getting
out the sticky tape and super glue and
trying to figure out how do we patch
this together and then they're like oh I
don't like the way this works you can't
rebuild it because it's part of the
fundamental architecture so you have to
add another layer of uh OB Fusion on top
to make it look like it works the way
the customer wanted it to work but
actually behind the scenes it just works
the way the developers originally built
it to work and now we've got extra
complexity we've got something that is
more difficult to maintain more
difficult to understand and you can
imagine that over time that builds up on
top and you end up with massive amounts
of funking layers appar effectively that
um inhibit your ability to deliver value
and that's something that I I would I
would quantify um with some some
some data I do a lot of presentations on
how the Azure devops team that's the
team at Microsoft that built the Azure
devops product um they in 2012 they were
technically a waterfall team they were
delivering once every two years to
production and they moved almost
overnight towards uh uh continuous
delivery and uh uh 3- week iterations
right so they were delivering usable
working product every three weeks they
were shipping to production every 3
weeks um and they've delivered every 3
weeks for the past I don't know
26 3 week Sprints right um
so back in 2012 with 650 people they
were delivering around 24 features to
production each year and part of the
reason that that number is quite low 24
features is that one the features were
really big but also the
the difficulty in adding the
features and
interacting with the code base in order
to get the product to do the things that
you wanted it to do was really difficult
because you had all those little layers
of things that had built on top and this
doesn't quite work the way it was
supposed to I think aure devops was
originally team Foundation server if you
remember those days and team Foundation
server was originally a bunch of other
products that were Native inside of
Microsoft um they had Source control
uh in-house Source control products they
had in-house work item tracking products
they had in-house other stuff um and
that was kind of cooled together in
order to um create the first version of
Team Foundation server now I'm sure so
lots of stuff was Rewritten and but
you've got that
fundamental architectural mindset right
even though you're rewriting something
you you're you're taking something else
so actually the the the genetics of that
product is is is quite long quite old um
and then you get to that point where
you're switching
from needing two years to get a piece of
functionality working
um to needed three weeks to get a piece
of functionality
working so they moved to this new model
and in uh 2012 they're delivering about
24 features to production um they then
focused
absolutely the majority of their
time maybe going majority is probably
too much their primary focus was on um
paying back technical debt building in
technical Excellence solving those
Effectiveness problems right of of
moving to that new model both in both in
their process and in in the product as
well and by 2018 they were delivering
280 features to production each year
with with the same number of people so
from 24 features to production 24
experiments 24 new features to try and
see if the customer likes to
280 new features the customer
experiments to try things that might
work and might help the customer now yes
those things were smaller right um but
they were also delivered
faster um
and that focus on technical Excellence
enables us to do that um if we don't
have technical excellence in the way we
do things then it just doesn't work I I
did a recent interview with Dan Helm who
was who is the the he runs as your
boards the work item tracking part of
the part of the
system and when uh he was quizzed on
definition of done and how that works he
didn't really have a solid answer and
that's because technical Excellence is
so baked into the way they do everything
at that level like all the engineers
know what it is they need to do what
level of quality is required um they
know um all of those all of those
things that they don't need to um they
don't need to focus on it right it's
just the way they do Business technical
Excellence engineering quality is just
the norm it's not an exception which
means that they can then focus on on
delivering value to the customer they've
reduced risk and they can focus on
delivering value they can focus on those
other things that's what technical
Excellence brings for um a product for
product management for product
leadership is the ability for them to
stop focusing on fighting fires on
fixing bugs on struggling with
complexity on being frustrated that they
can't get certain features done because
it's just too hard to do within the
architecture of the product and you
start focusing on the art of the
possible what is it we can do where are
we going what are we trying to achieve
you can then let go of those things
because you're no longer having to ride
that
quality that's a terrible analogy but
you're no longer having to to hold on
for dear life uh while this product
bucks around um you're you're you're
you're now in the in in the groove it's
smooth it's we're adding features we're
building capabilities we're we're we're
building an awesome product and that
that's part of that that that story of
mitigating risk building te technical
Excellence there's a myth as well
there's a huge myth in the software
industry that it's okay to sacrifice
some quality in order to go faster and
meet the market need um there's a recent
article I think it was a har Business
review article it might not have been
but it might have been a Forbes article
um but there's some studies done around
that idea of and what happens when we
cut quality in order to go faster right
and what's the trade-offs involved in
that and the ultimate outcome was that
it it it's not a valid tradeoff you have
M the the the impact of that reduction
in quality is much higher than the
benefit you get from being able to go
fast over the short term um so that a
cruel cuz a cruel of let's call let's
let's call it two things there's undone
work stuff that you need to do in order
for your product to run in production
that hasn't been done yet right that's
that 8020 thing that's where that pit
comes from and then there's technical
debt which is
shortcuts that deliberate shortcuts that
we make in order uh um that we do things
in a suboptimal way within the product
that's technical debt right um so both
of those things added together don't
acre linearly right it's an exponential
acre and that's where that Azure devops
team was at the start they were at the
top of that exponential curve only
delivering 24 features to production
each year but in focusing
almost H um
religiously Zealot like on paying back
that technical debt of getting rid of
all of that undone work and bringing
that curve back down to a manageable
level right and Beyond get it towards
trending towards zero right we want to
have as high quality effective a product
as possible they they actually in one
year nearly tripled the number of
features delivered to production even
though their main focus was on let's do
it right let's pay back the technical
debt they actually delivered more stuff
so that goes go reduced quality to go
fast is a losing prop proposition it
always has been a losing proposition
definitely do that what you want to do
is focus on technical Excellence if you
don't have a definition of done create
one if
your
organization doesn't have a definition
of done which it should your
organization um should be thinking about
from a technical Excellence perspective
what is the minimum level of quality we
as a business
require in order to have a product that
is fit for Mar fit for purpose right um
protects our brand our business as a
whole this product is representing our
brand or is or or or however that works
representing your brand um protecting
the people that are using it and
protecting like uh the the the um uh
post office scandal in the UK right
protecting the people that are using it
protecting your employees and your
developers right to make sure that
there's there that everything's done
right that right you don't want um like
think about boing right the reduction in
quality is just now seeping out um and
what what else do you need in order to
have a viable product in your Market in
your situation right so different levels
for different markets that's the
business's requirement for done and
we're not talking about feature there's
there's a big
um conflation I think
between features being feature complete
and quality engineering Excellence is
about quality it's not about having the
features right so let's take that put
that aside the what we're building we're
going to take that aside and we're going
to focus on the how we're building it do
we have the level of quality required to
meet compliance do we have the level of
quality required um to meet the the the
the the testing level that we we want do
we have the amount of telemetry in there
to see what's going on all of those
things are part of that that definition
of done which has nothing to do with the
features on only focusing on the quality
of the product um and that enshrines
your engineering Excellence so if the
organization doesn't have that standard
um it's the developers the scrum team
that or the developers that are charged
with creating one that is relevant for
your product um and significant enough
that you're going to be able to create a
usable working product every Sprint and
the reason you have a more usable
working product is to mitigate that risk
and um build out your engineering
Excellence so don't get left behind
don't get bugged down in the Quagmire of
engineering inferiority focus on
engineering Excellence build the best
product you can and maximize the value
to your customers