a good question so how can companies
derive a greater benefit from training
if they invest in a private course
rather than just sending people
piecemeal to public classes I I think
it's an interesting question and I think
it's because
um ultimately because you're able in the
context of that class to air your dirty
laundry a little bit more than than if
you go to a public class
um I always try and create a safe space
in public classes that people feel that
they're able to talk about things that
are happening in their company and
everybody else in the rooms going to you
know kind of pretend they didn't hear it
afterwards type of thing so that we can
we can talk about things but you don't
feel as comfortable as perhaps you can
be within the boundaries of a single
organization and quite often and I've
had this with with certain private
classes where
um I I'm talking about
professional scrum and I'm talking about
continuous delivery to production and
I'm talking about unit testing and I'm
talking about uh just all of those
things around around devops and agile
and
there are people in the room that will
say we can't do that here because of XYZ
and what's very interesting is you'll
have somebody in the room that says well
actually on our team we are able to do
that
and say okay well why can this team do
that in your organization but these
teams believe they can't
right that can be an important
discussion to have because if somebody
can do it you can pretty much all do it
right
um the the that that so dirty laundry
that realization of the possible
through talking to other people in your
organization if everybody in the group
is on the same team it's also a little
bit different I've done agile leadership
classes with the whole leadership team
for uh for an organization and that
brings up interesting conversations and
quite often their conversations that the
participants believe they should have
they should have already had right why
do I need to come to this training to
have these conversations but that it's
that they weren't provoked right it's
comfortable to to not have those
conversations do the same thing that
we've always done
um you know running running on the
treadmill getting getting things done
but sometimes you need somebody to
provoke you into thinking differently
provoke you into thinking about how you
do things and I think that's the same is
true for for Consulting and training but
especially for private training there's
a lot of provoking and asking difficult
questions and maybe the questions they
don't want to answer right because in
not one thing to answer it they realize
they realize something about themselves
as well so that for me is the added
value to private classes is that there's
a lot more Candor then maybe there might
be in a public class
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility