have you ever encountered the product
owner as an agile Bandit I have um I
worked with a product owner uh quite
some years ago um that believed that if
every single person on the
team just followed their detailed plan
and Gant chart with start times and end
times for all of the tasks if everybody
just followed that everything would work
out perfectly and the only reason it
doesn't work out perfectly is because
people don't follow his
plan that is an agile
Bandit a product owner is not a project
manager they're not uh uh looking at um
task to time they're focused on goals
and outcomes and what is it we're trying
to achieve and we've hired these super
smart H uh people to be able to deliver
these amazing products and a product
owner should be focused on Vision value
and validation where is it we're going
what is it we get out of
it and have we managed to actually get
there and in order for a product owner
to focus on those things they perhaps
need to let go of some of the things
that they've used in the past and focus
instead on enabling the team uh the
people around the product to be an
Engaged happy group of people have have
you ever met a sad unhappy group of
people that made amazing products or did
amazing things as a team I bet you
haven't cuz they don't exist happy
engaged people build great products and
if you've got a product owner who's
focused laser focused
on task and uh work breakdown you are
not going to have a happy engaged team
that is connected to the story that
we're trying to tell as a product that
person is an agile Bandit they shouldn't
be a product owner at all um they just
just it was just ter you should see the
team the team was just in a complete
mess that they they just didn't care all
they cared about was delivering stuff
I've got these things on my task list I
need to deliver these things or I'm
going to be in trouble from the product
owner there was no team so don't destroy
your team with agile banditry as a
product owner stop it if you're being
ambushed by agile bandits in your
organization then my team at naked
agility can help you or we can help you
find somebody who can you can set up a
no obligation consultation using the
links below don't forget to like And
subscribe if you enjoyed the video