How do you think Agile is evolving
since its inception in 2001?
I think it's been evolving steadily,
although often unfortunately not
in the way we would like.
I think...
That one of the whole purposes
of Agile and the Agile Manifesto
and the ideas behind it,
forget the names of the things,
right? The ideas behind it, is
that we're trying to move away
from those top-down steering
departmental organizations
towards something
that's more decentralized
and democratized, right?
So that we can respond better
to what's happening in the market.
And that's just not been happening.
Most organizations,
even those that say
that they're doing agile,
that even I would look
at and say, yeah,
they're doing pretty well, right?
Are actually still hierarchical steering
and budget comes from the top type
of organizations.
People aren't making that leap,
which I think it is a leap
from steering
towards decentralization.
And I think that's the
evolution that's happening now.
You're seeing a lot of movements
now talking about Agile 2.0,
talking about rewilding
of Agile,
right?
And those ideas are around, let's kind
of get back to the original ideas
which is getting rid
of these monolithic processes
that are perhaps getting
in the way of the standardized processes
which are getting in the way of
our ability to deliver value to
our customers and engage with our market
in a way that is dynamic and fast,
right?
And
that I think is the new struggle
is how do we get back to those topics.
And I think one of the things
that I've been trying
to do is use less agile terminology,
right? Because most
people I think are fed up
of hearing agile this,
agile that, mindset this, mindset that,
and they think it's just all a big pile
of bollocks now because it's not worked
for them.
But the reality is
that they haven't been doing it,
which is part of what's
not working for them, right?
It causes more friction to try
and create decentralization
and democratization
within the bounds of an organization
that is inherently command and control.
You're just going to
cause lots of friction
and then things aren't going to happen
and command and control wins.
So I think that, yeah,
I think that's the big change
or the big push that we're looking
at now and how Agile has changed,
it's gone through that phase
of not actually providing a lot of value
or nibbling at the edges
of providing value for organizations
and now we're starting to
see more organizations move
to embracing more of the underlying
concepts of empiricism,
self-organization,
decentralization and democratization.