technical debt is something that adds a
massive cost to your product and the way
you do things but I want to be really
clear that I'm including multiple things
in technical debt because that's how
people see it so from a technical
standpoint technical debt is is like
it's the implied
cost of future rework
because we prioritized speed over
long-term design right so that's where
we we we're we've come to a decision
point we have to we're building a
feature and we can either do it the fast
way or the right way and we choose the
fast way right that's that's that's
technical debt it's usually deliberately
incurred right was choices that we make
it's either deliberate by the engineer
deliberate by product leadership or
deliberate by the by the
organization there's also an an
unintentional technical debt that isn't
generally I mean in general people
characterize it as technical debt for
sure but technically it's not technical
debt trying to get my my brain around
that but it's it's poor
quality poor quality is not technical
debt po quality is just poor quality so
when people talk about technical debt
and they talk about we've got a lot of
bugs in the system they're probably not
talking about technical debt they're
probably talking about poor quality but
they don't want to call it poor quality
because that makes them look bad why did
you deliver poor quality says the CTO I
understand why you made decisions to
expediate a feature in order to ship
more quickly to our customers but why
did you ship per quality right you will
generally find that se Suite is not
interested in poor quality they want
high quality they want their product to
work and they want users to be
happy but they would be happy to make
design decisions that that expediate
right that get things done faster
so the problem is that
most I'm maybe being a bit jaded here
but I would say
most engineering
groups I'm using the word group very
specifically there like Department group
perhaps team depends on your context
they they they characterize po quality
as technical debt like it's a choice I
mean it is a choice they deliberately
didn't do the stuff they needed to do in
order to maintain the quality of the
product and that builds up over time so
technical debt builds up over time and
po quality builds up over time uh poor
quality is by far your bus biggest
killer
um
both create rework both qu create higher
costs of Maintenance both create slower
development it's harder to add features
to your product because you made what we
now realize is subpar design decisions
right we might have made the right
decision at the time but now it's the
wrong decision because the world's
changed or the Market's changed or we
shipped a bunch of crap to production
which is which is what I see quite often
I I I don't understand it but I see it
quite often with with teams and with
products um that we we we don't deliver
high quality usable product to
production we deliver barely functioning
product to production and when you build
new features on top of new barely
functioning features on top of old
barely functioning features you're going
to have barely functioning squared and
it starts to become excessive cost I use
an example in one of my other videos of
a a company I worked with that had uh
manual testers to 300
coders that was because of per
quality definitely some of it was to do
with technical debt but most of it was
to do with per quality it was horrendous
so
so this has a massive cost it has so
much cost and it's especially it's
especially easy for it to happen when
you take longer to ship your product to
production right so if you have a really
long product cycle let's say two years
between releases then you the last six
months is what they say is bug fixing
right but it's not really it's you're
out with the sticky tape and the super
glue patching it up to a to a state
where it can be shipped if it's patched
up that means it's not right okay that
some of that might be technical debt and
some of that might be low quality it's
the reason
that windows for example
is so much more stable now than it ever
was in the past in the past they used to
have a 6ear ship cycle right and and
that incurred massive amounts of debt
and cost and then when they came back
around at the end to clean things up
some things were now fundamental to the
product and they couldn't clean them up
they have to paper over them right
you've got the paper masche over the top
making it like a lovely glossy product
um but then hackers and nefarious people
come along and start peeling back at the
edges to get underneath and and and
exploit things in it with the new model
that the windows team work in where
they're delivering continuously to
production every member of every team is
in charge of quality or or part of that
story of quality of of
security they go back and fix things on
a continuous basis they don't build up
that technical debt anymore they keep on
top of it and the way you keep on top of
technical debt is to
continuously deal with it you're
continuously refactoring you're
continuously rearching your product when
things happen that you find you need to
deal with ah great example when the the
Azure devop I have a lot of stories from
the Azure devops team but the Azure
devops team ran into an issue that
the they'd moved to the cloud they got a
bunch of smaller Services one of those
Services was the profile service right
where you give it an email address and
it comes back with your profile data
like your picture and your friendly name
and all of those kind of things and the
profil something went wrong with the
profile service and because the profile
service wasn't responding the entire
system didn't work you couldn't change
work items you couldn't commit code you
couldn't do any of the things that that
anytime it called the Prof you couldn't
even view code because it was calling
the profile service to get the friendly
names for the people that were
committing the code right the in the
history and stuff or the work items
right you couldn't see anything in the
work items
I so but
why right I I if there's something wrong
with the profile service just show the
email address you don't need to go get
the friendly name I I might I I as a
user might go uh why is it just showing
me the email address but I can still use
the system but I can still work right
and that
that was there because they they they
made architectural
decisions
that were perhaps done for expediency
perhaps done deliberately but also could
be done accidentally right didn't
realize this was going to be a problem
in the future but as soon as they figure
that out they realized this technical
debt we had a production incident
because of our design choices right that
this this service was to tightly coupled
and we need to figure out what was the
cause of the problem well it's this
tightly coupling this what do we need to
do about it well we need to go re
architect and anywhere that calls this
service we need to introduce in this
case it was introduced the circuit
breaker pattern so that when it's not
working it just turns it off and doesn't
oh sorry turns it off that way and
doesn't keep trying to call it it just
stops calling it and then maybe every 10
seconds it goes is it working no is it
working no okay wait a minute is it
working oh yeah it's working now so we
can reconnect it right that's a circuit
breaker pattern in in in
so they did that so that they would
never have that problem again it would
never happen that this the the profile
service going out would result in
another service not working right so
that's paying back some of that
technical debt that you either
deliberately incurred or you found later
right you realized you'd got into into
debt over your head and you need to fix
it but you need to fix it you need to go
back and refactor it and there's a cost
to that right it's engineering work it's
time it's possible mistakes it's
reworking tests it's all of those things
to make that work and then I think a
year later they had a similar problem
with another
service so they took the decision at
that point to go and introduce the
circuit breaker pattern in all the
communication across their entire
service and then they never had that
problem
again so you're always going to incur
technical debt whether you choose to do
it deliberately or you discover it later
you should never have poor quality that
that you should have an absolute minimum
Quality Bar that's set by the
organization to protect the business the
brand your employees and your customers
right that's that's your your
organizations we I would call it a
definition of done right what's the
minimum quality level required by your
business but from a technical debt
perspective we still need to go back and
pay it back and it pays back dividends
when we go fix these things because it
pays it back in making it easier for us
to add new features to the product it
pays it back because our customers have
less issues so they're happier they're
they they they think better of our
product and if they think better of our
product then we tend to make more money
it's a lagging indicator but we tend to
make more money so managing technical
debt minimizes your costs and maximizes
your profit