the next harbinger of the agile
apocalypse is war and War manifests in
organizations um as a distrust it
manifests as politics it manifests as
disagreement and effectively results in
conflict and there are multip multiple
levels of conflict that happen within
your organization uh you might start
with just a simple dispute right we're
not sure how to do something we're
having a conversation those those things
are kind of kind of easy uh easier to
work through and as you move up you get
to um
more more conflict more things happening
more disagreement like I it becomes not
about what we can do to move
forward but it becomes what I can do to
make you
lose right that's when you transition
from a collaborative environment where
you do you do want constructive
disagreement right you want constructive
arguments because I I I I firmly believe
that arguments and discussion and debate
is like the the the the Flint on steel
generated the Sparks of ideas that start
the fires in your organization that
enact change that enact uh new products
enact new ideas right you need some
level of conflict within your
organization but as soon as it moves to
the point where I win and you lose right
where where that that that my job
becomes not winning but making sure you
lose cuz I don't like what you're doing
that's when it escalates into allout war
and it becomes not about collaboratively
moving forward it becomes about winning
and winning isn't always the right
answer don't let your your organization
degenerate into
war thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked
agility