okay
so the question was um what is the most
common aha moment
that people have in a scrum course and I
I think it actually depends on the scrum
course because there's quite a few
different different flavors
but I think
the biggest aha moment is the the the
total founding in empiricism that that
agility has and I see that time and time
again both
for for General agile and scrum when you
start talking to people in a training
class and explaining to them what's the
purpose of the events right causing the
feedback loop what's the purpose of the
the the the artifacts is to provide
transparency they start to realize that
they didn't understand what those things
are so that that kind of that
realization that oh I've been I've been
doing that wrong not because
I've been mechanically doing it wrong
but because I've not understood its
purpose I've not understood why this uh
uh thing is there and I've not valued it
right and so that that realization that
there is value in this thing that they
didn't even know was there even though
they've been doing it for years I was
teaching an APS today uh co-teaching
with Joanna and that that was a huge
realization for the for the for the
students there was that
um even the ones that I've been doing
I've been doing scrum for years
and then they're they're they're they're
hearing what we're saying they're
rereading the scrum guide and going
oh I totally didn't see the this this
that the empiricism was so important
that the scrum values were so important
that that this actually worked this now
you're explaining it it all makes sense
that the feedback loops and yeah that
that's probably the biggest aha moment
um and I think that
maybe it's just the way I teach it right
but that progresses across that one is a
staple for all the classes because at
some point you have to explain
empiricism and inspect and adapt and how
it interacts with scrum but when you
start layering on some of the other
capabilities and like hypothesis driven
practices hypothesis driven engineering
right
um that comes in with the PSU that's a
that's a big aha moment even because we
teach it in product owner as well as in
a more advanced in the PSU and that
realization
probably the the the the the
realization as well what the roles
aren't
that's actually a big big aha moment
that that people have and that's what I
love about the the advanced scrum Master
right is you you go into the advanced
scrum master and you immediately you
know put up that that
um uh uh the stances of the scum master
and it's the the negative scrum Master
stances and they say oh yeah you know
we've got that one and we've got this
one and we've got this one and I have to
do this one and I have to do that one
and then you've got that kind of it's
not really a reveal but that kind of
slow realization that oh you're putting
these up because these are the stances
we don't want
these are the stancies that that aren't
going to result in success that are
going to result in in in uh poor quality
and me not being an effective scrum
master and then we progress into the
stances that we do want what we're
trying to achieve and then go through it
that that's a big aha moment in the the
psm2 so I like that one
and in the advanced product owner I
really like it's it's actually the same
thing you've got these set of stancies
which are the the the negative stancies
for the
product owner and then we reveal the and
dive deeply into I think this is our six
I think there's six stances of of you
know like the Steve Jobs type and the
customer focus and it's it's just that
realization that there's so much more to
the role
than they ever realized so from the aps
it's the team realizing there's so much
more to being in a scrum team and the
capability there's so much more to being
a product owner there's so much more to
being a scrum Master than they ever
realized before and for me that's the
big Epiphany moment in in all of the
classes that just continues every time
and it never gets old
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility