if it's not in the hands of users it's
not done Writing code isn't done Testing
code isn't done Demoing something in a
meeting isn't done Done means that the
increment is live in
production Gathering telemetry
delivering real evidence against real
goals
At Naked Agility we help teams shift
away from celebrating fake finishes
towards shipping actual usable outcomes
because work that isn't live isn't
learning And if it isn't learning it
isn't delivering value Your customers
don't care about completed tasks They
care about what's available to them
right now If your teams confuse code
complete with done let's talk about
shifting to real value delivery