Simon synic talks about starting with
why it's a whole book on that topic and
the question is does it does it really
matter like who gives a crap and I think
I think the big piece here we need for
for us to understand it we need to bring
in bring in something else um start with
why is is is great but I think the
underlying reasons are a little bit a
little bit different and that's that um
what motivates
people so now we're we're we're talking
about if you want to look at up drive by
Dan
pink um and what Drive talks about is
what are the
underlying things that motivate people
um now we we all know the extrinsic the
outside motivators of people um you know
you want you want more money you want
that cool uh uh new PlayStation game um
so stuff money stuff uh a roof over your
head food right uh kids education uh
these are all things that are extrinsic
motivators they come in from the outside
and they're the most important thing if
they're a problem right if you're
worried about putting food on the table
then money is going to be your most
important thing if you're worried about
putting a roof over your kid's head or
your head uh then money is going to be
your most important thing and to get
that problem solved so that's my focus
but once people are earning enough that
those things are dealt with right
they're they're resolved we've resolved
all of those extrinsic or generally
resolved all of those extrinsic
motivators then more money is not
something uh that motivates motivates
people if it is right because in some
organizations they have that culture
where money's the motivator think of um
you know uh I'm thinking of stocks and
shares or sales or whatever they've
turned it into a game right they've
turned the being the best salesperson or
making the most money or beating the
quota it's not actually about the money
anymore it's about the points it's about
the game um but if you take all of those
things off the table and you don't have
that weird dysfunctional game culture
which probably works quite well in sales
right but is still dysfunctional game
culture then the underlying intrinsic
motivators the stuff that comes from the
inside of you is three things autonomy
Mastery and purpose right autonomy we
want to we want to feel like we're in
control of our destiny right we choose
how we do things we choose where we go
um um we choose who we work for right
all of those those types of things um
and then we've got
Mastery I I don't know anybody who gets
up every morning and thinks they want to
do a worse job today than they did
yesterday most people want to get better
at their job um they want to learn more
about the thing they're doing again
remember we've taken that purely
Financial motivation off the table by
we've got enough money uh uh to not
worry about those things so then our
motivation becomes a a a a a Mastery
right uh a way that that um money still
sits on the table is that um taoris uh
practice uh Taylor and Gant um um
Frederick winow Taylor and Henry Gant
came up with this this ideology around
paying people less than they need to
survive and then they have to work
really hard to get the bonus in order to
go above that survival line right that's
that's you're maintaining your
deliberately an organization is
deliberately and explicitly maintaining
people below that line in order to
artificially make money the motivating
factor um so that so that that's what
the focus is money money money money
money cuz maybe we've got lots of money
we're a bank right so we can throw money
at people and get more stuff all the
other stuff's hard autonomy Mastery and
purposes hard right money's easy so
let's make money the point by paying
them less right that's uh uh quite a
common strategy I I worked at a company
a while ago where um they paid about 10%
below industry standard for uh wages um
but there was a a 50% bonus scheme right
or was it 20% below so you you felt the
pinch on the base wages uh um like you
you could just make things meet but only
barely but then at the end of the year
you got that 50% 50% bonus if the
company did well um that might be called
golden handcuffs there all kind of kinds
of things around that so that's um but
if we take that off the table Mastery
doing the best job you possibly
can becomes more of a motivator than
money would you rather have people
looking for their next paycheck or being
motivated to be the best they can
possibly be at that job right so we've
got autonomy and Mastery and the last
one is purpose and that's where we jump
into this start with why right purpose
is do you understand how your work
contributes to some greater goal that
you care about right the greater goal is
also a a a book on this Topic start with
why why are we doing the thing we're
doing what am I then doing right now to
help visualize this this this why and
when when you start focusing on that why
right why we're doing the thing we're
doing what is it we're trying to achieve
the outcome of that is visions and goals
and when you when you move from
traditional project-based model towards
a product based model we start to remove
certain things from that process right
we start removing uh uh milestones and
deliverables um and those those things
that Gant charts those things that
enshrine that traditional project
management process but what the mistake
lots of organizations make is they don't
replace it with anything they have no
why they have no motivation they have no
goals they have no outcomes that the
team's trying to achieve so if you look
up team right for example if you look up
team in the dictionary it says group of
people working together towards a common
goal
so if you don't have any why if you
don't have any goal if you don't have
any outcome that the team is trying to
achieve or even the organization is
trying to
achieve how how how do we have teams how
could we possibly have teams how do they
what are they working together
towards right what are they
collaborating on towards so they have no
purpose right does this knock on effect
and we talk about this in the product
owner um the the the PSM P prodct owner
class um and we talk about uh uh
replacing the
um the these traditional elements with
vision value and validation right Vision
where are we going what are we trying to
achieve that that you'll get that from
your why right so the why is at the top
why are we doing what we do create a
vision that's how we're going to get to
this why if we enact this Vision we
should get to this this why we're here
and then what's the value we're trying
to achieve and that should inform your
goals right what's the next Big Goal
we're trying to achieve and perhaps
you've got a a set of goals or
hierarchies or okrs or smart or whatever
it is you're using to figure those out
but the way we know we've got the right
thing is that the people doing the work
can feel a connection from the work that
they're doing every day through those
however you're defining your your your
goals towards the vision and the why
we're here why are we a company why do
we exist and in fact if you do that you
engage your customers as well because
they see your purpose they see every
employee working towards that common
purpose and that common purpose
becomes that that that thing that makes
customers look at your organization wow
they're doing great things they're going
in this direction and that's
fundamentally what Apple has achieved
or did achieve uh many years ago um they
were able to achieve this almost Godlike
status that customers believed in their
Journey right they believed in their
journey and it wasn't because they had
some Vision that the customers liked
it's because the whole
organization every employee of the
organization every manager in the
organization every leader in the
organization are working together there
towards this common goal um so make sure
you understand why why is your company
there why are you doing this
work what do you get out of it thanks
for watching the video If you enjoyed it
please like follow And subscribe I
always reply to comments and if you want
to have a chat about this or anything
else agile scrum or devops then please
book a coffee with me through naked
agility