one of the ghosts of agile past is
certification we've been hearing a lot
about it recently with uh many folks
being very I don't know H dismissive or
pooping on certifications a
lot and I want to kind of add to that
pile little bit but also um um validate
some of the value that we get from from
certifications
um certifications have have had a
significant impact on our industry
because they they get in the way they
kind of get in the way of learning a
little bit they really shouldn't get in
the way of learning but they do get in
the way of learning people get jobs
because they have certifications not be
actually able to do stuff and people
chase certifications rather than the
knowledge that is the thing that those
certifications are supposed to assess
I'm going to say this now absolutely
categorically there is no 2-day course
that any of you can go on and then pass
a certification that will enable you to
be the thing that the certification
enabled you to pass at the very most at
the very most I think of it like passing
your driving test right at the moment
when you are 17 or whatever age it is in
your area that you passed your driving
test were you the most awesome driver
out there no you were not you were the
minimum you had the minimum information
you need to not be a danger to those
around you quite often not even that but
mostly the idea behind a driving test um
and the driving training that you get
which you don't have to do training you
can just sit the test um is to to that
you're not a danger a danger to others
and
does getting your driving test mean you
can also ride a motorbike probably not
can you drive a 10-ton truck probably
not right all of those things are
additional licenses and certifications
you need to get in able to in order to
do those other things and usually they
come with additional limits and
constraints as well and what I think the
value of certifications are um well the
certification itself if you just get
given the certification it's not
valuable the value in some kind of
assessment at the end of your course
regardless of whose assessment that is
uh the value of it is where you paying
attention to the core things that were
expected to be paid attention to did the
trainer manage to cover the core things
that we expected to be in the class did
I as a student understand the core
things um as they're intended to be in
the class those are the minimum bars
that we would like to meet and sometimes
things happen sometimes we don't meet
them and having some kind of
certification can help validate that
knowledge a little bit but
ultimately if you're using
certifications for job interviews or
you're using them for some kind of
professional Acumen
or forbid this if you've just passed a
scrum Master certification and now
you've put scrum Master on your LinkedIn
profile or agile coach because you've
passed an ICF
certification then get that off there as
quickly as possible unless you've got
the experience to back it up you are not
the thing my first scrum Master job is
not the same as being a scrum master so
if you're selling yourself as a scrum
master and you haven't even had my first
scrum Master Class job then that's
probably not a good idea most of the
best scrum Masters that I've met did not
go on a scrum course and become a scrum
Master they became a scrum master and
then they went on a scrum course and the
way they became a scrum master was the
team that they worked in selected them
for that role because they were the most
competent um person on the team within
the context of maximizing the
effectiveness of that team that's how
the best people become scrum Masters so
if you want to be a scrum Master my
advice would be join a team that uses
the skills that you already have and
demonstrate to that team that you
provide value and are effective and are
interested in their effectiveness and
can help them and they will select you
to be their scrum Master it's not really
a job
title
that's the certification ghost of agile
past if you're being haunted by these
ghosts of agile past we can help you
exercise them or help you find a coach
consultant or trainer who can don't let
these Phantoms undermine the
effectiveness of your value delivery the
longer they Linger The more they'll
haunt your team's progress um or even
destroy it send me an email to Martin at
nkd agility tocom and we will help you
get to the bottom of it if you want to
have a discussion about your unique
needs or situation then please book a
call or visit us at naked agility tocom
uh we also have our immersive and
traditional public classes on our
website and we'd love to hear from you