over the last 18 months or so we've seen
significant more interest and more
questions around these I this idea of
lean product development especially
within the realm of product ownership
right what is it that is
pushing that and I think there is a huge
push in the industry to get better at
deciding what it is that we're building
better at making the right bets better
at
understanding what we should and
shouldn't build within a particular
context and how do we minimize the
chance of building the wrong thing
hypothesis driven engineering practices
right that that those lean product
development stories and I think that
um this is such an important topic
that Joanna and I will be running our
Workshop
on product ownership and lean product
management we're only going to talk for
about 18 minutes and then we're going to
have about 40 minutes of q a for you to
bring your questions your ideas your
your stories to this puzzle of what it
is
um you know what is lean product
development what does it
look like going forward into the future
and why is it so important to our
organizations today
so that we can so that so that we can we
can waste less money in our organization
so that we can build more value
um for Less uh at money higher return on
investment that's really what it's all
about