but why does agile focus on values and
principles instead of a predefined set
of steps
um because there's no predefined set of
steps that will get the same outcome
every time in an agile space so that
that's where we start having that
conversation about the difference
between and however people want to
phrase it right because there's there's
different stories about how you would
you would articulate this but the way I
articulate it is that you've got
um you've got complicated work
right so this is about the work that
we're doing we've get complicated work
and if we apply
um best practices or good practices we
can turn this into into something simple
right so that's like
um whenever you go let's say you want to
do some DIY in the house uh DIY do it
yourself in the house uh you want to do
some some some home Home Improvements
and you don't know how to remove safely
remove the u-bend in the sink
you don't know how to do that I
guarantee you you can go to YouTube and
type in remove you bend and sync hit
enter and you'll find 20 YouTube videos
You'll watch three of them and now it's
a simple problem it's not a complex a
complicated problem at all anymore
right because you you know how to do it
you could probably even find a video
that has the exact same fixings as you
have uh on your sink right if you
watched a few of those videos
these are not hard tasks if you know how
to do them they're only hard because you
don't know how to do them you don't have
the knowledge
you've got these this complicated work
that when you apply knowledge it becomes
simple
right but then you've got this other
type of work which is
any time you're building stuff that
doesn't exist yet
right if you're building something that
doesn't exist yet there's no predefined
set of rules yet somebody has to
design the thing and then we create a
predefined set of rules like if you
wanted to design a brand new brand new
car brand new car platform
um you're not gonna it's not complicated
it's complex because you don't know what
the outcome is going to be
um but once you've built it you can then
create a production line and serve out
up lots of them that's you turning that
complex problem of Designing the new
product okay now we've got the
complicated problem of building the new
product we create the production line
and then we generate lots of lots of
things off it
but in the complex space every single
thing we do
is complex every single thing we do is
something that we've not done before
so if you're
um writing code right you don't go right
code that you've written before
because there would be no point it's
been written before so you would package
it up in a little framework and you
would reuse that little framework on a
constant basis so then that's that's not
complex work but everything you're doing
to wire up that thing is complex work
everything we do in software is brand
new anytime you're developing a product
that doesn't exist yet there are no best
practices there are only emergent
practices like what's the right thing
just now for what we understand just now
tomorrow it might be different in fact
in a couple of hours it might be
different right because the it's
changing so much and the thing that
happens in this space you can't make
this complicated right you can't make it
complicated there's no change between
that
and what happens in this space is we get
lots of surprises
right and some of them are positive
surprises that we want to go grab and
take advantage of and some of them are
negative surprises that we want to make
sure that we don't get you know don't
get messed up by that particular
surprise
loads of those types of things in the in
the software world but in almost any
industry when you're building brand new
products you're going to have surprises
right things aren't like you expect them
to be for whatever reason or something
happens the the impacts on what it is
that you're doing
so
the reason that agile focuses on those
values and principles
is that you
and your team and your company
need the tools
to be able to adapt to any circumstance
whereas as soon as you write down a way
to do things like here's a step-by-step
guide on how to do it and then the world
changes right your your world of how
it's going to work changes it's actually
harder to adapt to this because you're
like but I'm following this set of steps
right I want to follow the and this
one's failing why is this failing now
well it's because the world's changed
and when we enshrine things in here's
here's a way of doing something here's
one way that you should do this we
suddenly hit that problem of
we want to keep doing it that way and
it's harder to change whereas so we
focus on values and principles so we
don't enshrine if the word I normally
use for these enshrined things is
bureaucracy right the way we work you
don't enshrine them in the the the the
bureaucracy and you keep yourself Nimble
and adaptable and then hopefully what
you'll learn is to document and create
processes for the things that you can
move into that complicated space I.E
we've built something we need a process
for resetting users passwords we've
built a system here's the process to
interact with the system but if we're
adding new things to this system we
don't need the bureaucracy in order to
handle how we're doing that because we
want to be dynamic and adaptable but
then over here in using the thing we can
have the documentation and we can have
the processes and the the the rules on
how to do that
so that's why we focus on values and
principles and not just a set of rules