um so the question is what was your
worst day as an agile consultant and I
think the the worst well was it was it
my worst day or was it the customer's
worst day the worst day I can I I
actually think of is
um going going into an organization I'm
going to be on site for a week so I'm
Consulting right I need to help them fix
their stuff
um and I get into the office Sean to a
cubicle this was in the US so I got
shown to a here's your desk uh for the
week uh Sean's the cubicle sat down and
then the person that that sat me down
disappeared
um and I was sitting there for I don't
know two or three hours nobody had come
by nothing was going on
um so I just you know I called my my
boss at the time Steve Borg and I said
uh I'm just I'm just sitting here by the
way they're not doing anything he's like
what do you mean what do you mean
just just sitting in this Cube everybody
disappeared and he's like oh let me see
if I can find find anybody he made a few
calls they weren't ready for me yet so
he called me back and he said uh we
booked a flight for you just go to the
airport and come on home and it took the
customer three days to realize it was no
longer there
took them three days to realize that I'd
just gone home that's how long it took
them to be ready for me and that was
three days into a five-day engagement
right
um so that was probably the worst day
for the for the for the customer they
just weren't ready right they weren't
ready for any sort of change they
obviously weren't ready to listen
um and they weren't ready to do that but
I I'm not ready to listen I also did the
same engagement three years in a row
with a customer
same time a year same group of people
they would invite me to their
organization we'd sit in the boardroom
they'd talk about all the stuff they're
doing I'd give them a bunch of advice I
did a whole bunch of interviews with
everybody lots of different people at
different levels in the organization I
created a lovely report this was the
first time I went lovely report on here
are the things you need to fix the
things you need to try
um changes you might want to make things
you might want to do and then I would
come back the next year and they'd be
like yep we've done none of the things
you said let's have a chat and figure
out what we should do next and it was
exactly the same things because nothing
had changed right
um and I would come back year after year
to the same company for the same few
days on site with the same group of
people who would agree that they haven't
done anything to change anything and
then we would maybe troubleshoot some
small issues around the edges and help
them out but
um again
that's not a good day as an agile
consultant because you're not making
progress you're not helping the customer
you're not providing them with value
right
so I always feel like I work with lots
of customers and if
I'm not if I'm working as an agile
consultant and I'm not getting fed
problems
um by the by the organization right to
be able to help them out I'm gonna
wander off
right and I I'm usually pretty clear if
it's a longer engagement I'm usually
pretty clear on that up front right if I
feel like I'm giving you a bunch of
advice and you're you're just ignoring
it then maybe we're not a good fit and I
shouldn't be here anymore and I think
those are the days that kind of suck is
when nobody's listening to you you're
seeing the things you're saying this
thing's gonna happen if you keep doing
it this way and then you've just got to
sit there and watch them fall into that
trap
and then they come to you and say oh
we're so we're so broken can you can you
we're we're totally hosed now can you
help us fix and it's like we'll we'll
know like six weeks ago when I told you
about the problem was when you could
have fixed it now you you pretty much
want to pay the fine for non non
whatever non-contract completion and
walk away because that's all you've got
left I think those are the days that
kind of suck as a as an agile consultant
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility