Scotland 2023 is just around the corner
um or it's agile 2023 the Scotland
experience it's just around the corner
um I'm really looking forward to it Nick
jolte is sponsoring
um this year and one of the reasons that
that we decided to sponsor is that we're
we're Scottish we're a Scottish company
um I know I say that funny because I've
lived in other countries I I've spent a
lot of time traveling around the world
but I've always come back uh to to to
Scotland to to live
and I don't actually have
um although I don't have a lot of
customers in Scotland I'm always
interested in what folks are are doing
the communities
um I sponsor future of work in Scotland
as well
um which is a great uh uh event regular
Meetup event where they they get the
some of the best speakers in the world
um and I think this is going to be the
same I had your 20 23
um the conference as a whole has this
massive presence around the world
um I spoke at deliver agile uh 2023
um back in no well obviously not 2023
back in when did I speak at that
conference 2017
um and it was a fantastic event and I
think this is going to be the same a
little bit smaller scale
um but they're just starting out in
Scotland and I think I think it's going
to be amazing lots of amazing speakers
on the lineup
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility