so would I recommend the aps course to a
newbie scrum team I think that's its
sweet spot and what it was designed for
the the the EPS is
the thing I the the the the outcomes I
love about the EPS I've talked in other
videos about like what happens in the
aps but the the outcome is a realization
of what needs to be different in your
organization in order to give this thing
a try
so if you're a new team in an
organization moving towards scrum and
your organization maybe has done a
little bit of scrum maybe maybe hasn't
maybe it's brand new to them one of the
exercises near the end of the class is
based on everything that you as a team
you as a group of people attending this
class have learned
what are the things that are going that
you would need to change in your
organization in order to be successful
at this because we've just talked about
um what it should look like the levels
of transparency the interactions between
people the accountabilities and perhaps
those are just not present in your
organization so what does need to change
and especially when I have groups of
people that are new very new to scrum
there's a a moment at the end where we
create an organizational change backlog
um and it it works the best when you
have leaders in the room
right if you've got a big class and
you've got leaders in the room I can
actually say so who's who's the most
powerful person in the room who's the
hippo
right who's the most powerful person and
and I've done this in classes where it's
the CEO right and the CEO says uh that I
am I'm like this backlog's for you right
and I I literally give it to them and
it's it it that's one bit that's maybe a
little bit better in person because
you're ceremonially giving them this
huge stack I've had 50 cards out of a
class before here are all of the things
um that this group of people that have
just been through this class believe
need to change in your organization in
order to be successful at this that's
hugely powerful not only from the
perspective of the people feeling that
they're heard to come up with it but
also powerful from the CEO participating
in the class like demonstrating that
this is important enough that I turn up
and receiving that backlog but then
actually doing something with it and
that's where there's been the most
impact from the EPS is when there is
somebody in the room who can take that
backlog who can then do something with
it because you get like who's the most
important person here's your backlog who
can help them and people volunteer in
the room could one person from each team
volunteer to help this person uh action
some of these items and figure it out
and people volunteer and they feel
involved and they feel empowered and it
creates this
like I don't know get up and go this
gumption to go go make the change go do
this thing differently and try something
new right try something different and
see if it's successful and I think uh uh
that that for me is
why a newbie team
moving into scrum moving into agility is
is almost The Sweet Spot of of the EPS
class
it's also great to realign
people who have been doing scrum for a
while and think they know everything
right uh we need to be doing user
stories and we need to be doing story
points and we have to do estimation and
scrum says we can't change the Sprint
backlog uh uh after we've started the
Sprint and all of these crap things that
are nothing to do with scrum whatsoever
but people believe they are because
that's how they do things in the
organization and that that realignment
also results in some of the same
epiphanies as well it's not as huge as
new teams
um but but creating that organizational
change backlog oh we've got something
wrong let's adapt let's change it let's
bring some of that empirical process
into the way we do business as well
hugely important
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility