so if you're Building Products you
really need to
understand the cost of those
products so there are a number
of it's it's really complicated because
there's there's the actual cost you pay
which is normally
due in general your two big costs at
building software products is Hardware
that's the smaller one hardware and
people right so if you have uh 50 people
working on a product that's probably
going to be your biggest cost if you
deploy to the cloud that's going to be
your second biggest cost right so your
infrastructure infrastructure and people
those costs should be fairly
consistent so you you should understand
your cost profile I talk usually talk
about it it's what's the cost per Sprint
right why should we do another Sprint
what's it going to cost what do we
getting for it and are we getting a
clear return on investment for the cost
that we're we're we're putting in right
so H Sprints are part of the scrum
framework and they're a way of planning
and managing work right so the the the
the they don't imply an Engineering
Process it's just about the the the
management of the work part and planning
for for what's happening next so if I
was looking at a cost per Sprint let's
say I'm doing a twoe Sprint what's my
cost per two weeks of of work what are
my teams working on for those two weeks
and is it valuable it's also really
important in that context for the people
doing the work to understand the cost of
doing the work because they'll make
better choices right if if if you you
want to create an environment within
which people are spending the money as
if it's their money and if they
understand the cost of the Sprint
they'll think about what is it that
we're doing for this Sprint the cost of
the Sprint and try and maximize your
return on investment that needs to be an
evolution an effort that every single
person that's working on your product is
involved in otherwise you're not going
to have people working on the right
thing you're not going to have people
making the right decisions so so one one
way one effective way
to minimize your cost and maximize your
value is to have every member of every
team and everybody working on your
product understand what the costs are
within their context I I I actually I
I've spoken to some colleagues about
this and I've kind of come to the
conclusion that every team should be
running a
p&l right what not just not
just are we adding value in the product
because cuz value is a little
bit Eye of the Beholder it can be a
little bit difficult to to to actually
measure its
capability but Revenue we we can we can
absolutely measure that and what
percentage of the revenue is attributed
to a particular feature and this team
owns that feature therefore that's the
revenue they're making this is the cost
that they're they're they're having and
are we making a are we as a team making
a profit working on what we're working
on and if we're not making a profit
working on what we're working on should
be we working on something else right
that that that that Dynamic e and flow
of the team team within the context of
of teams to work within the context of
product management and product
leadership with deliberate choices on
investment in long-term efforts right
just like H an infrastructure build if
you were if you were running running
running a country and you decide to
invest in roads um that's a big capital
expenditure um to invest and that needs
that needs to be understood as a concept
as a as a as a as a a we're we're
investing a bunch of money just now so
it looks like we're making a loss in
order to get a larger return in the
future and that's a deliberate thing
that we're doing and but we're still
looking at the p&l we're still
understanding uh what it is that we're
we're doing so I I think from a from a
team from a group from a product
perspective we should be looking at all
of that information and every member of
every team should under understand it to
the extent that they need to right
within their within their
context and to do that you kind of do
need to understand a little bit more
about what your product is where you
intend your product to go what Market
you're in what's happening in the market
and how you're interacting with the
market and this is where I tend to fall
back a little bit on evidence-based
management so there's the evidence-based
management guide from scrum.org
and it it it doesn't I mean it does give
example metrics right but it doesn't
really talk about specific metrics in in
the context of the guide it basically
says there's four key value areas that
we need to think about there's four key
questions we need to ask ourselves and
in order to answer those questions we
need to have metrics which help inform
but not control those decisions so the
four the four key value areas that we
need to need to
monitor right in order to understand our
cost to Value profile I think that's
probably a good way to say it is we need
to understand where we sit in the market
for our product and that that market
could be an external b2c B2B Market or
it could be an internal what you call an
internal Market B2B
b2c eye to eye internal to internal I
don't know whatever you want to call
that but you you you
you're the people that are using your
your your your your product internally
in the organization that's why lots of
organizations have inter internal cost
structures as well you know I worked at
mer Lynch and if I wanted a a server or
use a piece of software even if it was
an internally built piece of software
that was a cost attributed to it and yes
it was a little bit of a fictitious
internal cost but it allowed them to do
a little bit more p&l and understand uh
what's going on with the the the product
they they definitely went too far bean
counter but it is it is it is important
but so we have to understand our our our
market value and that's made up of two
two areas there's current market value
what we've got right now what we're
delivering right now so that could be
customer happiness it could be employee
happiness it could be usage right lots
of information we can collect around our
current value and then we've got um HP
hypothetical value future value which
should be represented in our product
backlog right what's the future value of
our product and looking at
what Market opportunities we can open
and how do we measure whether we're
opening enough market opportunities
think of the example of of of of Netflix
why do they why do they choose to create
a new show first season of a new show
rather than at a second season to an
existing already success successful show
and that's because second Seasons always
have less users less people care about a
second season whereas first season of a
new show you
can big it up and on board new people
that weren't customers before right so
that's opening out New Market
opportunities rather than leveraging
existing Market opportunities and that's
what your product backlogs about right
so you need to measure and understand
those things within that context and
those things are really really hard to
measure that's one of the hardest parts
I think to to to to measure for most
most organizations are we solving
customers problems are there other
problems that the customers have that we
should be solving instead all of those
those kind of kind of questions but
that's that's your market value and then
the other thing that you need to
understand and have metrics and I'm I'm
deliberately
not I'm referring to metrics but not
specifically saying you need to use
specific metrics because it really
depends on your your your context your
industry what it is you're doing how
your product works you need to find
metrics in these areas that suit your
particular product in your particular
world I do work with organizations to
help them understand those things but
it's something that that they need to
understand right the people doing the
work the people in the organization need
to understand so that's the
market value and then you've also got
your your cap ability of your
organization so the two the two pieces
are are time to Market how quickly do
you get your product in front of real
customers right time to Market is about
how quickly can you realize an idea to
to to
data right so that's time to Market and
then the other one is ability to
innovate how much time do you spend
opening those new markets versus
maintaining and supporting existing
stuff right and this is where if you had
high technical debt you might spend more
time on maintaining and supporting if
you have low product quality you might
have more time on uh supporting
maintaining so those are the types of
things you might measure in in in that
world right what's our what's our our
technical debt we might do so in our
Cube analysis of our or our code base of
our product or whatever else you're
doing how do we understand like bug
Trends Liv site incidents we might be
looking at all of those things within
our ability to innovate context and our
time to Market we're looking at cycle
time and lead time right how quickly can
we get stuff out the door and what are
other things in your
organization that impact on those ideas
right what are the things that inhibit
your organization's ability to reduce it
time to Market measure
those right to get faster at delivering
your products what are the things that
are getting in your way that's what you
should measure if you're if you're
struggling to innovate what are the
things that are getting in your way
those are the the things you'd measure
right and once you've got a handle on
those things figure out what the next
thing you measure is to get your next
biggest bang for your buck and that's a
constant cycle so the metrics are
changing um over time some of them will
take longer than others to resolve but
measuring and
monitoring value that you're creating
Revenue in
p&l and the cost of delivering in your
product these other metrics that help
you get that holistic picture of what's
going on it is almost the most important
thing uh for a CTO for a business to
understand and disseminate through the
organization so that we can all at every
level make the best decision we can