to Be an Effective agile coach you need
knowledge you need knowledge in the
processes practices and tools that might
be effective for teams you need to
understand the underlying principles
yourself why might teams choose it under
what circumstances what benefit would
you expect them to get from it you need
deep technical expertise in the thing
that you're delivering for them so that
means that you might want to learn and
understand scrum you might want to learn
and understand caman and lean caman
method caman strategy what are the tools
and techniques that you think will be
most effective for you moving forward
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked
agility