one of the really powerful things about
immersive learning is that because all
of the trainers are experienced
professionals who've been working in the
in the industry that we're talking about
um they bring not just their ability
their Knowledge and Skills on the theory
and the ability to explain the topics
but they also bring a a swei of
experience of actually having done these
things of engaged with teams uh uh tried
things in organizations big and small so
you effectively get Consulting as well
as training right you get facilitated uh
uh debrief Consulting training you get
the whole package with immersive
learning