huge mistake that organizations make
when they're trying to move towards
having a DevOps strategy, having
engineering excellence, having that that
better suite of modern engineering
practices within their organization is
they outsource it to a vendor.
That is that is probably the least
likely way to result in a positive
outcome for your business because you're
you're giving the engineers in your
business a bunch of new stuff that they
don't understand very well that they
perhaps don't understand at all. Black
boxes that this vendor's created and
you're probably going to end up with a
lot of vendor lock in. and you're going
to need that vendor to come back and
redo things on a regular cadence and
it's going to be very expensive and
you're probably going to find that
there's going to be a long time between
those things, right? It's why you end up
on old versions of your product in the
first place. So instead of a vendor,
you need somebody somebody's
who are going to come in and help you
change that mindset within your
organization of of start moving people
towards engineering excellence. Helping
your people rebuild their workflows in a
way that makes sense in a modern
engineering context. Have them help your
people fix their problems. Um, and
that's something that I do with most
organizations that I work with is I'm
coming in and I'm helping their people
do it. I often don't even have
credentials in their system, right? I I
I'm not making changes for them. I'm
helping them make changes. I'm
encouraging them to refactor the things
that they're working on. I'm encouraging
them to break it down. we're talking
about the theory and uh uh philosophies
on like why would you want to move in
this direction and then I'm helping them
implement those things um as they start
hitting problems in the actual
technology right um just working with a
customer at the moment that's on TFVC
and we need to move them to git they
have SDN and TFVC and they need to go to
a modern source control system a
distributed source control
Um they're they're on they have stuff on
.NET 3 um yeah .NET 35. Um they have
stuff on old versions of of of
everything. And h how how do you tackle
that upgrade? How do you even get
started? How do you make that
progression towards the smallest piece
you can bite off and figure out how to
do that first? What are the implications
of making certain changes? Right.
There's a massive implication of moving
from a a serverbased source control
system like TFVC or subversion and then
adapting over to a distributed source
control system like uh like like git
which has a lot of implications of
branching strategy. It has implications
of what you put in your source code. It
has implications of how do you manage
your product towards production. It has
loads of implications down the line that
are part of modernizing your engineering
practices. And that requires
partnership, not a vendor. A vendor is
going to do the stuff for you. And your
people aren't going to learn anything.
You need a partner who can teach,
mentor, coach, and engineering
transformational experience within your
organization. That's something that we
can help you with. My background is
software engineering, not coaching and
training, software engineering. I'm a
Microsoft MVP in DevOps and GitHub.
I have uh engineering experience in
building out DevOps pipelines. I was a
DevOps consultant uh for many years and
helping teams get better at building out
um these modern engineering practices
and the implications of these modern
engineering practices for their existing
pract practices and building a strategy
to get between them is where I bring my
expertise and let's get you to
engineering excellence on Your terms at
your pace with expert guidance.