hey everyone hello
it's nice to be back uh working with the
team akaditi team thank you very much
for this opportunity
um it's a pity that thanks to
coved we're not able to be physically in
nigeria because i was looking forward to
that i think it's one of the few west
african countries i've not been to
because i've been to quite a number of
them but then hey kobe would go
and we would hopefully have the
opportunity
to do just that in the future
so today um i wanted to talk about
emotional intelligence or ei and team
performance because it's one of these
topics that i am quite passionate about
and i'll try my best to
um interlace it with
my experience working so far
in the scrum and agile space i just like
to ask
everyone to kindly go on mute
if you have any questions do note them
down and i would answer them at the end
of the session
because uh sadly if you're going through
the flow and you get diverted it's
a bit difficult to come back to what you
were saying
okay thank you
so today we'll be covering what
emotional intelligence is
then i'll take you through the five
elements of emotional
intelligence we'll then talk about
emotional intelligence and team
performance
seven ways to create an ei team
ei and scrum values and we would end
there so
from now i'm just going to call it ei
because emotional intelligence is quite
a mouthful so we'll start off with
talking about
uh what e.i is you know for example
um if one sits down and at times you
want to think about who a perfect leader
is you think of someone who
be um sort of whose temper is always
under control they manage their temper
well they have the complete
trust of the people they work with you
know they listen to their teams you know
they're easily approachable they're
easy to talk to and
mainly that is because um such
individuals tend to have
quite a high ei so i guess the first
question that comes to mind then is what
is e.i
is the ability to understand and manage
your own emotions and those of people
around you
so people with a high degree of e.i know
what they're feeling
what their emotions mean and how these
emotions can
affect other people so
one of the interesting things to note is
there are five main elements of
ei and at least 90 percent of top
performance have an a very high ei score
and simply puts their social and
emotional skills
and strengths that enable you to to be
successful both
personally and professionally um
these are one of the kind of uh skills
that
um one is easily it's good to have
such skill sets if you are a leader it's
good for your career progression
and what is it really good
to note about that as well is the fact
that
one may not have all the skills but it's
something that can be
learned and it really
is something that i would recommend
especially in the agile space
in environments where we work with
people and we interact with people and
that tends to be
almost every role you do right
so i'll just
move on to talk about the five main
elements of
ei and uh so i'll just start from left
to right okay
my cursor is there so i'll be moving my
cursor so you know where exactly i
am um we'll start off with the first one
which is about oops i think that was too
fast
okay
than i am so the first one is
self-awareness
which is the ability to recognize and
understand your moods your emotions
and drives as well as how they affect
other people
so it's just telling you of being aware
of the way you behave you know
and uh this is very important for
example
as an individual when we get
angry being able to understand that oh
i've gotten to that point you know
there's that point you get through
before you
lose it so being able to be aware that
this is that point where i
lose it and then i'll start saying
really crazy things that
maybe uh later on after that
emotion has passed you would actually be
embarrassed of what you said
it happens to all of us and you know i
i am one of the people that believe that
words have
a lot of power so sometimes for example
when you get really angry you would say
really nasty things some people are like
that so being
self-aware especially in a work
environment
of what your trigger points are is very
important
people that tend to do that tend to have
a lot of self-confidence
they have a realistic self-assessment
of themselves they have a
self-deprecating
sense of humor and some of the things
you need to know is that how you're able
to sort of
be self-aware of who you are is maybe
keep in a journal because you know
sometimes if you keep a journal on your
day-to-day basis
when you go back to read it you'll be
able to
uh sort of uh read and see where your
trigger points are
um and also one of the things
simple as it may sound one of the other
things
is to just and think
um i think someone's uh mike is really
interfering and if that person could be
on mute that would be lucky
thank you the next thing
is self-regulation
that's the ability to control or
redirect
disruptive impulses and moods the
propensity to suspend
judgments to think before acting
self-awareness and self-regulation tends
to go
hand-in-hand in my opinion
because with that one as well it's also
dealing with
emotional control and being able
uh to stay calm at all times
people like that tend to the whole max
for that is trustworthiness and
integrity comfort with ambiguity
being open to change uh tips for that
is that for example when you make
mistakes
just own up to it don't blame others for
that know your values if you know your
values and you know what you stand for
you know what you wouldn't like budge on
and you wouldn't lose sleep over that
and also another good thing is practice
being calm you know for example
uh if you get into a situation that you
think is getting out of hand
sometimes it's just better to just walk
away
as difficult as it may sound it's not
every battle you need to win
choose your battles wisely especially in
a corporate environment
uh yeah i think those are the tips tips
i'd give for self-regulation
motivation uh being passionate it's a
passion to work for reasons that go
beyond money or
status it's a propensity to pursue goals
with energy
and persistence motivation is very
important
when you want to achieve your goals
especially if you're a leader it's not
only about
motivating yourself but it's also
motivating your team as well to achieve
the goals they have to achieve uh
you also need to um always be
um mindful or remember the reason why
you did your role
or your job what you enjoy about it you
know
and that kind of thing hallmarks of that
is having a strong drive
to achieve optimism even in the face of
failure organizational commitment
uh basically just having a
positive twist to everything you do you
know for example for those of us
in the agile space we would always say
that
failure is good i i lecture at the
university and when you go
and you tell the kids that failure is
good they all look at you like you
you've lost a few
screws up there and i always like to add
to that by
saying that it's not the failure itself
that you should be concentrating on
but it's the lesson learned and then
moving forward how you would change that
so these are the kind of things i mean
by being optimistic at all times because
trust me if you're negative and if you
run teams and you come in the morning
to with your team and you're actually
negative and you have a negative
outlook it impacts
the whole team so as a leader it's very
important that one you're motivated to
do your own work to set your own
personal goals
but two that you motivate the team
you're leading
to carry them on this journey whatever
that would be
um the next thing
we will talk about is empathy
for me i think empathy is big
it's one of the biggest ones you have to
have in ei as far as i'm concerned
uh it's the ability to understand the
emotional makeup of
other people it's the skill in treating
people according to their
emotional reactions and
this is very important when dealing with
other individuals
and working in any environments because
when it's like that people that tend to
be like that
need uh tend to understand people
from their perspectives you know some of
the tips i would give uh
being able to put yourself in other
people's shoes you know if someone gives
you a reason or
someone you you don't necessarily have
to always be right
people because we're different will have
a different
view or outlook to a particular
situation and sometimes
these different outlook and views
also help when solving an issue so
always look at something from someone's
perspective
if someone is telling you something that
is contrary to what you believe
always think why is the person saying
that
or telling me this you know another
important thing
in this particular with empathy is
reading body language
and being attentive to the way people
communicate
you know um
communication is not just speaking to be
honest
it's there's a lot of different other
forms of communication so
one thing i always um recommend to
people especially people who want to
lead
is studied the other the various types
of communication because you know for
example
if someone is talking to you and they
they just can't stare you in the
eye then you wonder if what they're
saying is
it's the truth or not you know that kind
of thing so it's very
important that you you you you read body
language
also another tip is um to understand
how others are feeling so that you'll be
you'll be able to work with them better
hallmarks of this particular trait is
expertise in building and retaining
talent
another interesting one is
cross-cultural sensitivity
cross-cultural sensitivity especially
in this day and age we work in
is a very important
thing um simple example for example
for even me myself um going
um going to ghana uh
for the first time and seeing uh
people a lot of people you know walk in
like men who were friends walking
holding hands
uh women who were friends working
holding hands and i was thinking oh we
have a lot of
um you know the lgbt community is quite
big
in ghana than it seems and i was saying
that to someone i said because i see a
lot of people holding they said no
they're just friends you're like oh
okay so you know that kind of thing
or for example going to
to to uh you know like for for those of
us
who've grown up in the west there's a
lot of um
personal space you have so you don't
want people to come
very close to you or as you start
feeling a bit um
claustrophobic almost and you you come
and at times people want to come talk to
you
look very close huddle next to you and
you know having to deal with that all
for example even in the first
work space i remember earlier on when i
started dealing with teams in
india and you call and they just pick
the phone and the first thing they'll
tell you
is yes tell me and i used to feel so
offended about it and later i realized
that's the way they talk
it's you know they're not being abrasive
they're not being rude
and that kind of thing uh i think i
belabor the point a little bit too long
and another interesting one is service
to clients and customers as well so with
empathy it's very
important especially if you have
customer facing roles where you have to
deal with clients and they're bringing
in complaints
uh not to go challenge the clients for
example because
um i've seen that happen in interesting
scenarios and
that should not be the norm i'd move to
the last one which is social skills
and with that one it's proficiency in
managing relationships and building
networks
it's an ability to find common ground
and build rapport
now for that one social skills is also a
big one
that as a leader one needs to
continuously develop
this particular skill um
people that have have um this particular
skill tend to be
good communicators they tend to be able
to effectively manage
change another big thing with that one
is being able to resolve
conflicts diplomatically so
the hallmarks of that which i've already
stated effectiveness in leading church
persuasiveness expertise in building
uh large uh in building and leading
teams
so with that one the tips i would give
to enhance that particular skill
is to learn to conflict resolution
um also as a leader another good thing
with that one is to
learn to acknowledge good work that has
been done by team members
uh so to for this particular page the
only other thing i would like to add to
that
is these elements of
these five elements of ei actually um
help you to lead to to perform better
it helps you to effectively
relate to members at work and it's
it really deals with in the bottom line
it really deals with one's attitude
towards work and towards
each other your relationships with
people
being aware of yourself and how you come
across
and basically self management and
this is something that with time and
practice
would actually help one be effective
in their role
okay so i'm going to move on to the next
slide where we'll talk about
ei and team performance
so with with ei and team performance
it helps with the with group group
collaboration
and creating the right environment for
people to work creating the right group
dynamics
sort of uh like personal connection for
purpose
cultural emotional connection behavior
and one thing that one should understand
that when it comes to
creating these in in the team dynamics
it
is not an easy thing to do i must
reiterate because
sometimes these things come as close as
very simplistic
but as long as we're dealing with human
beings
who happen and we all know we are all
complex in our right
we need to understand that it is not an
easy thing to inculcate in an
environment
and in a culture but it is something
that
helps to create high performing teams
and that it takes time so one of the
things you need to think about
is the motivations as a team leader of
each person on a team to contribute to
the team
dynamic so with that one you're talking
about
um influencing patterns
of the way people think how how they
react to each
each other how you know you also need to
if you have a team you also need to
understand each
individual you have in the team and in
so
doing it's important that you know what
motivates each person you have within
your team in so doing you're able to
create
the right environment where each team
member
actually contributes to ensure
growth and ensure that the common goal
of the organization
is achieved and you also need to
ensure that each person will naturally
naturally contribute their strengths for
the betterment of the team
because if you have a team you have
different individuals within the team
you need to understand
what they're good at how best they like
to work in a team you know like for
example you may have some people
who are a stickler for detail they would
have want more attention to detail so
you give them tasks that is
that relates to that you have some
people who
would may not talk a lot more but then
they have the way they work so being
able to understand how person a
and person b works is always good to to
to be able to
create the right environment and get the
best out of them to deliver
it's also important to deliver to
develop interpersonal
and interpersonal skills intra
and interpersonal skills within the team
um you need to create the right
environments where
team members can work with each other
peaceably you know it's a place that
you need to create an environment where
the team members feel
comfortable to work when you know where
there
are um there would they're bound to be
conflicts
if you work in a team because we're
individuals but it
the needs that you need to create the
environment as a leader where
these conflicts had are nipped in the
body they're dealt with they're handled
immediately not something that is swept
under the carpet because trust me if
you notice that there's something that
could lead to a big conflict
and you don't deal in with it at the
earliest stages
it would explode and sometimes if you
had dealt with that
earlier it will just die everything now
and everything would go on as normal but
if you
leave it and ignore it it would explode
and at times
spoil all the team dynamics that you
created what
hard for you know all of a sudden the
worst thing you would want is having a
team with
this is supporting person b a and that
is supporting person b
i think even we had um i think i'm gonna
give my age here
when i say i remember there was a time
when the black stars of ghana
yeah football we all love it when it
comes to world cup there was a time when
we had
team members who one person thought he
should have been the captain as opposed
to the other
and you had team members not uh
siding with one person as opposed to the
other that means that even when they're
passing the ball they would not pass the
ball to
someone who supported the other side in
so doing
you have spoiled productivity you have
spoiled everything
now if in the beginning if the coach had
just picked these two people
talked to them and dealt with it from
the get-go
that would have sorted the situation
straight away
also ensure that you assess situation
from the point of views of others
um this keeps coming up over and over
again
i think that is because in most times
when we work with people if the person
does not accept things from your
perspective
and from your view at times you come
across
leadership that gets quite upset with
such
people especially if you're deemed to be
a troublemaker or voice over
or very voice affairs but you actually
need to listen to people
and to listen to why their view is
different and
understand it because in so you as an
individual also learns a lot
and in so doing when you do all these
things then you create an environment
where there's trust people
feel like they can be free and talk and
be happy because if you have a happy
environment
you'd have people who would deliver
because they feel comfortable in the
environment
within which they work okay
okay so let's move to the next one uh
this is um we're just going to talk here
about the
seven ways or steps to create an ei team
um
with these seven steps um i believe that
if you go through it
you you're on your way to a winner
so the first step at the top is
having a ring leader so
like i said earlier it's not easy to
create
the right environment where there's
trust there's a sense of group
and identity there's the sense of yeah
we're
building you know together we stand
together we fall that kind of thing
that's the right environment you want to
create but it starts with you yourself
you the ring leader you always there's a
there's a famous quote that a lot of
people in the change space always talk
about from
gandhi i believe which says that you
have to be the change you want to see
if you as a leader want everyone to be
at work at nine o'clock and you walk
into work at
midday hello they're also gonna do the
same
because i i for one always feel like if
you go into an environment
and you see the way people behave
it tends in most invariably in most
instances
to be a depiction of you the leader
yourself
so as a as as the ring leader you need
to start off
by working on yourselves you need to go
through
all the different steps i highlighted in
the previous slide with regards to e.i
like self-awareness emotional management
effective communication
social awareness uh conflict resolution
you need to be the kind of
leader that is respected by the team um
you need to create the the let them know
that you are there for them
you've got your the back of your team
members if i may say so
let that be polite and be be respectful
to your team members
show willingness to change listen
you know and listening is such an
important thing it's not the kind of
listen when someone is talking to
you're like yeah okay are you on your
laptop sending an email away or sending
a text message
no put everything down sit down make
time for whoever is in your team that
has sought you
out and listen to them because it's very
important
that the team members know that you are
their ring leader
when there are mistakes that you made
just go out and say i messed up guys
there's so much power in doing that to
you know
so always do that always be helpful
always be there for them
right and move on to the next one which
is identifying the team's
members strengths and weaknesses
it's not only about
just getting different individuals i'm
sure that
all the members in the team have been
hired because they have
their unique strengths and weakness and
their unique strengths and talents that
you think is best for the team but then
everyone has what they're good at
so sometimes it's good to know each
individual beyond what the workspace you
know
so you also know what they are
passionate at you also know
what they enjoy doing bring those
strengths out
also look at in every team you have the
quieter ones don't leave them
on this journey all galvanize them
encourage
people for like people who are stronger
technically for example
encore encourage them to pair up with
those that are
not as strong in a particular topic or
area so that
they can they can pass on the knowledge
for a lot for some of the teams in some
environments i've worked for fridays for
example
we have brownback sessions where team
members would come and teach other team
members within the team
a different topic encourage innovation
you know
uh that kind of thing and also
when you when people are doing work you
know let them
have do the bits they're good at you
know at the same time
hone in the skills skill sets of the
areas they're not so good at
so that you can have a well-rounded team
um the next thing would be to spark
passion within the team it's not only
about getting the right team
but it's also about getting
the right individuals that fit into your
your company culture that fits into
your organization that are in line with
your your goals your
vision that are passionate about it so
they can work
work as well to to to to achieve that
so it's very important to note that as a
leader when picking
people for your team at times
passions will deep dip you know
sometimes you know
life happens and it gets too much as a
team leader
always try to ensure that you notice
that
and get ways for people to re-engage to
to to sort of reignite their first love
if i may say so
even for those that are married for a
thousand years
with time they have to work at the
relationship for it to work it's the
same thing i'm using practical examples
so people can know
that it's it's doable um also another
good thing
is always recognizing uh
people for the accomplishments and the
good work they've done
also creating a flexible working
environment
especially for example now we have a
situation where
all of us are working from home so you
know but then
normally creating that flexibility is
always
uh important
uh to ensure that the passion is there
and the like
yeah i think that covers that much for
sparking passion
and then we'll talk about building team
norms uh with building team norms it's
always good
um even if you had a team to
create an environment where the team
members come together i always recommend
if possible that team members come
together and they create their own
norms and create um they state
this is how we would plan to work
together as a team
right and another thing that is good is
always
um saying thank you creating the right
harmony ensure that there is lack of
tension
creating a an environment where team
members
like each other because uh well
especially in the i keep saying i'd
refer to that as the old world because i
think the way we've done work
so far it's going to change but in
environments where we always
see each other every day it's very
important that the environment
is not full of tension and
that team members are working
as a unit you know and in so doing
they because i also feel like if the
team members have created their own
norms themselves
then they would commit to fulfilling
these norms because it is
it's a form of self-governance if you
ask me and in so doing you know when you
see the respect amongst
each other then there's a lot of banter
and the like and people
know not how not to go about crossing
the line
then i think you've that you've done
well in that
instance another big thing is developing
creative ways to manage stress
stress is bound to happen and
but then as a leader for example you
need to see
that's coming your way and coming up
with ways to
handle and deal with the stress because
if stress is not handled
properly it can even lead to health
issues
and having individuals being burnt out
so one of the ways you can deal with
that for example is how you
handle deadlines uh for example if you
have
projects you're planning when you plan a
project
create a buffer on the timeline by
buffer i mean
if you think that the development is
gonna take two weeks
then make it two weeks and a day or two
just for any eventuality because you
don't want
um the the the individuals working on
the projects to be stressed towards the
end that tends to happen a lot um
another big thing which i always keep
talking about is handling grievances
um trying to deal with schedules
also encourage team members to take
breaks
it's saddening at times you go into some
organizations
and you notice that the team members are
under so much pressure that they're
having their lunch
at their desk so encourage team members
to take
breaks to go out for a walk to get some
fresh air you know
to to to you know it helps you to really
recharge your energies and come back
uh to do your work discourage
multitasking a lot of people think that
multitasking will get some more work
done but
in actually in in in reality
it worsens the situation at times it
leads to
people having to go back to redo the
work or you're not getting
the the right work that the right
results
and the right quality you want of a
particular job
so try not to get any um
rush to job as well be
um empathetic this i cannot say that
enough
uh for example if you have team members
and you notice that for example
someone is not behaving like the way
they ought to
go and find out what is wrong you know
uh for example i had another instance
where i had a very team
a team member who used to be quite a
calm guy and all of a sudden was coming
to work and just the slightest thing
the guy was that shouting you know and
straight away i noticed oh there's
something not right here
so just pulled him aside saying oh let's
go for a walk we had a chat
and it turns out he's going through a
divorce now with that level of stress
he's coming
to work and he's shouting at everyone
because he's
going through a lot of drama at home you
know so
always be able to watch out when people
are not behaving
the way they normally do there may be a
problem there
try to find out what the issue is
and find innovative ways ask the person
how can we do to help do you need time
away from work do you need this
you know so in so doing because these
things it's just like having a rotten
apple in a box
full of fresh ones it's gonna
contaminate all the other ones if you
don't take it out
so stress is a very important thing that
you need to deal with
another one is allowing team members to
have a voice
let your team members speak up let them
speak
their their concerns teach your team
members to
communicate effectively you know should
not be aggression
it should not be a fight it should not
be that i need to be very
loud for my voice to be heard
let them do that let them talk to you
let their voice be heard
at times when you have
team members especially in teams that
didn't
that relates directly with customers and
end users
they at times come up with amazing
innovative solutions that as a business
you may not have even
thought about so let them pitch these
ideas uh
if you're working in an agile space this
is where another
great thing that the retrospective is
for let them talk about ways we can
improve
but let them have a voice and not only
having a voice
let them know that their voice and their
opinion
matters it makes a whole lot of
difference
when someone knows that i can go and say
so
and it's not gonna come up at the end of
the year when there's time for reviews
and for a pay rise
it wouldn't be used negatively against
me because some environments
do that in so doing if you try to go
down that route
you may be losing a good employee
or very good ideas will be lost
because you didn't listen another
important thing is encourage employees
to work and play together
uh for me i've always deemed that to be
very important well nowadays i don't
know how that's gonna change
although now we've been doing virtual
drinks online which is equally
interesting but
the important thing is that we spend so
much time
working so many hours that it's
important that
the team gets the time to play as well
previously for some of the teams i have
worked with for example
at the end of a project we would go
bowling we would go
you know a catering class where we cook
you know that kind of thing sometimes
going to eat
out there was a startup i worked
with and once a month they will do the
the guys will do a gaming night
sadly i was the only girl in the whole
company and i don't do computer games
but hey
i was happy to arrange it everything get
all the drinks and everything they
needed and they would spend the whole
night friday night until saturday
morning
i hear they'll stare spend it's doing
their fifa
they're racing whatever but what tends
to happen
is because they bond at that level
you notice coming back to work on monday
that
day there is this banter you know they
relate to each other better they handle
tensions better because they played
together so it's it's it's a very
important aspect and you know sometimes
in so doing you hear
beautiful things about people that you
wouldn't know you know
someone who's traveled the world someone
who maybe spends time for charity
you know that kind of thing so you
actually see the person
because seeing the person always out of
work helps when you come back to work
because you just don't see them
as person a with employee id xyz but
instead you see the person as maybe
peter
father of two peter likes to go mountain
climbing so you can talk to peter about
mountain climbing and everything because
then
you can relate to them at a personal
level so it's not just about work
because
the person needs to be to feel like they
matter
and i think for me with ei one of the
biggest thing is just
making team members feel like they
matter because as individuals
when we feel like we matter
we perform better oh that should be a
quarter i should copyright
okay so uh seems to wear agile um i'll
just
also i always always want to link this
with scrum values because
we shouldn't think that this is really
far from us
i've seen uh and i've mentioned some
amazing scrum masters
and one of the reasons why they've been
good at it
has been because of the
their high ei score because of the
empathy they have
towards their team members because of
the way they feel
and want to do everything and to ensure
that their team members are well so
um for me when i look at the scrum
values it just screams ei to me but
maybe i'm just a crazy agile lady so
when we talk about
courage um that is just talking about
scrum team members having the courage to
do the right thing
having the courage to work on tough
problems
but also having the courage to speak
what they think
when we look at focus it's everyone
focusing on the work of the sprint
and they're focused on the goals of the
scrum team because they committed to the
goals themselves
they are motivated to deliver these
goals
commitments people personally committing
to achieve the goals of the scrum team
because
there's nothing worse than having people
not committed to the work they're doing
you would not get the results you want
so being able to be to commit to that
is very important respect respect
is one of the biggest things as far as i
am concerned
because when it comes to respect scrum
team members need to respect each other
to be
capable and independent people it's not
only
about you know seeing someone and
calling the person mr a
and mr b no respect it's one of those
things that is so
difficult to achieve but they're so easy
to lose
treat people with respect you know it's
it's it's so beautiful when you go into
organizations and you see
leaders making time to speak to people
in the canteen
to the cleaners and everything in so
doing they have respect there was
um i think there was a video i saw on
the news once when the
i think it was the dutch prime minister
also who was walking around he spilled
his coffee
he took the mop himself he mopped it
despite the fact that the cleaning lady
wanted to do it in so doing you know
the respect he showed to that person
and the respect he earned was just
phenomenal because
everyone was talking about it and
everyone was talking about how amazing a
leader
he is so this is very important that we
bring that across
we give it and we receive it as well if
you want it
you have to give it respect to me
also means that when i'm angry i don't
shout at another person
that person at work may be
working in my team and i may be the
manager
but at home this person is is is a
leader in society
this person is someone's father or
someone's mother
who talks to them with respect so let's
bear that in mind
when we're dealing with people openness
being
open so the scrum team and its
stakeholders agree
to be open about all the work and
challenges with performing the work
if you are open i think that it's it's
freeing even to be
open because um when you're open you
just say the issues as they are
and if you in so doing most of the time
you actually get um your issues resolved
quicker than you would envisage one of
the projects i even worked on i had
an impediments board it was quite a new
project right in the middle because i
of the room because you open the door
the first thing you saw was the
impediments board because i had all the
senior stakeholders coming
and they'll look and say oh who do you
need to fix it and it's fixed
so being open is another good one i'd
end here by saying that
um in order to be successful in an agile
environment
one's e.i must be very high
and with that i come to the end of this
session
thank you everyone for making time to
listen to me
i'm gonna stop presenting my
screen uh and then
if you have any questions
i thank you very much thank you thank
you very much um
please are there any questions for our
wonderful
presenter i can see something in the
chats
thank you martin you're always a star i
enjoyed ears as well
old world nana
any any questions you can put in the
chat or raise your hands
um louisa you can also share your
linkedin um
link so that people can connect with you
too okay i will do that
okay so um
it's a new message so people are just
thanking you for a wonderful
presentation thank you everyone
thank you for listening i hope it's it
helps you in your
day-to-day life and with whatever teams
you
you you're managing as well you can also
put in my linkedin connection you can
also reach out to me if you had any
questions
yeah okay
you