okay this is Martin ho8
from Naked agility I come a few things
that I wanted to mention tonight I'm
going to be doing meetup for the future
of work in conjunction with the British
Computer Society at 7 p.m. UK time
tonight
I'm going to be talking about scaling
dragons the the things that are going to
be beneficial or destroyers as we move
towards scaling agility and things that
we need to consider and figure out so I
think that will be good fun we're going
to be I'm going to be talking about I'm
going to be talking about scrum
initially and then I'm going to be
diving a little bit into Nexus but more
from the perspective of the practices
that really matter for a large-scale
scrum team talk about them for a little
bit and then maybe we'll touch a little
bit on metrics and getting an
understanding of some of the key at
least starter metrics you might not be
the metrics I'm going to talk about
might not be valid for your organization
but you can use them as a starter point
as hints as a lead through towards
understanding metrics that might be
viable for your organization that's so
that's scaling dragons tonight at 7 p.m.
gmt with the future of work meetup in
conjunction with the British Computer
Society
it's also going to stream live on
YouTube LinkedIn and Facebook so if you
can't get into those events you can
certainly get into get into that but
ultimately if you want to be in an
interactive session then definitely head
over to the Meetup and join in the folks
that are organizing the meet are awesome
and we're gonna have a good fun
again that's future of work in
conjunction with British Computer
Society at 7:00 p.m. tonight I also
wanted to mention that I'm working
obviously there's no in-person events
going on so any time that I've got a
conference event we're going to be doing
it online if the conference event is
cancelled
then I will record or do a live event
anyway at the same time or separately
off of that talk and so that people can
join in and I'm also going to be moving
some of my training classes to be live
virtual classes this is a very
complicated thing all of the scrum the
dark classes that I teach are really
designed to be high bandwidth impersonal
classes so what I want to do is for the
classes that make sense we're going to
run some virtual classes we'll probably
run them as kind of like a 2-day event
and see what makes sense whether it
makes sense to continue to run it as a
two-day event or to balance that with
like a you know dude over 40 is four
half days or do two full days what what
makes sense for for that training so
I've been looking at the the
professional scrum master and the
professional scrum with you
acts are ones that I think I'm going to
run first in the next couple of weeks I
have classes scheduled in Edinburgh for
that so I want to convert them to live
events it's going to be really
interesting how we manage to run those
Edinburgh classes with that number of
people how do we run that virtually so
I've been looking at the technologies
involved I've been practicing with the
technologies involved and hopefully
we'll be able to come up experiment and
inspect and adapt towards some super
awesome classes and the other classes I
think that are going to be pretty good
online is the the professional agile
leadership which I have a class coming
up this month we moved to virtual and as
coming up in the the GMT time zone and I
have a agile leadership in the Mexico
City as well gonna move that to virtual
we'll see how that works I've got a
colleague that I'm working with to
deliver that in both English and Spanish
so hopefully that work out I'm also the
professional scrum of Kanban with Daniel
Vacanti then I'm running in month or so
we'll also be moved to virtual and
Daniel and I will be running that as a
co-teach over two days and we'll see if
that works out and I've been in touch
with the folks during during the
professor scrum at a man we actually use
the get Kanban game from get Kanban calm
and which I have physical copies of but
obviously that won't work for a virtual
class so how are we going to run that
I've been in touch with the folks that
get Kanban to see if they'd be willing
to implement a version of that of their
game on table topia table topia is a
virtualization platform for board games
I've been using that with some of my my
friends to play some be awesome board
games that we play I'm really figuring
out how to run these classes luck
from the dog community and has been
banding together we've been talking
about and exploring different options
for how to do virtual class he's how we
break them up how we organize that so I
just want to make sure that the reason
we're that there is a session tonight a
future of work session with British
Computer Society I'm going to be talking
about scaling scrum to the enterprise
and hopefully be able to join us at 7:00
p.m. GMT tonight and it's been a stream
live on Facebook and LinkedIn and
YouTube so you should be able to test
that ah feel free to follow me on
Twitter get in touch if you have any
questions I'm super happy to do sessions
with anybody who needs it on both
agility and DevOps if you want to talk
about DevOps practices if you want to
talk about maturity of a scrum team
principles and values if you want to
talk about and just as your DevOps
DevOps in general whatever you want to
talk about ping me on Twitter we can get
on a call we can chat maybe you just
have a question that you want an answer
maybe I can just give you an answer and
let's let's figure out how to use this
time that we've all got enclosed in our
forms to the best benefit of everybody
else normally I'd be off at traveling
the world consulting in person which is
obviously my preferred way to work but
at the moment it's not possible so let
me know if you need any help if you just
want to chat I'm not talking about
charging you for that I'm talking about
just having a chat if we can spend half
hour on a call and figure something out
or I can do a webcast on a particular
topic that helps solve a problem for you
I'm super happy to do that if you're
looking to get two days of time with me
then we can figure that out as we go but
I'm really looking forward to
the different form are experimenting
inspecting and adapting with the
different forms of interaction that we
can have over the next months as we are
stuck where we are and luckily as I
consulted travel worldwide obviously I'm
happy to speak to and hear from anybody
anywhere in the world I've been training
in Saudi Arabia which was super fun very
different than I expected and I trained
in Ghana in Africa which is one of my
favorite places to be and I've also been
out to Azerbaijan as well so I'm happy
to work anywhere in the world you're
mopping okay thanks very much for for
listening and and I hope you you get in
touch and follow me on Twitter to find
out what's going on okay