I have this picture in my head of Ken
saying it to me many years ago um just
enough and no more and I believe in fact
he actually I think he said that um no
matter what quantity
question I ask
him the answer is going to be just
enough and no more doesn't matter what
the quantity question is right so how
much backlog should we have just enough
and no more how many developers should
we have have just enough and no more how
much time should we spend on refinement
just enough and no more same for
planning upfront that
Mantra of being focused on what it is
we're doing and minimizing our effort
one of the the um principles in the
agile Manifesto is maximizing the amount
of work not done