I think the biggest misconception about
a scrum Master is that they're they're
an order Giver they're somehow in
control of anything
um ideally the scrum master has no
Authority whatsoever
um within the context of the team and in
fact is selected by the team so you
could say that there are servant leader
a leader who serves for the team
um so the biggest misconception is that
they're in charge of anything that
people should be giving them status
updates that they should be writing
reports these are all ridiculous things
that are not part of being a scrum
master and if you want to know more come
to the advanced scrum master class and
find out