there's an idea out there the agility
equals
speed and I think this is in the same
category
of agile project manager right it's an
oxymoron it doesn't exist it's not a
thing that's not what agility is
about agility is about spending your
time
well that's probably probably a bit I
think that's a good way to describe it
prob spending your time well the time we
do spend is on valuable Endeavors we
spend less time doing the wrong thing
and more time doing the right thing
that's the idea that we're trying to
achieve but in order to find the right
thing we've got to try 10 things to find
the three things that work right so the
idea that agility is about
speed is a complete
fallacy because we might have to do nine
things before we find the one thing that
works so if each of those things took
two
weeks that's 20
weeks and we did one
thing well why don't we
just decide what those 10 things are up
front look at them and go let's do that
one let's do number five and just do
that one thing and then we're done we've
buil a product right
well is that the right product does it
have Market fit are people going to buy
it is it even the right feature does it
actually provide value to the
customers we don't know any of those
things we could have just built the
wrong thing L lots of organizations fail
because of
assumptions they fail because they think
they're building the thing that they
want but they're but they're not they're
not building the thing that the customer
wants my favorite example was was um I
use this one I use this one a lot sorry
that um I was was they've been bought so
now the product sucks but um I was an
average user of a product called Zoom
AI right so this was an awesome product
and what it allowed you to do um was
multiple things it was basically a
calendaring tool right one of those
calendaring tools but its unique
Focus was on a kind of kind of Bot based
calendaring tool so you could have a you
had a bot I I use teams so I had a bot
in in teams that I can just go message
it and say um I want to meet with Simon
um at 4:00 on Friday go organize that
and it will email Simon and say Simon
Mar wants to meet at for Fridays this
work for you yes or no would you like to
pick some times that that you and Martin
have available okay pick some times and
then it comes back and that that was
that story so it was a bot-based
interactive it was maybe a bit early
right
probably the the versions coming now
with AI are are going to make this a lot
more effective but it it worked um and
it was great but I and almost all of the
other customers found that they didn't
really use it that way what they used it
was was a calendaring tool send people a
link here's how um here's my free time
go book book a slot cuz it was just just
easier right you didn't even have to
write a message to some you just send
them the
link
so while they were Zoom Ai and this AI
story um they actually very much ended
up just changing the whole company ethos
and focus from that to calendar hero um
and they were just another calendaring
tool but a very good one they've been
bought by somebody else now and
everything has gone crap but um cuz you
know you're really good somebody comes
and buys you and then they absorb you
and eat you and now you're no longer
good but the the
that
idea of completely changing not only
your your business your focus um your
your company name is around why is your
Market fit and what a lot of big
organizations fail to realize is is that
their Market changes it's not that they
fail to realize it it's they don't
understand how to take advantage of it
because they build up rust right in all
of the bureaucracy that builds up around
the organization we shouldn't have a lot
of bureaucracy if you have a lot of
bureaucracy in your organization you're
doing it wrong right that's that's all
you're not able to respond to Market
changes quickly enough if you have a lot
of bureaucracy um local optimizations
right so
this comes back to that idea of agility
is not equal to speed the purpose of
agility is not to go
faster if you think you're going to do
Agile to make you go faster you're wrong
it's not going to work that way if you
have 300 things to
do it's going to take 300 things worth
of time to do whether you do Agile
waterfall whatever you've got 300 things
to
do the way agile makes it seem like
you're going
faster is maybe you don't need 300
things maybe you only need 100
things that's how it might seem like
it's faster because we do 100 things and
we're
done right uh think of the Sentinel The
Sentinel project right that's the big
famous one that was the US uh FBI uh uh
Records keeping system uh 1995 brand new
system was delivered it was green screen
with terminals right we all had Windows
95 at that point and they realized it
was obsolete the moment they shipped it
so they started working on the new
version project Sentinel right and they
had money from Congress so $400 million
and I can't remember the company might
have been ly Martin that was building it
um and they spent four years $400
million and at the end of that they
didn't have a working product no working
product so they had to go to Congress
get more money $300 million 5 years
spent $300 million another 5 years
no working product right not very
fast got
to I don't know
2012 they've been going for nearly 10
years this project had been going for
nearly 10 years maybe 2005 anyway nearly
10 years and um they decided to quit the
whole thing they took the best people
out of the the group that they had
building it they hired them the FBI
physically hired the people people um
set up scrum teams in the basement of
the Hoover building so they had about 40
people went from 400 people to 40 people
and they delivered to production within
a year so you could say that they went
faster but they didn't go faster they
just didn't try and build the whole
thing they just built the first
piece right they got to production
within a year that's the speed that
we're talking about we're not actually
talking about delivering what you
thought you were going to get faster
you're going to get a better product in
the same amount of time so the best way
to think about it is if we have a let's
say it cost $10,000 per Sprint um we've
got $100,000 we can do 10
Sprints we can do five things per
Sprint do we just do these 50 things we
decide up front or do we figure out as
we go which 50 things are the best 50
things to build we've still spent
exactly the same amount of time but we
have a better 50 things that we've
delivered we've got 50 of the wrer
things than just the 50 things we
thought we needed at the start and
that's why agile is not about speed