[Music]
[Applause]
hi my name is Martin Intuit I'm the
owner at Naked agility and I'm a
professional scrum trainer and Microsoft
MVP I'd like to talk to you about
professional agile leadership training
from scrum de-torque professional agile
leadership essentials is a two-day
hands-on workshop that uses a
combination of instruction and hands-on
exercises to help managers and other
leaders who work directly with agile
teams understand how best to support
guide and coach their teams to improve
their agile capabilities the workshop
provides a foundation for the role that
leaders play in creating the conditions
for a successful agile evolution leaders
and managers are critical enabler in
helping their organizations be
successful
yet the role of leaders and managers in
an agile organization can be quite
different from what they are used to now
this workshop uses a combination of
instruction and team based exercises to
help participants learn how to form and
support agile teams to achieve better
results and how to lead the cultural and
behavioral changes that organizations
must make to reap the benefits of an
agile product delivery approach becoming
an agile organization is a profound
evolution that requires senior leaders
middle managers and agile team members
to change the way they organize their
work manage their work and measure the
results of their work agile teams cannot
do this on their own they need help from
the entire organization the changes for
all involved are profound but so are the
results when everyone's goal and way of
working are aligned
to succeed in a changing world
organizations need to become more agile
more responsive to customer needs and
market changes this workshop will equip
leaders and managers to help their
organizations change by providing
participants with an understanding of
how agility can help you improve your
organization's performance an
understanding of how you as a manager or
leader can help your organization
achieve the benefits of agility an
understanding of how culture and values
influence your organization's ability to
reap the benefits of agility practical
skills for helping to guide and coach
agile teams and to help them remove
impediments an understanding of how to
measure the benefits and impacts of
agility in your organization by the end
of this class you will understand where
and how agility can help your
organization improve by addressing
challenges you can solve in no other way
you will also understand how agile teams
work and what you as a manager or leader
can do to help them improve you will
also be able to qualify the benefits of
improving the agility of your
organization through concrete measures
this class can be delivered on site or
as a live virtual classroom in a
specific organization to help its
leaders understand their important role
in evolving their organization or in a
public class setting
you