start small grow smarter a perfect
definition of done doesn't happen
overnight you don't start with
perfection you build towards it
incrementally deliberately and
strategically early on done might just
mean usable then it evolves adding
automated tests telemetry security
compliance continuous deployment each
improvement makes your increment
stronger each improvement builds trust
quality and business resilience at naked
agility we help teams evolve their
definition of done over time without
overwhelming people without losing
momentum and without sacrificing
outcomes done is a journey not a single
decision want to involve your standards
without overwhelming your teams let's
start the journey