definition of dun in scrum is one of the
most important pieces of the puzzle uh
definition of done uh really represents
the level of quality um that your
product
has but
it's that it's almost that line you have
to cross if if you look at the the the
US Department of Defense uh guide
detecting adile [ __ ] one of my
favorite articles uh you'll see it talks
about um working product in front of
real users every iteration including the
first the agile
Manifesto talks about um working usable
product um at least every few weeks at
least every few months right and scrum
is
probably
the strictest of them that says you need
to have usable working product at the
end of every Sprint every Sprint you
must have usable working product that
doesn't mean you're going to ship it
although why would you build a bunch of
value and then not advertise it right is
that right but the minimum for
scrum the minimum to be doing scrum is
that you need a usable working product
at end of the Sprint that usable working
product is the
foundation of risk mitigation in scrum
It ultimately usable working product is
the foundation of risk mitigation in all
of agile practices right um but it's
also that that moment of
transparency right if you think about
the other transparencies in scrum you've
got transparency of the future with the
the the product backlog you've got
transparency of the present with the
Sprint backlog and then transparency of
the past is the increment right and the
way we enable transparency of the past
is through committing to the definition
of done without that commitment to the
definition of done having a definition
of done that represents usable working
product and meeting it at the end of
every Sprint then the other two
transparencies are
irrelevant right unless we can see what
we've done how can we know where we're
going if you don't know where you are
and where you've
been how do you know how to get to where
you want to be you you have to
understand what's in your product
currently whether it works or it doesn't
I is it finished or is there more work
to do to make it get to that
point before you can figure out how do
we if this is the future State and this
is the current state and our backlog
represents a diff between those two
states if this is a false State i. it's
not transparent where we currently are
maybe we're here maybe we're there maybe
we're over here if we don't know then we
don't know the journey we have to take
between those two points right so
definition of done is the commitment to
Quality that enables us to have that
point and then the next little
journey is your your Sprint back clog
but we still have to know where we are
to know where at the end of the Sprint
we need to
be right so that's that critical
importance and we we use that as our
risk M risk mitigation in scrum in
traditional models you're going to look
at across the entire life of the product
the project right you're going to look
at all of the risks that might possibly
happen and then you're going to create a
bunch of mitigating actions should those
risks arise and that's part of your your
plan for for the whole thing but in
agile we're we're not planning that far
ahead head we're planning more often but
in smaller chunks to see if we get there
so the way that we mitigate risk in that
story and we don't go off in the wrong
direction we don't build a bunch of
stuff that doesn't actually work and
then we find out later right that's
adding risk we need that working usable
product so the definition of done is the
most important and foundational Concept
in scrum and I would suggest all of
agile knowing what it means to be done
is that important yeah so that
definition of done being so important is
absolutely critical to the success of
any product and here's a good test that
you can use with your team um if you
have a team if you work with a team if
you're a leader and there are teams
right go ask somebody on the team
perhaps bring it up at the review right
ask ask what the definition of d is if
they haven't articulated it to you and
if the answer is anything other than our
definition of done is this if it's
anything other than that they don't have
one if the answer is it's on the wiki
it's on the wiki right they don't have
one because if it's on the wiki and each
individual member of the team can't
articulate it what are the chances that
they're meeting it therefore it does not
exist
so have a definition of done get one if
you don't have
one definition of done the most
important thing in agile and scrum
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked
agility