question is is the PSM 2 course
or psme right an advanced scrum Master
Class
validation of your skills or does it
develop your skills and capability as a
scrum master
and I think it's the latter right
um there's there's
if you if you're coming to A A PSM an
advanced scrum master class and you're
just validating your skills go take the
assessment and don't bother with the
class right that's that's that's the way
I would think about it
um and I feel that there's actually not
in implementation there's actually not
that much relationship between the
intent of the PSM the advanced scrum
master class and the intent of the psm2
assessment right they're they're
slightly different things
and I think the class is much broader in
that it's designed to develop your skill
and capability as a scrum master
whereas the assessment is just assessing
the knowledge part of that story
um so a key key differentiator is that
the the advanced scrum Master Class
focuses on
um facilitation it focuses on the scrum
Master being a professional scrum Master
rather than just an admin for the team
which often happens right it focuses on
that difference between uh being given
the job title of scrum master and
fulfilling the accountability of the
scrum master that it talks about in the
scrum guide
that's that's the real purpose of of the
class with a whole bunch of uh the way
it kind of does it is
that's the story of the class right and
then we're going to talk about not just
that part but what is the scrum Master's
accountability to the team what's the
scrum Master's accountability to the
product owner what's the score Master's
accountability to the organization right
that's the story of the class
but in teaching the class
and participating in the class
we're using facilitation techniques to
help the students understand those
things that also teaches them how to use
those facilitation techniques
right so a
the way I teach the class it we I use a
lot of liberating structures in the
class uh we I use a lot of strings of
liberating structures so Liberty
structures connected together to get to
a kind of longer outcome so a bunch of
exercises that go towards a an overall
story
and I try and explain the meta process
in the class as we're going through like
what is the the the exercise that we're
doing why are we doing it what's the
outcome that I'm trying to achieve
and then we've actually done the
exercise you've experienced that how
could you leverage that as a tool to use
with your students as well or not your
students of your scrum master your your
teams your organization the people that
you're going to be working with
so learning those facilitation
techniques learning to leverage
liberating structures is for me a huge
part of that class it's not the only
part right because there's also the
story of the class
um but then there's the techniques that
we use to get there so so for me that
classes are almost entirely about
um the skill and capability of you as a
scrum Master both from the perspective
of
how do I become a better scrum master
and understand the scrum Master
accountability more but also that meta
process of what are the tools and
techniques that I can use to do those
things with teams
and included in the class is a whole
bunch of effectively take away exercises
um that we have we have uh posters we
have
um cards we have exercise content that
we provide you at the end of the class
that you can then go do some of those
exercises with your teams
and in fact I can imagine
um as we move towards
um a more immersive learning model
that what we'll do with some of those
exercises is you know will teach you how
to run the exercise and then we'll send
you off as a scrum Master to go run that
exercise next week with your team and
then you come back the week after and
tell us how you get up got on what were
the difficulties you hit how could you
have run it better what did you learn
share that with everybody and then we'll
talk about the next bit teach the next
exercise and then you go off and to use
it with your with your team and that
would be the immersive version of the
psm2 which I think would be fantastic
um
yeah
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility