the question is why why might recessions
be a great time to re-evaluate our
opportunities with with agile and I
think it's deeper than that forget the
agile story right I think
um
the the time when you should be
investing the most
in marketing from a sales perspective
right when you should be investing the
most in your people from getting the
most out of the out of the people that
you have is is when the world's a
troubled place around your your
organization when you're when you're
when you're struggling and life is
difficult that's when you should invest
more time in the people and the
um and and and getting people to
understand the markets and add more
value to your customers right
so so that
really brings you back around to that
agile conversation right we talk about
agile but what is agile really it's
about responding to the market more
quickly
more quickly that's not English
responding to the market quicker
right
um so we want to respond to the market
quicker and in order to respond to the
market quicker we need people
with the skills and capability to be
able to respond to the market more
quickly
I did it again with uh um with the the
the
accountability and
to be able to do that right that they
they are able they feel like they are
empowered and to be able to go and go
and make the changes necessary because
that was that was the thing from from
from years and years ago
um when a lot of the organizational
practices were created it it was
designed to slow the change in the
organization because the markets were
slow right you wanted to be able to take
advantage of your market for as as long
a period as possible because it's going
to exist for a long time so you didn't
want to change the company let's create
some burratic bureaucratic processes to
enshrine the way we do things uh push
responsibility up the organization
rather than down and the people at the
top made the decision so the people at
the bottom who are closest to the market
have to have to realize it has to be
painful enough because they don't
actually care about your business right
it has to be painful enough that
something's wrong in order for them to
tell their boss that that something's
wrong and then painful enough to go all
the way up the chain to the top and then
eventually a decision is made to do
something different and comes all the
way back down own um but the time that
response comes back down the market
hasn't shifted in the old way but today
the market that opportunity's gone right
we we don't have that opportunity to
take it or we've lost a bunch of money
in the delay it takes to make that
decision so so I think
um
so I can't think of a better time
to invest
in the ability
capability of your organization
to deliver value
to your customers the more value you
deliver to your customers the more
favorable your customers will look
because they're getting a higher return
on investment therefore if there is a
choice in our highly competitive markets
then they're going to pick you over the
competitors
that's that's how you survive a
recession and they don't because you're
able to more quickly adapt to the market
demand
and provide your customers with more
value
so the purpose of agility
right is to help companies better
respond to changing demand in the market
give customers more of what they want
and less of what they don't
so yeah that's perfect time to do that