one of the signs of the agile apocalypse
is
silence quite often this
manifests uh in your Sprint reviews when
you're trying to get engagement from
stakeholders perhaps you can't even get
your stakeholders to turn up when they
do turn up you ask them for any feedback
in a tumble weed floats past and that's
all the feedback you get perhaps when
you ask for feedback you already know
before you ask that question that which
person uh the the usually the the
loudest um and most outgoing person you
know they're the one that's going to
answer that question and nobody else's
feedback is going to be offered because
they don't want to because they would
be I don't know sometimes there's
there's there's a a little there's fear
if you're in a room with a lot of other
people that your feedback is going to be
invalid um there's fear that somebody
else in the room might have a different
idea than your idea and they might be
more senior and you don't want to step
on their toes by offering feedback that
perhaps goes in the wrong direction so
it's very difficult to get that feedback
break the silence and get people to
actually talk about your products talk
about the direction of your products
talk about more than just the features
that you've built even what are the
things that the stakeholders that you
have in the room understand about the
the the the business and the business
choices that have happened since your
last Sprint review what does the
stakeholders understand that we maybe
don't understand about the market
opportunities that are presenting
themselves that since the last time we
had a Sprint review or that have been
manifesting over a period of time and
and suddenly they're they become
important this is all part of that North
Star that direction as well as trying to
break that cone of silence so we have
good communication quite often another
way that silence manifests is all of the
stakeholders that do turn up
know they know that they can go have a
private chat with the product owner
later and get their agenda heard and
they can beat that product owner into
doing things differently than they know
other people in the room want to do
things or other people in the room know
that some other direction is more
important to the business so they want
to go browbeat that product owner
privately so that they can get their
agenda rather than the whole
organizational agenda cuz that makes
them look good not the other people in
the organization we don't care about
them right so how how do you do how do
you create break that silence and get
that engagement from people you need to
stop uh uh building the wrong thing
right if you're building the wrong thing
stakeholders ain't going to turn up I
was working with a team in Norway and
the product owner didn't even turn up
for the Sprint reviews how do you think
the team felt about the work that they
were doing and the value that it
provided to the business so what did
they pick at their Sprint planning
whatever they felt like and they thought
was cool to work on because nobody
cares so we may as well come up and care
about the cool things we're working on
right rather than working on the right
things working on the things that they
thought was cool that's not who should
be making those decisions those
decisions should be informed decisions
they're still making the decision about
what it is they work on but H what
bounds what context are they making that
decision making it based on what's cool
for them to work on or what's right for
the business and supporting the
customers and the overall strategic
direction of the product so that Silence
has created that
that lack of Engagement lack of care in
the product and if you do get people
stakeholders to turn up build something
they care about that's how you get them
in there ask them to come to offer
advice stop having those side
conversations right product you're going
to have side conversations but you
product owners know the conversations
that I'm talking about those site
conversations where you know you're
going to get brow beaten where
somebody's just going to be spouting
their agenda not the organizational
agenda instead of having those meetings
in private bring those discussions bring
those topics into the Sprint review
where you've got more voices to be heard
that the gastal can look critically on
that idea of let's serve this one part
of the business at detriment of the rest
and they can say no that's not a good
idea because it's going to have this
impact and have that
work for you rather than against you so
build up those ideas have those
conversations during the Sprint review
break big groups down into small groups
I was recently at a Sprint review and 60
people turned up right there's 60 people
at the Sprint review uh Lots it was
quite a big team right Lots of teams
working on the same product so a lot of
them were team members but when they
asked for feedback there was maybe two
people that spoke the 60 people in the
room why would you bother having 60
people in the room if you didn't want to
hear from 60 people in the room that you
didn't want a collaborative experience
with 60 people in the room so do
breakout rooms use liberating structures
send people out to do small parts of
that story perhaps take some stuff off
the product backlog that you think might
not be right and give little assignments
out to smaller groups to go figure out
what we could do better and what we
could do next and then bring it back
and bring make it into a more cohesive
story it's all sorts of things you can
do to break that cone of silence around
value around Direction around what we're
actually doing um discuss budgets and
release schedules every every body on
the team everybody working on the
product everybody working with the
product should understand those things
because they will impact on the
decisions that we make we want people to
make the best decisions possible not be
making decisions within that cone of
silence we're not going to talk about
anything so make sure that you don't
have silence on your teams that you
engage with people product owners this
is your
accountability thanks for watching the
video If you enjoyed it please like
follow And subscribe I always reply to
comments and if you want to have a chat
about this or anything else agile scrum
or devops then please book a coffee with
me through naked
agility