if a client
so if you're doing agile why should you
incorporate devops
I think
the core answer is that
um you can't really if you're building
software products I'll caveat that if
you're building software products you
can't do one and not the other
um devops is really synonymous with this
idea of engineering excellence
right um of shortening the feedback loop
making high quality code shifting left
and those things are part of that that
devops story
and they need to go up in kind of logger
step with your agile practices and if
you're doing something else let's say
you're doing marketing right uh you're
delivering marketing out output then
your agile practices will increase but
you need to increase your capability of
your teams to deliver marketing content
right that's that's that would be that
technical site in the software world
it's devops right
um and building up that expertise if if
you're amazing amazing it
delivering products to production really
quickly
um of delivering high quality products
to production really quickly but you
haven't figured out how to
um adapt your organization so that you
respond more quickly to the market
then you're still not going to get the
value from the devops right push it in
[ __ ] out
um so trying to figure out how you
maintain keep increasing your levels of
of technical capability of uh
engineering Excellence right on one side
at the same Pace as you're increasing
your ability for your organization to
respond to the market right whatever
Market you're in
um is really important you have to
balance that out
um I mean one can get further ahead than
the other but you really do need them to
go in in Step so once you start bringing
in uh those those engineering Excellence
or devops practices you're able to
um
allow your engineers to really focus on
how how do they shorten uh those those
feedback loops not just the business
feedback loops but the actual
engineering feedback loops and build
products that they can get into
production as quickly as possible so you
can validate all of the assumptions that
you made when you were designing it
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility