if you want to
build teams and an
organization that can deliver the
highest possible value for the
investment that you're taking maximize
that return on investment for your
business then naked agility can help
you in
advising and coaching at any level in
your organization be it team members who
are actually doing doing the work in the
engineering practices that they're doing
all the way up through to you as a CTO
or CEO trying to understand hypothesis
driven practices trying to understand
which features should we bring in which
features should we not how do we budget
across our engineering practices
organization so that we maximize a
return investment and
maximize the care within which the
people doing the work take of their time
and the spend that they are making which
is hugely important understanding that
context enabling the highest quality of
work right we want if we're building
software
products regardless of whether we're
that's our main business or whether it's
a side hustle for our business right is
an enable
for our
business we want to build products of
the highest possible quality every
product that we build every line of code
that is written by the people in our
teams is an organizational asset right
these are things that provide it's like
buying a building it's infrastructure
right it's stuff that you've built that
you've invested in that you get return
investment on that you get a continuous
return on are they of the highest
quality if you bought a bill
as a as as as as a leadership in an
organization you're going to do a lot of
due diligence and the due diligence for
that is well known when it's software
there's a lot of opacity there's the
stuff the magic Wizards do that build
the software and we don't often
understand all of the ramifications of
that so we need to have some technical
expertise on hand whether it be in-
house or bringing somebody in
that helps us understand some of those
relationships and some of those the
things that connect to each other in
order to maximize the value that our
business is able to bring to Market