so the question was what are immersive
training courses
and I think that's a that's a great
question because there's been a lot of
Buzz around immersive training classes
what's the difference between
um
the different types of classes and I
think the the traditional class format
has always been the two full days
right and part of that is because if
you're a part of that is because if
you're going to get a whole bunch of
people together for a training class
um you want to in a small amount of time
as possible so that you're not paying
for hotels you're not paying for
um people traveling around however it is
you're getting those people into that
place plus if they're going to be out of
the office
for those days and they've got to travel
to the trading location you only want
them doing it twice you don't want them
doing it
four four half days right
um but with the virtual space I I moved
all of my classes to four half days
which was kind of a start of this
process and the advantage to four half
days initially was twofold one is you
can have uh people are only out half
days right so they could still get work
done in the afternoons or the mornings
however you're running it and but also I
tried uh introducing activities so more
of the flipped learning experience uh
first step towards
um the the immersive experience and in
the flipped learning of experience
people get small assignments to do
uh where they're they're Reading Writing
watching uh content so that kind of
interactive much more interactive
experience self-paced learning as well
as the The imperson Experience
um but the way
that's also not as good for the way
people learn
right
um it's better than to fill this
um flipped learning is better
but what's even better is if you as a
participant to a class are able to spend
some time learning something and then
able to go try and implement it
in your real world
and then come back around and share that
experience with other people who have
tried the same thing in their companies
or in the same company right
um and then learn some more stuff
and then go try that new stuff in your
organization in your company
so the immersive learning experience
instead of being at four half days so 16
hours what I've been doing is is four
half days with probably about two hours
of additional possible material
right uh each day
um is moving it to eight half days over
eight weeks so you do one session a week
and at the end of that session
um the the participants are given an
assignment to do in their organization
so we're starting with the product owner
class so they're maybe given an
assignment to try and
um and do something a little bit
differently figure out maybe try and
figure out what is value to your
organization right
um and that might be that might be the
first one that might even be one of the
assignments right so go to figure out
that in your company so then when we
come back we probably spend the first
part of the next session talking about
what did they discover what did they
discover the the their organization
values how
um does that change the way they think
about the product and what it is they're
creating did they find that that maybe
their company doesn't understand what
value is and they had to come up with
something brand new to figure out what
value is and then how do you test that
within your organization so all those
kind of questions and discussions
and I think the the there's there's two
huge that different but both equally
great value propositions between a
private class and a public class right
because in a private class everybody in
the room is from the same company
so they can share the same dirty laundry
right and perhaps
um have have have conversations about oh
but I tried this with these people I'm
working with and that worked great and
then they can maybe a little bit more
sharing right so that's that's a good
value proposition
but I think the public value proposition
is also good as well right you've got
12 people in the class each of the 12
people have gone off into their own
company and tried their own thing and
then they're bringing back these very
different experiences because it's
different companies
um and then sharing them with each other
and what could we do differently and oh
yeah I've got somebody in my company
who's just like that person and yours
perhaps we could work together to figure
out how we how we do that
so that that
is like the progression of the flipped
learning that you don't just have some
um activities that are offline learning
like self-paced online stuff I'm gonna
read some stuff I'm gonna watch some
videos but I'm actually I've actually
got a production assignment I'm going to
go into my organization
try to do something in a particular way
that's to do with the things that we've
been talking about in the class and then
come back and pull it all together with
the other people in my class who have
been learning the same thing
that would be the immersive learning
experience
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility