so one of the key reasons to do uh PSM
to scrum Master advanced class is to
gain a deeper understanding of the three
different Focus areas of the scrum
master and even realize that there are
three is is a great one as well uh the
focus on the team right how do you help
the team be more effective right after
getting rid of all the crap that you
think of scrum master has to do how do
you actually help them how do you help
the product owner be more effective at
your product management
and also how do you help the
organization right what are the scrum
Masters UH responsibilities to the
organization and helping them adopt
these practices and be more effective