one main thing that should be top of
mind is what do my stakeholders care
about
right so so one of the big values of a
Sprint review is engaging your
stakeholders getting information that
you as a scrum team so that's the
product owner the developers and the
scrum master that we as a scrum team
don't have
how do we get that out of uh the
stakeholders and in order for those
stakeholders to engage they have to care
so you you your your
engagement with them during Sprint
planning has a lot of marketing in it
you're you're what have we done for you
the stakeholder in the last uh two weeks
or or four weeks right what have we done
for you here's the cool stuff we've done
for you
no here's the API changes that we've
made or the database triggers we've
updated because the stakeholders just
gonna basically fall asleep and probably
not gonna want to come next time
so that that focusing quite heavily that
one big thing is the engagement between
what the team is creating and producing
and the stakeholders and how do we
maximize that collaborative experience
um and and perhaps even maximize the
number of people that turn up I find
that in a lot of Sprint plannings uh at
teams struggle to get the stakeholders
to actually turn up let alone engage
once they're there right but struggle to
get them to turn up and it's because
they don't care so are we building the
right features right are we
communicating them in a way that those
stakeholders need them to be
communicated in order for them to
understand what it is we're doing and
engage with what it is we're doing
because if you don't have that
engagement the purpose the purpose of
the Sprint review is to make sure that
when we walk out of the Sprint review we
have the the the most transparent and
up-to-date product backlog so when we
start the next Sprint we have the most
transparent and up-to-date information
to get started with and you're not going
to get that if you don't engage with
your stakeholders
um so getting that engagement is
absolutely key
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility