Building
Products
is always doing something that's never
been done before any anytime you've got
a team writing code they're doing
something that's never done been done
before if they weren't doing something
that's never been done before you
wouldn't be writing code you would be
buying the product right you would be
buying the framework you'd be buying the
thing so anytime we're we're building
products we're doing unknown things
right that's why we have such a high
degree of variance in software
engineering and in the business space
there is something that kind of ah does
it kind of equates to that or an analogy
within the business context purely
within the business context and that's
entrepreneurialship right if you've got
an idea for a for a for a company that
delivers some kind of value regardless
of how that value is
achieved then you need to go and find
somebody to invest in that idea and that
works almost the same within the context
of a of of an organization than it does
in the context
of me if I wanted to go start a new
business I would need probably need to
go speak to the bank I might need to go
find some Venture capitalists I need to
convince them I to find people in my
company I need to convince them that
it's a good idea that needs to be
promoted up to a level of somebody with
some some some some spending power and
that person with some spending power
offers me the ability to to go try this
out and I but I have to convince them
right but new ideas things that have
never been done before are are not
guaranteed they're not guaranteed to
work they're not guaranteed to have the
return on investment that you expect
them to to and if you're in business you
already
understand this concept right I believe
I
believe my numbers might be slightly off
but I believe that 70% of new businesses
fail within the first year and 30% of
the leftovers fail within five years I
think I might I might be underestimating
the second part the fiveyear part it
might be more than that so the risk
there is a risk profile to everything
you do when you're investing money
in a possible outcome within your
business or external to your business so
you need to figure out what your risk
profile is for investment in things that
have never been done before and you need
to gauge the return that you're
expecting to get on the investment that
you're putting in and this is exactly
how products should be funded as well
and if we're going to fund a product in
that way and I'm going to be the one
funding that
product I want to see value and Market
fits as quickly as possible right so
what we tend to do is run lots of very
small
experiments so I might come to you and
say I need some money sorry I'm
switching personality here I'm going to
come to you say I I need I need some
money I want to try out this idea hi
I've got this idea for a a database of
movie stars right and you're like how
are you going to make me some money
because you you want to return on your
investment so I'm thinking well I I
really I'm the geek right I want to have
uh a database of all the movies with all
of the actors and then then you can ask
well can we have the budget for the
movie in there can we have how much each
of the actors made can we have and
suddenly you've good an idea of who you
could sell this product to right what
its possibilities are going forward into
the future with a little bit of ideation
from that geek idea of of having a movie
database and IMDb is born right which is
which is massive now if if you don't
know IMDb has two halves it has the
public free half uh which is where we
just go look up movies uh but then it
sells inside of the industry um and can
give directors for example who are
looking for a a a leading man or a
leading lady um it can give them data on
who can make my movie the most money oh
it's the rock well well I can't afford
the rock who's within my price range for
the budget for my movie that I can get
that's going to maximize the amount of
money and they pay LinkedIn a sorry they
pay IMDb a lot of money for for for that
story that that's not something that was
within anybody's anybody's budget it was
a venture capitalist effort right so you
want to be thinking within the context
of your business you want to be thinking
more like entrepreneurs thinking more
like Venture capitalists what's your
return on investment if you put money
into this product or
project what do you get how much do you
get what's the longevity of what you get
what's what's the story for this I want
to see a business plan I want to see a a
lean even a lean canvas right on on what
does this look like have people thought
about the the different aspects of it
before I'm going to let them spend some
money and even once they're spending
money I I want to I want to see a little
thing I want to see a proof proof of
concept right let's get something out
there see what it looks like get it in
front of some other people let's let's
does it does it resonate with people
does it seem like it's going to provide
value okay what's the next stage what's
the next bigger thing we can do what's
the next experiment that we can run I
talk about it as hypothesis driven
engineering practices lots of folks out
there use the phrase
MVP they're mostly I see MVP minimum
viable product being kind of misused
minimum viable product is a proof of
concept that you throw away at the end
before you build the real
product I know lots of people use it as
a small experiment so whatever context
you use it within but we want to be
running lots and lots and lot of small
experiments we know lots of experiments
are going to fail but we're going to
find the ones that work and then we're
going to invest more in those invest
Less in the ones that don't work and
that's how you stay within budget lots
of little little experiments that have a
hypothesis right what are you what are
you going to
do what do you expect the world to be
like afterwards how are you going to
measure whether you've been successful
and we want to see the numbers and we're
we're going to Cull anything that is not
living up to its expectation unless we
can be convinced otherwise right there's
there's heart as well as as data and and
build your products and stay within
budget