of the agile apocalypse is chaos chaos
oh my chaos is everywhere in teams um it
manifests as not having a plan of not
knowing which way we're going not having
goals and what would you expect when
everybody doesn't have the same goal
this they're not working together
towards a common goal you end up with
chaos everybody's pulling in different
directions and this applies not just at
the team level but all the way up your
organization why would you think
everybody would be going in the same
direction if they don't all understand
the goals of the organization the goals
of the product and how the work that
they do every day contributes to those
goals thanks for watching the video If
you enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or dead Ops
then please book a coffee with me
through naked
agility