so the applying metrics for
predictability course from Pro caman is
really focused on a deep dive into how
you can use the the the the metrics um
coming from your camand strategy to
really focus on improving the
predictability of of your teams right
the predictability of our ability to
deliver um so we need to understand uh
uh what the impact of the changes like
how we want to change the metrics in
order to improve predictability how do
we identify uh uh in the graphs what
things might be the issue like how um
how do
we uh uh interpret interpret the graphs
in order to maximize uh uh that that
changes to predictability um and how do
we make uh forecasts right make accurate
forecasts for for single items for
multiple items looking forward into the
future to understand what we're going to
do do next um and really lots of teams
struggle with the two questions when
will it be done and how much will I how
much work will I get um these are really
important questions that the business
has that most teams are unable to answer
and these metrics for predictability
really bring that answer to the to the
Forefront how do you in how do you what
data do you collect how do you interpret
the graphs how do you analyze that data
in order to make good choices around
increasing predictability um and how do
you improve the FL upflow of value into
production um how do you increase the
flow of value to the business which is
what we're all here for if you want to
have a discussion about your unique
needs or situation then please book a
call or visit us at naked agility tocom
uh we also have our immersive and
traditional public classes on our
website and we'd love to hear from you