an APS class is appropriate for um a
scrum team if they are in fact a scrum
team right that's that's in my book if
you're a scrum team uh then the aps
class is a great way to both get started
get H scraped those Barnacles off right
off your ship but also um I think
there's a difference between the
traditional APS class um all the way
through to the immersive APS class so if
you think about the the traditional APS
class is usually two full days or four
consecutive half days that's usually the
traditional traditional format um and
that's really appropriate when man we
just we we as we just don't have time as
an organization to really invest in our
our our our change and we need we just
need a like like quick punch right a
quick one two let's get started let's
get going let's solve a couple of those
couple of those problems you're probably
not going to solve a lot of the problems
right you you'll from the class the
people that are attending will pick
particular things that they're like
that's the thing I really just really
annoys me and and they'll help you fix
that and it'll probably be only a couple
of things but that's still valuable
right super valuable in in organizations
that are getting started the immersive
class is more the Lo the longer term the
longer term investment in in change for
for your team and your organization um
it enables you to have continuous a
continuously adaptive learning process
so that you can close those feedback
loops um have that double Loop learning
right so that you can you can get
feedback on the things that you tried um
and if you're doing it as an APS your
whole team can get feedback rather than
it being an individual assignment uh
which a lot of the other immersive
classes have if you're doing it as a
private class inside of your
organization it's more like it's a team
assignment what is your team going to
try this week to help them be more
effective what are they going to try
next week to be more effective all come
back together let's have a retrospective
right a debrief
on we tried this did it work out could
we have done better is there stuff we
want to keep stuff we want to stop doing
right and you can then continuously over
10 weeks improve the capability of your
team Identify some of the impediments in
your organization as you go through and
perhaps you can fix them during the
class getting feedback uh from the
trainer um the trainer providing some
you know Consulting for your
organization to help them uh deal with
some of those issues um that that's
really the aps class is appropriate for
any team um if you want a hard one
two let's get some stuff sorted get some
crap out of my team's way uh the
probably the two-day APS class in a
private company is is the one to go to
but if you really want uh uh to solve as
many problems as you possibly can within
your organization have as much learning
as you possibly can within your
organization and close as many of those
feedback loops right have it in as
empirical a process as you can um then I
would definitely definitely suggest the
immersive
APS thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked
agility