organizations and people are too scared
to address the real problem which is the
way the system works right so they're
they focus on the little bits and pieces
around the edge oh let's push
responsibility down the organization for
some things but not other things let's
uh what else do they do let's let's
let's have people run these ceremonies
right uh we're going to we're going to
do a daily we're going to have a daily
that'll fix everything right but these
are the the
mechanisms not the thing that you're
trying to achieve you're you're
measuring the wrong thing if you think
that having those things is going to
result in a different way of doing
things you should be measuring return on
investment you should be measuring uh um
uh uh a profit profit per per per team
member right uh you should be looking at
your your your your feedback Lopes and
your cost to deliver and your meantime
to repair and things your time to learn
right closing those feedback loops you
should be measuring um what you don't
know right what what does your product
not do that it could do that is a market
opportunity and where do you go looking
for that information how do you as a
business find that this stuff is hard
and 70% of all startups right 70% of all
ideas that people have are going to fail
easy 70% of ideas are going to fail in
fact 70% of startups I bet it's a much
higher percentage of ideas because not L
all ideas manage to convince somebody to
give them the money to start the idea in
the first place right ideas are the most
nebulous one and if you're building
products and you're trying to capture
Market you have to be focused on what
helps us as a business be as effective
as we can be within the context of those
markets and that that doesn't come uh um
from Not Having the
courage to admit that you need to change
more things so the the common one that I
see in organizations is that an agile
coach uh uh comes in I've been I've been
this this I wasn't an agile coach at the
time uh but my my biggest regret this is
my biggest regret in in Consulting it's
from years ago I was still wet behind
the ears I wasn't uh a very
sophisticated uh consultant at the time
um this was probably nearly 10 years
ago and a CEO pulled me aside and
basically said look we've just gone
through a major
reorganization um and they'd reorganized
into silos by the way just different
sort of silos and he
said
um all the things that you're talking
about I was talking about devops seem to
be
different from the way we've organized
ourselves do we need to throw all of
that out because it was very expensive
right to do that reorg reorgs are
expensive or else don't do reor it's
expensive um and do we need to change
the way we do things
completely and I
said
no you can change slowly and iteratively
towards the thing you want to
achieve and that was a bad
answer the right answer would have been
yeah rip that Band-Aid
off disinfect the wound that you just
created by changing your organization to
even more silos right in the wrong
direction and
move faster and with less constant pain
and suffering and hemorrhaging of money
to a resolution to a different system
that enabled you to be more successful
and that is the difficulty the difficult
call that lots of organizations have is
that the
fundamentally the reason you can't take
advantage of agile the reason agile is
so difficult the reason you've got agile
atrophy in your organization that people
are just like I can't be B what that
don't don't mention agile to me anymore
that kind of attitude is because you've
not addressed the changes that need to
happen in the way you do
business in order for agile to be
successful it isn't just magically
successful you need to fundamentally
change the way you do business at every
level in your
organization in order to move towards
what people are calling agility right
this agile movement big a agile or
little a agile but really it's about
your organization systematically and
continuously improving its Effectiveness
in sometimes small jumps but sometimes
you need big jumps to improve that
Effectiveness and do you have the
courage to make that change if you want
to have a discussion about your unique
needs or situation then please book a
call or visit us at naked agility tocom
uh we also have our immersive and
traditional public classes on our
website and we'd love to hear from you