my favorite agile course to deliver is
the applying
professional scrum class and it's my
favorite class to deliver because I
think it generates some of the greatest
epiphanies for for for students
so in that class we actually practice
scrum and that that's different from all
the other classes as well
so we do four sprints
um I've been adopting Minecraft
in in these sprints
uh so the the we break everybody up into
teams uh we do a Sprint straight off the
bat
and the reason we do the first thing we
do is a Sprint is that people use the
techniques they're used to in organizing
when they do the first print
so there's this huge realization at the
end of the first Sprint about how
chaotic it was and how difficult the
process was there are people in the
classroom that have never used
played a game before let alone Minecraft
and that simulates that Real World
experience of when you get onto a brand
new product or a brand new project and
you've you've got no idea what's next
you get no idea what you need to do
you've got no idea who you need to speak
to you've got no idea who the customer
is I'm trying to figure that out and
that that for Sprint demonstrates
the chaotic is not the right word it
just it generates I don't know the
cluster [ __ ] of uh at that first moment
when you start working on a product or
project and
in the real world that can last for an
incredibly long time
right because there's there's who comes
in and tells everybody how they're
supposed to do stuff at some point maybe
a project manager gets hired or a
project manager is there and they manage
to get around everybody but it's
generally chaos so then we go into
teaching them scrum
and we have a a kind of I guess it's two
two half days we're gonna teach them
scrum but the first part of the first
half day is the Sprint and the second
part of the second half day is another
Sprint so we teach some scrum in between
and then they go into that second Sprint
with that knowledge of here's how are we
we're going to organize all the stuff we
do in order to try and Control the Chaos
and figure out what it is we're going to
do do going forward and and they do
planning they have a conversation they
agree what they're going to do then you
know that doesn't always happen but they
have that agreement they have those
check-ins they have that reflection at
the end and they themselves what that's
the second Epiphany moment for the
students is they realize
what it is that that they're there for
right they realize what scrum is trying
to achieve they realize the benefit they
could get from it in the real world