the question is why is the professional
agile leadership Essentials class a kind
of core Evolution
um for a scrum master and and I think
again there's two there's two great
reasons the first one is that
um it enables
a scrum Master to hear
the questions that leaders have that
leaders and managers have about scrum
about the contacts that we're talking
about right
um they get to hear some of the other
ways that it's important to them or that
we can solve problems for them
um but also it enables
I I I think of the scrum Master as being
the first rung on the leadership track
right the the this idea that
um I call them kind of gold shirts right
like the Star Trek idea you you get
people that are on the leadership track
and you get people that aren't really
interested in the leadership track
there's loads of people out there who
are quite happy being software Engineers
right they're quite happy uh uh um you
know being being Scotty running these
engineering department they don't want
to be in charge of the ship at all
so
um we need to be able to cater for both
of those groups and the scrum Master is
a natural uh uh uh position of of
leadership they're a leader who serves
the team
and then the next level up is the leader
who serves a bunch of teams and the next
level up is the leader who serves a part
of the organization or the leader who
sells or serves the actual organization
right
um so that gives you that kind of
um leadership track of the organization
and for the scrum Master learning the
language the Lexicon the problems
um the the leaders see it those levels
will help them better serve people at
those different levels in the
organization
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility