dipping without telemetry is flying
blind If you ship and you can't see
what's happening you don't know if it's
working you don't know if it's broken
and you don't even know if anybody's
using it No logs no metrics no real
feedback At Naked Agility we help teams
make telemetry part of Dun not an
afterthought not a nice to have a core
requirement
Every increment you ship should gather
real data usage performance behavior so
you can validate outcomes spot problems
fast and make better decisions Because
until you're gathering telemetry you're
not learning And if you're not learning
you're not delivering real value Ready
to stop flying blind after you ship
let's make telemetry part of your
definition of