one of the the key issues I see in
organizations is the great difficulty
that product owners especially new
product owners find in getting your
stakeholders to turn up for your Sprint
reviews right and often times it's hard
even if they do turn up to get them to
provide you with feedback right you ask
them for feedback and all you can hear
is tumble weeds rolling through the
desert right you're trying to engage
them and they're just not getting there
and that's to me a marketing issue they
don't understand the value of what
you're showing them they're not
emotionally engaged in what you're
showing them if they were emotionally
engaged they'd be desperate to sneak
into that c that discussion and provide
that feedback provide you with more
information and that is part of
marketing