one of the seven uh deadly sins of agile
is gluttony and I see this a lot um in
teams where they're they're they're
backlogs and their products become
bloated um bloated and full of basically
just full of crap that needs to go right
so one one uh common um entry is is is
the product backlog if you if you go
into a team you're working with a team
and you go to look at their product
backlog and there's let's say there's
six or seven people working on this team
and they have 5,000 things in their
product backlog they're doing it wrong
right there that's that's greedy they'
they've eaten all those backlog items
they're sitting in their belly and they
can't walk around they can't move
they're not going to be nimble right
they're not going to be agile because
it's it's almost impossible to
understand like what is our value what
value is in our product backlog diving
into that thing is just just not a good
idea right you you've get too much stuff
in your product backlog another another
way gluttony manifests is during Sprint
planning right shoving more stuff into
the Sprint backlog uh than the team can
possibly deliver in a single Sprint and
that continually results in the team
having to vomit uh uh backlog items into
the next Sprint right if you think of it
that way perhaps teams will stop doing
it um taking on too much and then it
spews into the next Sprint and if it's
if it's one or two things that move into
the next Sprint and maybe not every
Sprint is probably okay right you're not
going to be successful in everything you
do but if you're constantly
got tons of things from a Sprint flowing
into the next Sprint flowing into the
next Sprint perhaps there's need to
consider um are we taking on too much
work um are we doing too much are we
taking on too much work um so that's
that's the second second form of of gney
uh that I see in teams and the third
form is uh leaving stuff that nobody
uses in your
product right uh this Standish group uh
in Boston used to create the chaos
report every year and they analyzed
about 70,000 projects worldwide and they
found that only only 35% of the features
uh that we build are used by our
customers 65% I think the phrase was use
little if ever 65% use little if ever so
so hopefully we can stop building them
in the first place right that would be
great let's stop building them in the
first place but if we we have built
them why are you keeping them in your
product why are you continuing to spend
maintenance hours support right how long
does your build take um how long would
your build take if you removed 65% of
the code that's in your product right
because you've got rid of those features
your build would be faster your teams
would be able to work faster there's a
less complicated uh body of content
you'll just get better and faster at
doing doing doing things
so the way to to to ah man loads of
teams just need a gastric bypass for
that right um how how do you how do you
restrict the the the amount of um stuff
that's in a in a product that's really
hard because it's it's that's that's
much harder than backlog or Sprint
backlog right um is to figure out what
percentage of the features of your
product are actually used and the the
worst is continuing to invest in
features that are of no use right
features that aren't used by your
customer because I guarantee you loads
of teams do that uh years years ago um I
worked with a A Bank in
Boston and um they were absolutely
adamant that this 65% was crap and that
they knew their customers way way better
than anybody else um and there's no way
they were they were wasting 65% it was a
lot less that's what they said so we we
we we said to them what's what's your
Flagship product that you build what's
the product that you think you know your
customers best and are building all the
awesome features like this one this
one's the best so we got in amongst the
code we added application insights app
insights is a an Azure uh uh feature
that can be plugged into any application
anywhere which basically collects data
so it's support course all the
programming languages all the setups and
you can out of the box it does a bunch
of stuff but then if you add this is a
feature right and you can say if some
how many times do users click that
button of our body of users how many of
them have clicked that button you can
get all of that data and we analyzed
their their their their product uh end
to end so we collected data for 3 months
um and then we went back to them and
said here's the 7 and a half% of
features that your customers use all the
rest was waste right um over 90% of the
money they invested in their product was
waste and what was really interesting
was that more than 80% of the items in
their backlog at the moment were going
towards additional capabilities for
features that weren't used by their
customers right so
no don't don't don't eat the whole thing
right you've got to figure out how do I
pick and choose what I'm going to eat
don't eat the whole feature at once
right you don't know if you like haggus
yet so don't order a whole plate full um
get like a like a starter that's got a
little bit of haggus and try that first
and then obviously when you realize you
do like it um and your customers like it
then you can make more right but don't
don't over uh uh OV eat um on your
product backlog don't e over eat in your
Sprint backlog and don't overeat in the
features in your product thanks for
watching the video If you enjoyed it
please like follow And subscribe I
always reply to comments and if you want
to have a chat about this or anything
else agile scrum or devops then please
book a coffee with me through naked
agility