building a high performance delivery
engine in your organization is super
hard we we need to
have expertise within our teams within
various contexts and I
think we mostly underestimate the level
of competence that's required for the
people participating within the the the
software delivery process to to build
those those those High performing teams
High performing delivery engine to get
get stuff out the
door we need not only competence in the
technical tasks that's that's usually
what most organizations focus on we also
need competence within the context of
business right business and business
need and how business works and what
business
wants every member of the team should be
a a a a product developer well every
member you're you're going to have some
extremely um unusual technical people
who probably just want to focus on the
technical side but you want to have at
least a high enough number of product
developers rather than just software
developers on your team and what I mean
by that is that they're focused on
product and delivering a successful
product which includes many different
things right you don't just magic ically
deliver a successful product you need to
focus on the the the do we have the
right Technologies do we have the right
technical skills to be able to deliver
this product do we understand the
business need do we do we have the right
hypothesis to be able to test our
product within the market have we got
the right Market fit do we need to
change the way we do things this is
every member of of of the team are as
much as possible thinking about these
things as they're building the product
as they're developing features
and then you also need a keen a keen
understanding of the
the
philosophies and theories Behind these
things that we're talk we're talking
about agile we're talking about devops
we're talking about lean talking about
scrum right and mixing a few things in
there but we need to understand the core
philosophies theories and practices that
underpin these things
so that we can apply them in a way that
adds value to our organization right
because we're we're trying to deliver
we're trying to create a high performing
delivery engine we're trying to deliver
lots of stuff and lots of the right
stuff or as much of the right stuff as
we can and for that we need to be able
to leverage the right emergent practices
right the the evolution of our practices
over the life of the the product side
cycle and how we we pick the best stuff
and to do that the people doing the work
the people managing the work the people
overseeing the work all need to be
practitioners right they need to be
playing at the practitioner level to
understand how those things influence it
I I usually the the analogy I usually
use is if you're you're renovating your
house and you want to remove a wall
right so we we we we want to change the
way we fundamentally do something and
see whether it makes sense can we just
knock down that wall well no we should
probably do a little bit of due
diligence we should probably understand
the structural Integrity of the context
we should probably understand whether is
this a good idea to remove the wall or
is it a bad idea and if it's a bad idea
is there something we can do to mitigate
it so we can do it because we want to do
it right and and and you can abs
absolutely remove any wall in your house
any wall in your house with due
diligence to the structural Integrity of
the building same is true when you're
changing your business when you're
changing your your team structure when
you're changing your system of doing
work you need to have the competence in
your high performing delivery engine to
build it in a way that enables you to
maximize the value delivery to your
stakeholder