the question is how does the the a scrum
team plan and prioritize work
effectively let's leave aside for a
moment that the word prioritizes
singular rather than uh plural because
that always always triggers me a little
bit but
um the the how do they plan and
prioritize and that's actually
it's actually quite difficult because it
it depends on the business it depends on
the organizer like what is the business
trying to achieve
the the the work flows from the business
so you need to understand what the what
the business is trying to achieve what
are their goals where are they going and
then align the work
towards those goals and outcomes and
how they might actually do it they
they might
um
they might do sizing right I'm trying to
avoid the e word right the estimation
word
um they they they might do they might do
they might do some form of sizing right
we want to figure out how big some of
these things are because that's going to
impact on the ROI of the item
um they need to understand well how
valuable is this item which is a bigger
problem because now the business needs
to understand what value is Right which
is a whole whole bigger problem for the
product owner and once you kind of
understand how much how much how much
value there is and you understand how
how big things are
you also probably want to understand how
risky
things how much risk is involved in this
item
um
and with all of that information then we
can start to figure out uh um like value
minus risk divided by size there's a
poor man's order of your your product
backlog right there's a first order and
then you could Nuance it from there but
the reality is that I I really don't
expect people to have that many things
in their product backlog the the one of
the most important things that folks can
do to help plan and prioritize the work
is not have so much crap to plan and
prioritize right and if you've got 5 000
things in your product backlog it's not
a product backlog it's a Dumping Ground
right there's there's no 5 000 things
that the product owner and the scrum
team and the stakeholders can actually
understand
what is in there and what this thing is
they would need to
um
um remove as many of those things as
possible get rid of the the the
I don't know all the stuff that's just
getting why is there so many weeds in
the way to try and find the value that
you need to need to deliver the best
product backlogs are small
um the best product backlogs are
probably
um two or looking two or three Sprints
into the future maybe a little bit more
if you're a large organization but the
further out into the future you look the
kind of higher level the item is
therefore it's less granular and there's
less detail I.E less weeds right because
it's a big thing it's a tree rather than
being a plant that you can go deal with
and move around and I think
that that d scaling de-escalation
removing as much as possible so that
they can focus
they can focus on the things that
they're trying to create what is what is
what is the business trying to achieve
select the things that go towards that
achieving that business goal and iterate
right you need to be collecting data and
looking at are we actually being
successful one of the key key pieces to
to to planning and prioritization is are
we even working on the right thing and
how do you know if you're working on the
right thing if you have no collected no
data to understand how your customers
are using it what your customers want
um You're Building features are they
still being used by your customers
should you be removing stuff from your
products instead of adding it I think it
it all comes down to a massive of of of
data analysis and understanding of
um what it is that that you're trying to
achieve so merging those those long-term
goals of the business with the
short-term goals of the product and the
data to back up to validate your
hypothesis right
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility