so organizational agility provides a
competitive Advantage for organizations
not because agile's the point because
it's not right lots of organization
that's why a lot of our agile
Transformations agile Transformations
fail is because the the the agile
becomes the point not a tool to get to
the outcome that the business really
needs which is being able to respond to
the market faster that that's ultimately
what it is
um that we're trying to do with with
agile with devops with lean with kanban
with all of these practices are designed
to enable your organization to respond
more quickly to Market changes if you
can respond more quickly than your
competitors to Market changes you get
there first and quite often the person
who gets there first is the one that
gets the prize right
um it it it it's really hard for a lot
of organizations to be able to
um respond to the same right so I I
think something in the market changes it
could be a customer complaining it could
be
um like a fundamental shift in the
actual Market
um and and your business needs to
respond how long does it take to respond
because the signal happens we need to
make a change and does it have to go up
your organization through different
layers to the person at the top and then
the person at the top makes a decision
and then those decisions go back down
and it sounds like well that could be
quite quick we've got a quite a flat
organization but the problem is that
because the person who's dealing
directly with the market doesn't
actually
care quite often they don't they don't
care that much right they want to do the
right thing but not it's a job right
um they're they're they're looking at
that change and going well that's not
painful enough for me to escalate it to
Bob because it's a pain in the ass
talking to Bob so I'm just gonna shut up
for a while and then a couple of months
later well this is now getting painful
enough I'm gonna escalate it to Bob so
it goes goes and talks to Bob and then
it has to be painful enough for Bob for
him to escalate it to the next level and
then painful enough to escalate it to
the next level
so it can be a really long time before
it escalates up the chain and then how
often have you heard leadership in your
organization say you know we're changing
strategic Direction and we're going this
way
and nothing happens right and it's
because that that communication has to
come all the way back down the
organization so a lot of agile and a lot
of agile practices is about
um pushing responsibility down the
organization enabling the people who
have the most information about what it
is we need to do to actually respond
themselves to the market right they
don't have to go ask anybody let's just
deal with these things that are
happening so your business responds more
quickly but that means you have to
provide those people with a lot more
context a lot more understanding uh if
you go look up turn this ship Around by
David Marquette
um that's a a perfect story talking
about that how do you know when you can
do something if it's within your power
to do it well you need more contextual
information about the right decision to
make
um and that's really what agile is all
about it's about enabling us to go uh
faster and in the in the in the market
right deliver things more quickly
respond to that change more quickly and
surprises there's good changes and bad
changes right but respond to the market
more quickly
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility