there are multiple schools of thought on
code reviews one school of thought is
that code reviews help us improve our
code quality help reduce defects because
we've get multiple eyes looking at the
product but I think that's only part of
the story as we shift left another
school of thought starts to come to the
Forefront which is our code should be
pre- reviewed a a code review a a a
person manually code reviewing our code
should not actually be required because
our code should already have been
reviewed by the time we submit a pool
request and that would then enable all
of our pool requests to be almost
totally automated or as automated as we
can get to so that the pool request
process itself is not becoming a blocker
to deliver value in our business so
there are lots of different techniques
and practices within the context of code
reviews I very much support and value H
code reviews and pool request systems
that are in place in in GitHub and inure
devops I I would absolutely recommend
that nobody is able to commit code H uh
to to master to main without going
through a pool request and without
passing uh validated checks but those
Val validated checks should be as
automated as they can possibly be within
the context of your system and naked
agility has helped others and can help
you create automations and practices and
procedures that enable you to have the
highest quality possible code and detect
defects as early as possible