one of the seven deadly sins of agile is
lust is is loads of
organizations are um talking
about agile transformation digital
transformation whatever
transformation they they want something
different because they've
realized that the mark markets have
changed right it's taken them a long
time to realize the markets have changed
they changed years ago right in fact
1930s was when the market started to
change 1970s they were totally changed
and it's taken until now for a lot of
companies to actually realize oh [ __ ]
stuff's changed what's going on right
why why isn't our old processes and
systems uh uh working so now they're
looking around for something new they've
got that I was going to say 7year itch
right but it's the 70E itch um and
they're looking around for new processes
and practices that they can use and they
see this agile thing doing really well
and they want it right they want they
want it desperately and they don't
really want to do the work for
it they just want to buy it I think
there must be a useis for that but I
think I'll stay away from it um they
just want to they just want to buy this
thing they don't want to actually spend
the effort and the time and the energy
to figure out what it means for them and
their business they just want somebody
else to come in and install it they just
want to pay somebody to come in and do
it for them right that's what they want
to do and that's why you see a lot of
organizations bringing in and you know
the big four Consulting companies you
see McKenzie and Accenture and Boston
Consulting Group coming in um giving
giving giving advice but the problem is
they're giving advice based on all of
these other big organizational
Transformations there is no precedent
within your organization for agile you
can't just look at what somebody else is
doing and lust after it and bring it
into your organization you need to build
your own unique way of doing things over
time and actually do the work to get
there and
that's uh why you can't just lust after
this agile thing you need to do the work
to bring it into your organization
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked
agility