while our seasoned agile coach will
definitely include all of the knowledge
uh that that a scrum master has it will
be a deeper with more experienced
effectively more battle-hardened they're
usually somebody that has had long years
of experience working in organizations
uh developing and implementing agile
practices within organizations and
learning the Deep technical expertise in
in lean agile
scrum kanban that they need in order to
be be successful and ultimately they
know where all the bodies are buried
right they've seen the successes they've
seen the failures they know what works
and what doesn't
um and they're there to to to Really
help the organization Excel