Steve Jobs said you can't connect the
dots looking forward you can only
connect them looking backwards and and
he's he's he's absolutely correct any
dots that you connect looking forward
into the future are are based on
assumptions are based on probabilities
maybe it will happen maybe it won't but
what we can do to help get a greater
inform of the future to help inform us
more about the future is to look at the
past look at the things that have
happened in the products that we have in
the teams that we've got and that will
help inform our choices moving forward
but we still need to validate and check
that they're not bad ideas