hello and welcome to Nikhil agility with
Martin Intuit I'm Martin Intuit and I'm
going to be talking about the life sight
culture and site reliability in the
azure DevOps team at Microsoft
[Music]
okay hey I'm welcome today I want to
talk a little bit about site reliability
engineering it's something that um I
spend a lot of time thinking about
because I have many customers who also
have operational needs as well as having
the the typical engineering needs that
they have and I think it's important to
find that balance between engineering
and operations and there's your DevOps
team have an interesting story about how
they've managed to create that that
balance and create a culture inside of
their organization supporting live site
and and doing it with engineering teams
so we're going to cover quite a few
different topics and I have I have a lot
of information here about how the azure
DevOps team do their work as well as how
they interact with us the customers but
just to give you an overview we're going
to talk about a transparency and how to
how they manage to build trust with
their customers and we're going to talk
about the amount of telemetry that they
collect and how they organize that so
how open and transparent actually are
they with customers and how much
telemetry did right
and then how do they organize themselves
around responding to things that happen
so there's going to be plenty of things
that happen they do they do scrum they
have three week Sprint's how do they
make sure that they're still able to
deliver value and while also being able
to and get other things done as well get
their operational what if the site goes
down what if there are other pieces of
work that would make the site more
efficient and less likely to go down how
do they prioritize that work and so
stuff around that and then we can have a
little bit of discussion about
automation automation is very important
for an agile story we talk about all the
time in in scrum that your definition of
done at the end of every sprint your
application should be potentially
shippable with no further work required
by the engineering team to make that
happen so if your business decides let's
ship to production there's not anything
else for the engineering team to do
ultimately your product owner can just
push push a button and ship to
production and that should be as much as
is necessary and and then there's a
little bit of a discussion around
investigation and getting to the root
cause and how to continually improve in
your environment and I think that's
that's important as well we talked a lot
about in in complex systems it can be
impossible to get to a root cause and I
think if if that were true we would
never visit the doctor because there
would be no point there are certain
causes that we can identify we may not
get everything but we can certainly do
our due diligence and figure out how to
get there but first I have a little
short story about an organization that
you may or may not be familiar with
it's the story of how a company with
nearly 400 million dollars in assets
went bankrupt in 45 minutes because of a
field deployment um this was a company I
called the knight Capital Group they
were listed on the New York Stock
Exchange and they were implementing
effectively a new order handling system
that allowed them to create child orders
this allowed them to do something they
hadn't done before but it required that
they replaced the old code with new code
and be able to integrate from there and
and it was really nine nine years of
application building that had gone into
this system so you can imagine if you
have nine years of code in there there's
going to be maybe a lot of spaghetti
there's going to be a lot of difficult
areas lots of leftover things that
people have just built and ignored for
many years so they did decide to
repurpose an existing flag in the system
in order to activate the new code so
that was one of the things that they did
which potentially could have a negative
result or negative impact and but at
deployment time their engineer their
technician during the deployment only
copied the new code to seven of the
eight fireman's
then they flip the switch turned on that
flag and they went live
because they had that Fault in the
number of servers that were active at
with the new code and the system was not
I was gonna say performing correctly but
not not operating normally
it was doing strange things it wasn't
able to process the the orders at all
that we're coming through and they
started losing at just under two hundred
thousand dollars per minute and
[Music]
because the system wasn't wasn't working
as expected
they then obviously they're gonna try
and fix it so they drop everything
everybody's here's on fire they come
running trying to figure it out and they
just they couldn't figure out what the
problem was
for that whole D so they spent a whole
day with the system down and they
couldn't figure out what the problem was
they didn't understand that it was just
one server that was acting up everything
looked like it was normal you go test a
seraph things good why is this not
working couldn't figure it out and at
the end of that day they were losing the
the the they lost four hundred and sixty
million dollars and they filed for
bankruptcy protection an interesting
question you may ask yourself is what
would be the impact in your organization
of our key or critical platform that you
create or that you create for your
customers being being down for that
length of time what what can you do to
prevent it it's interesting we know a
lot about what happened to the night
capital group because there are publicly
where a publicly listed company and you
can see their SEC filing and going to
see what happened but they had no
automation and they they no procedures
for back-out plans no no no anything so
that's it was a massive at risk of the
organizations and and really we need to
think about how do you get better at
doing something like that one of the
things that I see a lot of organizations
doing is thinking that they can create
they can create a back-up plan that they
can reverse the thing that they failed
to do forwards and be successful at it
if you can't be successful at deploying
your product the chances of you being
able to reverse that deployment are a
lot lower than your ability to deploy in
the first place
so I think it's really a losing
proposition one of the things that I see
most engineering organizations that move
towards continuous delivery move towards
DevOps move towards delivering faster is
that the observe our roll forwards
mentality rather than enabling things
like rollback which are just really not
not viable anymore so Microsoft has made
a lot of changes over the last few years
ten years ago Microsoft was a waterfall
organization no matter how much they you
know you you saw tools for maybe doing
agile things they were a waterfall
organization they were deploying a
visual studio and TFS every two years
that's the particular department that
I'm going to talk about today instead of
Microsoft and times have changed
they were deploying every two years they
were in a service pack halfway and
that's no longer viable it's no longer
okay to respond to feedback from your
customers on those type of timeframes
and and a big example of that has been
Windows with their windows 8 a massive
failure of understanding the customers
needs so there was a big disconnect and
a multi-billion dollar lost therefore
basically not having tighter feedback
loops so it is important it is something
that you will need to do with your
customers shorten those feedback loops
understand their needs a little bit
better and get things out the door and
even the windows team who deploy to
nearly a billion machines worldwide and
have four and a half thousand software
engineers working on their product are
now doing continuous delivery to
production and the the we get it you get
it as a general public and every 30 days
it used to be Patch Tuesday
now it's whole new version of Windows
Tuesday and has new features new
capabilities on that continuous cadence
so they can get feedback they do have
short okay
Ceaser's as well they're not just
deploying once a month and I have two
machines here that are on the windows
insider group which I get weekly
deployments as long as everything looks
good
and if you're inside of Microsoft and on
a corporate build machine which the CEO
is then you get daily builds from the
dev branch of the windows so it's
important quality is important so
they've actually gone from maybe
deploying once or twice a year across
even all of their products going to
production once or twice a year and to
something that looks a little bit more
more staggering and over a hundred and
sixty three thousand deployments per day
that's to any environment but that's an
incredible bigger across the across the
organization and that's with ninety six
thousand engineers so there's more than
one deployment per day per engineer
inside of Microsoft now 2 million git
commits per month 500 million text
executions per day this is this is a lot
of data a lot of things going on and in
order to support that the team that
builds the product so Microsoft uses a
product called Azure DevOps which used
to be called TFS it's also been called
visuals to do online it's also been
called TF t F services what else has
this had a bit of an identity crisis
over the years but the azure Devi's
platform and has been Microsoft's
platform of choice it was built in order
to support their transition towards this
new way of working and almost everybody
inside of Microsoft is now using it to
manage their work and deploy some of
them have moved over onto github for
source control but for work item
tracking for automated builds at the
majority of folks inside of Microsoft my
understanding is they're using a huge
DevOps and so it was built with with
that in mind with scale
mind with things that that large in mind
and this latest from Donovan Browns
presentation this fairly big numbers
so in order to support this and so
creating the the platform the Microsoft
and many other people around the world
use to to to manage their their
engineering efforts the azure DevOps
team had to create this live site
culture inside of their organization and
one of the things that they really
focuses on is M you you code it you
build it you deploy it you run it if
you're going to be the one that writes
the code you should be the one that gets
up at three o'clock in the morning
because the thing that you've written is
not working properly there's some
caveats to that we'll talk about as we
go through but ultimately the software
engineers the people writing the code
need to feel the pain of any sort of
problems with either deployment or
supporting the product or managing it
online of security of all of the things
there would be a problem so they don't
necessarily have other departments that
manage these things no this is one of
the big transitions between other big
yeah transitions the right word but the
big flip for organizations is that
change from being a predominantly
departmental based organization towards
being
cross-functional delivery teams who are
able to take an idea and get it all the
way to production without needing to be
dependent upon external teams that's
really important for that transition
towards a greater degree of agility
because if soon as you're dependent upon
somebody else outside of your
organization that has different
motivations different priorities then
you're not going to be able to get
things done very quickly because you're
gonna some point you're gonna have to
wait for them we have to remove those
wait times so we bring rather than how
we're going out to an external part
Department we bring that department into
the team so there's representation on
the team of security of legal of
obviously coding engineering test
operations and all of those ideas those
hats those roles are represented inside
of the team you need to automate you
need to learn and share with each other
all the time we need to be getting
better at what we do constantly and and
we need a lot of data to help us figure
out what's going on what's happening and
anybody that manages our live site will
know that live comes first no matter
what you're doing if production is down
you're gonna have to drop everything
you're doing and go go figure that out
so how do we make sure that we support
that in a way of organizing people and
this is about how there's your devops
team I've managed to do that so this is
this is an example a story of our way
that you can do that and don't just hate
the way they're doing things that
implement it yourself you want to see
what works for you in your organization
in your organizational within your
organizational constraints within your
application and platform constraints as
well this particular team is building
our our web application but there are
other teams inside of Microsoft that use
a similar process in order to
managed at desktop as well as windows
and other types of application models
so you need to create a culture within
which this this this this works and
LifeSite is about bringing the right
people together from both app and
platforms so that we can continue and
it's been to keep our system up to have
the the lovely things that we as users
of the system really really want but why
why is it so important to keep
everything up as some headlines there
are great examples of how those things
have been difficult for organizations in
the past Visual Studio online which was
one of the names for Azure DevOps and
has has had outages they have had
outages and it's not possible for a
system not to have outages it's about
how you deal with them when they happen
so Visual Studio online as your husband
down Amazon has been down and there's a
start-up with 25 million in funding in
crisis because when employee deleted the
wrong files these these things happen we
want to do our best to prevent those
things from happening we want to do our
best to respond to those things when
they do happen and we want to do our
best to make sure that things that do
happen don't continue to happen and
that's how we build trust with our
customers because really we've got to be
able to deploy new features that's the
the the ultimate and battle between
engineering and operations is that idea
of engineering is measured by the number
of fantastic features they get into
production but operations is measured by
uptime and generally those things are
antagonistic if you want to keep it up
you don't deploy new features if you
want to deploy new features you're not
gonna be able to keep it up so there's a
fight there but when we bring
those two groups together they can have
a real conversation about how they can
do both of those things and still be
able to delight their customers have
high levels of uptime have fantastic
features and be able to move forward and
that's really what I want to talk about
as we go through this today um so first
thing I want to talk about is
transparency how do we how does this
team build transparency with their
customers so I'm gonna kind of split
trying it split between good practices
complementary practices that you can use
with your scrum team or your Kanban team
as part of your agile practices as well
as what this team specifically has done
it's why I'm going to show some of the
details and governs of the work that
they've done around that um but we need
transparency to build trust with our
customers we need to be understanding of
things when they happen as well as doing
our best to understand how and why they
happened and so that we can figure out
what to do about it
customers are not happy if you just tell
them the system was down we rebooted the
server and now it's back up again why
was it down
is it going to go down again we no
longer have a level of confidence in
your ability to maintain that system if
you don't even know why there's a
problem with or why it's going down so
we need to understand that and build
transparency to build trust with our
customers so this is an example of some
of the output you will get from the
Hosier dev ops team you'll be able to go
find on and the visual studio well
that's this is a from the Veals to team
services blog it's the same blog it's
just been moved around a little bit but
it's there's your DevOps blog and they
do a full post-mortem and they publish
all of the data they publish it to shore
and here if you maybe
I can well that's not what I wanted to
do I wanted to zoom in there was my
magnifying glass there we go
they they show the data when things went
bad
what they've investigated in order to
understand what went bad how they've
managed or tried to mitigate it the
actions they took and the timeline that
that went through so it's a really
powerful story there and they also at
publish an idea of what they're going to
go do to go fix it as well so if i zoom
it there we go they're going to make a
bunch of commitment to their customers
to improve the service to make sure that
that type of problem those outages don't
happen again for every outage of Azure
DevOps at big and small you will find at
these types of posts and this type of
data the smaller the outage the the less
impact the outage obviously the less
effort you want to spend in some of
these areas but when the whole system's
down you're gonna see a post and that
looks like this with a bunch of data in
it and
the leadership of the is your DevOps
team is adamant that they want to create
that transparency this is a post from a
reply that brine Harry who was the
product unit manager for that department
who really instigated those ideas of
moving to the cloud and am empowered
that part of the organization to make
the changes that resulted in them being
becoming an agile organization
delivering to production and at least
every three weeks and you can see the
type of transparency that he's trying to
create he's saying you know we're not
going to be successful 100% of the time
that's just reality we have to accept
reality there's no such thing as a
hundred percent uptime it's just not
possible no matter what folks say you
have to have downtime from maintenance
you have to have we have to have a
little bit of wiggle room you can't be
100 percent up but how do we make sure
that we minimize the amount of downtime
that we have well there's lots of things
that we can do the first is to the
communication letting people know that
you know that those downtime that
there's some sort of problem that and
there's an issue this is an application
that the user DevOps team have created
in 2013 it was just a spreadsheet and it
was 45 minutes was their time to notify
but their customers and as the users and
but in 2017 that's down to 15 minutes
within 15 minutes of that red button
getting pushed understanding that
there's a problem there's something up
on the Status page there's something up
on the blog and for the internal
Microsoft customers and the key
stakeholders there are emails going out
to the people that need to know and I
have a couple of customers who are in
the top
20 largest customers on Azure DevOps and
they get notifications almost before
they know that there's a problem which
is really powerful for them as well to
then be able to and have the real
discussions they need inside of their
organization yes we're aware of the
problem Microsoft's working to fix it
you know those things that build trust
if we know we understand we're aware
that we can do that so in order to to
preempt this you've got the I remember
one of my good friends at Microsoft when
they first moved to the cloud said one
of the reasons that he made his first
got onto Twitter first it was when they
moved to the cloud because he found out
from people on Twitter that the system
was down before his engineering team
knew that the system was down because we
as software engineers being that the
customers are software engineers as well
are particularly aha em windy and
complaining group of people we are happy
to point the finger when something's not
working properly and he found out first
there so how do you create an
environment within which you know first
not your customers you don't want your
customers to know before you do that
there's a problem with the system and
for that we need telemetry we need data
and we need to understand that data in
order to create the right alerts to know
what we're supposed to do and when when
when that problem arises is that a
problem we need to care about is that a
problem that might go away do we just
need to um in a saunter up to that
problem or do we need to run up to that
problem with with everybody that we need
so um figuring out what we can do to
prevent incidents by looking at the data
and seeing when things might be you know
okay that was a bit that data did not
look good if we'd had
more users on the system at that point
in time we would have had a problem what
can we do to make sure that next time
whatever that data is that spikes or
drops in the way that it did how do we
make sure that we get that moving so
incident prevention at continuous
improvement how do we continually go
around those loops identifying the root
causes and figuring it out because your
DevOps team have created their own
telemetry pipeline so that they can
understand that data and do something
with it they have implemented it in a
lot of the work since their servers are
deployed to Azura they can take
advantage of some of that is your
infrastructure that's there for
everybody anyway they don't have any
special powers in as your as your treats
them like customers as well albeit
pretty big customers and somebody
internal that has everybody's email
address and can go look them up but
that's a different matter but having
monitoring agents installed on all of
your servers and having a set of metrics
that can help you understand what that
looks like and then feed that all into a
big data at platform they have they've
built something called cosmos where they
feed all of that data in and then
they're able to use a query platform
called that they built koku store that
allows them to analyze that data and
look for for trends look for things that
are worrying and so you can have
monitors and you can have alerts that's
reactive the alert triggers you had a
notification you're gonna go do
something about it and but also is there
trends that you can look for in the data
analysis to see when something's going
to happen even maybe before it does so
they have access to as your Diagnostics
they use a pin sites application
insights is built on top of your and it
allows you to on any platform and they
have api's for all the platforms it's
just a set of services
collect and analyze metrics and then
they feed all of that data into an azure
data leak and a lot of these systems the
the features were built out as part of a
lot of teams at Microsoft moving towards
this model a very powerful platform I
use it myself on on on my tools as well
and something that they they really
realized was that they have to gather
everything there's dessert there's no
data that is unimportant are you gonna
to gather data about your SLES you've
got to gather data about alerts your
DevOps pipelines your experiments that
are going on you're going to collect
data about your network performance your
platform all of the things that are
going on even then to Tracy's telemetry
power flux everything is going to be
collected in that way and at the moment
or at least at the point in time where I
got access to an understanding of the
volume of data they were collecting
about seven terabytes of data per day on
average with people using the system and
getting an understanding of all of that
data KPI is job history pair of
characters Tracy's activity logs
platform and network capabilities so in
order to do that you really have to
understand the the customer experience
telemetry so a user accesses the system
it goes through a bunch of tiers
possibly it potentially accesses the
database and then serves as a result
back to the customer or all of your
interactivity with with many of these
systems is user activated and when it's
user activated you really have to
understand the flow and one of the
things that the azure DevOps team do is
they have an IDE that is generated for
every like call into the system that
they pass all the way through down to
sequel server and they collect
performance and trace across the board
there's actually our front end flag that
you can turn on and I'll maybe try and
look it up or or speak to one of the
teams to see where you turn that on
again I can never remember oh underscore
Diagnostics on let's see if I can figure
it out
dev comm
bring that across I will bring it across
in just there
let me butt
not there because that will not get
directory where is my [ __ ] did you leti
I'm just switching to I have are a lot
of Azure DevOps that I have access to a
lot of different platforms and systems
so I'm just going to
bring that up
it is just taking its time to load so
maybe I stick it over here and do it
will you that once it's loaded oh no I
have to hit switch at the bottom then
you'll love it when you've got a tall
screen in the buttons way at the bottom
that's a user experience so are they're
able to collect that telemetry that pair
of telemetry across their entire
organization so let me go into my
migration tools setup let's see if I can
remember how to do this I'm pretty sure
it's underscore Oh
is it underscore Diagnostics it is
that's what happens when you've been
working with the team for too long so if
I turn on Diagnostics and perf bar and
you can do this on any of your accounts
as well I just want to show you what it
is that you know the kind of
capabilities that they're collecting you
can see at the bottom of the screen it's
very small can I pop a mic can I pop a
magnifying glass my fire there we go
whoa that is not what I wanted yet
whoo
okay that's not working very well but if
I hit I suck at that I need to get
better at nope it's not letting me
they wat bump here we got if i zoom in
no
right there we go
you can see I don't know if you can see
that hopefully you can see that
okay maybe not but there's our path bar
at the bottom of the page here you can
see at performance if I pop that up I'm
gonna kill magnifier so it makes it
easier to see this but if I pop that up
it's collecting the the trace and time
and things that have happened throughout
the entire system all the way through
every web service down to every database
call every plugin so that you can go
analyze that if you're one of the
developers on this team you want as much
data as possible to go figure that out
and you can see at the bottom there's
actually a little smiley face there um I
don't know if you can see that all the
way down there little smiley face that
means it met the KPI for how long pages
are supposed to load if you have a
smiley face if you have a side place
things are not going so well and it says
all is good all the checks are working
out so that's one of the ways that the
team are able to leverage that and for
some reason I have lost all of the
buttons on my office so let me just
close that and reopen it so I can get
back showing you
there we go I've got a pack
don't you love it when find where where
we we we're about there a it's like ah
so they have this ability to correlate
everything across the board end to end
and have that set up and and working we
can see all the dependencies they can
get all of the telemetry data and set
all of that up and it means that they
can check I have metrics and trend
analysis to see what's going on and when
something goes below the trend that they
want they can dive in and see exactly
when things happen what the problem was
how many people were affected and be
able to take to get to get that pair of
get access to that extra information
that they have
I'm getting that extended down all the
way to their dependencies so if they are
dependent upon the sequel server and the
sequel services then they're able to get
all of that as well and see the
dependency activities I mean the amount
of data that they collect is
unbelievable because they need to keep a
system up with all of the software
engineers that are users of this system
you know checking in code think think of
if as your DevOps goes down all of the
millions of people that use it and all
of the companies that have their
software engineers reliant upon it
they're all down there all unavailable
it's not a good place to know to be and
so you need to be able to go deep on the
telemetry and really understand at
what's going on at every level
ah they do have activity looks schema
I'm just gonna go through this very
quickly I am happy to provide the slides
out to anybody who wants to give me a
shout I will do that but they collect
all of their at telemetry across the
board really understand and that tool
that I just showed
oh there we go there's the URL I did not
even know it was in here but they
surfaced that data at to the developers
so that they can they can see it and get
access to it so you can do that as well
and see that performance on your copy of
the system to see what data is available
and they also aggregate it across the
entire service so they get an insight as
to and what's going on holistically but
also per customer as well if you've got
everybody at a particular customer
that's down then we need to go deal with
that it it's it's not okay to say we
have 5,000 customers and one customer is
down so that's not so bad but one
customer is down everybody at that one
customer cannot do at the job that they
do on the service so you need to make
sure that you can see that as well and
see it in real time so that you can do
something about it and get a true
understanding of what's going on so I
think that's that's super SuperDuper
important okay and that idea that
customers are a bag of sand I love that
one
em every grain of sand is a customer and
every grain is important if somebody is
having a problem they're gonna tell ten
of their friends that they have a
problem and you can see here they're
they're doing an impact threshold and to
understand when do we need to have a
bigger conversation when we're in breach
of SLA so that we can go do something
about it but also the the team I know
that they go back over this data to see
even the
the smaller blips when people had
problems or performance problems let's
go talk to the customer figure out what
the problem was and what can we do to go
and fix that up and you've got to find a
balance between the amount of noise the
amount of data you get and having you
know the alerts to the developers you've
got to be able to push new features at
the same time so if everybody's
interrupted all the time so trying to
minimize those alerts so that they're
only the things that are important you
you'll know if you get an email that is
you get a hundred emails from one
service you're going to either turn that
service off turn the emails off or
create a rule and shove them in a folder
somewhere where nobody will ever see
them so that's that's oh I went the
wrong way that's really important so
balancing at that noise to signal so
then you also need to be able to respond
as quickly as possible to the problems
that come up and you can't have the
development team chucking that code over
the wall over the fence to the software
engineer the operations team and because
what they offer up what's going to
happen is the operations team are going
to just bolt on some type of monitoring
that they can do what they can do
whereas if engineering the dev team is
building out the monitoring they are
able to add deep holistic monitoring
into their application and have a much
better experience for the engineers out
trying to figure out the problem
operations who are trying to support and
maintain it so they built around this
idea of s re bringing DevOps and s re
together they'd already had they used to
have
developers coders testers and operations
as completely separate teams now they've
got a combined engineering team which
has featured team engineers which are
your traditional coders and testers
that's bringing bringing that group
together and that's your feature team
engineers but also on the same team
they have live site engineers okay and
they have two two pieces of that story
I've got it here in blue and purpose re
purple and blue yeah blue and purple
they have a feature team life site
engineer which is a rotating role for
the feature team engineers so at least
one of the if not two of the feature
team engineers for a sprint will be
designated as a feature team live site
engineer that live site engineer em is
not going to be looking at value work ie
your traditional sprint backlog they are
solely going to be looking at work to
help improve stability of the platform
maintain and manage that and they also
have access to site reliability
engineers who are dedicated site
reliability engineering folks and that
have deep expertise in platform and
monitoring to leverage and they're all
part of the same team you have a
combined engineering team that could
includes the rotating roles as well as
the dedicated
LifeSite s our site reliability
engineering is an important concept to
create a world in which we can we can
get very quick delivering to a platform
that's up as much as possible and so we
want to automate as much as possible but
there are always going to be things that
we we have to do you might have some
kind of compliance security those are
all things that we have to do and this
is the the
the the pyramid of things we must do up
to the most valuable things at the tops
or product contributions are at the top
and a live site engineer that that
feature site
life site engineer and site reliability
engineer are going to be working
together and and doing stuff at the
bottom of this pyramid and then flowing
as those things are complete up to the
top of the top of the pyramid so the
last thing they do is product
contributions when everything else is
complete that's a powerful story because
they have to be able to respond to
allowance those are the folks they
assigned feature life site engineers are
the ones that get woken up at 3 o'clock
in the morning to go deal with that
problem the team the there's your DevOps
team have built and I don't know what
you call it an alerting system and auto
routing system with different ways those
elapsed can be triggered social at
humans that's a support call alerting
and customer support and goes into a
rules engine and then allocates that to
the the
the combined engineering team that is
accountable for that part of the system
that part of the code and then they will
do an impact assessment and decide what
they want to do how are they going to
respond to this to this problem are they
going to do a generic business errors
investigation they'll put it on the
backlog we'll get to it in the morning
when everybody wakes up and or are we
going to have to wake a bunch of people
up and do the 24/7 live incident and
when the live incident happens they're
going to create a bridge an incident
bridge with all the people on it that
they need it to go figure that out so
the feature team life site engineer is
on there they're the allocated person on
the engineering team as well as the sres
but maybe they need to bring in
additional partners like if sequel
server is operating slow then maybe they
have to bring in somebody from Azure
executive leadership might be brought in
there may be an incident manager there
are all sorts of things that are
triggered in order to make those things
happen get everybody together and get a
resolution to the problem that idea of
having those a life site team inside of
a software engineering team so they have
slightly bigger teams than you would
traditionally see for scrum teams scrum
teams are traditionally between three
and nine they this drug do between ten
and twelve people they have two people
on the team that is the live site team
so they have a feature team which are
looking at the sprint backlog and
dealing with those issues and then the
live site team only deals with live site
issues and interruptions so they're
shielding the team from those potential
disruptions while still working on
things that would add value to the
product but from the perspective of life
site issues so mitigating things for
future life site issues
and that that group has a rotating group
it will be a different group each each
sprint so again they have priorities if
there's a live site incident that's
their highest priority if there is no
life site incident then they're going to
be looking at past life site mitigation
tasks so that could be things that
enable us to get better at life site or
it could be things that we've identified
as being a problem that really end up in
that category of technical debt things
that are not automated things that are
not quite in a way they need to be and
do that and then they're going to look
at improvements in monitoring telemetry
and alerts way before they look at
adding any any new features that is
their focus so the team that works on
this they do three week Sprint's so
during sprint for example during sprint
1:24 the deployment is ongoing for
sprint 123 it takes a long time to do a
deployment on a large system like this
so it takes more than a few days takes
more than a week to be honest to get
that deployed and so they have the
LifeSite engineers are working alongside
at the feature team but they're kind of
working at loggerheads there
so they also need to be able to manage
things at scale and the only way to do
that is to automate we need to automate
everything need to automate as much as
possible people people make mistakes
that's one of the reasons to automate
people need to go to sleep and people
forget things
think about that engineering team at the
start for the night capital group that
Nick elected to deploy to one of the
servers people forget things people make
mistakes automated processes can tell us
when they fail when they don't get
everything done so being able to
troubleshoot those ideas if we're
automating we can have alerts that find
things much much quicker and realize
that something's wrong and once you
start mitigating your problems you you
might have some manual mitigations that
you have to do that would be you know
the first thing that might happen but if
something like that happens often and
you have the same mitigation task you
can get it to be automating the
mitigation as well have the automated
engine let that switch and then notify
the engineers that there's a problem
they need to go fix but you've already
mitigated the problem that doesn't mean
we don't have work to do and because
we're we're monitoring the health all
the time we're understanding when those
mitigating tasks have been activated and
how do we get better at not having those
problems in the first place that's
really important
getting to the root cause is important
doing some kind of post mortem to really
understand and what can be done to make
our product better to improve quality so
that we don't have those issues in the
future and each team each feature team
has their own goals and measures and
repair times that they can monitor and
see what's happening and be able to be
able to respond to change more quickly
how do we know when the team is being
good at responding to change
they should be repairing problems that
come up quickly they should be having
less problems over time these are
indications that we can we can look at
to go see so kind in conclusion we need
quality and transparency to build
customer trust we need to have a full
transparency so the customers see
everything that's going on we we we
taught them about the problems we helped
figure out how to make them better and
we we make sure everybody's involved and
we collect as much telemetry as possible
so that we can have better insights into
what's going on
we need to organize around responding
more quickly so that's with alerts with
coal chains with understanding who do we
have to go deal with who do have to go
wake up and the LS es an engineering
team live site a team inside of the
engineering team is is what allows for
that for this group and automate
everything as far as I'm concerned if
it's not automated its technical debt
that's something you need to go work on
you shouldn't have anything that is not
automated and then you have to get as
close to the root cause as possible in
order to continuously improve and try
and figure out what those things are and
just to
and there are some goods well I'll make
myself smaller there we go
there are some good articles videos
there on sre at Microsoft how the
different teams do it and what they mean
by that if I how do I make myself
disappear
Desktop No
heywhat I'll move over here there we go
so you get a picture of that and go to
that URL and you will be able to
download this presentation please feel
free to get in touch with me anytime you
want to I am on Microsoft teams on that
URL I'm on twitter and you can whatsapp
me and find more information on my blog
I'm happy to share presentations all you
have to do is ask ok thank you very much
for listening and I hope you're able to
come to one of our scrum classes we
deliver a number of scrum data classes
and we are delivering all of our courses
and material as live virtual classrooms
at the moment and so please go take a
look at nkd agility calm ok
thank you very much like and subscribe
[Music]