so
the question is what what is a product
toner
and that is again an interesting
question because the the product owner
is
an accountability
so not not a job title right so I
wouldn't expect to see somebody whose
job title is product owner and I
wouldn't expect uh to see somebody
walking around going at you know I'm I'm
I'm I'm I'm the product owner but the
product owner accountabilities are
something that somebody in your
organization picks up and it's being
accountable for maximizing the value of
the work done by the scrum team
so that doesn't mean
doesn't mean that they're called product
owner doesn't mean that they only focus
on product ownership right they probably
have other focuses as well but it also
means that other things need to be true
in order for that to be successful right
maximizing the value of the work done by
the scrum team
is not ordering a product backlog right
that's that's a small mechanical element
of of that accountability
um in your context right your corporate
contacts your organizational context
you're going to have to figure out what
does product ownership mean in our
business right how do we maximize the
value of the work done do we need to
understand the market do we need to be
plugged into an understanding of what's
happening in the market and what
direction it's going do we need to be
plugged into an understanding of how
people are actually using our product
and interacting with it in different
ways do we need to be plugged into what
our customers are saying right that's
another thing that might piece of piece
of information that might be helpful
and the answer is you have to plug into
all of that and much more right the the
the the the more understanding that the
product owner the person who's picking
up the accountability of the product
owner has of what's going on in the
world that may impact on what it is that
we're working on what it is that we're
doing
so
um the product owner is absolutely
essential as they kind of set that tone
for for for product leadership for
strategic direction of the product for
uh um
um
building building something that really
resonates with the market and if it
resonates with the market that means
it's resonating with your customers that
your stakeholders understand what it is
you're working on what they're doing
that everything is being communicated
openly and transparently so we all
understand where we're going we're all
going in the same these are all things
that that product owner that
accountability of the product owner is
meant to represent now in in in scrum
product owner is one person not a
committee although they may chair a
committee right I thought that was an
interesting caveat
um but in in in the world I see lots of
different types of product owners I see
part product owners that are from from
the customer if you're a Professional
Services Company your customer is a
product owner you might have a proxy
product owner that liaisies with that
customer you might have somebody on your
team who is the product owner who was a
software engineer who is now becoming a
product owner you might have somebody
who was a scrum Master who's now a
product owner you might have nothing at
all right and there's a big gap and how
can you be successful if we're not all
going in the same direction that that
Gap is why the product owner is so
essential that
um you need to you need
the way we as humans organize around
solving a problem is we understand that
problem we work together towards solving
that problem right we work together
towards a common goal and part of the
the essential nature of the product
owner is to to to set communicate uh
understand set and communicate those
common products Vision strategy goals
that we're going towards so that
everybody
within the bounds of that product whose
cares about that product can get behind
it whether those people are customer
stakeholders or the people who are
actually building the product how are we
all working together towards a common
goal a common Vision a common Direction
um I mean it's it's it's so common that
you see teams and products and customers
like the team delivers up
something that the stakeholders are like
what the heck is this and customers are
like we don't like this we're not in
tune we're not all working together
towards a common goal and that's really
the power of the product owner that's
why they're essential
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility