businesses want
predictability predictability enables
them um to to focus on achieving the
outcomes that they desire in a
consistent way it reduces uncertainty
and helps them achieve their business
goals but
predictability is hard to
achieve um it it there are all sorts of
things that kind of get in the way of us
having predictability as a business now
the things that we can't avoid that get
in the way of predictability are things
like um Market volatility right the the
changes in the market the unpredictable
nature of the world and the ecosystem in
which we're in
are things we cannot control right so so
we have to um include that in our
story but there are a bunch of things
where we get
unpredictability that we can control
that we can do something about so having
having clear goals um or unclear goals
right causing unpredictability
operational
inefficiencies uh creating
unpredictability you don't know how long
things are going to take because
everything takes a different amount of
time to go through the system um and
really having an undefined system if you
don't have a description of how things
go through each of your systems you
could have many systems in your
organization
then how do we know that each thing that
goes through each system is going
through it in a consistent way which
enables that predictability right that
we can optimize the way things things
move through it um
so that will all all of those
unpredictabilities those
frictions um to our ability to do stuff
and inconsistent frictions to our
ability to do stuff will will impact on
the performance of our organization
ation it will impact on Revenue growth
it will impact on profitability um it
will impact on our ability to be
competitive in the market so the role of
agile in this story the role of agile in
in enabling predictability or agility in
enabling predictability is um in the the
application
of the ideas
it it's a lot about changing from rules
to principles instead of having a bunch
of rules that people mindly follow
mindlessly follow have a bunch of uh
principles under which the the folks
that you have within your organization
can make decisions Define the systems
that you have um and how you want them
to work not just as a as as leadership
telling people how to do it but but the
people that are doing the work Define
the systems that's pushing
responsibility down the organization to
the people who are actually doing the
work um and agile or the mindset of
agility um the agile philosophy is about
enabling people in our
organization
to improve the predictability of our
business
outcomes by impr improving the
predictability of the things that they
do and I think one of the difficulties
is that most organizations most people
in organizations are not looking at
predictability metrics they're not
looking at the the the the the data that
indicates um instabilities in the system
that are the things that you want to you
want to control you want to um where it
can be controlled where you want to to
to make changes so this this whole idea
of um increasing business predict
predictability is not something that
just randomly happens it's not something
that um just installing agility in your
organization is going to going to going
to result in an increased level of of
business predictability but it's
something that is systematic that is
deliberate that requires effort and
consistency of application and over over
a longer period of time to start making
the changes moving the needles to
increase the level of
predictability within your business
there's a myth that I see all the time
in
organizations um at every level that
because we're doing agile um we can't
plan or predict what's going to happen
we can't do we're not supposed to do
estimates um we're not supposed to be
looking forward too far into the future
um and all all of that is kind of bunkum
right
agility the the the fundamental
principle of agility is about minimizing
the amount of work you do until it needs
to be
done we we don't want to do
documentation that is going to change
frequen frequently un unless we need
that documentation in order to
understand what we need to change we'd
be better building some product right
build some product tested in the market
see get get into those tight feedback
clips and that's one of the key things
that I find that organizations really
struggle at within the context of of
predictability they they don't close the
feedback loops um so if you're if you're
looking at what you're doing within the
context of agility this myth that you
can't plan for the future is is just
that a myth uh the poster child for for
agility um is is Microsoft's transition
in the last whole 10 12 years and um
they they do they do planning looking
forward over 18 months right the
granularity is really uh really high
level but they do plan over over 18
months um they do a season based model
and they plan for 18 month seasons and
there's nothing wrong with that there's
nothing anti- agile about that but it's
the way that you do it it's how you
implement it is that 18month plan
something that is enshrined in this is
what we're going to do how changeable
and malleable is that plan over time um
and how much effort do you spend on that
plan versus doing the work that you need
to do just now those are all things that
belly this myth um that you can't plan
or predict because you're doing agile
you absolutely can you just use
different tools and techniques to be
able to achieve there's a really famous
quote
um plans are irrelevant planning is
everything and that's the key to
success within the context of business
predictability right if you want to
increase the predictability of your
business you need to stop creating
plans and start planning what is it
we're going to do next where do we want
to go what do we want to achieve if
we're answering those questions and then
communicating it effectively within the
business we can enable a level of
strategic alignment with everybody in
our organization that we become a team
if you look up team in the dictionary it
says a group of people working together
towards a common goal how can we do that
if we don't have that common goal and a
goal is a single thing it's not a whole
bunch of things so what is it that your
business is trying to achieve that you
want everybody and every product and
every effort to align behind for a
particular product within the context of
that business what is the thing that you
want everybody working together towards
the outcomes of that product to a line
behind what's the product's goal what is
it we're trying to achieve the vision
the strategy what are we trying to
achieve and these are things that are
commonly missing in organizations and
that creates a
fragmentation of effort right so the
effort that people put in is in a
direction of their choosing each
individual on a on on on the team's
effort of their choosing each man
manager effort of their choosing each
leader effort of their choosing each
product owner effort of their choosing
how do we enable us to be all working
together towards that common common goal
and that requires planning to get
predictability um so we're not really
talking about um risk mitigation as a as
a document right we're talking about
risk mitigation as a holistic strategy
for our organization we're not talking
about uh resource management at the
individual level we're talking about how
where are our investment opportunities
as a business that fit inside of our
strategic goals and strategy and how
many uh um how much money right are we
applying to solve that particular
problem or gain that particular
capability and that will denote the the
number of people that are available that
we can hire to go work towards that
outcome so that this this whole idea of
planning to gain predictability is to
enable your business to have a
competitive advantage in the market
against other businesses in the same
Market naked agility can
help you increase your your business
predictability by enabling you to be
able to do do that so we we can't we
can't come in and just provide you with
um increase your business predictability
we can't do that you need to do that
it's your business it's your
organization it's your department it's
your team the only people that can help
you increase that predictability or that
can increase that predictability are you
we can bring our knowledge and expertise
of what has worked in other
organizations we can bring um ways and
tools for analyzing the data what's the
current state of your system helping you
define your system so that you can then
see where the problems are that are
reducing your predictability so that you
can fix them right so one of the big
things we bring is visibility so that
you can see what's going on if you can
see what's going on you can make tweets
to the way you do things you can help
the people that you work with make
tweaks to the way they do things to
hopefully increase that level of
predictability within your business now
that can be be data driven right we can
we can look at data for for team morale
and capability we can look at data for
um Knowledge and Skills but it's a data
driven we can look at profitability of
the business and where we're spending
the money these are all datab driven
approaches we can then help bring um
Frameworks and and methodologies right
ideologies philosophies what are
things that are holistic to all
businesses that can enable you to look
at things in a different way to be able
to see what's going on to make make
those changes so things like Perhaps
Perhaps scrum is a good idea perhaps
caman is a good idea um perhaps lean
thinking is a good idea perhaps lean us
is a good idea there are all sorts of
tools
Frameworks um ideas available that have
been shown to work in many different
sorts of businesses that we can try and
analyze and see if it works for your
business in your
context so what we're offering is a
completely custom solution for your
business that doesn't make you like
somebody else's business one of the
things that I commonly see as as a as a
bad thing I guess trying to think of the
words but as as a negative consequence
to going and working or pulling in a
large Consulting organization that
brings a standard methodology and
practice and then applies it to your
business is that you
become like every other business that
they've applied it
to and one of the things that made your
your business
successful was its unique ability to
take advantage of a niche that you've
built in a market right you your
business grow to take advantage of a
niche and if somebody comes along and
applies their business practices or
their system or their thing on top of it
then you're just like every other
company that uses that same system like
uh a great example is is uh
um uh uh Road Road Road hauling right if
you're you're moving Goods around um
it's maybe not a good example because
those businesses are fairly standard
but businesses that use the same tooling
as every other business that does the
same thing is just the same business
just with a different owner right or a
different
funer they're they're not different
there's no dis valuation in the market
they're just filling that market how do
they open new markets how do they
ingenuously solve problems in
interesting ways that helps them adapt
their business towards a new Niche or
new capability or open up new markets
well they can't because they're working
within a structured system that doesn't
allow them to to explore other
opportunities so what we want to do as a
business is come up with our own way of
moving from whatever it is we're doing
now towards a greater degree of agility
so that it's our business processes it's
our unique way of doing things to fill
that unique Niche and if you look at
every
single commercial successful
organization that has adopted um agile
practices especially agile practices at
scale you'll see that every single one
of them has created their own Sy system
that fits the way they want to do
business and is shaped by the way they
want to do business they're not just
installing somebody else's system um and
that's why Microsoft used the season
based model Spotify have have what they
do right Google have have have their way
of doing things every single one of
these organizations has a unique way
that's bespoke to them of solving this
problem of how do we increase our
business predictability ability and our
ability to serve the markets within
which we're in it's pretty
hard to
describe what does it look like sound
like or feel
like once you're on this journey and
you've made some progress
towards uh um a greater degree of of of
of adaptability of a higher degree of of
predictability it's going to impact on
everything in your organization a great
um uh uh uh Microsoft is often asked um
what changed right when when you made
these changes and adaptations to your
business what changed and the answer is
usually
everything every everything changed the
way the way they do financing changed
the way they do business changed the way
they find new customers changed the way
they manage customers changed the way
they build the products has changed the
way they engage with people who build
the products the way they engage with
the people who build the products and
the outside world has changed every part
of their um business processes have
changed in their entire
organization and now that's a little bit
of an overestimation not everything has
changed they still have they're still on
their Journey right they're still on
their journey and they've not addressed
some things that they probably could
address but they've done a good job of
tackling some of those big things
a great example you can go look up is
the the the the change in the way they
measure um bonuses for sales people
right it used to be that they were
measured based on the amount of time
Azure time that they sell because Azure
is the big selling Fe right how much is
your do you sell but now it's on usage
because if you measure how much time do
they sell the salesperson gets the
customer to clinch the deal they're a
closer right that's who you want as a
salesperson is a closer
and then the customer has paid the money
the salesperson gets their bonus but the
problem with that is what happens at the
end of the year when the customer hasn't
used the thing they've paid for and it
expires right they bought a year worth
of stuff they've used 10% of it now
they're annoyed angry that they've had
90% of their funds have been wasted so
if you switch that around to usage that
the sales folks get their bonus based on
usage they then need different skills
they're not a dual closer right this is
this is an example of a little tweak in
the way a business functions that has a
massive impact this the the perfect
salesperson is no longer a closer
they're an enabler they enable your
company to help this customer use the
service more and more and more so for
example perhaps the the closer uh brings
in an expert and to bamboozle the
customer with all the cool things that
you can do and they close the deal and
they're done right but what the enabler
does is it brings in perhaps out of
their own budget they're going to bring
in and pay external consultants and
helpers to help over a longer term
enable that customer to use the services
more so now we're talking about what
enables you to use as your more agile
transition right Dev cobs all of these
things mean that you need to consume
things more quickly and it benefits both
parties right it benefits both Microsoft
because they get to sell more asure and
if it benefits the customer because then
they're they're able to adapt to their
Market needs more quickly and more
effectively and that is that core what
does it what does it look and feel like
it looks and feels like everybody
working together towards a common goal
right we're not working against our
customers we're working with our
customers we're not working against each
other we're working with each other and
that is the
superpower that brings this whole story
together so it changes the the the the
behaviors of people in your organization
it changes the organizational culture it
changes the experience that both
employees and stakeholders have and it
changes the way that you measure success
in your business so everything will
change if you embark on this journey but
you'll have at the end of that Journey
at the end of that Journey it never ends
but once you've made some progress on
that Journey you will have a a a more
predictability in your business and a
higher ability to take advantage of
Market opportunities when they arise
because you're then able to deal with
surprises because you've got that level
of predictability