if you're doing caman and you aren't
limiting your work guess what you're not
doing caman it is a crucial element to
controlling your work in process to
understanding what's going on when in
your system and enabling you to see
what's going on limiting work allows you
to see when you have constraints in the
system um it enables you to allow people
to focus and what's necessary to deliver
the value and it's really really
important to delivering high quality
usable products because you have to
maintain that flow of work through the
system that's working at a sustainable
Pace limiting workin process is
absolutely crucial to having a cam band
board