hey welcome to naked agility I'm gonna
be doing my episode 5 leading agile
change webcast any questions you have
please send them on to me I don't
promise I'll answer them during this
session because I'm going to be busy
focusing on this but I have a Q&A
session on Tuesday where I will answer
any of those questions that I can I want
to do a little call out to my
professional agile leadership class that
is running on Monday this is a virtual
live virtual classroom we currently have
six people and we're going to be talking
about the the movement for management
from that that management traditional
management style over to leadership and
what that means today I'm going to talk
about a few things in this leadership
presentation so I want to talk about
what what the problem is and where it
comes from I want to talk about that
the who the what and the how and how we
can organize some of those things and
get them let's get started
naked agility is available for DevOps
and agile training and consulting
contact us for a free consultation
okay so the first thing to talk about a
little bit is um what the problem is and
really it's around that idea that things
have changed and not just because of the
current situation with kovat at 19 this
is something that has been happening
over the last 15 years the world has
been changing very quickly and firms
companies have been really struggling to
keep up with that floor some of that
floor has come from and that idea of the
expectation from users if you're in the
commercial world of delivering value to
them a little bit more quickly and some
of that has come from those users then
being in organizations and expecting
more from their employer whether that be
they want to bring their own device
rather than use the corporate device so
they want more freedom on the network
more freedom to do things inside of the
organization to have ideas and move
forward that's that's really what what
what that difference is companies today
need to be able to take advantage of
things that change in the market market
opportunities or difficulties like the
current situation and in months or weeks
instead of years and I think that's
something that you're seeing a lot of
companies struggling with now that move
to home working where maybe before they
were we're not going to do any sort of
home working and then struggling to to
really get that in working times have
changed
effectively and they've changed very
much in the last few weeks at so I'm
going to talk more than from kovat
perspective this is a presentation that
I did at M agile in Africa in 2017
for my good friend Nana and I thought it
would be a useful presentation in these
in these dire circumstances that we're
in so I'm gonna be focusing on product
and I'd like you to think about this
let's say we've got two two groups that
are building a product one group a group
a has a business plan they are well
established in the market they're well
funded and they hire the best people
okay that's that's one group the second
group B people are going to be working
for free we're not gonna pay the people
that are doing the work they're gonna do
it in their spare time
fire the goodness of their heart just
because they want to so which of these
do you think would be more likely to be
successful
if you're an additional mindset you're
gonna be gravitating very hard eh and
but II was in fact a large product
called in Carta Microsoft Encarta which
some of you may remember um and Group B
was Wikipedia and the thing that I find
that kind of funny is the Wikipedia
entry for Microsoft Encarta at Mike's of
Encarta was a digital multimedia
encyclopedia they just couldn't keep up
with the change they deployed their
application on a disk physical disk that
was sent out to your many physical disks
as it were and it was just impossible to
keep up with the change in the world and
Wikipedia and Wikipedia one because they
had the most up-to-date data but people
give up their time for free I'm
wondering if you can think of any other
companies that have really struggled and
maybe completely gone out of business
I was thinking maybe of Bob Buster
that's a very common one it was funny
the the blockbuster was represented in
the and what was the the the movie the
Captain Marvel movie you saw Helen
didn't have blockbuster at the start and
that's that's it's just it doesn't exist
anymore I think I seem to remember an
article where the blockbuster CEO said
he didn't believe that anybody would
want to stream movies and that was a
couple of years before Netflix came on
the scene I was also at Kodak for those
that don't know Kodak is still around
and they aren't doing really photography
and stuff anymore they're doing
blockchain because if you can't figure
out what to do and you got to reinvent
your business look Jane apparently but
Kodak the Kodak invented the digital
camera
more than 50 years ago they decided that
they would bury that technology in order
to protect their film business which was
the most profitable part of the business
so they buried a new innovation but the
problem is once something's discovered
it doesn't go away somebody else is
going to discover it again they're going
to go down the same routes and maybe
come up with a better product if you
don't get to market with the ideas that
you've got even if they're going to
disrupt your existing business then you
you you're going to run into problems
that annoying also really we have this
challenge we have a number of a number
of challenges that I'm going to talk
about and in the what the WHO and the
how but we have somebody with an idea
who creates who creates an idea I've got
something I want to go build something
problem I want to go solve and we go off
when we create a product and release it
to customers and then the either like it
or they hate it a good example of
customers not liking the thing that was
delivered was Windows 8 Windows 8 was
released and people there was a massive
expectations gap between the product and
what people perceived that they wanted
so max I've had to roll back a lot of
the changes that they made in Windows 8
and in the UI in order to appease some
very unhappy customers and to get higher
levels of adoption and that's
unfortunate it was a good product it
just had a mismatch between what people
want eaten and what they got so they got
a lot of negative feedback from
customers but you might also get
positive feedback so we have a number of
variables they want to look at in the
what WHO and the how and the first one
until the cat is the the challenges in
the what space
the idea that we have to decide what
we're going to build in detail up front
is definitely an old tailor istic
practice you should go read my are sorry
watch my video on how to detect a duel
[ __ ] and the tyranny of Taylorism
but in the what challenges fifty sorry
fifty sixty five percent of
functionality that you build it will not
be used by your customers this is data
is based on a report from the Standish
group in Boston they collect data on 70
odd thousand projects around the world
and the the averages are 65% you might
be better than that you might be a lot
worse than that
but that lack of focus on the the
strategy of the product and is what's
causing that rather than building things
that are strategically going to achieve
pieces of value for your customers a lot
of organizations are just building a
bunch of stuff without really
understanding that relationship between
that because we're used to those long
detailed elaborate product backlogs
where you you I go into organizations
all the time and this I say can you show
me your product backlog and they pop up
in the product backlog and those 5,000
things in the product backlog there's no
way that a product owner that somebody's
setting strategy and direction can even
remotely understand what's in there
which means they then have to have an
army of minions to spelunk
all of that data and figure out what
might be important but those people
looking at the the minions are going to
be surfacing all the things they think
is important which they might not have
as much information and
as the the product owner or as the the
person who is setting that strategic
goal so ultimately because we have these
big backlogs or a lot of organizations
have these big backlogs 35% of your
requirements are going to change over
the life of your project and that's just
reality 35% is going to change
so if 65% is not used 35% is going to
change that's not a really good picture
and some of that comes from not really
having a good description or definition
around the responsibilities of product
management what are they actually
supposed to do and also whether you have
somebody who is has the role of product
owner or you have that term in your
organization or not you have people in
your organization who are fully fiscally
accountable for delivering value based
on the money spent those folks I would
call product owners and but often that
accountability is delegated to people
who are weak or not authorized to be
able to make the decisions that they
need to make in order to live for your
organization to get a significant amount
of value from that and ultimately we
have this focus on project rather than
product I'm not saying that you can't
have a project you absolutely can but
the overall strategic focus should be on
delivering value in a product projects
are time limited very definition of
project and if you are as an individual
or accountable for delivering something
in a time limited fashion you're
interested in getting that thing done
but there might be choices that are made
during the life of that project that are
detrimental to the overall product and
it's very common for large
projects that are going to result in an
ongoing product or be added to an
existing product to result in
significant additional levels of
technical debt and additional levels of
complexity and really things that don't
need to be there part of that 65% of the
functionality not used we delivered that
functionality 65% of it wasn't used so
did we look back round figure out which
65% is not used and take those things
out and leaving stuff in your product
means you've got to support it maintain
it it's care and feeding you want to get
them out if you can and that idea of
those long long cycles many
organizations still deliver less than
once a year
organizations can be 2 or 3 years
between releases still for some large
organizations but large products but
many organizations are moving to quicker
delivery quickly delivery does not
necessarily mean once a quarter quicker
delivery in the the agile space is 30
days or less you should be delivering
your product into production at least
every 30 days in order to solve some of
those problems but that's not common in
the industry yet we're going to talk
about that so then we have some problems
around who is doing the work or the the
people problems who is going to be doing
the work and so having an effective
change transition management ie we've
got a bunch of things we're doing things
change things are different than we
expect how is that communicated across
the organization how do you make sure
that and when the the engineers are
actually doing the work can they find
out things are a little bit different
than they expected to be that's filtered
back to through the layers that you've
got in your organization to your
customer
then and also the resultant information
is then transitioned back the other way
organizations on average lose 50% of
their time for ineffective collaboration
and basically the the handoffs being
being very inefficient ineffective this
idea of servant leadership and I think
servant leadership is often
misunderstood and it's not about just
getting getting the coffee or doing
things for your team it's about creating
an environment within which your team
can be as effective and efficient as
possible
and that is often very lacking in
organizations that's why an effective
servant leadership there might be
servant leadership but is it actually
effective and then having a misalignment
of objectives are we going at all going
in the same direction and are we focused
on delivering the value that our
customers need in our product in order
to increase our market share in order to
deliver that value and that will give us
the thing we need and contributing to
that 50% of an effective communication
and is unimpaired scrum masters can they
can't they maybe know what they should
be doing but they can't do it those of
the organizational bureaucracy that is
there maybe they're ineffective in the
first place and a lot of complexity
around who makes the decisions how those
decisions are made how many stakeholders
have their finger in the pie is that
where to get things done so that's a big
who challenge losing 50% of our time for
for that kind of collaboration problem
the other other big area is how I'm
really the biggest issue in the whole
world is this thing that we call
technical debt technical debt isn't
always the best name to use it depends
who you're talking to and their
understanding of the world and of
finances I've worked with a number of
CFO's who have told me that technical
debt it's not the best thing you can
call it because ultimately technical
debt is not what sorry that is not all
bad we have mortgages we have loans for
cars
you might take a loan out to get your
your sofa and paid off over a couple of
years those are not necessarily bad
debts however all technical debt is bad
you'd be better at thinking of it as an
unhedged fund for those that are
technically monday minded you've got an
uninsured risk effectively in your
product you have risk in know no
mitigation and this can technical debt
can take lots of different forms and I
usually sum it up by saying anything
that is difficult or anything that is
manual are all of that is technical debt
but if you have any manual processes
between your your software coder
committing code to your repository to
getting that item into production then
you have technical debt that could be
manual testing that could be manual
environment provision provisioning
manual deployments manual anything
anything manual anything that's
difficult if you're wondering why it
takes so long for your engineers
get things done when maybe when your
product was was new and green it was
very easy to get things done it's
because there hasn't been enough care
taken about how things are written how
things look and how repeatable things
are can I go back and edit and
understand this part of the system
easily have I made changes to the system
to allow that to be easy easy easy to
read easy to understand easy to change
and the software will call that
refactoring refactoring is something
that should be going on all the time it
should not be an optional thing that
somebody decides to do or not it should
just be how we work just like if you
were going to release our press release
you were going to some big announcement
for your organization that was maybe a
little bit controversial or could be a
little bit controversial I'm are you
just going to write those things down
are you going to write that press
release and Shepherd Act you just gonna
email it to everybody I would hope not
you're probably going to reread that
thing make some changes to make it make
more sense you're maybe going to loop in
one of your colleagues and say is this
on message is this the thing I'm trying
to get across quit this be misunderstood
and then you're gonna go through some
more iterations and then maybe you'll
look pen at somebody else in your
organization look then somebody from
marketing loop in somebody from
engineering look and somebody from
contracts from legal from sale all of
those departments make sure it looks
like it says exactly what we want as an
organization to present and then we'll
release the press release so there was a
lot of refactoring there going back over
the things that we had done to make them
make them better make them easier to
read easier to understand same applies
to everything we do
so we talked about a lot of problems and
this results in a lot of loss so what
what does that look like if you crunch
the numbers a little bit
so I again I lasted this presentation in
Ghana in Africa and I have Canadian
cities as my currency there but you can
think of any you can put any currency in
in that space and the numbers meet the
same so if I have 500 cities pounds
dollars at whatever it is and I'm going
to invest that in my product I'm gonna
get my engineers to build something what
does that what does that look like well
if I lose thirty five percent for
building the right features yeah
so I sixty five percent of my features
are used little effort by my customers
and then thirty five percent are the
right features so we've spent a hundred
and seventy five cities pounds dollars
on delivering actual value if we lose
fifty percent for effective
communication and collaboration what
does what does that look like well 50%
of our 175 that we had at left is eighty
seven and a half so we get eighty seven
and a half pound cities or dollars and
then we spend thirty percent of our time
on average building new features there
see struggling with technical debt so
that's the complexities of the thing
that we've written the the difficulty in
understanding the thing that we've
written of the manual error-prone
process is that we've got results and we
are only able to spend about 30 percent
of our time adding value to our product
certainly percent every time cause just
struggling with complexity that's all
we're left with twenty six
and a quarter but 26 and a quarter and
out of our 500 so what does that look
like on $50,000 that looks like two
thousand six hundred and twenty-five
dollars and I'm not sure that's I've
violated return on investment and
anybody's eyes hopefully in your
business it's not and this is why the
business is concerned about the amount
of value that they get for their
investment in the software world and why
the software world is often considered a
cost center rather than a profit Center
which it should be we need to address
some of these things we need to change
these numbers in our favor and that can
be super difficult so I've got some
suggestions that are pretty hopefully
there they make sense for you the first
suggestion is around or suggestions are
around the what the value that we
delivered the first one is to try and
focus a little bit on product rather
than project so while you can have a
bunch of projects going on inside our
product and make sure that decisions are
made based on the outcomes and changes
in behavior you want your customers to
have rather than on delivering on a set
of items delivering on a set of items
does not necessarily provide value to
your customer focus on the value and
hopefully you can make some shift shift
those percentages so we spend more time
delivering the things that we really
needed last time working on things that
we our customers aren't going to
actually use
have a product owner have somebody with
full fiscal accountability or delivering
value in your product at the to be
accountable for maximizing value there
should be solely responsible for the
backlog so don't second-guess them you
might not like some of the decisions
that they make that's sometimes just the
way it is there they're thinking about
they're taking a bunch of information in
from market competitors what the board
wants what stakeholders want they have a
lot of information and they're making a
decision holistically for the best
result in the product based on that so
ultimately you can get an inadequate
return on investment maybe you want to
stop funding that project if you're not
getting the return on investment that
you're expecting maybe the pro toner
needs more teams to work against the
product you need a new product owner but
they need to be empowered to make
decisions about the product and nobody
else should be able to tell the
development team what to do effectively
a product owner hires the development
team the development team hires the
scrum master and that's that's the the
chain of hierarchy within the agile
world and specifically in scrum now
caveat everything I say with it has to
work within the context of your
organizational constraints you're going
to have you have a unique organization
that you work in you're going to have to
decide how you want this to work
depending on that organizational
constraint might be some things you
can't change but maybe there are things
that are inhibiting your team and your
organization's ability to adopt some of
these practices and those are maybe
things you want to address maybe you
need to bring HR into a discussion
around what what do we need to do
differently maybe you want to bring
sales and maybe you want to bring
contracts in make sure everybody's
involved in looking the outcomes you're
trying to achieve so don't think of
agility as
thing you're trying to achieve this is
you want to get specific strategic
outcomes for your business and how are
you going to work towards those
strategic outcomes and maybe these tools
are going to going to help you with that
because ultimately we do still have to
do planning and it it's important for
the business to understand where we are
where we're going how long we think
we're going to take to get there and
that needs to be okay
those are answers that we need to be
able to provide for the for the for the
business its how business gets done so
we have to be able to provide them but
we want to change the way we look at
those things this is from a
complimentary practice from the way
Microsoft is currently doing they're at
long-term vision and planning you can
use bits of this you could use all of it
you could use something else that's okay
this is just an example so here they've
got three week Sprint's this is for a
particular team there's your dev ops
team like Microsoft they do three week
Sprint's and then they plan over three
three Sprint's so that's nine weeks
planning they understand more or less
what it is they're going to be doing
over those nine weeks beyond that
they're not so sure but inside of those
nine weeks they have a reasonable
understanding and then they have this
seasoned model so six months seasoned
model you'll hear Microsoft talking
about the the fall and spring updates
from any of their products that's based
on this seasoned model so they have a
six month what are we trying to achieve
in those six months and then they have a
12 to 18 month strategy here are the
high level objectives that we're trying
to get to
then they'll reassess those on a 12 to
18 month basis reassess the features
they're going to deliver towards those
strategic objectives in a six month
cycle Andrea saw assess the individual
things they're going to add to the
product the implementation plan on that
three Sprint's three weeks basis so
ultimately in their world the team is
responsible for the detail so the the
scrum team which includes the product
owner for that for that team and are
responsible for the Sprint the plan and
a good way into the season what are we
actually going to do what are we going
to implement in the product and what are
the the things we're going to go build
but leadership is responsible for
setting strategic direction to make sure
that we're all going in the same
direction they need to set that and
decide what what are we what are we
investing in where are we spending our
money holistically ultimately we need to
shorten as much of our feedback loops as
possible and the quicker we know we're
building the wrong thing the quicker we
can stop building the wrong thing and
build the right thing the worker we can
find out that something that we are
going to build is right or wrong or
needs to go in a different direction the
better so we want to be able to get into
that loop of delivering as quickly as
possible and this particular group this
team delivers to production every three
weeks so every single sprint goes to
production so they're able to get the
output of the work they just did in the
current three weeks in front of the
customer during those three weeks they
actually do continuous delivery and and
then get feedback from them right away
as soon as users are able to use that so
we want to shorten those feedback loops
by shortening the time to market in
order to really
understand how those things are
happening you want to be able to get an
understanding of what's going on in
these four areas the specific metrics
that you measure are going to be up to
you but you want to make sure that
you're looking and at what's your
organizational capability and how do we
improve that so the first part is time
to market obviously how quickly we're
getting our product out to our users and
we might have a bunch of metrics that
we're going to monitor those metrics are
going to change over time as we get
better some metrics become less
meaningful if we're in continuous
delivery how quickly we delivered the
customers maybe become such a small
number that it doesn't matter anymore we
also want to look at our ability to
innovate and in our ability to innovate
we're looking at are struggling with
complexity there sees new features in
production our ability to add stuff to
our product baracy struggling with
complexity sets our organizational
capability and then we also want to look
at the the market we want to look at the
current value that we're delivering how
do we know that the things that we're
creating are providing value to our
customers how do we assess that value
and increase work to increase that value
that's one thing
Abaddon's you've also got unrealized
value that's effectively opportunities
you either weren't able to go after or
or didn't didn't know about didn't know
about one's a little bit difficult to
measure but the unrealized value is
important to balance out at that picture
of what's happening in the future
so increasing value and in the what
space is all about product not project
although projects may be going on and
one decision-maker called the product
owner you can call them whatever you
want the rule is the product owner
regular planning and realignment so
instead of having a long term plan have
much shorter plans usually three to nine
weeks and have them cycle through I am
most the most common cadence I've seen
for that realignment of planning is two
weeks sprint of two weeks is this is the
normal now it used to be 30 days a month
us what the scrum guy talks about part
of that is because technology has
changed over the last 20 years that
scrum has been around 20 years ago it
was really hard to ship your product to
production on a continuous basis today
it's easy to ship your product to
production on a continuous basis and I
teach a class called the professional
scrum foundations class in the
professional scrum foundations class and
the team's this class is designed for
for everybody in your organization but
you need at least one software engineer
per team per team of five so one in five
people in the class is a software
engineer you can do it and and we build
software in the class and I have had a
team do a 30-minute sprint and at the
end of that sprint they've set up source
control they've set up a continuous
delivery automated build they've got
that automated build feed into a
deployment pipeline and they've got the
deployment pipeline deploy the
application out to a production place
where anybody can access it and and they
did that in 30 minutes as well as
creating product and that was a team of
five think what that team could do in
two weeks if they could do that in 30
minutes
so being able to get as early feedback
from customers as possible and and
measure the value rather than activity
so don't measure how long people spend
per day doing the particular tasks it is
completely meaningless it's about the
value that you get for your users a good
example of that is that same team that
I've been talking about and this is
features delivered per year with the
azure DevOps team which was the TFS team
at Microsoft and in 2012 they were
delivering 22 features to production
each year they spent a lot of time
reorganizing themselves paying back 10
technical debt moving to a three-week
cadence for the dalish to production
every three weeks and over the next
what's that in the in the graph six
years there they're still going in that
model bits from 2012 to 2017 they ended
up moving from 22 features to production
each year to 260 plus features to
production each year most of that paying
back technical debt lack increase
collaboration so we remove that 50% and
spend time working on the right features
rather than the wrong features you can
get these optimizations as well if
you're willing to change your
organization change the way you do
things in order to get there so what
about the the who the culture in the
organization we need to change a lot of
other things to make it work and really
it's that flipping it on its head that
you you you hear about a lot rather than
customers being at the bottom and the
CEO being at the top and you customers
are around the outside and you have
delivery teams delivering value to those
customers on a continuous basis and with
CEO online of business leaders setting
strategic direction at that level as the
modern digital organization
is based around that idea of we have a
cross-functional delivery teams across
our organization continuously delivering
value to our users and we're getting
feedback and adapting that idea one
thing to note is that is that culture
eats your strategy for breakfast
whatever whatever that strategy is it is
your people and that will both make it
happen and get in the way of making it
happen so we have to bring bring them
along we have to make sure that we cater
for the needs of people they are not
resources that's traditional terroristic
thinking where most modern management
practices were designed around managing
factory workers Industrial Revolution
and factory workers is a whole different
ballgame from knowledge workers so
there's a really good book by a
gentleman called Dan pink called drive
and it's about moving away from the
carrot and the stick
towards something a little bit more
modern so carrot and the stick really
only talks about extrinsic motivations
motivations from the outside so if you
as an individual do not have enough
money to feed your family you're
struggling to feed your family put a
roof over your head the only thing that
matters to you is solving those problems
and that's going to be more money
however once and I hope all of your
knowledge workers are in this category
and once you're not struggling to put
food on the table motivation changes to
intrinsic motivations and those
intrinsic motivations are autonomy
mastery and purpose and autonomy is
being in charge of your own destiny you
decide
what you work on when and how mastery is
about being good at what you do most
people in knowledge working space want
to learn more do more be more capable
and better over time and have a purpose
so they want to feel like the things
that they do actually matter but we have
to have a balance there and you got a
balance autonomy an alignment if you
have too much alignment you're going to
stifle the innovation of these smart
people that you've hired to go do the
work
if you have too much bureaucracy in your
organization then they can't go solve
problems and interesting and innovative
ways that will get you to market quicker
but if we have too much autonomy then
you end up with a bunch of people going
in different directions so you need to
find that balance inside your
organization you need to figure out
maybe where you are right now where you
would like to be take one step in the
direction you would like to go see where
you get to and inspect and adapt those
changes to your organization as well
make a change see if it worked
getting those changes in front of people
they don't have to be perfect you just
have to try stuff see if it works and we
need to try and shift shift the needle
from management over to leadership
rather than talking about deadlines and
timelines and project plans we should be
talking about a flow of value getting to
our customers because the deadlines
don't really matter you might have
deadlines that do matter you might be in
a regulated industry you might have to
meet legal requirements those are
constraints that are out with the bounds
of this conversation I can't help you
fix those they were just things that
happen you might have FDA regulations
you might have whatever but within the
bounds of your organizational
constraints how far can you go towards
folks
on product owners on floor and on value
how far can you go you want to get as
close to that as you can and instead of
having providing people with answers
again a tailor istic management practice
because people don't need to think if
they're doing monotonous factory work we
want to enable our self-organization
with our scrum teams so they get that
autonomy they feel like they're in
charge of their own destiny so these are
some changes that we want to move away
from towards those from management
towards leadership and in order to do
that it's important to establish Scott
strong scrum mastery inside your
organization there is I feel that
there's a very tight relationship
between a scrum master and a leader
inside your organization they have some
of the same roles and accountabilities
they're just maybe operating at
different levels inside the organization
so a scrum master can the role of scrum
master again it's not the up title the
role of scrum master can operate at any
level they can be a change agent for
your organization they can be a coach to
individuals and they it can be a new
management role but it should never be a
servant or moderator for teams that's
not the role of the scrum master you're
hiring smart clever resourceful people
take advantage of that
that's this that's really where you want
to get to in order to achieve that scrum
masters Cana and we talk about in the
agile community this is from the agile
coaching competency framework that they
had your floating Institute and the many
stances of a scrum master and so if
you're a lean agile practitioner you
understand the foundations of agile you
understand the foundations of lean and
you figure out how best to use some of
those techniques in your organization
and you're going to need certain skills
depending on which level you're focusing
at depending on the size your
organization as well may be constrained
but you need some level of technical
mastery so that you can help teams be
able to do do this thing this DevOps
thing do a continuous delivery do
feature flags hiders how do those things
work and how do we encourage our teams
towards those models how do we encourage
them towards doing TDD and having code
reviews and doing all the things they
need to do we need your masters need
some level of business mastery how are
they possibly going to be able to help
the the product to owner become a better
product owner if they don't have some
level of business mastery so you'll find
that many agile leaders have that
business mastery already what about
organizational transformational mastery
if we're going to make changes to our
organization we're gonna try and get
better at delivering remove bureaucracy
in order to actually get things done and
how do we do that how do we make those
changes at the organizational level
these are these are all important
questions there's no right answers I
would recommend looking at the agile
coaching Institute's classes and courses
and seeing what you can do there you can
also take the professional scrum master
class where we talk about and introduce
some of these things or the advanced
master class from scrambler dark where
we talk about liberating structures and
how we can organize people around
getting the best most is the wrong word
getting getting the most effective
outcomes from groups of people
facilitating that a much higher level
and it's a very powerful powerful class
so professionalism the how what are we
going to talk about here so um there's
an interesting misunderstanding that and
everybody on a scrum team has to be
cross-functional that's where this well
this is where I believe this magic
unicorn of the full stack developer that
came from and these people that are
cross cross functional but they seem to
be a suicide me knife they are actually
very rare many people will say they're a
full stack developer and they're they're
not they're actually just a generalist
they might have deep specialism in one
two maybe three areas but they're a
generalist my background and expertise I
was a software developer for ten years
then I moved into the DevOps space with
TFS and as your DevOps and I helped
customers optimize their their processes
for many years and I moved very quickly
towards that process agile scrum lean
Kanban all of those things as well
that's my expertise my expertise is not
in testing however I have taught testis
I have a general enough knowledge in
testing on what tests mastery should
look like in order to go help and coach
a group of people around getting better
at testing they are going to be the
experts I'm definitely not going to be
an expert in that
but I can help them move towards getting
them also fit so I can be a generalist I
can do testing I just am NOT an expert I
can do DevOps I am an expert I can do
documentation writing oh maybe I'm okay
at document writing we all have lots of
different skills if you look at a
Harvard Business Review article from
1986 called the new new product
development game it talks about all of
the research that was done to figure out
that a team of generalists will almost
always outperform individual specialists
because that now my dear that somebody
smart comes up with yes debunked by
somebody else you have somebody to
bounce your ideas off you know that
thing where you have a problem you can't
figure it out you go talk to somebody
who maybe has no idea what your problem
is but in talking it through you figure
it out they helped you figure it out if
you have a bunch of smart people
together you can surf ideas you can
figure out the nuances of those things
bring those different backgrounds
together Microsoft I think has done
white paper on how much diversity is
important and the outcome that I
understand is that the more diverse a
team the better and that was race
religion culture
background everything technology the
more diverse the people in a team the
more are the better the outcomes that
the team has so in that vein the old way
was that and again this is the tailor
istic practice from factory workers
we're gonna have a management team we're
gonna have a development team and we're
going to have test team and we're gonna
make sure that they don't talk to each
other and that the the you know just
send bugs back and forth or instructions
that really doesn't work
so these your DevOps team at Microsoft
move very quickly at the start they made
a lot of mistakes in this process don't
get me wrong but they got a lot of
learnings as well because by making
mistakes we learn things and they move
to a single engineering in fact they
also pulled in other roles as well like
service delivery UX UE all of those
things coming into at one place and then
they created teams our own server or I
have delivery teams around people from
engineering paired with somebody from
program management so that you get that
holistic strategic direction plus smart
ideas for for doing and delivering on
the work so bring them together but you
still when you move away from that idea
of having M core I'm just looking at
test and you move towards having a
cross-functional team and you maybe
start to lose some of that expertise
that testers can share with each other
when they're sitting together in the
same department now there are on lots of
different teams so the way we tend to
handle that is with communities of
practice and it's kind of like a user
group you know if you want to meet up
you'll find it by
user groups you can go to the Knitting
user group how do you make sure that you
share knowledge inside your organization
run internal user groups on whatever
topics make sense I would expect
communities of practice around
architecture in order to make sure that
the the teams are understand why
architecture is important rather than
telling them how to do their
architecture educate them on what good
architecture looks like same for
security same for tests same for coding
that same for any of the practices that
need to happen inside and around the
team so they can share share that
knowledge so for this particular team at
Microsoft you might be asking well what
changed with just the things that I
talked about things that changed or did
more things change well really
everything changed for this team they
moved from delivering software they were
actually on a two-year cadence with a
service pack halfway for many many years
and that built up a lot of technical
debt because you generally didn't go
back and change the same thing over and
over again on an iterative basis as you
learned more from the customer it was
more fire-and-forget and lots of bugs I
think at one point they had tens of
thousands of reported bugs in the system
and it got too much they were struggling
under the same complexities that
everybody else struggles under even
though their main business seems like
its building software Microsoft's main
business is not building software they
do what everybody else does they build
software to support their main business
productivity tools whatever whatever
that that is so in order to move forward
you need to create professional teams
they need to be empowered delivery teams
that are able to take ideas that people
have
turn them interval into increments of
usable software things that people can
actually use shorten those feedback
loops and reduce the technical debt
maintain communities of practice and
measure the outcomes don't just assume
that the features you build are going to
be useful to your customers make sure
they're going to be useful to your
customers so if I was to have some
takeaways have product owners with clear
ownership that maximize value to your
customers and create professional teams
that embody technical excellence and I
can't stress at technical excellence
more and is really really important and
have strong scrum masters that are
empowered to be organizational change
agents that are not going to accept the
status quo that are always going to be
pushing on those things that maybe we
can't change right now but we should be
changing in the future how do we bring
HR into that story how do we how do we
do that so I talked about three well
really four areas I I described the
problem that we have where we're losing
a lot of time where we're losing a lot
of resource where we lose hemorrhaging
money all over the place in engineering
and software development at the moment
and we talked about where those problems
are coming from at the who the what and
the how and I'm in each of those areas
we talked about some of the things you
can do to try and reduce the level of
waste in those areas and improve the
situation even small improvements even
if you made a 1% improvement think of
the budget in your organization and what
does 1% mean to your business even 1%
can be important so don't think about
I need to change everything think about
what's the first thing that you need to
do to try and improve things do that see
how you get on okay so let me see if
there are any questions if there wasn't
I don't see any questions that doesn't
mean there wasn't any questions I know
that there was some questions to my Q&A
last time that didn't pop into my thing
uh but please feel free to contact me if
you need anything um I'm available on my
website
nikki agility comm and KD agility comm
there's my email my phone number and my
twitter you can contact me anywhere you
would like cool so there we go but the
one I want no that's the one I want so
hopefully that was useful and I hope to
see some of you at the Q&A on Tuesdays
okay thank you very much naked agility
is available for DevOps and agile
training and consultant
contact us for a free consultation
you