so the question is why is the PSP all a
great fit
um for the eight week immersive learning
experience and I think it's a great fit
because they're even more than
I think even more than all of the other
classes there's a huge disconnect
between how we teach and explain the
breadth of what the product owner is and
does
and people are actually trying to do it
in their organizations
um we're we're talking about the product
owner as a an agile product manager
right so it's still product management
all the tools and techniques of product
management but then we're bringing in
this idea of the product owner moving
from a scribe right that's the the the
the lowest form of product owner through
a journey towards
um mini CEO or entrepreneur of that that
product
like they're they're the top of that
product totem they totally own the
product full fiscal and uh commercial
accountability for this this product
within within your their organization
and then they're able to uh focus on
other things that maybe they didn't have
access to at a different level so things
like how do you bring in marketing how
do you bring in sales how do you bring
in contracts right if you've got to
write contracts with customers the
product owner needs to be involved in
that because how you write the contract
matters to how you actually deliver the
work and they're in control effectively
delivering the work or deciding what
order we're going to do things in right
so
that that immersive class allows us to
create better connections but between
those activities that we're going to
talk about in the class and the the the
the the stuff that they need to do in
their organization and perhaps how they
have conversations about how they do do
that stuff right how do they if they
can't directly
um control that thing which is quite
often the case right if you're in a
bigger organization the chances of you
controlling branding and marketing it's
probably pretty low right but
perhaps you could influence it maybe you
can be part of those conversations that
then your voice becomes respected at
that table as well so that
they're going to be more involving you
looking at you would you think as well
because you've had some great Insight on
that topic and you need to be credible
in all of those spaces you need to be
credible in in that conversation about
legal and the conversation about
marketing contracts all of those things
so that you can have that engagement and
this
iterative and incremental immersive
experience is going to help you bring
empiricism into that story right you we
can we can talk about stuff we can talk
about stuff till we're blue in the face
but you can go actually try that thing
in your organization and then come back
and say well that didn't work
right then we can have a conversation as
a group which is great because you'll
have a bunch of product owners there
right who've all tried the same thing
right they've all gone off and tried the
same activity in their organization or
different parts of the same organization
and they can come back with help and
advice they can provide the help and
advice I tried it my organization is
also a bank right or the same bank and
we were able to do this because we had
this conversation with our compliance
director and they were able to say yes
we can do it that way that's different
from the way we were doing it before
oh awesome I'll go have that
conversation with my compliance person
and see if we can't come to the same
conclusion right that that sharing and
collaborating of ideas is is going to be
exponentially increased as part of the
immersive learning experience for the
the product owner
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility