oh that's great so that what is my
feeling on creating agile
apprenticeships I think it's going to be
the logical progression of the of of of
the immersive story as well
um and I feel like I do some of those
things already I have a number of uh
people that have come through my
training classes that's kind of how I
got introduced to them
that then then just keep hanging out
right that's that's uh um I don't I
don't
um how best to describe it like I I've
always at least for a very long time I
provided this capability for for
students for anybody on the internet
just to book a coffee with me right or
or uh uh a free consultation right
whatever you want to call it freak on
stage that cost 30 minutes and but also
for every training class for every
student
and they get an extra 60 Minutes of
Consulting time right and I think that
that lots of students don't use it I
think I worked it out the other day I
looked at the the the the data and it
was about less than five percent of
people that come through the classes
actually used the one hour of of of
coaching Consulting so when uh for
example Rickard who's who's who's a
scrum master and when he comes back and
says can I get another error or can I
get another error or he phones me in the
evening to talk about the cool stuff
that he's been doing in in the office
and how it's impacted on his team and to
ask some questions and what do you think
might be better or
um you know even just he's he's he's
telling me about his awesome day right
that that
interaction for me is hugely valuable
because records the getting more value
providing more value to his company to
his organization because he's able to
you know maybe serve some extra
information or even just chat you know
sometimes sometimes you just need to
chat with somebody who might even not
know anything about what you're talking
about right but can provide you with a
sounding board and if it's somebody that
and that that's that that
um internship idea right or
um that that ability for those scrum
Masters to have somebody that they can
come and talk to to say well I tried
this and it didn't work out what am I
doing wrong and it might be well you're
not doing anything wrong right that
could be the biggest value that they get
from that conversation you're not doing
anything wrong that's just the way it
works here's something else you might
want to try
so I think that
um mentoring internship
um model I think is is really important
to people's learning and I expect that
off the iterative the the the the
immersive
um type of training that there'll be a
lot more of that uh type of experience
for people and people wanting more of
that experience so I'm actually really
looking forward to that because I love
uh having a chat and finding out how
people are actually using the things
that we're talking about
um and being successful at it because so
many times
um companies that call me in to help are
only calling me into help when things
aren't going so well for them
so I don't see a lot of the successes
right because with the time those
successes are generated I'm already off
to the doing the next thing or working
for the next company and they're
implementing the ideas but being able to
have those follow-on conversations where
somebody's actually implementing some of
those ideas trying stuff out it's just
just awesome
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility