one of the main ways to mess up the
implementation of your your cand
strategy and not get the value that
you're expecting IE we're doing better
than we were before is to is to not look
at the data right I I I see this in in
in team after team uh they say they're
doing
caman but all they have is a board with
some
columns they don't have any whip limit
um and that's it they just have a board
with some columns and they call it caman
I'm sorry to say but that is definitely
not enough to be uh Canan Canan strategy
right it's just not enough uh one of the
key things that they they miss out is is
not looking at the data or using vanity
metrics oh my goodness me the vanity
metrics coming up my ears uh uh story
points velocity uh burnd Downs W get rid
of all that crap it's terrible it's not
going to help you maximize the flow of
value for your customers it's not going
to help you um see what's going on
enough to be able to ask more
interesting questions that allow you to
change your process in order to optimize
it those metrics are not absolutely
absolutely not uh not good enough in
that story uh there are there are there
are four key metrics in cat
that you should be looking at um they're
all fairly straightforward easy to
collect most of us are using digital
tools today um so you you effectively
only need one piece of data well
technically two pieces of data for each
piece of work that flows through your
system um the date and time when it
started and the date and time when it
finished that's it those two pieces of
data if you're using jira if you're
using Azure devops if you're using
Trello all of that data is collected for
you it's in there and you just need to
render it in a way that makes sense
so if it's started but not finished it's
part of your working process right
that's your whip right if it's started
uh but not finished you can also see how
old it is how long's it been sitting
there that's work item age um if it's
finished if it's crossed that Finish
Line you know uh how many items you've
delivered per unit of time right so over
each 30-day period how many items do we
deliver there you go we've got that
number by by just by virtue of that end
date and if you have the start date and
the end date you also have the cycle
time right how long it actually took uh
to deliver each of those items and then
you can do a bunch of math which is
pretty standardized um you can go or
look at a bunch of pieces of information
in that but without that
data you can't see what's going on right
transparency
inspection and adaption where's the
transparency if you don't have the data
or you decide to look at vanity metrics
or metrics that don't actually provide
you with anything actionable that's the
key it is the data what are you doing
with the data you're looking at how you
changing the way you work based on the
outcome of that data if you're not
you're either not doing it or you're not
looking at the right data because the
data is not telling you something that
helps you
change stop looking at back data as part
of your cband strategy stop looking at
vanity metrics and improve your process
if you're struggling to implement a
cband strategy we can help or help you
find somebody who can click on the link
below and get in touch