how does a scrum master or agile coach
motivate a scrum team
I don't know is that their job
I think it's part of their job I mean
the the the
[Music]
accountability of the scrum Master is
the effectiveness of the team how are we
as effective as possible and sad unhappy
people doing work are definitely not
effective if people don't care about the
work that they're they're doing if they
don't feel an empathetic connection to
the product an empathetic connection to
this to the stakeholders or the
customers then you're not going to get
great products that's where great
products come from
so if a team is eminently demotivated
you've got to figure out a way to to to
get some mojo back into that team
um so that they can move forward a
really common thing that I I see is the
reason why teams get demotivated
um is we're building the wrong thing and
nobody turns up at the Sprint review
right that's one if even the I I had I
worked with a team in in Norway and the
product owner didn't even bother to turn
up for the Sprint review so why would
the team
care about what it is they're building
if even the product owner doesn't care
about what it is that they're building
right that's that's that's really
powerful message there
um but
quite often it's because of the Sprint
goal
um because teams tend to create Sprint
goals that Encompass the entire Sprint
right so this you need the entire 10
days and a two-week Sprint 10 days to go
well in order to achieve the Sprint goal
or
um you've got a Sprint goal that's
complete these 10 things right that's
also that one or these three features
that's the other one that I see as well
right they're they're all [ __ ] sprinkles
because what what happens is the chances
of success are smaller
and I don't know about you but if I say
to my customers I'm going to do this and
then I have to listen to them complain
about how I didn't manage to do that for
whatever reason I'm not a happy team and
if you do that Sprint on Sprint on
Sprint on Sprint why would you think you
the outcome would be anything else other
than a demotivated unhappy uh team that
isn't able to to deliver working product
so
figuring out that the Sprint goal
doesn't have to be your whole Sprint
right and if you've got three important
things you're working on pick one what's
the most important what's the not even
what's the most important thing for the
product right that for your Sprint goal
what's the most important thing for your
stakeholders at Sprint review right what
do they care about that's
your sprinkle it might only be 20 of the
work you're going to do in the Sprint
that's your sprinkle that's what you're
committing to show them at the end of
that Sprint everything else then
effectively becomes optional that's your
your buffer zone but you're gonna do as
much as you can of that other stuff that
needs to happen
right it could be long-term
architectural changes are happening it
could be two other features that you're
working on in the product
um and and but reduce the size of that
Sprint goal so that you have more chance
of being successful at the end of the
Sprint and if you're successful into the
Sprint it'll add a little bit of
happiness to your team you know we were
able to be successful we did something
we provided it if you focused on
something that's of value to your
customers then the customers are like oh
great job team right this is awesome
we've this is exactly what we want and
here's how we want you to just because
they're engaging right so the team sees
people that care about what the work
that they're doing engaging with them
and that builds that motivation
um so if you really goes back to Dan
Pink's book drive right autonomy Mastery
and purpose
right hey that that purpose piece if you
don't have purpose it all falls apart
um so it makes sure that your your team
um understands how their work helps
other people and have those other people
part of that Sprint review so that they
can tell the team that yeah this is
great it's helping us we've solved this
problem we've solved that problem here's
the next thing we need to work on and
you'll start to build that motivation in
the team
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility