very giving you trouble
ah
[Music]
Russell is a bike it is most he is back
awesome yeah i and better than anything
it was I Internet and my whole home
network brushed I believe because I'm on
a cabled connection here oh no just
it totally disappeared but we are back
Wi-Fi went as well everything went I
don't know what happened maybe I'll have
to reboot there
well I think I think we were much coming
close there was anything you wanted to
add what what the things that we could
do differently us
I think that police technology
mr. Burke
wanted
so those a bit of a disadvantage but I
think there's some other ways that we
can technology because connected in ways
that we aren't in a live class same room
but I can't flip out a video I can't
whip out a website and expose it to
everyone
quite as quickly as I can in the live
virtual class so I think that I'm going
to take more advantage of that to to
increase the value that the students get
that candidly they that's one area that
we can that we can offer students that
in ways that isn't quite the same as a
live class for instance I'm in front of
the class but if my laptop is behind me
then if I want to show a video or an
image then it's a bit of a I have to
walk back and then touch my machine and
because I'm not but I'm teaching in
front of a class I'm in front of a
whiteboard or a flipchart or you know in
the back of the room and I'm not hands
on keyboard all the time so one of the
things that I think I'll do it and to
make it better is to try to leverage
that technology to improve the
experience for the students I totally
agree and I tried my best to have
Oh oh you did know don't get me wrong I
just think that that there's if you
think about strength finders right like
what are what is the strength of the
medium well we can double down on the
strength of the medium yeah I was
actually thinking about how we talked
about a bit Marquette's video and we
talked about some other things maybe
there's a way we can and that that
content when it becomes the streaming
software I used sends me an email when
the stream is finished
been able to cut the slack
now what were you saying there because
you lost
was simply saying that what I was saying
when we got cut off but after after I
didn't hear you I added that there's
probably some some things that came up
contextually during the course that that
had I anticipated and I think well you
know now that I've experienced them this
is my first live virtual pal II class
and so now that I in stit I think I have
an opportunity to have some things in my
hip pocket that I didn't never had the
opportunity to utilize in an in-person
class and so that's what I'm trying to
do next
next time I participate in a pally in a
live virtual training circumstance yes
yes disadvantages there's some strong
advantages to lack of having to travel
right lack of having to have physical
contact with people that candidly you
don't know if they're well or not there
are some travel expenses that people
often incur to take training and so I
think that that as as people begin to
hear experiences of other students
they're going to realize that that
although we love the live training
there's some in my opinion there's in my
experience there's some significant
advantages that aren't always obvious to
people who haven't ever experienced it
before that makes sense it does and I
think we're running up against at flakes
be honest I'm just saying I think we're
running up against that every season
7:00 p.m. and UK 8 p.m. in Europe and
everybody you mean oh I think which
probably there hopefully will be able to
do their class together as well oh well
I will hopefully work with you again
okay
look forward to it Martin naked agility
is available for DevOps and agile
training and consulting contact us for a
free consultation