one of the reasons I love the immersive
learning experience for students is the
fact that they don't get
indigestion there are a lot of things
that we talk about during the classes
quite often people talk about drinking
from the fire hose um but if you if you
actually imagine a fire hose hitting
somebody they get knocked off their feet
and that's sometimes what it feels like
with the amount of information in the
very short space of time um that we have
generally for the 2-day classes so what
I love about the immersive classes is
that there's there's less indigestion
there's more bite-sized pieces and you
get time to chew