oh that's a good question how how will a
psm2 class
help a scrum Master progress on their
career
I think the thing we tackle in the PSM
to
or the the the advanced PSM is
the things
we try and tackle a lot of the things
all right how do I explain this Croft I
think Croft is a great word for this
right when you do things for long enough
Croft builds up all the things that are
are holding you back like the Barnacles
on a ship right they're they're making
it slower it's less effective it's it's
less sleek and the psm2 is about
scraping those Barnacles off so that you
can go go win the race so you can be
more effective because we we pick up all
sorts of weird weird things that we we
it's the way we work right our ways of
working get
indoctrinated into the company's way of
working right and sometimes we're forced
at certain points in our career or in
doing stuff to make compromises
and those compromises work great in that
space But then they become enshrined in
the way we do things our craft right we
adopt some of that craft and we need a
little bit of a reset to figure out what
is and isn't uh the ship and what is uh
the bit we can get rid of right if I'm
back to the Barnacle analogy so
um the the PSM is about removing the
Barnacles from the ship that's really
what it's about it's about identifying
those those things that you find that
scrum Masters get pushed towards in
organizations because perhaps when they
were starting out as a scrum Master they
didn't have the the the the confidence
to say no or the confidence to correct
leadership or the confidence to
challenge leadership and say no we need
to do things a little bit different to
be more effective and and then that that
that craft gets just added to our
baggage so it's really uh
um
that that
differentiation of again what does a
professional scrum Master look like here
are a bunch of things that we've learned
how to do
um
and then bring it bring it towards and
what we do want people to do as a as a
scrum master and I think it also there's
lots of people who are scrum Masters who
um perhaps scrum Masters for quite some
time and have had no formal training
right they've they've they've not had
any experience whatsoever of uh um
exposure to to maybe they might not even
have ever read the scrum guide right
that's that's that's quite I have met
those those folks as well
um and they've been doing it but they've
been doing the role they've been picking
up the accountability they've been doing
uh the things in the organization and
they don't want to go do a scrum master
class because they're like well I know
how to be a scrum Master right they
don't but I don't know how to be a scrum
master and
um perhaps the advanced scrum Master is
a good way to to to level set a lot a
lot of those
um myths and that's something that we do
do at the beginning of the the PSN to
the advanced Grandmaster classes and we
we kind of try and kick some of those uh
common myths that you see people
fulfilling as a scrum master and reset
very quickly like at the start of the
class is a quick quick reset to here's
what it should look like like and then
based on it what it should look like
what are a whole bunch of I don't know
skills uh workshops activities that you
could run with your teams which is I
feel like that's what the the advanced
scrum Master really teaches is it's got
that short sharp level set at the
beginning and then it goes into a
teaching through experience right
through participation teaching different
techniques so we teach a whole bunch of
different liberating structures to help
not you know make getting a bunch of
people together suck less because it
generally sucks in organizations how to
uh different uh things to go look at
right so so how do you help the team
understand and improve their definition
of done well there's little little
workshops and things that people can
take away and do that which is why I
think at the end of the class there's
like is there 30 posters 20 between 20
and 30 posters a big infographics that
you can uh takeaway to maybe leverage
with teams and help help then help
you've become a more effective scrum
Master how do I as a more effective
scrum Master than help my team be more
effective as well so there's kind of two
sides to it
um there's the the craft that we've
built up doing the role even if we wear
a professional scrum Master right we
passed our PSM psm1 like five years ago
or even 10 years ago or uh 13 years ago
like myself
um and we've built up some some some
some crafts and Barnacles that get stuck
to the hollow we need to knock them off
or we never had any formal training at
all and we've been doing doing the
accountability trying to do the
accountability of the scrum master and
perhaps we've learned from other
people's like we've adopted other
people's Barnacles onto our way of doing
things and we need that that that level
set and then what are the tools and
techniques we need
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility