so the idea of the presentation is to
show you where we stand today our
investigation regarding how we would
like to break out the that get the
biggest of the collections and our
concerns about migrating to a source and
things that we would like to clarify
with you yeah so whatever it is that
refers that to be scenario is the idea
that we have this huge collection that
we want to break down in order to
provide access to different teams and
have the rights elated environment so as
it is right now it's a bit of a huge
strain if we have one project collection
that has multiple repositories multiple
branches they contain implementation of
the core product functionality as well
as customizations that are project
specific so what we want to achieve is
let's say separate these two and have
the product component in a separate
project and it's project specific
implementation in its separate one so
instead of having to implement the
security restrictions within the same
project in the collection break out this
huge project into something like let's
say this having its own repositories its
own pipelines its own teams its own
administrative team who is going to
define which members of which team is
going to have access to what and since
we are going to be migrating let's say -
as well we have the common project
template with the work item templates
that have the additions and the
customization that we have and build
agents that are going to support the
field pipelines on its project that are
going to be a topic for the next slides
as we go on
so we have a couple of things that we
would like to check one thing is that we
need to migrate from this cluster of
repositories that it is right now into
different projects and repositories of
their own and keeping the history I saw
that we could move associated work items
from the pool to different repositioned
projects but we had to use the analytics
feature which I couldn't quite get to be
working yet and when we have to migrate
it to Azure DevOps services online we
would like to have an inside of whatever
restrictions they may apply for example
I found that known as the web service
there is a hard limit of 300 projects
where organizations with organization
for the rest released in our case is the
project collection as yep Eric now
so one thing we have to consider is this
maybe there are others but that I
haven't found out yet so for example as
I said we have a custom process template
that we have set up that's based on the
scrammed
so it has epics and PBIS and so on while
we have done so far is that we have
changed the work item templates added
new fields or changes in the form layout
or the workflow we have incorporated
steps of our own very same change in the
XML for the requirement category I guess
this is for it to be shown and treated
for the bugs to be treated as tasks in
the in the backlogs the process
configuration XML I have seen that there
are changes compared to the described
template as it comes out of the box and
we are using custom global lists that we
used to populate set and drop-down
fields and are in our form templates
so what we need to consider when we are
going to separate this huge collection
is for example that's a hosted XML
process will have to be the basis as we
create it's a project we do not have to
have common fields and the workflow is
going to be common and we have to check
whatever limitations there are for the
globalists for example I saw there were
limitations on the number of items you
can have on a list in the polar project
collection the number of lists you have
in a project collection and when we are
migrating to a zoo there are things that
we would like to clarify concerning to
the existing restrictions to existing
customization I ran across documentation
for migration tool that was describing
some limitations in the number of fields
you can have per collection it was
something like a thousand something yep
but I wanted to clarify for example if
these are unique reference names in the
XML for example or they it's time you
deploy a new project that is based on
the process templates you are adding to
this pool the unique reference names so
it's unique reference names I also came
across the fact that we salute the
Bobson you have the the concept of a
migrated inherited process template so
it's all the rest of the guys it's
something like keeping the scram
template which is the out-of-the-box you
have been injured at one with us your
customizations and it's time you deploy
a new project you say it's based on the
inherited and the obvious let's say
benefit is that whatever change you have
to perform in order to include a new
field you do it on the iterative process
template and it's project that is based
on the process template is automatically
getting the change whereas today we have
to upload with with admin via plate
dated XML on it's different project now
for example I saw that there is a
different limit when you're using
garrotted template it's 8,000 something
but I don't know if it counts the number
of prints bit different way so instead
of using the unique reference reference
names so we are always we are using for
example the power tools it's a plugin
for visual studio to upload the maximals
I don't know if we are going to be
requiring another tool in order to
upload the xml's of the process template
you will it's very different
ok because I saw when you're using the
inherited process you actually
performing whatever changes you perform
on
TFS itself but yes so the next thing is
that we have custom integrations with
TFS yeah what what we're doing exactly
we have two types of issue tracking so
it did say it's PSM by HP and spiritus
for in factura so we have used the
an external tool that the systems and
orchestrate or platform that will allow
you to organize tasks in sequences and
therefore automate certain procedures
and give you a template in order to
write code you know to find to cleave
provide the functionality for the
integration these things are running
with using the TFS extended client so in
the REST API so we would like to see
this working also in
when we go to a zoo I guess that the
only thing we have to take into account
this the different URL but we're going
to be accessing TFS in the project so in
in in theory yes the all the REST API is
work the TFS extended client works just
now but it is deprecated ah so there's
gonna be something else for she's out to
degrade - yeah so there is the REST API
so then there's a if you're not using
the extended client then you're using
all the REST API so you can do all the
same stuff and more but yeah I've got a
whole bunch of stuff built on the
extended client as well so another thing
we use is we have external apps that are
triggered during the build pipeline so
we have command line tasks that instruct
the bid agent to execute a certain
except hunt these are also using the TFS
extended line where I stay API if the
fact that it's version two is because we
build it when it was fashioned - so I
guess version 5 it's something like this
now so this let's say it's a bit of an
issue we need to discuss because the
build definitions are we're going to see
later on uses variables with UNC path
names and accounts that are local to
ours so in order to also to be able to
trigger this external apps I guess that
the build agent will have to remain
local in our environment yep so pretty
much this sums up in this part which is
the concerns about the buildin release
pipelines we have tasks that are
supported out of the box we have tasks
that we have incorporated from the
marketplace like we have one that
triggers bills from different
definitions within the same sequence
the star executes custom bad scripts and
parcels tactile keyboard the invoke the
external applications that we have and
when we want to where we are considering
about migrating to the online
environment would like to see exactly
that the fact that we use variables that
refer to assets that are returned to our
system we will have to be also supported
so I guess the only way to go with that
is with a local days and as we have
today I also read somewhere that if you
have had not dawns from the marketplace
you have to reinstall them so there's no
migration to that so we need to take
care if when we are going to be
migrating that big definition that
already has tasks that are from the
marketplace do we also need for example
to remove those tasks migrate the big
definition and record them or we can
migrate them you can just migrate them
that's ok ok so another thing we have to
consider us that we use a local
repository for nougat and NPM packages
we use project which is let's say a
server that holds the NPM s and then you
get so it can be used during the build
sequence when we are going with a new
gate steps again about invoking the
extent that the external apps during the
build the fact that we remains that we
use the applications with extended
client the rest api get library get to
start to clone the rebels perform the
commits impose change saying git command
line in our environments so in terms of
a security as it is right now we have
the on-premise TFS so it's our active
directory that does the job
and we restrict access to various parts
of the let's say the collection by
manipulating the TFS group access rights
iteration area restrictions and so on so
when we are going let's say to split
with the huge collection we are going to
be enforcing the security access rights
to its project within the collection as
it is but when we are going to assume
the web services like yes the
authentication will use this Azul Active
Directory so it's no longer our Active
Directory we need a different set of
credentials let's say or it is the
process off part of the process of the
migration is we will link your internal
Active Directory to Azure Active
Directory and then it would effectively
be the same credentials or what does use
a different mechanism okay we can have
continuity of that for sure just for
let's say the sake of completion I found
that we can also provide MFA or IP
restriction if you want to further
restrict down the access to when we are
online the fact remains that because we
are using for the sinking of TFS with
the external issue trackers and not be
dangers using some accounts of our own
we would like to have control over the
password expiration policy so of course
since they are internal users in our
Active Directory you can enforce that I
don't know if we are syncing with a
Azure Active Directory is possible yeah
okay if you if you expire the password
then that syncs to I soon as your Active
Directory it will sync the password
expiration as well okay so in doing a
little digging in the internet what's
things that might affect us when we are
going to the unlined now you read
somewhere that reporting as it is with
Excel is no longer applied because the
ad dome is using only the connection to
the on premise is this accurate so and
the sequel server reporting services and
data warehouse are are not available on
your DevOps services you will have to
use the BI connector and the analytics
service ok what we do is the most common
thing we do is that they set up a query
they save it under set queries on TFS so
we have this plug-in on for the office
integration and we can download the
results and Excel is there still working
over how about the student run nope
let's start working because I read
somewhere that you need to access what
it was called
Azul boards or something like that so
there's a new way of doing some of that
the old way will still work but it's
dependent upon the extended object model
therefore if the a which is deprecated
so if they expire the the old the old
object model then you would have a
problem but it's there right now ok ok
as we said the extensions will need to
be reinstalled we haven't implemented
anything of our own so I guess we are
not having trouble because everything is
from the marketplace just note that
mentions of users in work item
discussions
it says will remain but reference to on
premise identities is going have to
change a subscription notification I
guess they are migrated as well ok and
the thing that you asked and I've
probably didn't answer concerning
licensing we have when the number of
users we have
that are non visual studio yes I counted
67 something but I guess we have to
exact that because I think it's with
paid subscription I find the Sun
correctly you have access to the zoo
their Web Services okay so we need to do
a checklist so this is the basic layout
where we stand and yep when we would
like to go and a first step break him
down with cubes project collection so
that have independent components
accessing it by independent teams and
taking that broken-down scenario all the
way up to us who develops this has been
mainly targeted on these kids let's say
collection but the rest of the project
collection are rather simple
they don't have this let's say massive
and complicated repository system they
have their own repository they have
their own customizations of the process
template so I guess what we are going to
do with a huge one we're going to do
with the rest of them as well yeah that
is a big collection just to confirm is
just over a terabyte yeah check it's the
number I show you yeah I think it was
one point I can't remember what you say
at one point to one point two terabytes
which is
that might take a minute
yeah yeah 1.2 terabytes
so the largest collection that I've
uploaded it was 2.8 terabytes
it's all a little bit of effort to get
it up there because obviously data
speeds and various things there's some
things we can do around that to make it
much faster on D of migration and
effectively we can take up a copy of the
database prior to the day you're gonna
move over and then just cake take a
differencing up which makes it much
faster but it will take a long time to
process on as you're DevOps probably
close to 48 hours for them to be able to
process it process it into the system
guys sorry this is panna he's from the
screenshot here it looks like 120
gigabytes not 1.2 terabytes
yeah decimal point somewhere then that
would be definitely be 120 gigabytes
that would be fairly straightforward
then much faster another thing I would
like for us was some projects of ours we
have set up CI bills and using pull
requests the set up is going to be
migrated as well
okay so all effectively your your
collection with migrate I am as as is
and I would want you to do at the very
what what we would do first is we would
get the collection ready to migrate and
then we do a dry run during the dry run
you would get a copy of your collection
up on Azure DevOps and then you would be
able to
asked all of the extensions that you're
using effectively it the import sequence
am is pretty close to full fidelity it's
not complete full fidelity you did note
some of the the differences in your in
your presentation when you move up those
additional work to do afterwards but
it's not mandatory for example you would
stay on the XML process when you
initially moved up and then you would
need to migrate through a process to the
inherited process and that's an
important thing to do in order to
support a greater number of projects do
you know how many projects you have
right now and right now it's six
projects okay and six bigger projects so
you you also need to consider the
relationship between boundaries and the
project inside of your DevOps just
inside of TFS in general and so all of
the planning tools the agile planning
tools and the team based tools only
function inside of a single project so
you would know if you're in multiple
team projects you would no longer be
able to create at the same level of
reporting across those projects that
you're able to do just now because
you're inside of one team project yeah
it's related together does that make
sense yeah yeah yeah this end because
right now there could the only report
think that we do is through the search
queries thing and the integration yeah
so and then when we break down let's say
because their circle areas are going to
be referring to action items that are
different called projects within the
collection you can do a merge of those
yeah you can do it in an Excel yeah so
you will get the access to the analytic
service which is a little bit more
powerful and can report across multiple
projects at that level so the other
things that I had on my list was process
the migration the size yeah so it's
raining out the extensions that you have
that you're using around the object
model and scum operations manager that
is one bit that I am not sure works in
Azure DevOps so even even if the team
that makes it says it doesn't work
doesn't mean it doesn't work it just
means they don't support it so we would
want to test all of the extensions once
we get a copy of the the collection up
into a your DevOps will also be able to
test the migration we'll be able to test
the account access to to that and and
Microsoft does something called a dry
run which means that you have a copy of
the collection but is expected to be
deleted so it's not incorporated into
the overall system so you'll be able to
access it and I think it stays up for 30
days by default we'll be able to access
it we'll be able to set things up
configure anything you want change
anything you want and try out and all
the different things to make sure
everything works as you expect and so
that you have the minimum amount of
[Music]
problems when you get up there it is
important to note that once you do the
production run and it's going to be M
off it's not just a forward only process
but you want it to be
as forward only as you can make and so
if you do end up with lots of small
niggly had small problems maybe some
builds aren't working or that kind of
thing it's better to roll forward and
and fix them in production as it were
than to fall back to your TFS on premise
because you'll have data out of sync and
that's not easy to reify does that make
sense yeah yeah understand and so once
we've got there we can do multiple dry
runs we can make sure everything's
working and we can get that up there
have you managed to run the analysis
tools for the migration no I haven't
tried anything yet
so that part of the migration and
Microsoft's migration tools there's some
analysis components that we'll check and
there's lots of work we can do up front
to make it as easy and seamless as
possible it will check your collection
for any faults or things that haven't
been done from past upgrades sometimes
it's just process template changes or
fixing up things that there was a
command that was in the documentation
hidden somewhere that nobody ran and
that that's okay everybody's in that
position which is why this tool exists
and it will give you a list of things to
go run to fix everything out and it will
also tell you which of your process
template customizations will work in as
your dev ops and which will not work in
as your dev ops including the sizes of
your and global lists so you can have a
maximum of 64 global lists with 512
items pair pair list which sounds like a
lot but it depends how how much you're
using it yeah I was afraid of us because
actually we are using them to populate
films and some of them are dynamic for
example they are listing the big numbers
as they are generated
and yet quite a big list that needs to
be manually trimmed down it's another
time so we have to understand that this
list is going to be effectively
duplicated across all the projects in
the collection so we may have to come up
with a smarter way of handling how we're
gonna mark the big number on the items
that are included in the bill so I would
I would just use do it as a text box and
have the system populate it and then
it's not a drop-down list to be a
drop-down list because it's not human
selectable but we can look at some of
those things as they come up and some of
those automatic build fields are are
they migrate them for us out of the box
but it will definitely truncate some of
those items but fields with values won't
lose their values they'll just maintain
that text value and can't be changed if
that makes sense
okay for me there they say what I have
to check is this analysis tool it's part
of the migration tools I have to figure
fine and run I guess yeah I can give you
a link to that as your DevOps migration
tool from Microsoft has migration guide
and the tool let me I'm just gonna stick
it in can you see the chat I just added
it to the chat if you can't see it I can
always eat I'll make it as part of the
email at the yeah okay well those are
step by step migration guide which is
what I would follow as well and it does
provide
like lots and lots of tips on how to fix
most of the common problems that folks
have and and it will provide the tool
will definitely that fix more stuff for
us but you do need to be on as your
DevOps
at twenty nineteen dot one dot one M or
as your DevOps 2019 update one and I
think speedo versions for import and but
you need to get there in order to import
to as your DevOps
anyway so you definitely want to try and
I don't know if you're on that I think
you said 2018 yeah yeah and so the the
documentation will describe the versions
that are supported and it takes at least
two or three weeks after a new version
comes out before they change the import
to support the newer versions and they
support to two back and so generally
there's not a huge problem but you just
need to make sure that that we're on a
version that's supported and then run
the validation tool and which will do a
bunch of things to to fix a bunch of
stuff automatically but it will also
give you a list of lots of things that
you have to go fix manually some of it
is just running command lines with
elevated privileges to fix stuff other
stuff is changing the process template
and fixing that across all of your
templates before it will allow the
upload but again they're all things we
have to do anyway and I think the
important thing for your circumstance is
getting getting those extensions and
your your plugins checked against as
your DevOps so what you could do even
before you've managed to get a copy of
your collection up to as your DevOps is
set up
it takes some of your chords across to
Azure DevOps just a generic location and
as your DevOps and make something and
then set it up as if it would have been
migrated and see if you can do your
builds you can do the plugins you have
the automated tools that set up them
that will help isolate what things might
need to change what extra effort we need
to have I mean I can help you guys with
that as well okay so the idea is whether
we take the collection as it is we push
it to Azul we're in the test pass we
start the breakdown of the collection us
so you won't you won't be able to do
that until it meets all of the criteria
for doing an upload but you will be able
to just take some take some codes a copy
of a piece of code that you know builds
locally put it in a get report in Azure
DevOps and then build it in Azure DevOps
so you've set up and the the the
different plugins and things that you
use at the moment and make sure that
they work and even before you've
upgraded your on-premise server even
before you've you've got a copy up into
the cloud which will take a little bit
more effort okay anyway we have to let's
say check out this with extended client
because we depend heavily on it so yep
I mean extended client does work in fool
against Azure DevOps all of my tools
that work against your DevOps are using
these using the extended point and they
did have our em January 2021 expiry for
the extended client but I think that's
been pushed back okay but it's not going
to be indefinite
I don't know if the rest of the guys
have anything to add yeah
can I ask about SharePoint we use
current a SharePoint with the I think we
usually the grated version with that
comes with TFS so can we use the
pleasure of SharePoint that comes with
office 365 as a company no I mean yes
you can but there is no integration
between as your DevOps and SharePoint
that to be fair that's probably a good
thing the integration was never super
awesome in the first place it was
literally just file access we can do
anywhere on our pcs I don't think it
really added anything super valuable you
may disagree for sure the other question
is how can we do a bandwidth analysis to
make sure that you know we set up the
correct bandwidth between our company
Mazu yeah so there's a system what's
called my Microsoft have I have a system
for creating a dedicated pipe between
your internal network in and Azure and I
do have I have a recommendation around
that the M has worked well with other
companies in that you want to try and
avoid a restriction that requires
connections to Azure to go through your
internal network when people are working
remotely it is going to be a huge
bandwidth implication for your
organization I know everybody's working
remotely just now but even once you get
in back into the office it's ok having
people connecting out from the office
but having people outside having to
connect in
VPN - then go back out - as your
resources is going to add a significant
burden there's enough security in
specifically as your DevOps but as
you're in general to enable the ability
for machines domain join machines to
connect directly to and services and
resources and as your DevOps in a secure
manner it it's it's not necessary to go
through the internal network I
understand some organizations want to do
that but it is going to be a significant
burden and slow things down a lot did
that make sense yeah but do you have any
recommendation about the average
bandwidth fair use or something yeah so
so unfortunately there's there's no such
thing as an average user when it comes
to - like as your DevOps and I would
look at the I would I would look at the
bandwidth that your users are currently
using against your your your TFS server
and it's not going to be any more than
that luckily you're using gate so the
majority of traffic would be source
control traffic under normal
circumstances but once you've cloned
they get repo and it's obviously you've
got a copy on your local machine so it
would just be work item tracking and
some of the build data what's going to
be more important or you I think is your
on-premise build agents and the data
being passed from the build agent
downloading the source code from Azure
DevOps
and then pushing it back up again and so
you you should look at what current data
transfer are you getting between your
people on your network and your existing
TFS instance and it's probably not going
to be
not much more heavy than that it'd
probably be less heavy but it's not
gonna be more heavy every organization
has a different profile for how their
users use TFS and as your DevOps and not
a it's just not a standard
what what is a good idea is when you're
thinking about that traffic you can
monitor it between the the your current
instance probably want to think about
and what of that traffic that connects
internally on my network can I move to
the cloud in some way so that it's not
communicating through my internet pipe
so for example you said you had our
artifacts repository for NPM and and you
get packages that artifact repository
probably currently resides on your
internal network that could run em in a
juror I just as a server in your your
your as your private network and also
your build agents that you run and on
your local network could run as build
agents in a private at work in a juror
no they do because we have to access a
lot of database that have to run
interment so you will create an even
worse okay okay yeah yeah that's what
you do we have
so I I there's a number of organizations
I work with like slumber J which are oil
and gas and they've moved everything all
they don't have internal servers and
networks anymore that everything's been
moved to and as your Google or Amazon so
that they don't have that internal data
problem but yeah I understand if you've
got a lot of on premise data that's
pushed around then you'll probably need
stuff to be on premise there any
additional questions just the final one
from me at least because I think I
missed it
don't send to the scenario that would
break down the current project multiple
ones yeah I guess it's best that we move
because this is going to be a gradual
process we're not going to do a split
from day one we keep on let's say
separating its project specific element
yep bit by bit so I guess the process
would be to boost the collection as it
is right now or clutter it up and break
it down on a zoo recommendation okay my
recommendation there and there is a tool
for moving data around in Azure DevOps
code there's your DevOps migration tools
and they allow you to move data with as
much history as is possible it's not all
possible but with as much as possible
for work item tracking and get is easy
but work item tracking data will move
the data with history but the the a lot
of other things are more manual and you
kind of want that anyway because you
want to pick and choose what you take
with you okay you want to clean up as
you go
yeah okay I'm good for now
there's gonna be more I guess oh no I
have no problem and I'm always available
if you need to chat about some of these
things and help figure it out
I go else is there any anything you need
possible next steps I think having
conclude this discovery I think next
step is to go from outside describe
probably our what actually we want from
the project from you and after that you
to come back with an effort estimation
and a budget in order to to submit it to
our IT steering committee and I think
also it timetable okay probably from any
the setting is not three or four months
work so hopefully yeah so we need some
indication for availability yes sorry
I'd also like to say sorry to interrupt
and uh the the and I I would want you to
own everything that you have to take
forward and use me for things that you
don't have to take forward so for
example the the some of the getting
stuff into Azure DevOps
is a one-time thing you don't need the
skills internally to be able to manage
and maintain that going forward because
you do it once and then it's done but
for example and some of the the
migrating of data or really
understanding the process template if
you have people that already have that
knowledge or that need that knowledge to
carry forward and it would be better use
of my time to help those folks get up to
speed so they can do it and then not
only do you minimize your your costs
with me you maximize the value that you
get out of that engagement yeah on the
other side because we need to it's one
of them except for the business
requirement this is also an audit issue
with visual studio license so personally
personally I need to assuming that the
business Yanni's VV panelist is okay
with the approach I need to move fast
so velocity against cost probably
velocity is more critical to us this is
this is my understanding because I have
a the otic two behind me to kick me in
my ass every quarter but but I think
maybe we have to discuss our side
okay if we have all the information from
outside yeah knees with apologies Nico's
and Sonia and we are able to prepare the
requirement document for Marty I think
we are okay for now I'll reply to emails
that we've had with a link to some of
the documentation that I talked about
and hopefully that will add some value
there okay okay okay great
you're very welcome good to get from you
okay thank you I do I do still
occasionally get emails from your TFS
database server to tell me that you've
run out of this space so I do hear from
you every so often something that our
all the department has fine before two
weeks ago so okay yeah I haven't seen
one in a couple of weeks so thanks
thanks Jenna because if I likely find
this be an issue for us because who is
this vendor I don't know if Yan is
released if you do have additional
questions feel free to fire me an email
or our message me on on teams and I'll
get an answer as best I can
I'm I'm training for days this week so I
might not respond super quickly but I
have tried my best thank you
nice evening
yeah you too you too have a nice night