in work and progress less is more
wow there's a lot of math to unpack
there if you if you really want to go
into it but but ultimately the the
Mantra in kanban is is
um a different way to phrase what you
just said is stop starting work and
start finishing work
and it's the idea that the more stuff
you have on your plate the more you're
jumping between the things that you have
on your plate
um and the more time you lose to Jumping
between those things
um a great analogy that maybe only works
for the Geeks out there is paging in
Windows right you have to when you want
to do another task you have to unload
all of the information and contacts that
you've got from the previous task and
reload the next task and then continue
doing that for a period of time and then
you every time you swap you have to
unload and reload that's why your
computer goes mental and stops running
when you try and get it to do many
things because it's having to unload and
reload all the different tasks and
people are just the same our brains are
just big computers if you give people
too many different things to work on
then they they're they just get
overloaded and aren't able to to
function so the that matters not just
for for projects right so if you there's
a there's a book by Gerald Weinberg
systems thinking book by Joe Weinberg
that did a bunch of data and Analysis on
um context switching and the cost of
context switching and it's about 20 of
time that you lose per additional thing
that you have all they'll be up to I
think if they analyze one to five
projects and if you're working on five
projects at once
um you get about 20 of your time to
split between those five projects
everything else is lost for this paging
right context switch and that's just as
true
for scrum teams in sprints
when they have a bunch of random crap in
their Sprint backlog right rather than
focusing on one thing are you having a a
Sprint goal and having focus and moving
in One Direction if they just have uh 10
things they have to do
then you've got fragmentation and if
they start too many of those things at
once there's too many of those things in
progress at once they've got more whip
work in process then it starts to grind
to a halt because they're struggling to
switch between them struggling to get
things done
um so less is always more
smaller is always better in in
engineering work in Building Products
you want to do smaller things and you
want to have less things on the Go at
once and then things move through your
system more quickly what's a great
analogy for that I think of it like oh
this is a terrible analogy maybe I'll
maybe get shot at for this one but I I
think of it like pipes right and marbles
flow through pipes less effectively than
water flows through pipes right because
water's smaller molecules than marbles
are and if you throw a couple of rocks
in with those marbles big things it's
potential to clog up the pipe right it
might get stuck and then the marbles
have to flow around the this rock when
it gets stuck so then the amount of flow
is smaller and that's the way I think
about work flowing through the system of
your team
right if you've got things that are too
big they can more easily get stuck and
then once they get stuck everything else
has to flow around it and it's a
struggle right because you're trying to
get rid of this big thing while you're
doing these other things
smaller things are better right they
flow through the system better
so have smaller stuff
have less stuff on the go and you'll get
more stuff done
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility