So the question is an overview
of immersive learning experience.
And I think we need to start
with what the heck is immersive learning,
right? Because
that's just a word
that somebody's using.
But in the way I'm describing it
and the way scrum.org describes it, right?
Immersive learning
is taking the traditional model,
right? Is that
you do a two full day class
or it's four half days consecutively.
That's the kind of traditional model.
In the immersive learning
approach, what we're trying
to do is connect more the things
that we're talking about in the class
to the participants'
real world, right?
So we want to connect them with the story
that they're telling in
their business rather than
our made up story.
Because in most of the classes,
especially public ones,
we have to use case studies so
that everybody's talking
about the same topic so
that we can create those relationships.
But in an immersive class
which we can connect it to
their real world
and we have more time to talk
about and connect it to each
individual person's real world, right?
Even if they're from multiple companies.
So what we're gonna do
in the immersive class is instead
of doing consecutive days
or short four half days,
we're going to break it up
into more sessions,
because we're gonna make each
of the four half
day sessions has more stuff in it now.
So instead of just doing the content
and then they go home or doing the content
and here's some homework to read,
it's the first part
of the session is we're going
to debrief the previous assignment, right?
So obviously in the first session we're
not going to have one, but we're going
to debrief the previous assignment.
That's probably an hour to an hour
and a half right that's that's
that's going to be quite a lot
of time if you've got six people
in the class we want to hear
from everybody talk
about the problems we're going
to discuss it how it went
and then we're going to have some
some some learning we're going
to learn something
as well right we're going to talk
about some new stuff in
that and then we're going
to give out an assignment
for the next week.
And that assignment is something
that you can do in your real company,
something you can go back
and practice, right,
for the next week, right?
What's the difference between musicians
and martial art?
What's the similarity
between musicians and martial artists?
They practice, right?
So we need time to practice,
and this is part of that story,
and you can practice within
your organization by bringing in
your real stuff.
So it might be, I don't know,
I'm trying to think
of what an assignment might be.
An assignment might be
figuring out in your organization.
I'm being very high level here,
but figuring out in
your organization what does
value mean to your business.
If you're a product owner, class,
what does value mean to your business?
Your business might
not even know just now.
So as part of that assignment,
we would give you some help,
some pointers, maybe some
workshops you can run in
your organisation to try
and figure out what that information is
and what it means.
And the answer might be
your business doesn't know,
right? That might be what you come back
with the next week. So then we
can have a discussion about,
well, what else
can you do to figure it out?
And that's how we're connecting
that story back.
So this means, because
we've got this debrief part,
that we've got the four hour session
that we were just doing,
you know, the content for the
course, means we've got less time,
probably only half
the time to do new content.
So it's spread out
over a longer period of time.
So instead of four half days,
I think the PSM is seven half days,
done one a week.
So that gives you a week's worth
of time, should be five business days
or four business days, right?
To be able to practice that
or try the thing that you're going to do.
But each of them's different.
Each of the classes is different.
So the APS,
I think is 10 weeks.
I think the PSPO is eight weeks.
It depends on how the exercises
break down within it, but it is
that different format, right?
And it's different
from the traditional format
because it makes those connections.
That is the point there.
And the reason I really
like this format is because I feel
like it will give more value
to the students.
Lots of people come
into classes and they leave,
especially the two full day classes,
they leave with their brains full
of knowledge and they're going
to remember 10% two weeks from now.
They're not really going
to connect it back to the way they work.
How are they going to apply it?
Do they even understand how to apply it
within their organisation?
Within their, perhaps,
corporate context, right?
With all of the corporate rules
that they have.
How do they then get questions answered.
So this format really allows
us to directly connect what we're talking
about back to real things
in every participant's company.
That's why I think this format is great.
Thanks for watching the video.
If you enjoyed it, please like,
follow and subscribe.
I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this
or anything else Agile, Scrum
or DevOps then please book a coffee
with me through Naked Agility.