so there's a quote from Ken schweber uh
which agile is not about rituals it's
about developing software in a different
way and I would broaden it out first and
say um agile is not about rituals it's
about developing products in a different
way it's broadening that out in in
organizations the the goal is not
agility the goal is not the rituals
right they're part of the system
but they're not the thing you're trying
to
achieve um most organizations seem to
measure success in adopting
agile as is everybody doing a daily
scrum does everybody have a Sprint
review um and those
things those measures the behavioral
outcome from those measures is that you
end up with zombie scrum or mechanical
scrum right or mechanical processes
people are following the processes
because they're told to follow the
processes not because they believe that
they are the right processes to follow
in order to get the outcomes that the
business needs and that's where the
failure is why are people just following
the
rules why don't they believe in the
rules because if they believe in the
rules they'll perhaps make better
decisions right if they believe that
this is the way we need to do things
they'll figure F out better and more
effective ways to do things and this is
this is actually why it's it's really
hard when you um purchase large scale
sweeping software systems um that take
care of like let's say your entire
procurement pipeline is now fully
automated uh but now you're stuck in
that automation you're stuck in the
rituals that that automation has created
um and that's the difference between how
we've
implemented the Toyota Way in the west
and how Toyota implemented it Toyota
didn't have a fully automated production
line they had lots of pieces of
automation for the work that people do
but they had people checks at the end of
every one of those pieces of automation
because you're building big complex
products it's a big complex system and
computers are not actually that great at
managing big complex systems cuz they
only manage what we think of for them to
manage right we have to think of it in
order for it to be managed so you end up
with stuff built on top as you figure
out different edge cases and different
scenarios and it's the same with our
policies and procedures in organizations
right it builds up this organizational
or software crft uh that is all the
rules around which it runs um and that's
and that's the same as delivering trying
to deploy or install agile in your
organization it's not about the rituals
it's about doing things in different
ways right you want to uh build software
in different ways you want to build
products in different ways you want to
do business in different ways that
maximize the return on
investment that's what agile ISM all
about doing things in different ways if
you want to have a discussion about your
unique needs or situation then please
book a call or visit us at naked agility
tocom uh we also have our immersive and
traditional public classes on our
website and we'd love to hear from you