until I hit the button it's continued
are you sure you understand or anyway
yes oh cool I just started its life
that's awesome I usually - right now I
don't believe that they can hear us oh
yeah well because the bit that's live
with the red box is what they can see in
here
that is the that is that is your day
yeah
and they can hear us but they can only
see the screen they can't hear us we can
positive hear us and I'm gonna make a
start
well you mean you make your face fake
yeah I don't know what you mean by big
but yes and then I will hand over to you
all right oh that's good oh that's me
that looks like me
Wow well um welcome everyone that was
Martin and I doing a little bit of gonna
figure out exactly what was going on so
thanks for joining us this evening in
the last of our mates closing eight what
has been an excellent month over June in
really cool and actually this evening as
you have noticed for doing a little
experiment and we are trying something
slightly different
just because Martin likes teams and he
prefers it to zoom but here I have this
to be all the time so yeah warm welcome
T if this is your first time thanks for
joining us hope you'll have a great
evening we do to probably use him as a
say but we're trying something different
tonight this is a live event easy teams
so I'm kind of forgetting my way around
the UI as well so Martin and I have been
on fun with this evening as you know for
those you've joined us before we do over
call the conduct in short we ask that
you are respectful to one another you
want everybody to have a harassment the
experience we will do the usual
community show types at the end in terms
of the Q&A we have a slightly different
facility to zoom but there is a nice
little option in the top layer which is
the show Q&A which is your facility to
put questions to our speaker tonight so
please do use that to get your questions
and then I will relay them back to to
Martin as I've already know keep them
coming in maybe we can pause a couple of
points and ask the questions but it'll
be great and yet so welcome to Martin
Martin is well-known to many of us I
have known it for some years he's
very experienced and established scrum
the org trainer amongst other things is
also consultant is all stuff an agile on
DevOps space and he's also makes MVP
I've trained with him twice and had a
totally good experience on both
occasions I've also seen him speak on a
few occasions and yeah we all really
good debate some videos are job related
topics this evening he is going to share
with us his amazing talk on telling me a
little and I Joe be spotting out your BS
which I need seen the floor show it's an
awesome talk and I'm sure you will enjoy
it Martin welcome back to see thank you
very much
it's a foul I just sum up for for for
staff a little bit of gistic s--
logistics I can't even speak and this is
not our normal teams meeting is this is
something called a team's live event I
think it used to be called Skype
broadcast and it's been rolled into
teams and we have kind of a weird
producer set up here going on where we
control what you can see which is
different from zooms or just a normal
team's meeting where whoever's talking
is the one that gets center stage in
this tool we get to control it so if
they were you're not looking at the
right thing then it's either my fault or
Satpal probably mine because I'm kind of
the one in control and we're just trying
trying this out I took this opportunity
to try and it looks like a lot of fun so
sat knows and if you look at the Q&A I
can Thank You Craig Craig's just said
that I'm a little bit jumpy I'm hoping
that we'll iron out a little bit as we
go my views not jumpy but I can see that
the live view is getting a little bit
and jumpy let me those there's a stats
but I can see maybe our megabits thing I
don't know let's let's see how it
and we will look at the Sapphire if you
look at the QA you'll see that there's
new comments
there's published comments and there's
dismissed comments so jargon just said
good evening nobody else can see that
Jurgen said good evening until it is
published I just hit the publish button
and now everybody else can see it and we
can reply to the questions does that
make sense at
oh you're on mute sir you can't speak
when you're on mute telly - yeah I think
I think I got you you - I'll figure it
out
it's the school with I'm pretty
comfortable we're awesome
so let me do this which should send the
slides to you and then if I do this and
this and this then you should see both
me and the slides there we go
this should be an option somewhere for
folks dialing in to add subtitles as
well I don't know how that works
but I think I set it up with Dutch Welsh
and Spanish subtitles I think but you
guys can let me know whether that is
what you what you expect or is even
working so um thanks for the awesome
introduction Seth and as he said my name
is Martin hi - whit I obviously I'm
Scottish although maybe not those that
are Scottish on the call will think I am
not Scottish because I sound a little
bit American I lived in Seattle for
three years as a consultant so that's
why I sound a little bit weird but for
those that are not Scottish there will
be no doubt in your mind that I am
Scottish it's one of those weird things
when you're from a place people think
your accents weird my grandmother has
lived in Scotland all her life and
nobody in Scotland would think her
anything but English however she goes
down to England and people think she's
Scottish that's the fun of accents but I
want to talk about - really it's two
things but I think they're related and I
kind of try and tie them together one is
the tyranny of Taylorism I know there's
a lot of an agile folks that come in at
to this event so you'll know what I'm
talking about by Taylorism but I will
explain it for everybody else and then
talk a little bit about how to detach
detect when people are telling lies
there was a recent paper published by a
very large organization it was published
in 2018 that talks about
the things that have to be true the
minimum things that have to be true in
order for an organization a group a team
to say that they're agile
I like this list not everybody will
agree with it but I think it's I think
it's an awesome list so I wanted to
share it with you and there's a link in
the slides for you to access the the lie
the the actual document but you can
google for it and find it as well so let
me the first thing and that I just want
to caveat the situation the reason that
this document exists and it's from a
very unlikely source I'm deliberately
being obscure with that but that's that
80 81 percent of all development shops
worldwide say that they're agile this is
from Forrester Research so even back in
2017 eighty-one percent say that I do I
would like to assert that almost eighty
one percent of them are lying that's
what I would like to accept I think
they're trying to serve us a nice little
turd pie for our consumption and they're
just making it up and the reason that I
think apart from long experience working
with companies I'm sure a lot of you are
the same one of the reasons is that only
22% of those eighty-one percent that
were surveyed are doing short iterations
and by short means shorter than four
weeks four weeks are shorter so
obviously from our perspective or
depending on your your thoughts on this
that doesn't sound very very agile it
sounds a little bit long what about the
only 16% of them have an ordered backlog
that does not sound like I like
something that that that we want for our
agile teams or even
at only 13 only sick I went the wrong
way only 13% do retrospectives if you're
not doing retrospectives I think
retrospectives are a fundamental part of
agility you can't really be doing say
that you're agile unless you're doing
some form of inspect and adapt unless
you have some sort of feedback loops
this is the source data of that you can
go find it online I just highlighted the
bits that I thought were important and
actually while researching for this this
late date the first time I was
presenting it
the-the-the I happened upon this post I
have no idea who Brian wine is but he
had a very astute thing to say and it's
really just the reality most
organizations while even if they look
awesome from the outside or not a lot of
fun on the insight I worked for
intelligent finance back in the day if
enemy remembers intelligent finance out
in Livingston yes staff pal is doing a
face I I worked for them for three that
was it five weeks I think it was five
weeks I quit after four weeks and and I
was the shortest employee ever and it
was just appalling the the the level of
just what was going on inside I just
could just beggar belief and that was
early in my career when I didn't
actually know better so we we've seen
that it's hard to change that it's
difficult for organizations to make make
this difference but I think it's worth
investigating a little bit on why a lot
of people attribute it to waterfall but
unfortunately that's only the tip of the
iceberg
Waterfall is just the start
of our problems it's not the source or
it's just a bit we can see at the top
and and we all have seen something that
looks like this requirement Center
design and implementation verification
and maintenance and this is not just
something that's applied to software
it's something that's applied in many
other different system many traditional
manufacturing processes traditional
organizational processes having
departments where you hand things off
between those departments the analogy I
use for the non software world is is
contracts signing the contract that then
results in work you have a salesperson
who convinces the customer that this is
what they want to buy and then they're
done they hand off that information to
the contracts team who then negotiate
the contract and they're completely
separate they're measured completely
differently and don't care about the
sales box they also don't care about the
other people don't align their only
concern is protecting using a contract
and then they hand that off to the next
group of people that may be involved in
in that process so that but at still
departments it's still pushing things
along so it's worth asking ourselves why
do we work that way where did this way
come from what we kind of need to go
back in time we need to go back in time
about a hundred and thirty years to the
1880s so that's got a little time travel
there we're now in the 1880s and just
before the 1880s the the world was a
very different place especially for
building products we weren't building
products at scale for sure so there was
definitely that difference but also we
tended to build our products and work
very close to where we lived and and if
we had a problem we were the only ones
there to solve it or we got somebody in
to solve it and for example if you were
the cobbler making shoes
you had a mastery of what you were
working on so you not only were building
the whole shoe but you understood the
purpose of that shoe and not just of a
shoe because I'm sure we can all a
certain purpose of a shoe but what about
the specific individual for which you're
buying that I'm Pike building making
that shoe if you're making a shoe for a
farmer or making a shoe for the local
police officer or you're making a shoe
for a storekeeper there's going to be a
different set of requirements and if you
as the cobbler nor that person you have
a much bigger greater degree of a
connection and affinity to those things
so you can build a better shoe because
you care you care about the person you
understand their needs you understand
how their needs differ from others which
is very powerful but then the Industrial
Revolution came along and and a lot of
money was made that's you know a lot of
people get jobs a lot of money was made
people's living standards changed for
many people that meant increasing their
living standards and albeit that my
great grandmother started work in a
cotton mill at the age of 8 however
living standards did go up even if some
of the principles did not but if you
look at these pictures and ask yourself
what what does the person at each
individual station understand about the
product what it is how it's going to be
used who's using it do they even need
that understanding the system here in a
factory floor is set up in such a way
that you do not need that level of
understanding in order to to build your
product you're effectively Charlie from
Charlie and the Chocolate Factory is dad
you're screwing the top on toothpaste
bottles
for a living and that that's it there's
no more there's no less than that and so
the the difference between these two is
very stark on the Left we have our
craftsmen taking pride in their work who
understands their customer works with
them constantly it's probably not the
first issue the first of that same
product they've built for the same
customer therefore they have a greater
degree of understanding and whereas the
the people on the right just they they
don't care they have no connection to
the customer they've got no connection
to the work apart from I get paid at the
end of the day and because of that only
connection being I get paid at the end
of the day there's a disconnect that
happens we disengage from the process
just don't care anymore that's a human
thing if we don't understand why and we
don't understand the context we don't
really care about the work so much so
this mechanization of the workplace
because we didn't have the technology to
have robots back then this mechanization
of the workplace we have to use people
instead of robots resulted in something
called soldiering which is a different
use of a word that were maybe more
familiar with but it really just means
to work more slowly than one's capacity
and or to loaf or malinger I don't know
how to translate I don't know that the
words for that in Dutch or German is
basically people not one thing tip to do
the work you just don't care I'm gonna
figure out how to work less so I've got
a little exercise for everybody
luckily there's a lovely URL which I
will see if I can just copy if I can
figure out how to get to my slide deck
while I'm looking at this is the other
screen and I will copy the URL I'm sure
some of you will be able to type it
quicker than I can copy it but we will
put it in the chat let's make an
announcement
you are out far
[Applause]
[Music]
there we go I just pasted a link into
the Q&A if you use that link it will
open in a browser and in that browser
you will have this thing called mural
you may or may not have used it before
your up there's a few people in already
I can see folks coming in and you just
fine - clicking go in and anima Slee
you'll see viewers and other people's
nice Mouse mousies mice floating around
all over the place and you can zoom in
and zoom out uh and try not move
everything around let me let me just
quickly lock that I must have left it
unlocked ah look there we go that we
can't drag about the thing now and I'm
gonna give you a little exercise we're
going to and pretend that we are have
been hired by a paper mill owner to
improve product productivity and it lost
due to people disengaging from the work
with the soldiery to work more slowly
than one's capacity I'm going to put two
minutes on the clock and I'm going to
ask you to create post-its for as many
ideas as you can now if you're wondering
how you create a post-it you just
double-click anywhere on the screen and
it will create a lovely post-it that you
can type in my first idea what idea
there we go
well part of my can't spell but that's a
separate problem what I like to do I'm
going to put two minutes on the clock
Oh
being two minutes are on their way and
and I'd like you to create as many ideas
as you can on that em posters for how
you could you as a management consultant
defeat soldiering and remember this is
this is the 1800s right there we don't
have politically correct we don't have
be nice to our employees because that's
a good thing or you'll get you'll get em
out heed on Twitter and we have do
whatever you want in order to facilitate
you getting the results that you need so
I'm hoping for as many ingenious ideas
as possible are you adding some soft pal
rushing from my own you know I I am busy
facilitating this event
doing otherwise I will not partake in
your exercise oh that's sad
I will leave our lovely attendees to do
that and then yeah share that amazing
ideas with you
there is about a minute left I'm going
to open another browser window but the
minutes will stop counting down and oh I
like this so we've got gamification no
toilet breaks yeah that's uh that's uh
that's a good one uh or just just record
toilet breaks you have to record the
toilet breaks and then have some sort of
punishment for people that take too many
that toilet breaks paper unit by time
far the slowest ten percent it's
definitely something that can be done
bonus for hitting targets no recreation
area yeah people will tend to find the
recreation area if you don't if you
don't provide one but yeah shout at them
to work harder these are all fantastic
ideas is about five seconds left and
then I'll pull that pull that up over
here cool let me pull that up over here
there we go so we got a lot of crazy
ideas here but really are they that
crazy I somebody I know used to work in
a call center and this is five or six
years ago and they had their toilet
breaks monitored and they got called in
for a meeting if they spent too much
time on toilet breaks it's a pretty
common in the call center industry to do
that what have we got pay by product
bonus for hitting targets breaking down
work into a series of steps that sounds
pretty good we need to plan all the the
steps
give them a beating if they're
malingering I think that's that's
definitely a good idea sack them and
hire new ones yeah I mean are all of our
workers our cogs in a machine yeah
they're they're not high skilled labor
we can train anybody to do this work so
if somebody's not doing the work well
there's 100 people waiting at the door
for for a job these are all really good
ideas
ah yes from I like that one Seth promote
bastards to be supervisors that is
definitely something that you would you
would see and in fact some of these
ideas that you've come up with are are
are fairly and fairly hit on the nose
let me let me jump into something here
there's a gentleman called Frederick
Winston Taylor he was the thought leader
at the time he was our and Craig
Cockburn of the time and he said his his
hypothesis was that hardly a competent
worker can be found who does not devote
a considerable amount of time to
studying just how slowly they can work
and still convinced their employer that
they're going in a good pace that I
think if you think about it that is the
fundamental basis for traditional
management practices your workers are
being nefarious they are not intent and
working and we need to figure out a
carrot and the stick how do we make them
work so he came up with this thing
called the scientific management method
and all of the ideas that you wrote down
were kinda part of his thinking he
developed standard methods for each job
break it down into a set of steps plan
all the work divide workers into
appropriate ability based groups is
collecting all the marketing people
together all the contracts people
together all the legal people together
and they're just going to do that work
train everybody in just the standard
method so we're gonna plan everything
that they do
remove thinking cuz we don't want people
coming up with new ideas managers are
smarter we're gonna tell you how to do
your work and then have wage incentives
for increased output and if that wasn't
bad enough he had a disciple called
Henry Gantt yes that Gantt
who came along and he created the task
and bonus system so we're still talking
1800s tasks and bonus system basic wage
based on expected low performance and
bonuses for exceeding excess expected
proficiency and give bonuses to managers
for motivating their staff to exceed
proficiency promoting bastards that's
exactly the outcome that's going to
happen there and I work for an
organization in Glasgow called a Greco
they're over in the East End of Glasgow
they are actually if they're a very good
company but they did have golden
handcuffs they have a 40% bonus system
they pay about 15% below the average for
that job in the industry and then they
payout up to a 40 percent bonus system
at the end of the year so you want to
hang around for for that bonus and you
want things to do well and something
else that drew my attention is that we
have this thing called the modern school
system and don't be confused by the word
modern I'm using modern school system as
an own even though I kind of forgot to
capitalize it the toward modern here but
it's unknown it's this idea that rewards
for fulfilled tasks everybody sits in
rows everybody does the same thing at
the same time and incentive based
learning and I would ask what's the
difference between these two pictures
and how you motivate people the modern
school system that most of us on the
call today and my parents the school
system that we grew up in was designed
to Train factory workers to train people
to work in factories okay these systems
were optimized for output not outcome
but it didn't stop there in 1908 Harvard
started why I guess it was before 1908
but 1908 was the first graduation class
of MBAs and you can see there's a
definitely a lot of white males there
but that's the MBA graduating class of
the time and they were taught these
practices taught these are the the
fundamentals from which you need to
build your business you need to build
your employee structure and manage
people so we ended up with hierarchical
organizations in the 1950s they started
really heavily into this idea of
analysis design implementation testing
and maintenance and you can see on the
right that those has new ways of saying
the same thing that was said in the
1800s but this is in the 1950s and then
the largest purchaser in the world took
on this concept which is the u.s. the US
military the US military industrial
complex is enormous you would not
believe how big it is I have some stats
in a little bit and it's just enormous
they took on this new way of working
they enshrined it in the way they do
things and it just became part of their
procurement processes just became part
of their procurement processes and it
became part of many other organizations
procurement processes at the time you
can see the folks they are building
clocks once it was enshrined and part of
the procurement processes it's just the
way we do things then we kind of tried
to apply it to software development and
things did not go very well we were
trying to apply management practices
that were designed for the predictive
world to this new empirical world where
the only way we figure out if
something can be done is by doing it we
can't plan everybody's work upfront so
hopefully most of you are already
familiar with these ideas moving from
predictive management practices over to
empirical management practices I don't
want to go into them all but that idea
of autonomy mastery and purpose once you
take money off the table for people at
carrot in the stick no longer works and
in fact has a negative impact so if you
as an individual have your extrinsic
motivations or your your your you have a
roof over your head you have food you
have a roof over your head and you have
those things sorted then you're not so
worried and you're not worried about
money like where's my next meal going to
come from then carrot and the stick
no longer has a positive impact if you
read Dan Pink's book Drive or just watch
the 15 minute YouTube video if you're
not a reader is that is that you serve
your reader he's nodding cool he's a
reader read the book it has all of the
background if you just don't care watch
the video and just assume that
everything is true but if you want the
detail you can go read the book
so obviously this has put everybody in
that position of these hierarchical
organizations which we're all familiar
with departments silos and and
procurement practices that force us
towards that world and having big
budgets up front and these big projects
so who would be the least likely person
to understand how messed up the world
has become because of these things I'm
going to give you a hint they have a
seven hundred and thirty eight billion
dollar budget and 2.8 million employees
that's direct employees that doesn't
count consultants contractors and all
those third party people it is in fact
the US Department of Defense
who didn't start this mess but they
definitely enshrined it in all the ways
that we worked we made it much more
popular than maybe it needed to be but
they are trying to clear up their mess
what they found was that as they moved
towards agile practices they realised
that agile just becomes a buzzword of
software development and therefore all
software projects suddenly declared
themselves to be agile so they released
this guide called the div guide
detecting agile BS it was shipped out in
2018 to all of their procurement
officers anybody in the the US military
the Department of Defense who was
responsible for who had purchasing power
in order for them to understand what it
looks like to be agile so that they have
our litmus test to negate doing the
contract with somebody so I have one two
three four five six I have six questions
okay
and I usually ask folks to stand up if
I'm doing this as a big room event but
obviously you can you can't do that so
and what we are going to do is I am
going to just ask those questions what
I'd like you to do is imagine you're
standing up in your mind and I want you
to sit down in your mind friend and I
see something that is not true for your
team I'm hoping there'll be a lot more
folks standing up at the end of this
session that I would normally get and I
software development conference or in a
private organization okay so the first
question I have is are your teams
delivering working software to at least
some subset of real
users every iteration including the
first and gathering feedback so I'm
gonna caveat that a little bit I'm gonna
define what they mean by real users cuz
it's defined in the document real users
is production real users are people who
will be using your product and using it
in anger yeah you eighty does not count
as real use real users pre-production
does not count as real users some subset
of your users have to be used again in
production for this to be true
I wonder how many people sat down in
their head because if you don't have
this then it's not agile it's agile bs
back in question is there a product
charter that lays out the strategic
goals do all members of the team
understand and are they able to see how
their work contributes to that overall
success
because if not it's not agile people who
are doing the work need to understand
the whole context so that they can make
better decisions okay
our team is empowered to change their
processes based on what they learn I'm
hoping everybody who's attending here
would be able to say yes to that one but
if it's no it's agile bs it's not
agility is feedback from users turned
into concrete work items for sprint team
teams on timeline shorter than one month
if not it's not agile
and our teams empowered to change their
requirements based on feedback you've
got to get those that feedback
integrated into your system otherwise
you're still not going to build the
right thing so if not unfortunately it's
not agile
and then the one that I find even if I
have folks still standing up at this
point in a conference is the full
ecosystem of your project agile agile
programming teams followed by linear
bureaucratic deployments is a failure
it's not agile you need to have an
end-to-end process in order to see that
you're you're doing agility now while
this is from the Department of Defense I
would stand behind all of those
statements and say if you are a team
working in the agile space and the
answer to all of those questions is not
an absolute yes a resounding yes then
your unfortunately kidding yourself
kidding yourself on and it's not as
agile as you would like it to be this is
the diagram that is in the document you
can go download the detecting agile BS
if you just google detecting agile BS
you will get that information I think
it's awesome
ah so funnily enough
I used to get people coming up to me and
saying our jewels only for small
projects it doesn't work for big
projects that's what I used to get
probably five ten years ago now I get
people coming up and saying exactly the
opposite I'll add jewels only for large
projects it's not for small projects
this data here is from the Standish
group in Boston who analyzed about
70,000 projects worldwide as they do a
chaos' report every year and something
they found it was the agile practices on
small projects are 32% more likely to
succeed I'm gonna define small for you
because their definition of small is not
the same as mine their definition of
small is 50 people or less so for me
that that that tends to be big but that
you know 50 people or less is small but
large projects get 600 percent more
likely to be successful and that's due
to the extra levels of complexity as you
add more people over 50 so if you're
moving towards your journey of agility
is it a good idea to go look at what
everybody else is doing to get ideas on
how you might make changes and the next
thing you might do absolutely you should
be doing that you should be looking at
all the different practices and
experiences that everybody's having your
colleagues come to two sessions at the
future of work Scotland and learn ideas
and then try them and see if they work
for you however you can't use somebody
else's process you can only be inspired
by it if you are just taking somebody
else's process and I know newer versions
of safe are a little bit more flexible
than they have been at the past but safe
was designed and built by demophoon well
in one
company and then used as a blueprint in
other companies that is inherently not
agility it was for the first company but
then for each subsequent company after
that it's not many companies come to me
see how we're doing the Spotify model
and I'm kind of like what's the Spotify
model there is no such thing as the
Spotify model there was a white paper
written by the folks from Spotify that
talked about their point in time on
their journey towards agility their
agile evolution their continuing
evolution here's a what we're doing
right now
Spotify are not doing anything like
what's in their white paper anymore and
haven't done for a very long time it's
just a point in time they are on their
journey and they were just trying to
give people ideas so if you're just
installing somebody else's process you
are not being agile and and I find I
found something really interesting
online I found this memo this is this is
the result of the memos like a
clarifying slide but it talks about I
actually have a copy of the memo but
it's not really that interesting this
has the interesting stuff in it this is
from the the chief of a current chief of
software operations or the person who
runs IT for the US Air Force and and he
said they highly discourage discourage
their folks from using rigid
prescriptive frameworks such as safe
they point out that safe might be
potentially useful for teams who don't
have DevOps
but it will inhibit teams using DevOps
they will inhibit their ability to move
towards high degrees of agility and they
point out that safe isn't used by any
successful software commercial
organizations if you can think of one
please let me know I would like to make
sure I Kathy
this with the correct thing we go let's
and smart people here at future of work
Scotland that have lots of experience I
have never seen a large successful
software commercial organization using
safe nor the Spotify framework well
apart from Spotify obviously by doing
something different now I think that's a
very telling piece of information
DevOps an agile are not magic magic
bullets they're not the thing that is
going to save the day for you
I thought I just put the windows flag on
the cat just for you because I know
you're always commenting on my comments
on on Microsoft II stuff
we can use some of these capabilities
that we find in agility to help improve
our processes and practices and make
things a little bit better but something
is really important and my good friend
Russell Miller mentioned it why buy a
counterfeit when you can afford the
genuine article why would you go install
somebody else's framework that was built
for their culture for their
organizational context for their
business processes build your own every
large successful organization that has
moved towards agility has done so by
creating their own process based on
their their individual needs and how do
you get there one step at a time
just find the first step you can take
and take that step to get there so thank
you very much
I actually forgot to update that link at
SAC sorry about that but you will get
the presentation from that link if you
want to copy the slides are there any
questions that hey that do come through
Lauren I'm just
oh I okay so if it's what percent of all
team doing DSR Jared it's about energy
have the US military limited the
engagement to nineteen percent but that
is a really good question yeah so I
didn't say the US military we're doing
it well mmm
this was their they're trying to educate
folks inside of the organization so they
can see when they're making good
decisions and when they're making bad
decisions I'm sure there are
circumstances where they're between a
rock and a hard place and I can either
choose that doesn't meet the agile
requirements or that doesn't meet the
agile requirements and I have to pick
one so they are working closely with
their vendors with their their providers
to help improve agility with them but
those practices are currently required
by the Department of Defense's
procurement rules so technically if a
vendor is not agile not doing continuous
delivery is not providing them with a
usable increment even of a missile
system on a regular cadence on timeline
shorter than one month then they are
breaking the contract that they signed
so maybe they're not a limiting their
engagement but they can certainly sue
the crap out of them for not not meeting
the the requirements so that's an
interesting one yes yes I usually did
wanna make spark a little bit of thought
I'm sure within the loop for yourself so
each new system of working solves the
problems that went before and what are
the problems are agile cancel so we can
see what might come next other than
maybe just doing our job properly I like
that thanks Chris I do
I like that Craig Craig always has very
very good insight and I think that it's
is a valid it's a valid statement to me
I I don't know if we can answer that
question because we don't know what we
don't know I guess um but I I maybe I'm
wrong and I'm perfectly happy for for a
creek to correct me maybe I'm wrong but
my my understanding of agility is it's
moving from a model where things are
rigid because we have a defined world
yeah our manufacturing production line
or our building 300 houses or making
clocks on our on our factory floor and
we're moving from that world towards a
world where we need an empirical process
control system we need to be able to
adapt our reality our reality our way of
doing things to the realities that are
happening for us as a business as an
organization an agility for me just
means moving towards that model so that
we can accept change
so isn't agility the vehicle through
which we can adapt and come up with new
ideas for whatever's coming down in the
pipeline so I'm not I'm not sure that we
maybe need anything else maybe doing
agility properly is something we should
be doing but again I disagree with the
word properly I don't know about anybody
else but I don't think there's one way I
think saying doing agility properly is
kind of like what we all do say for we
all do this one thing I think it's
different for every organizational
context and everybody has to make up
their own way which means incrementally
and iteratively moving towards the
outcome that you want I think it's like
lips release its point say yeah yeah
justjust just well you're kind of
covering that bill so let's have a
question well then get your question of
sorts and the problem isn't the
Dreamworks a lot of a speaking of ugly
with Arnold
safety sebastian right and you and i
want that conversation many times but
it's the Mackenzies and the b CGS and
the being spitting the work the work the
the frameworks in because that's what
the management wants to buy right so
it's it's these things
positioned and sold and nothing nuts
I've been part of that right I
I totally agree and and it it's there's
not really a light at the end of there's
not a light at the end of that tunnel
they're not going to magically get it
as as long as executive in or executives
in organizations don't care enough to
understand the problem they will always
just want to buy either way into a
solution and that's just the reality I
firmly believe that those companies will
not go anywhere yeah III think of it as
it's like Darwin Darwinism animals grow
into the niches that are available that
they can optimize for and companies do
the same companies fill a niche and if
that niche changes enough then the
company has to change if the company
can't change they go out of business so
those organizations that adopt change
adopt models that allow them to adapt to
those changing circumstances will
survive and I think the world today
changes much more quickly than it ever
did before so they need to change true
one step at a time
yeah I've got one for you here which
might clean nicely to your your your
scrum and Kanban training for sure can
you can you share what you qualify as
the for splint so I want to get an
astronaut discussion but what what could
you allow you to take place before
Sprint one eg new team deciding wellness
research experiments understanding the
customer flaw new offering team coming
together to understand the problem and
look
dito eagle in the floor is yours that's
a really good one I like that one so I
don't know what what I would normally
say it if you're at the point where you
have a team because you're contemplating
sprint one I'm going to make a little
bit a bit a bit of an assumption and I'm
going to say you've had to create you've
had to do enough to convince somebody to
give you some money okay
so you have an idea about what niche
you're trying to fill with this new
product this new thing that you want to
do and I would suggest just get the team
if you have the team together with the
product owner and decide what's the
first thing that you could do what's the
first thing that you could test what's
your hypothesis if we make this product
this is the behavior change that we
would see this is the the measure that
we're going to use whether we're
successful what's the smallest thing
that we can create that will meet that
measure and you're trying to find
something that's small enough that you
can do it in two weeks there uh if
you've got a team of five or six people
there are very few things you can't have
some basic concept of in two weeks yes
you're gonna spend a lot of time in
infrastructure building architecture
building servers but if you're using I I
work when I eat one of the classes that
I teach is the professional scrum
foundations class in the professional
scrum foundations class I break
everybody up into teams and I give them
a backlog for it's an animal website
right so they have to build an animal
website so they have stories like have
you been through this one Seth no so
they have we have stories like you know
it has to be generally attractive it has
to have a home page it has to have these
types of information and have stuff
pictures and an image gallery and all
these kind of things so a backlog of
information and we just give the team's
the backlog and we
don't give them any instructions about
how to go turn that into a working
product we give them 30 minutes prints
so 30 minutes of Engineering inside of
the sprint and I have almost never had a
team not be able to create something by
the end of the Sprint and that's a
30-minute sprint and I'm gonna caveat
now I had one team which I was loved to
work on this team I had one team of five
people that by the end of the 30 minute
the first 30-minute sprint sprint having
never seen the requirements before and
just picked their animal mascot for the
team okay they managed to create using
they were using visual studio they
created their website in visual studio
they had it stored in a git repository
they had an automated build system
created to pick up those pcs from the
Builder from the from the git repository
build it into a cohesive product and
deploy it to production in Azure in 30
minutes
team of five people what could that
group of people do in two weeks I think
I think its last about what can we
create but what can we create in two
weeks give them the first thing and let
them let them play for two weeks do you
know what that gives the product owner
it gives the product owner two weeks to
go come up with the next most important
thing just get started I think is my
suggestion
absolutely a really good one for you I
love this o if you are stuck in on Jovie
is what steps might you start take the
model to get out of it and enjoy SBS one
love it depends which of the BS is your
in I guess but so so the thing I see is
the the biggest BSE is an agile apart
from and I'm talking about a team
there's a whole bunch of product owner
product value be a sees that that
organizations seem incapable of
understanding value but I'm meticulous
and if we're inside of a team
if that team is not able to create a
usable increment so what what the
minimum bar for scrum is transparency we
need transparency that's part of our to
have an empirical process control system
we need transparency the increment at
the end of the Sprint are usable
increment that is production-ready might
not be defied production but it's
production ready is the minimum bar for
doing scrum if you don't have that
you're not doing scrum yet you don't
have transparency you've got the the
product backlog which gives you
transparency of the future you get the
the the Sprint backlog which gives you
transparency of the present and you've
got the increment which gives you
transparency of the past that is the
whole purpose of scrum we have those
transparency so we can see what's going
on so I think the first one I would
focus on is getting understanding what
our definition of done should be versus
what it is and every single sprint every
single retrospective look at that death
here's where we should be in order to
create a potentially releasable
shippable product here's what we can do
hey what's the next thing we can do to
close that cause that gap that's that's
what I that's what I would start that's
where I would start
but then my background is engineering so
I would start there yeah so in your
experience for aspects of senior
leadership stroke management or for
tuned to these efforts I don't know
really again and which are supporting
them so I think that last bit screams
the ignorant ones are thwarting us and
the enlightened ones are enabling us
it's really that simple there are there
are a bunch of folks and organizations
that don't don't understand why Fredrik
Winston Taylor's thinking thinking's are
a bad idea they don't understand that
because that's all they've ever known
so there
looking at what you're suggesting to
them from a position of ignorance and
they're looking at that and they're
thinking I can't operate in this world
because I don't understand it
therefore I will lose my job therefore I
need to get in your way that that's
that's really what's happening and the
thing that the changes that is education
same as sorting ignorant anywhere
whether it's government ignorant or
people ignorant you need education that
that's so sad pal that was definitely a
lead-in I have a mmm professional agile
leadership class you do I do
just coming up on the oh well actually I
think that dates wrong it's on my
website I think I think is it the 29th
it was good to see you hope that day
strong right because that's London yeah
it's not that one haha it's after that I
moved it I moved it that's what it was
so it's not that date it's the week
after maybe I think it's the week after
anyway it's on my website so you will
see it there so just naked agility if
you google makes agility you'll not find
anybody else although you find some
scooters there's naked scooters I don't
get it but there we go and but if you
find that class we're doing it over for
days 8:00 a.m. till 11:30 so that
managers can attend so that those people
in leadership positions who won't turn
up to a two-day class can actually turn
up because you know they're finished by
11:30 every day and I have two people
signed up from Singapore so I'm with
forward I'm looking forward to that
class I just thought I'd throw that in
that wasn't that's just a that's the
sales part animal it's it's all good you
were happy to do that also happy to
shoot in the link to your well you
revamped your website right not still no
you did it for me but I did it because
of the new normal I want a couple things
yeah what we're doing virtual training
now so instead of focusing
on location we're focusing on time zone
yeah so if I less
i I did the first thing I thought of
when the folks from Singapore signed up
was our is that inside of their time
zone and it's a two to thirty till 5:00
p.m. for them so it makes perfect sense
so so definitely take take regardless of
what do you want to take it with me I
the professional agile leadership is a
great class not just for leadership but
for us to help understand what
leadership should be doing if we have to
go explain to them what they should be
doing so we talked a lot about
delegation with which which class did
you go through a pal sir
no no yeah you did our PSK come on yeah
so so yeah it I I have a lot of fun
teaching classes but we're doing all of
them virtual at the moment obviously and
I'm feeling like I like the virtual way
of delivering a scrum that arc has found
that there's a six percent higher pass
rate for the assessments with folks
taking the virtual classes we're not
sure yet why that's the case but I would
assert if you've seen my LinkedIn posts
I've been posting some of the awesome
murals that my groups have been creating
in the scrum classes and oh the ability
to create all of those things having
those big wall exercises without having
to fight to get access and see the wall
is is unbelievably powerful and we PDF
them at the end of the class everybody
gets a copy I think that's why there's a
greater degree of learning in the
virtual classes even though you've got
kids running about in the background and
all kinds of things going on that's it's
it's it's
it's all good it's all part of the fun
and I think that it's the new normal I
think we're going to be doing virtual
deliveries and working from home a lot
more than we ever did before
so so I had to change my website come on
give it up second before lockdown I was
doing a hundred and forty flights a year
300 days a year and doing about 16
different countries a year 34 countries
in the last ten years
hmm so I would prefer not to travel so
much so a couple of and then yeah so can
you talk a little bit about agile for
calling each other's work yes right and
perhaps the small steps are invisible to
people looking obviously from the apes
they didn't and people really say the
ORAC you've obviously what's most the
freezin butts off and relate to that to
shift your give move things forward a
little bit closer to where they want to
get right but there is a lot of that
what's your perspective on what I think
I think it's I we do a lot of work to
slowly move organizations I've been
working with a company called slumber J
and I worked with them for four years to
organize one team it was 600 people but
one one product into some semblance of
having the same source control system
having the same work item tracking
system just having some standards across
their organization it took them four
years to get there that that sometimes
things just take a long time cultural
change is hard but I think what is it
it's the Cotter model that says the the
biggest danger is declaring victory
early if we call what we're doing agile
and it's not we're declaring victory
early while we've not finished the fight
people get complacent and stop trying
because all we've won so we don't have
to do any more work I think we need to
stop talking about transformation and
start talking about evolution where are
we on our agile evolution we might not
be it we are there are are not agility
yet or what what up what's some the this
list that I have is just one
organizations definition of what agility
is don't don't take it and look at your
own stuff and go while I'm not agile
then you need to decide where you are on
your journey towards agility your
evolution and it's a continuous path
that never ends so there will always be
changes always be improvements I just
like I personally like this litmus test
of can this organization see that
they're agile or not am I looking at
that on their declaring victory no it's
not true I'm gonna buy us off I'm gonna
give you a bunch of money to build me a
product and you're telling me you're
agile how can I tell if you're lying
why should I have to know why should I
have to expect that you would be lying
but that's what happening for
organizations how many how many am I
what's the the term consulting
organizations like the Accenture 's the
sultan's so those sorts of organizations
how many of them would you consider to
actually be agile or just effectively
taking the piss from their customers and
saying whatever they need their cost
their customer needs to hear in order to
win that contract I mean that that's
really where this focus is if you're
working inside of an organization and
you have a team and you're providing
services this is not your litmus test
this is a litmus test for an
organization spending eight hundred more
than eight hundred billion dollars on
buying stuff yeah they need to make sure
that they're they're spending the money
effectively and their folks don't know
whether those organizations are telling
them the truth that's why this litmus
test exists so don't don't definitely
don't use the same measure as as safe
for the Spotify model don't don't just
take this as route and make your own
assessment this is just one example I
don't know if that answered the question
I tried my best
yeah
I could just say I'm not pooping all
over your attempts to make your
organization more agile I'm just maybe
pooping over saying it's agile if it's
not that's maybe what I'm saying did you
consider the space p6
as an agile company they would feel the
the sex question test quite like that so
yeah yeah yeah I do programming teams
followed by linear bureaucratic
deployments as a failure because their
their deploy so
yeah I'm not I'm not gonna hold them to
the same if you are working within on an
organizational context which SpaceX is
one such an organizational context where
it's not a possibility to to be you know
you you don't have your rocket in space
every 30 days but maybe they'll get
there isn't that isn't that their plan
like a continuous delivery of they're
going to be launching on a regular
cadence they're increasing that cadence
I don't know maybe you could say they're
they're still on their evolution they're
not at this measure of agility but
they're doing super super well at
everything else so I wouldn't poop all
over them for not booting one of these
requirements if they are doing so
awesome anyway if that makes sense you
you have to look at the value deliver
delivery in your organization it's it's
agility is not the goal
I think that's something that that folks
often miss or misinterpret but the goal
is not to be agile the book all this
time an awesome business that does well
and your customers customers needs meet
your customers needs yeah I meet them
well you want delighted customers I
don't know the SpaceX have delighted
customers if they do they're doing
awesome I don't care what measure you
use against them they're doing awesome
if they don't have delighted customers
then maybe they're doing something wrong
I don't think it's as easy as that no no
so okay we'll take a couple more than
all other good ones coming so if you
were to give one piece of advice to the
individual whose company execs is not
they are agile but everywhere in the
globe news that's not the case oh gee
say to them I would say email that
executive the detecting agile BS
document just email to
print it out leave it next to the
executive bathrooms I don't know that
that person that executive needs
educated yeah they're there they have
they're ignorant on that topic and I
think this document makes people think
it's its title is deliberately you know
pushing that and that's why I used it in
hey I want to make people think don't
just assume you're agile think about it
and I think that one piece of advice is
send them a link to this presentation if
it's too if it's too long maybe I could
do a shorter one for you yeah but
sending them a link to the document has
a lot more in it
honestly I'd really recommend perusing
this document it has lots of useful
things in it it talks about DevOps it
talks about continuous delivery it talks
about feature flags it talks about
controlled exposure to production it
talks about a lot of things that are
part of our new modern software
engineering practices that we really
should be encouraging moving towards
blah blah blah so yeah I would
definitely print off a copy leave it in
the executive bathrooms that's that's
that's definitely my recommendation and
subtle yeah sometimes it's not subtle
but put it on his desk when he's not
there he comes back what's this thing Oh
detecting ID you'll be a so maybe that
oh oh [__] well that that is I was okay
well maybe maybe I need to make some
changes maybe I need to do stuff it a
lot of the time it's cuz shareholders
are measuring organizations based on
some of these ideas as well cuz
shareholders don't understand they just
want their money so well we know we'll
get more money if this an agile
organization so you should be agile so
the CEO goes okay we're agile now that's
the declaring declaring it
I don't know answer but it was an answer
this one of this one approach
and I like a John's comment thank you
most of my time has been adding
transparency that's that's what we're
always doing in organizations that's
really the only thing that matters
creating transparency if things are
transparent if problems are transparent
people will do something about them I
like to think of em sometimes my job is
just to shine a torch in the dark the
thing that we need to go fix and keep
shining it even when people think it's
fixed already or don't want to deal with
it that's shine a light in the dark I'm
gonna make this the last one I don't are
you familiar with is it true like who
likes loss of leadership I am NOT I know
but know that somebody has mentioned
them
I will go google it so this is my this
is this is my favorite thing about these
events every week I learn something you
how good is that so cruel acts laws of
leadership I genuinely never I've never
heard of them I just put it on the
screen true like slow ship states that
the future of an organization is in the
hands of the privates in the field not
the generals back home are quickly
developing world supporting or River
tails your leaders need to nurture yeah
I I totally agree so I didn't know what
it was but I totally agree with it and
as laws would you follow so that are
obviously a number of them so yeah that
definitely requires a little bit more
digging I agree with what I just read
that way you're nuts
open this up to something year's evening
so you can go research and read and
maybe it maybe I'll incorporate it into
my agile leadership class yeah yeah
States yeah okay we're gonna change
minutes okay you feel that many
questions even as you always do and it's
been excellent and and and we learnt
something new so that's really cool so
just to say thanks it's great to have
you along again
always great talk I've seen it before
and it's like different twist on it so
that was pretty awesome I felt was
slightly shorter so did you know there
was more slice
I don't like slides anymore how was that
one days I'm trying to do less slides
and more discussions and content and
stuff I've been teaching I've always
been a slight monkey for teaching my
strong classes and I just taught
professionals from foundations class
this week with no slides at all I think
I did cheat I copied some slides into a
mural and but maybe only six or seven
things I copied I copied across I have
the slide deck has something like three
hundred slides in it but I did
everything as interactive exercises from
end to end and discussion so yeah that's
a lot of fun okay well Toby along thanks
for being with us because I can't see
anybody else I'll give me a little round
of applause it's just very different
you guys did what were used to which is
cool but ya know I would be interested
in folks at feedback on the excuse me
because this looks like a great tool it
actually it actually supports up to
20,000 participants 20,000 attendees
which is a little bit more than zoom but
maybe it's not as interactive because we
don't have the ability for other people
to mute yeah but then maybe it's better
because you get to pick and choose the
questions I don't know I would be
interested in feedback pros and cons of
it see bruising come exactly exactly
no but no thank you everyone for joining
we did try this little experiment so as
martin says the team and i'd be really
keen to get your you know your thoughts
and your feedback will always have to
try things will be back to zoom next
week you'll be competed so
thanks for joining us keep the feedback
coming and yeah that's us bringing
Giunta cause I'm really excited about
July we have five sessions for you as it
credible there are five Wednesdays and
like you believe them on so we have five
events for you and we start off next
week with 10-day Ricky who joins us to
talk about innovation transformation
this talks about intrapreneurs can drive
transformation it's really cool he's
just released a new book pilots in the
Navy I mean cycle interesting Chuck
so do tune in for that lots of interest
to you and we have a whole host of other
ones I'm Artemis cunningly presenting
his content I was publishing one of our
outstanding events for our joy which is
with Steven Wendell will be joining us
from the States
he's also got a new book out on really
cool behavioral stuff and research he
doesn't really again a really insightful
mass and really really good content I'm
an interesting ideas support really work
so yeah hope you'll join us for that
community shout outs our friends that
Scott this I've got their next meetup on
Tuesday I believe it isn't xxx Tendo
will join us on Wednesday and then our
friends at Lena Joanne brought out their
next event on the forests II think
that's about a joke each our universe of
interest sign up for that and yeah
thanks again for joining us moving enjoy
acoustic Martin again we'll see you
again and yeah thanks and enjoy the nice
Tod
thank you thank you for listening
everybody thank you
um this durian this end big red in
button suck is that the one is it
I can hear you know