without shared standards quality is a
coin toss when every team defines done
differently you don't get value you get
uncertainty and risk different
interpretations mean chaos production
risks and invisible liabilities it means
you can't trust the increment at Naked
Agility we help organizations define and
align on a single clear definition of
done a standard that every team
understands a standard that ensures
every increment is truly usable and
validated because predictability doesn't
come from a fragmented process it comes
from a shared standard that everybody
honors when consistency and
predictability across teams let's align
your definition of done