naked agility limited is a professional
company that offers training coaching
mentoring and facilitation to help
people and teams evolve integrate and
continuously improve
to allow us to focus on reflecting and
practicing in the classroom
our training courses leverage a flipped
learning approach that delivers some or
all of the theory as self-study the
course content is divided into learning
blocks
each with presentations and lectures in
the form of videos reading material and
writing activities that are provided for
self-study complemented by half-day
virtual sessions delivered online using
microsoft teams and mural these live
interactive workshops create a dynamic
and interactive environment where we
dive into the core concepts through
group activities interactions and shared
experiences all with the guidance of an
expert professional scrum trainer
professional kanban trainer or microsoft
mvp
obtaining new knowledge through
self-study materials and having an
in-depth rich engagement in the class
allows students to enjoy learning that
sticks students will complete the course
ready to take the globally recognized
certification exam included in the
course fee as part of our learning
experience for every participant we
provide a 30-minute learning review
60-minute coaching session and access to
future courses at a 30 discount
we recognize the positive impact that a
happy and motivated workforce that has
purpose has on client experience
we help change mindsets towards a
people-first culture where everyone
encourages others to learn and grow
the resulting divergent thinking leads
to many ideas and opportunities for the
organization's success
and all participants gain complementary
access to the premium professional scrum
space in our public community the league
of extraordinarily and agile
practitioners i hope to see you there
click the link below to find out more
[Music]