the question is how how does the immerse
at the new immersive learning experience
change the game in terms of entry-level
capabilities I I think it really
connects
the skills that people actually need
to the job that they're doing
because normally in a in a two-day
training class we're teaching a lot of
theory right it's actually very
difficult to connect that to people's
real world
um and we perhaps use ways to connect it
to something that they can then connect
to the real world
um but it doesn't
it's still single Loop learning right
they're still absorbing the content and
then they have to go figure it out for
themselves whereas the immersive
learning uh uh uh program allows
us to teach a small small amount of
content small amount of theory
and then they get seven days five six
days a week to go
figure out how do I do some of this
inside of my organization what's the the
the difficulties that we run into what's
the roadblocks that we hit what's the
questions that we get asked by other
people in our organization
and then come back closing that feedback
loop right making making learning an
empirical process and have that double
Loop learning where they're then able to
um have a conversation with the group
figure out how do we solve some of those
problems how do we answer some of those
questions how do we change some stubborn
ideas right some folks have have this is
the way I've always done things why
should I listen to you and do it a
different way
um and you can then start coming back
around and that's also why we include
additional uh coaching and Consulting as
well as part of our our training class
everybody just gets that so not only do
you get in an immersive class and get
that group
double Loop learning but you also get
individual learning as well where they
can come back and get additional
coaching as part of that program
thanks for watching the video If you
enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a chat about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked agility