when I'm talking about evidence-based
management I generally talk about four
key value areas with specific metrics in
those areas the reason I talk about 4
key value areas is because they cover
different aspects of um our holistic
system view right rather than a a
suboptimization um a suboptimal
optimization at a at a single level we
want to ensure that we have metrics in
in all of those key value areas and the
key value areas the four key value areas
in scrum the orgs evidence-based
management guide um is kind of broken
into two categories so there's two key
value areas in each of the
categories um the one that is more
business
focused is the market value so we need
to if we have a product and we're trying
to um we're building a software product
and we're trying to get it into the
market there are two places we have to
look for where our value is one is um
the current value of our product right
that's the product that already exists
potentially right if we don't have a
product that exists yet that one maybe
doesn't have any metrics yet um but if
we do have a product and it exists and
we've got it in front of of real
users then we want to think about what
our current value is and how do we
measure our current value the value we
have in the system right now so I might
have
Telemetry in fact don't might just do it
get Telemetry on your product if you're
a product manager and you manage a
software product you should have access
to Telemetry that shows you what
features in the product are used how
often they're used which users and which
of your customers if you've got bigger
customers which of them use those
features right that's part of your
evidence-based decision-making process
um but also are your customers satisfied
with your product right are they
actually satisfied so you could do that
with surveys that's a very lagging one
Telemetry is almost immediate real you
could have real time Telemetry um on
what's going on in your product or near
real time right and that's us
understanding our current value the
product we have in the market right now
and it could be how much money we're
making from it right now is also part of
that or Revenue by employee or you could
there's a bunch of metrics you can use
in that current value
space um but then we've got this idea of
unrealized value that's value that could
be in our products that isn't yet
um we store a list of the things that
we're going to go build in our product
backlog so that's part of the story is
your product backlog um but also you're
probably looking at market analysis
competitor analysis you're probably
looking at industry
Trends um to figure out where how can we
open out new markets for our product
right that unrealized value piece is
actually
the the scenario I I I like to use
for um market value is why
um TV
showmakers generally prefer to invest in
a new show brand new series than to add
a another season to an existing Series
right and the
reason is that a second season to an
existing series is almost never going to
have a higher audience never almost
never going to have more your first
season is your maximum amount of
audience and then over time it's going
to dip and how good the show continues
to be will be you know either be a oh
holy moly that's that's bad or you know
it's a slow decline over time and that's
why you have shows like um Halo uh which
was just cancelled the new Halo show
which H uh it showed a steep decline in
the second season so they're not going
to do a third or you think of another
show I think it's cable and wireless um
which was Supernatural which went for 16
16 Seasons 16 years uh before they
finally brought it to an end and that's
because that that line is is declining
but it's declining at a slower Cas so
there's still enough money to be made to
make it worth investing in that in that
in that show um but if we do something
brand new that the audience has never
heard of that doesn't know whether it's
good or bad right uh then we can we can
we can
just open out that new market that new
group of people and bring it into seeing
seeing that show so you're more likely
to have a higher audience for a new
thing than you are for adding features
to an existing thing that existing
people use because existing people are
the ones that are caring about it you're
already shortening your audience and the
same is true for features in your
product right whenever you add a net new
feature to your product um that's you
opening out new markets New
Opportunities new capabilities for your
customers brand new capabilities that
will hopefully be able to bring in new
customers that you didn't have before or
even whole new segments of customers
that you didn't have before into your
into your story
um but
H that that that takes a lot of effort
and focus and data and Analysis right
and trying stuff experimentation
hypothesis driven engineering practices
sit in that space where where we're
going to keep trying new stuff to
re-engage or engage re-engage with users
um in that that unrealized value space
so that that's our market value at the
top um that's the focus of I mean it's
the focus of
everybody right let's let's be clear
that we want to have as many product
developers as developers in our team um
and not
just jobbers doing the job right product
we're looking at how do we all work
together to make this products a
success um we need experts as well that
maybe don't care about that stuff they
care about their piece but we want at
least some of this but that's where
product ownership kind of sits right uh
in the in the scrum world is focusing on
unrealized value and current value the
market value and then up into the rest
of the business so product management
sits in that space and hopefully we have
some product management skills in the
developers on the team product
developers we have a good product owner
who is a product manager who has
understand scrum and we have other
people in the organization also looking
at this you might have marketing that's
people from with a marketing skill set
that's looking at this people from a
sales skill set that's looking at this
and all working together to start
funneling features and capability and
ideas into what are we going to do do in
this
product that's market value the other
piece is organizational capability
this is the piece that
um if you're on an engineering team you
lead an engineering team or you're part
of an engineering organization this is
the piece that you have 100% control
over right there are no excuses in this
space it's all you it's all you and that
those two key value areas are ability to
innovate right so ability to innovate is
about um how much Focus how much time
how much effort do we spend innovating
net new functionality right how much
time do we spend on that net new
functionality versus on the other stuff
that we have to do that we do have to do
right we have to do a lot of other stuff
as well but are we maximizing the amount
of time um we we are able to spend on
that and minimizing the amount of time
that we spend struggling with complexity
right so technical debts in that space
of ability to innovate any technical
debt is going to reduce your ability to
innovate any undone work is going to
reduce your ability to innovate anything
that is slow is going to reduce your
ability to innovate right you we have to
spend time on the slow stuff rather than
the fast up um and then the other side
of that is time to
Market time to Market is uh how quickly
can we go from that change we've made
all the way to production so those two
make up organizational capability and we
need to measure them as well so our
ability to innovate uh can be measured
in in lots of different ways I actually
I have some I have some metrics examples
uh that I can use over here ability to
innovate has loads and loads of metrics
uh I generally um my background is
engineering so uh my list is going to be
a little bit engineering focused uh but
if we're building a product that has um
customers that take versions of our
product either because we run private
Cloud for them right private instances
um and we don't continuously update it
they choose to take a version of the
product or because we're building
something that people install right they
either install it on their their phone
their desktop their their
environment I probably um want to be
looking at our uh
um percentage of people that are on the
current version of our product right um
I probably want to be looking at our um
time spent merging code between branches
right how much time do we spend on that
if you've got a branch branching policy
usually that's H if you if you promote
by environment this is really old school
devops right but if you promote by
environment H Dev Hua uh uh uh staging
production right so normally it's four
environments and you promote by
environment I.E you're merging code
between those those actual versions of
your code that are then deployed to
physical environments that's really old
school by the way don't do that anymore
um but if you're in that world then we
might want to measure the amount of time
we spend merging the code between
branches
right um yeah that that's that could be
a lot of time I I worked with an
organization a few years ago that had 90
teams in 13 locations uh in nine
different countries I think they know
who they are when I describe that um but
they they had a single product that had
90 90 odd teams working on it 90 odd
active branches um and then merging that
down and creating a unified product was
was a lot of work and a lot of effort a
lot of work and a lot of effort um so
getting a new version of your product
was was was was difficult right ensuring
that everything works together ensuring
that all of those things work well so
that could be um something you measure
so installed version index uh time spent
merging codes at production incident
count how many incidents are you having
in production because if we're
innovating and we're shipping
pad quality code then we're going to
have a higher level of instance in
production right so we need to have both
positive and negative measures like
we're doing the Innovation really well
yeah but we're delivering crap to
production okay well we need to fix that
that's not going to um help ensure that
our customers are happy with us on the
top side of that story right um but
probably the the the the the biggest
ones in there are um the two biggest
ones that that I think are easiest to
collect from a data perspective are
Innovation rate uh so what percentage of
your time do you spend on net new
functionality uh versus maintenance
versus support right um this is the
age-old capex versus Opex uh uh
conversation or can be right depending
on on on your product and your
organization um so how much time do you
spend on on on those things obviously
you want to be spending more time on
capital expenditure because it's taxed
differently anyway right that's that's
from a financial perspective that's a
good idea but also um we want
to the the capital expenditure investing
in our products future and new features
and new
capabilities is
um the thing that's going to bring in
net new users which is hopefully going
to translate to to to to revenue so we
want to be looking at Innovation rate
that's that's a big part of the story
and the other one that I like to look at
is technical debt technical debt is
really important um I generally use
sonar um sonar Cube to do that you can
do on prime or you can use their Cloud
version if you're open source it's free
if you're not open source you have to
pay right but sonar sonar Cube looks at
code bases using industry standards and
recognize industry standard metrics for
technical debt um it looks for known
code flaws right so there are there are
constructs that people create in
specific languages let's I write in C
right so or parach but if I'm writing in
C and I run sonar Cube against it and it
tells me here's a whole bunch of
security problems you have in your code
I should really go fix them right
they're
potentials known potentials at least
don't have known potentials for for
vector for attack right um there will be
other vectors that you don't know about
but at least don't have the ones you do
know about it could have code smells
right things that are just constructed
in a way that means it will be more
difficult to maintain and support these
are things that we can fix that we can
monitor and we can fix uh when you do
run it first it's going to look nasty
it's going to find like 6,000 things
that are a problem um but if you have a
policy of leaving any code a little bit
better than you found it then if you're
going to edit some code look up the
metrics for that part of the code base
fix any of those problems then make
changes to the code then uh uh uh
revalidate and you should find that it
gets a little bit better over time
that's that's just policies and and and
procedures for the team right make
things a little bit better um so that
technical debt is super important and
it's much easier to collect than you
think uh you just apply sonar Cube but
it's really hard to do something with it
um there's definitely a human thing that
when we see 5,000 things dumped on us
that your thing's rubbish we we get
dejected I think that's the right word
unhappy um with that and then let ignore
that right instead uh so that's that's
really important ability to innovate is
one of our key stories here and but the
other one is time to Market
time to Market is about how quickly we
get our product into production um good
examples or in the industry of fast time
to Market are things like Facebook 12
and a half minutes from developer code
commit to production 12 and a half
minutes that's including all testing and
load testing and stress testing and all
those kind of things that's super quick
right um uh Starbucks um at least when I
company I worked for engaged with them
back
uh 13 years ago is um they had decided
that their effective planning Horizon
I.E time to Market effective planning
Horizon for for for changes they needed
to get was 48 hours so from um
implementing a thing that they wanted to
get out into production to actually
being out in production they wanted to
be 48 hours that was a business decision
right um another one is and this this
one's a little bit more it could be um
what's it called when it's uh not
uh like a tail rather than rather than
reality uh but I heard tell that it's
not my experience but I heard tell that
when um after Windows Vista quality
debacle fixed in Windows 7 and then the
Windows 8 usability debacle fixed in
Windows 8.1 a year later um that Satia
the CEO of Microsoft reasonably new to
it at the time went down to that H Team
the windows team which is like four and
a half th000 software Engineers cutting
code every day right so it's just a lot
of people um and basically said to
leadership that we've taken a business
decision we want to see working copies
of windows in the hands of real us users
at least every 30
days um we want it rolled out to
everybody in the world at least every 90
days and they said that's impossible you
can't do that and he said it's not my
problem that's a engineering problem
this is a business decision your job is
to make it happen go figure it out um
and that business decision is what
birthed Windows 10 and that new release
Cadence and that now the ability
the the the they're less than 24 hours
from code to production inside of
Microsoft uh a week to production for
what is it 17 million people in the
Insiders program um and then every three
months they do that big ship to
everybody in the world the 950 million
other people that are that are using
Windows um so that that Cadence means
that you need a higher quality on a
daily basis so time to market we've got
the technical debt story on the other
side um but the time to Market story
brings in things like cycle time release
frequency how often you release I think
um uh back in
2012 is 20 let's call it 2010 probably
to be safe um you could probably count
on both hands the the releases for major
in fact you count on one hand the
releases for major software products
from
Microsoft right the releases to
production for for major software
products from Microsoft um as of about
2018 they were doing
86,000 deployments a
day right that that's a huge difference
and it takes time and effort to get
there you have to pay back your
technical debt you have to build
architectures in your product that
support it you have to build teams and
Knowledge and Skills that support it
but once you get there and you're on
that continuous cycle you can fix stuff
much more quickly you can any changes
you do make have a lower impact right
because you have that instead of
promoting through environments where
it's easy to miss stuff um they promote
through it's usually called a ring based
deployment structure or controlled
exposure to production where you're
actually in production very quickly but
on a small subset of users and then
continually increase the potential blast
rate radius um and you're hoping right
if if each of those rings has enough
people in it um and you're monitoring
the Telemetry and understanding what's
going on within that space you should
minimize the chance of things making it
into production perhaps that's something
that crowd Strike should have done I
just saw a post uh from those guys that
said yeah we're going to start doing
that now it's like yeah you should have
been doing that already you really
should have been doing that already um
so that that move that time to mark
Market getting things quickly uh lead
time cycle time uh um how quickly you
get things in front of customers uh time
to change direction right if you're
doing something and you find out it's
the wrong thing how quickly can you
change direction um time time to build
time to self test uh how quickly can
your developers test things locally I
think the Azure devops team was like six
weeks to get a build out the door um
back in 2010 six or eight weeks to get a
build out the door um and now they're
doing continuous delivery so they're
delivering it out the door every day and
and that time to Market reduction even
just time to self test how quickly do
your
developers
know that um they've caused a
failure right how quickly can they find
out they've caused a failure got perfect
example um for for something I've been
doing recently um I build maintain and
support a tool called the Azure devops
migration tools um it's for moving data
around in in in Azure devops so you can
copy bulk copy work items with their
history from one server to another
server one environment that thing um but
I decided to update um the the automated
build systems so I have a fully
automated fully integrated end to end
pipeline for continuous delivery to
production with that so I make a change
I send it to the repo uh I merge it into
Main and it ships to production right uh
uh and I had it in an old tool and I
want to move it to a new tool which
means I had to rebuild the whole thing
in a new new environment and it takes
about 12 minutes to do run the full
process so whenever I make a change I a
convoluted process to get it into a
place where it will run
everything and then running the whole
build takes 12 minutes so I have to wait
for 12 minutes to find out if the
changes that I've made have a result and
it took me probably two weeks to do
something that I should have been able
to do in a couple of days whereas when
I'm making change to the
codes of the product that it was
shipping I just make a change run all
the unit tests and within a few seconds
I know whether the change I made was
successful or not and now I can make
another change and a few seconds later
another change another change so
heightening that cycle shortening that
ability for your developers to find out
they've done something wrong I think the
your devops team at one point was 48
hours right uh with their automated
builds and and because they had mostly
end to end system tests don't do that
either anymore right that's like so 15
years ago end to end system in fact so
20 years ago end to end system tests are
are not a way to validate that your
product works that's the pands I can't
be bothered actually building quality
into my product and I need to test
quality in way of building of of of of
ensuring that your product works unit
tests unit tests Behavior driven
whatever you need to do but unit tests
fast running super quick unit test I
think the Azure devop team went from 48
hours and then it took them four years
to take all of those I think they had
like 30,000 system tests and turn them
into 990,000 unit tests um and the
90,000 unit tests run in 3 and a half
minutes and the 30,000 system tests took
two three days to run right that's
that's a huge impact on your engineering
team's ability that Engineers are
waiting for those things to be
successful if they're not waiting
they've moved on to other things and now
you're suffering contact switching and
cognitive load between those things so
from a from a organizational capability
perspective all of this stuff is 100%
within the control of it of engineering
of whoever builds the product do that
right if you're able to do that really
quickly and really
effectively that gives the business the
incentive that that well we can ask for
something and get a change really quick
so what should we be asking for perhaps
we should start thinking about
hypothesis and trying stuff and testing
stuff that we can get into the product
testing production and then perhaps we
ditch it out the product because it's
not providing the value that we think it
should um
so this idea of evidence-based
management as the the the four key value
areas uh so current value which is your
product that exists right now collecting
Telemetry understanding what's going on
and how users are using it your
unrealized value which is things your
product doesn't do yet so it could be
stuff you know it doesn't do yet or that
you don't know that it doesn't do yet or
you don't know you don't know that it
doesn't do yet right that's getting new
markets opening up new markets getting
new customers getting new capabilities
right that's your market value and then
at the bottom you've got your
organization capability with ability to
innovate how much time do you spend
adding that new functionality versus
supporting a maintaining existing
functionality and time to Market how
quickly does it take for a change you
make to get into production and
hopefully close that learning Loop all
the way back to your products and have
that full time to
learn cycle in there that is the four
key value in ideas of evidence-based
management