we love taking Japanese words and using
them not quite right for their meaning
uh but one of the the key phrases that
we use all the time in kamban is kaizan
um and kaizan is really just about
continuous Improvement it's keeping
changing things hopefully for the better
because you're observing improvements in
the system or measuring improvements in
the system so the idea of continuous
Improvement continuous change um
continuous optimization of your process
of your system um is generally referred
to in the cang community as kaizan
kaan's not limited to kaian Canan it can
be used absolutely anywhere you like we
should always be continuously striving
for anything that we do to be a little
bit better every time we do it and that
continuous nature is what we mean by
kaisa