you can't have spent any time in uh the
agile space without encountering people
doing uh some kind of special Sprints
they might be doing Sprint zeros they
might be doing refactoring sprints they
might be doing bugfix sprints they may
be doing hardening
Sprints whatever special type of Sprint
they're doing um it is absolutely agile
banditry and those that are doing it are
just Bandits they're not doing uh uh
good things um special
Sprints reduce and dilute our ability to
deliver usable working product so the
whole purpose across the board the whole
purpose of agile practices is to
enable that visibility and connection
with the stakeholders with continuous
delivery of usable working product and
that's how we manage risk in agile in
the old traditional model um we managed
Risk by having a detailed plan right
that was our management of risk here's
my full detailed plan because things
aren't going to change that much this
plan will work um but in the the the
complex cognitive space that we tend to
operate in when there is more unknowns
than known
you need a different way of managing
risk and in all of agile we do that uh
by creating usable working product right
that's our that's our key uh risk
mitigator because we can't document
everything that's going to happen
because there's too many surprises so
having those uh uh uh um usable working
product mitigating that risk no special
Sprints is key there um and a great
example of that is a scenario that
happened to the to the Azure devops team
uh when they first started moving
towards uh uh this agile thing they
actually they were kind of moving
towards this scrum thing um and they
decided
initially that they would have uh six
Sprints six 3we Sprints and then they
would do a a kind of hardening bug
fixing you know safety net some kind of
sa safety net Sprint I don't remember
specifically what they called it was
some kind of safety net Sprint and what
they expected to happen was as as each
Sprint H started and completed that you
would have a kind of EB and flow of
undone work right whatever you want to
call it h uh of undone work of technical
debt of things that weren't quite right
and they would have this little little
uptick uh and then towards the end of
the Sprint it would come back down again
and then the next Sprint would have a
little bit under and then it would come
back down again maybe there'd be a
little bit left over at the end of a
Sprint but then we'd pay it back the
next Sprint but because they had that
safety net and because every single
member of every single team knew that
they had that safety net they thought
constantly well I'll just leave that for
our our our safety net we'll leave that
for our safety net Sprint and it
happened so much that instead of that
kind of e and flow of undone work they
ended up with a nice little upward curve
trajectory of undone work and they got
to that sixth Sprint and realized that
they had more work that they could do in
the safety net to pay it back and create
a usable working product it wasn't
working um so what they did they
restarted uh the whole thing let's start
again and we're just going to do three
week Sprints and at the end of every
three week Sprint we're GNA ship to
production not a maybe we're going to so
we have to have good quality we have to
have paid back our technical debt we
have to have as little undone work as
possible going into the next Sprint
because there is no safety net people
who have safety nets take risks and if
you have a safety net that's agile
banditry
if you're being ambushed by agile
bandits in your organization then my
team at naked agility can help you or we
can help you find a consultant or expert
who can you can set up a no obligation
consultation using the links
below don't forget to like And subscribe
if you enjoyed this video