so the most useful element of the aps
class for beginner scrum teams is really
that grounding in understanding
complexity and empiricism right um so
that's something that we really focus on
and double down those two those two
things so the first one is is complexity
right
you there is a
difference as you as you increase in
complexity and usually it's an
exponential scale right right the type
the type of processes and practices that
you use need to change as you increase
in complexity so if we have very low
complexity um let's say it's just
complicated or even it's simple then we
can probably plan further out into the
future and and and be okay right we can
plan let's say we're running a a a
textile mill and we have a thousand
machines producing fabric um in general
you'll be able to predict how long to a
very high degree of accuracy it will
take to fulfill whatever order comes in
right because you understand the Cadence
of the machines you understand how long
it takes to retool the machines for
different types of fabrics or different
patterns you you already understand all
of that stuff up front and it's fairly
consistent there's the odd thing a
machine breaks down something else goes
wrong somebody gets injured right these
are all things that can surprise you or
get in the way but generally the
variance is very small as soon as you
get into really high variance work the
aps really focuses on that piece that
high variance work and quantifies what
does it look like and how does it feel
right how does it feel for the people
involved um so we do that through an
exercise that enables people to
experience complexity depending on which
class you go to will depend on what
experience that is uh we've done um
building websites uh we've done uh
Minecraft right that's my favorite one
is is using Minecraft in that class um
to to create that complexity so that
people actually feel it once they
realize the difference between
complicated and complex they feel it
then we can start talking about well how
do we how do we mitigate risk in that
world of um of complexity and that's
where we focus very heavily on
transparency inspection and adaption
right that's why we talk about
definition of done really heavily we
talk about the product backlog and why
it needs to be transparent um we talk
about the the Sprint backlog and why it
needs to be transparent all of those
things are the important piece cuz
everything else is built on top of it
there's no point in doing a Sprint
review unless you have a transparent
product to look at there's no point in
doing a Sprint planning unless you have
a transparent product backlog to look at
you need those um artifacts those three
artifacts in scrum with their
commitments in order to be able to do
everything else and that's what makes it
valuable thanks for watching the video
If you enjoyed it please like follow And
subscribe I always reply to comments and
if you want to have a about this or
anything else agile scrum or devops then
please book a coffee with me through
naked
agility