Hey
okay welcome
makes agility I name
national scrum trainer
but once
naked agility is available for DevOps
and agile training and consulting
contact us for a free consultation
[Music]
Oh so I am wanting to have a little ad
event a few things this is my mmm office
hours
office hours is where I answer any
questions that I'd asked Baris is going
to be moving from Tuesday's to
Wednesday's as of next week but you can
effectively ask me I think I have a link
here to go to forum where you can ask
anything
this is somewhere where
I nobody knows who you are and what you
said so don't put anything in the
content that
we don't but I have a few questions that
have come up over the last couple of
weeks and I just finished a professional
scrum master class for a program who to
cling in are we a regular class that I
and check for questions we are going to
talk about and story point evolution
I the conversation on Twitter with
somebody asked whether what I thought of
story points
I was buying to Daniel the counties
thanks that at story point have damaged
are
our industry over the last 20 years as
put it back amount but I replied and
said I I agree with Daniel um I used to
think that story points were awesome and
I don't so we'll chat about that and I
talked about team size because I think
the traditional six plus or minus three
is
as we get or our complex at building
software and I had a question in my
class around how to sell emergent
architecture decoders if you do want to
ask a question and you are on either
LinkedIn Facebook periscope or gup-a
please feel free ask the question in the
comments I should be able to
as they come in maybe a delay but be
able to see as they connect platforms
you can also go ask questions form and I
will ask
so I have just a quick update on the the
classes that will be running the Oslo
class has just finished they only have
one more class on my schedule I'm going
to update my shape
liked more
at
but I have a professional scrum unban
cool
annual Vacanti
aims on currently have a couple of
students registered and we are hoping to
have a lot of fun in that class as we
use a new technique to de live a virtual
classroom and to eight experience Daniel
I found
eita analytics
or flow better and bring that in
part of this
old
ah so let me see
Oh first up is story point evolution
story points are they've had an
interesting life been around for quite a
long time and I think I agree with
Daniel Daniel candy said that they've
damaged our let me see if I can find
that tweet
and you'll
you
or we go as photos
but
this
you
oh I made me small
so the reason that I don't like story
points is they don't actually provide
value I'm sure Daniel would do a much
better job of describing the additional
value that you get then different
measures story points are something that
we've been trying to use in the agile
community for a long as they are
relative estimation
they don't have a have a em value
outside of the team because there
reflective of how the team
effort there's a bolt they are not
something that we prepare across teams
because each team come up with different
values they are not something that we
can measure that team by but they are
traditionally used by the development
team to understand based on their
history of point delivery like ah city
based on that and how many how many
things they might be able to bring into
their sprint and also at the
product owner looking at what's the
progression that acting with the back
lock problem the story points is that
they're their standard deviation of what
you think you're going to get what you
get and maybe that that em worst case
the best case that standard deviation is
so wide
or than 30%
the starvation is so wide the ability to
predict so 30% sprint own sprint a huge
difference
getting stuff and not getting stuff so
what can we do
stat well M as part of the PSK class you
can go download and read the Kanban
guide for scrum team we talk instead
about through report doesn't care about
size whereas velocity at story points
cares about the size of the item so
you're gonna sum up the story points
backlog all right in the spin backlog
paucity sorry Rupert and only cares
about the number of items per unit of
time so that unit of time could be print
sum how many things that I deliver one
of the advantages of that is if the team
want to game that ie they want to make
the numbers bigger to look better they
need to reduce the size of the items
size of the items is good get smaller
batches and actually
I process a lot more quickly but it also
allows us to look and instead if we
collect throughput so we calculate very
we know our throughput we go are at
cycle time from when we decided the work
has started to when we played ends at
collect our am working process how many
items currently have between by unions
and we'd work start even when it
finished no matter how many columns
an idea of how long things have in light
are those even you can have it bonds as
well you can break it out that way but
really
if we can model that we can use em
littles law
get an understanding of um if we reduce
our work in process that we could
potentially increase our cycle time and
if we want to deliver more things we
need actually smaller we can't tell any
of that just from
story points because they're not just
size dependent but an objective measure
rather than a subjective measure
so I started off at liking story points
and I then moved towards thinking 30
points make sense for immature teams
because they're easy to understand easy
to pick up quickly I get started with
but that the limitations of story points
I think cause more damage
at a time and I would rather a team
started they as possible being at at
their throughput liked in their cycle
time broke item aging and process if
they start that sooner rather than later
they get used to it a lot more quickly
they're able to look at the data and
maybe make better optimizations make
better decisions
from events as legal but that was my
thought process my journey towards that
story points are a bad idea and maybe
not as against them as Daniel is but I
definitely think there are a thing of
the thing of the past
rusty
Lord so the second one second question
was around team size and we talked a lot
in in scrum about team size and we have
our particular questions in the
[Music]
but particular questions in the scrum
training around
and a team be smaller than B yes it can
the scrum guide recommends it at team
at 3:00 and 9:00 but it doesn't say they
have to be the other question is usually
a
oh yeah first they can t be better than
19 teams can be way better than 9 is
that gonna be optimal are they going to
be able to dictate and understand what
everybody's working on and work together
effectively that might be a different
question in that space though um what
what I would like to discuss is I work
with a lot of team I worked for a long
time as a at Microsoft MVP
yes used to be a fast and I was EV UPS
I've been working with those along with
the other for a long time and their
teams are bigger ballet than at night
they have team and in 12 and the reason
they have teams between 10 and 12 is
because they're doing a lot more things
inside of the sprint or that they're
able both having high quality working
software in production Utley
something that they use is a state
reliability techniques but they have
engineers inside of the sprint and I
think if my understanding is correct it
might have changed since the last time
that I spoke to but and they have two
people at pair sprint allocated to the
website reliability
in each team there are two people
dealing with that so anytime they have
an outage they are the first responders
that outage not interrupting the team
working on adding value to the product
they may have to bring in other people
that are currently adding bout figure
that out there but they are your
hopefully not going to have an outage
if there is an outage the root cause
analysis this and the time they're there
they're dedicating up up spending that
time to pause analysis figure out all of
the things that might need to change in
order to make the product better some of
them may be small things some of them
may be big architectural change
get those things onto product backlog
and then as their day-to-day job when
they're not dealing Energon
their job is to work only those site
reliability tasks making your
application more stable efficient less
buggy and our architecture and I would
use an option that rule site reliability
engineering is rotated through the team
so that you don't have somebody just
through time as a specialist in that
role we need to get it running
X
option now they also give responsibility
to their team function obviously they've
got SR Easton so teams that build a
feature or responsible buying a feature
and doing and maintaining it in
production so they have to cite what
telemetry they're going to capture they
have to look at that telemetry
everything's good partly there was that
there was SR ease
but it does leave the rest of the team
be the focus adding value and be
interrupted that means that the team
needs to be that little bit bigger -
bigger than you
from team
well but maybe 10 to 12 is an extra
person still than the name we generally
look at and the reason that they have
that extra at person is that they're
doing more stuff during print in a
traditional project market product cycle
and especially the old TFS product cycle
from the door they would have shipped to
production once a week Bruce and had a
service pack F we at so every year here
they have a service pack then I respect
I'm in that model a lot of work got left
end cycle you have a code freeze and
they have to go and stabilize the code
and that's our Ollie and be my technical
debt fixing bugs that kind of thing but
there's also work to secure the product
to run security checks to run
performance benchmarks do all of that
work and now in modern techniques
that they are using they run all of
those things inside of the team
so they're not running them
they're not running them in our
secondary age I do the tea by a
different Department gives them feedback
Veltman tea elves making sure but good
purity the automation around the
security that I knew done and even the
rest he could write exercises to get the
additional stuff the theme
so their teams are a little bit bigger
and I think that is an indication of
things to come from any team
that may be the traditional thing the
people about 5 to 6 from team
not going to be enough as we bring and
not not only have we got quarters and
testers
also bring in security experts and
operations and functions
metrics as we're bringing those things
that are national
Lilly understand
quality of the work that the Bing and
the act
half on production and on
and what ad looks like I am a trade to
know what broken something or whether
the varmints or whether are actually
using the feet
eight or all thing
I did be
all our tea
bigger and so
I want to see
bigger than elf that's that for me is
quite a quite a big team but I think
it's within the context of the
organization some organizations will be
all of those things talking about and
still have small teams other
organizations will have to add
so that was the the second one we talked
about at story points and moving towards
the the more and style metrics talked
about
so the other one that I had was a
emergent architecture I think I'm going
to be interested if I can have a decent
answer but this one the question was
around how do you sell marriage in
architecture to be cold
that idea that we're not going to know
up front it's a it's not possible for us
to know up front and there may be things
that we would have added to architecture
in a waterfall or terrific project
management model where we would have
made a bunch of decisions or features
that we actually build
I would be a yeast and to have our
architecture in urge over time maybe in
the first sprint wheel and fit I'm
adding value that's the time we're we're
working with architecture
are you bow you we cannot get speaker
name
time to do it I'll have at slack
arge amounts of new phone
but selling imagine architecture to
stakeholders the organization I think
this is this is something that's just a
change in a organizations
organized in order to facilitate
adjuvant practices I'm not talking about
just agile within buffer engineering
team rest of the organization in order
to take advantage but speed
both we're team and really that I mean
let's go back a bit because that's
that's not the point the hope the whole
point is that a business needs to be
able to take advantage of opportunity as
they arise in the market to be able to
see an opportunity go let's let's build
something around that take advantage of
that whether that's getting a new
product into the market whether that's
adding new features into the market ah
whatever that is if you look at the
current at covent crisis and the number
of the shift that organizations have
made in the fever's
or delivering especially in the space of
virtual pain so all the video
conferencing applications ramped up not
only their infrastructure but
potentially certain features Microsoft
have already started rolling out 3 by 3
instead of 2 by 2 windows they've
already started rolling out at hand
raised as an infant part of the product
and other things end call was one of
them the the zoom add to pivot a from
adding new features towards adding
security and actually adding the
incorruption said was in the product
actually doing things very different
other than before the crisis happened
and even things like I use our platform
called Lord order to pour game is
remotely
and by four months ago they were lucky
if they hit 5,000 you
even be accessing their system now
they're having 5,000
having to ramp up Orman's scale their
server skill their instances like
everybody else
but these pivots of both what features
were going to build when we're going to
miss them as well as scaling up are
things that organizations that have been
able to have it like that word but
change what they're doing to be
prioritised
Burke the organization's I've been able
to that more quickly are the ones that
have been able to take advantage of this
opportunity or them to our market share
to visibility across the board so it's
important
are able to sell the ideas behind
architecture idea
in our ability to change a longer time
and
I don't know that I did a good job of
bring that but you will probably let me
know in the comments and I don't see any
comments coming in so let me just check
my list of things and I did have our
conversation with um a couple of folks
after the class around how do you get
executive buy-in who do you get people
and God executive and leadership who are
not yet on
process the ideas ility of changing the
week not just level but about the
organization too
ditch the idea of the tip hierarchies
our mental model move towards stick
Dylan
a shallower hierarchies that's I I
didn't have a good answer at how do we
change I mostly worked with
organizations I've already decided to
change
bring me in to help them with training
help them coach and they're there
already on a path when I have the first
conversation with
yeah I didn't have an answer for that if
you have an answer to that please let me
know
we could get you on
I know at out that topic so if you're
interested in talking about executive
buy-in
well I think that's all of the content
that I had just now I don't see any
questions coming in now let me just
check the booth oh there's only two
answers though
please ask questions I have our link to
ask questions anonymously you can also
put them in the chat law here and I will
happily answer them
so if you it would be really helpful for
me if you would subscribe to YouTube
rubber option button is and hopefully I
will either see you in class
soon hopefully 9 o'clock or so empty or
in another class that we should do
oh and if you're in Atlanta I am cool
I'm helping facilitate professional from
product with Russel Miller anta find it
on the scrubland org website
pretty awesome class so I think our
YouTube up for that if your
anywhere
okay thank you very much naked agility
is available for DevOps and agile
training and consultant
contact us for a free consultation