as well just in case
just in case there's a problem
so is it just it's just the three of us
four of us
yeah well let's talk about board games
instead
so did you get my link for the mural
[Music]
perfect
i see you're in there uh i definitely
give you some recommendations
four for two player two player yeah two
player games
um i've got quite a few quite a few good
ones in that category and it depends it
depends how complicated you want to do
things
uh it's one of those things i was
looking at you know um
because
after after you put the kid to sleep we
just watched a tv but something
different from watching tv yeah i know
it's such a pain in the butt
you're sitting there watching tv going
like we could be doing something else
um
[Music]
it is a lot more interactive and that's
actually why i uh enjoy them because you
get a level of interaction that you
don't get
um
and that's where it depends how complex
the thing is
uh so whether you like stories
whether you like luck
so one of the first choices is whether
you like luck or you don't like luck
right that's one of your first choices
because american games are full of luck
so you're going to roll dice and then
you know so
you you're at the the behest of the dice
and then europe european games tend to
be more
um
uh strategy based so that you can get
games that are zero luck yeah it's all
about strategy um
so
let's oh i've got for some reason
there's a bit of text sitting in the
middle of that
i will ignore it
um
so if i just summon since there's only
uh four of us
we can we can we can do this
uh uh
just as a group we probably don't need
many breakout rooms okay
so
i've got a number of kind of statements
or questions or
um some things here so we can just go we
can just go through them
and see
uh what's going on
so the first one there is uh what are
requirements
what are they
i guess requirements
um
certain objectives of the business
needs in order to fulfill their
um decision making or
operational
um
needs
okay
so think things we need
yeah
perhaps
perhaps things that are required to
happen
happen that aren't happening yet
okay
what else um
[Music]
what else could requirements
be okay it could be a change on existing
process or system
yep could be a change to the existing
system enhancement
could be it could be compliance with
a law
yeah
okay
so what are not requirements
i think it is not i think i think it's
relative to the
user's
need so to speak so if they don't want
it then it's not a requirement
um
yes
i can i can definitely go with that
what else
anything out of scope
well it's still a
wow yes see that's why i don't like the
word requirement
right
because uh but it as a general thing
meaning something people want
um then it's okay for a requirement to
be able to scope right i would posit
that it's not really a requirement then
um but
uh
i would suggest that our requirements
are not solutions
right if you got the solution in there
um they're
they're the requirements don't
necessarily represent the final
deliverable
they're what we think we want
at the start which might not be the same
as what we need at the end
does that make sense yeah yeah yeah
they're not generally treated that way
are they
no
um so they're not a source of truth
about what the product does
so one of the common mistakes that i see
organizations make is they give the same
requirements to their engineers to build
and their testers to write test cases
for
now suddenly you've got
two different
opinions on what those requirements mean
and what happens when the testers go to
test what the engineers have created
it always fails
right it's almost never going to be
successful so you're maximizing the
amount of rework you're maximizing the
amount of consistency
um i i don't like the word requirements
for that reason i like the word
desirements stuff we would like the
product to do that it doesn't do yet i
think that just reflects what it is more
doesn't it
yeah yeah
um
how do you how do you do your
requirements just now
well i just started this week so i
haven't done
do you write user stories just now
we will be
but um i don't know maybe maybe dave
david has started something
well i probably haven't done anything i
do
receive requirements to people that
people want but i guess i've not really
been using an
agile methodology so in that way it's
hard to sort of give examples but i mean
asia very small small small contain
tasks but it's
you do you get you get a requirement you
get a request like i want this to do
that or yes so you get you get given a
solution
you are asked yeah you're asked to
implement a solution
i already know what problem i want to
solve i already know how i want it
solved
david just do this
to an extent yeah yeah yeah i know that
there's always wiggle room but yeah yeah
[Music]
where do you store your requirements
uh
at the moment for example we have sort
of a basic spreadsheet of okay
tasks and sort of notes and
things people said they wanted to do
with those tasks
very it's a very basic system
as your devops yeah
i i would definitely recommend not
storing them in excel
only because it's very difficult for two
people to edit it at the same time
um unless of course you start on
sharepoint and then maybe that's okay
uh but you can
if you like
the excel view
you can
plug
your excel sheet into azure devops um
and have your excel render a query from
azure devops in
excel and then you can do stuff with the
data
so if you if you like excel because it
gives you some extra special powers and
maybe david dura a excel
guru
who knows how to do all of the pivot
table craziness for for to get the data
and reports that you want
um there is a a plug-in for
office
uh which i can't remember what it's
called but it's the
visual studio
as your devops plug-in for office that's
probably the best query i've got
um and it it gives you uh the ability to
to to connect um an excel sheet
into
um azure devops and you can both
uh uh create
work items so if you already have all of
your data in excel you can just import
it into it into azure devops
there are some nuance to that but it can
be done reasonably easily
um
reasonably easily
and then you can you can have an
interactive sheet where you can see
here's all of my
features
uh here's the current state that they're
at and it will change dynamically and
stay up to date
so that's quite good
you know that is it that
interesting because i mean we are here
because we want to move away from just
having it on an excel table and into a
more important way of doing it yeah that
gives you a little bit of a halfway
house because lots people like excel
because they can do all the pivot table
malarkey um and and and they're they're
they understand excel functions but they
don't necessarily understand this new
azure devops thing and so it gets you
the best of both worlds
at least in the interim
don't tell anybody that there's also a
plug-in for ms project don't tell
anybody that
that's that's that's not a good idea
um but there is you can you can have if
you if you do a lot of if you use ms
project for dependency management you
can have it create the predecessor
successor links
in azure devops and then you can do
stuff with it you can actually do
dependency management in azure devops as
well
so there's probably i think is there a
session i think there is a session we're
going to have on
specifically on azure devops and how to
how to interact with it again we only
have 90 minutes i
i have i even have a five day class that
i run
just on how to use as your devops um so
we can definitely i can definitely show
you where all the features are
but maybe can't don't necessarily we
don't necessarily have time to dive into
how they all work right how you get use
and benefit out of them
so what what is a user story
if we've heard of this thing what is a
user story
anybody got a
is it talking in sort of a wide
way of
kind of how they want things to happen
oh that's a good one
talking in a wide way i like that
although wide means something different
in glasgow but i know what you
um
wide means you want to fight that's
that's what it means in it but you want
a conversation right so maybe maybe it
kind of kind of works out i guess a
fight is a conversation in glasgow i
don't know
that seemed that seems perfectly
reasonable
has anybody been to glasgow
yes
does does that sound reasonable
no well technically i was only passing
through where i went to like a museum in
the city center just looked around let's
go
so i you probably went to the
the big
the car museum okay because
oh the the transport museum it's awesome
that's fun yeah yeah yeah yeah transport
museum's awesome then went to
one of the shopping streets i think
i would either be sucky hall street or
argyle street but sucky
we might be renaming it
okay because sucky hole
is
the surname of uh
evil person
who you know they used to like hold the
evil people up on pedestals and now
they're gonna
revisit that idea
um so i have so for me user stories i
know you asked the question is the
stories user story captures
what the um
what the user wants
um
why they want it
um maybe because of their rule or an
activity they need to do okay
it also captures
um how they know you'd have delivered
what they requested based on setting
high level
checks or
how they validate your delivered what
what they have requested but those are
kind of kind of like the key components
i i remember from user story so it
normally starts with something like i
want
xyz
because i am the tax manager running
all these reports and i know you have
given me this when
i can do x y z or something something
along those lines we are going to
definitely get to that but there are
some characteristics
of of user stories that we want to think
about
um so i've got a little uh it's called
the invest
circuit business
yeah yeah a lot of people are familiar
with invest like they've heard of it um
but maybe the the the implications
aren't always
uh clear so i've created this little uh
um
fun fun well i think it's fun exercise
we'll see if you think it's fun as well
uh welcome david are you on the mural
other david not david b david mcsee
your mic's very quiet and fading in and
out it might be that you're
i don't know if it's sticking up
let me shout out
ah
so you're on backup
yeah
what laptop are you using that's
terrible sound
uh a terrible laptop yeah yeah it sounds
like it you need to get yourself a
surface
they have they have a hd on the
directional microphones that filter out
background noise automatically at a
hardware level that's pretty cool
okay that's that's not what i'm on right
now i'm on i'm on mental levels of
uh
um
i don't know capability
it is
so i if if you're if you're are ever
looking for for stuff to augment
your home office i heartily recommend
elgato
as a as a product vendor they do
streaming for you know live streamers
um so they have good cameras they have
really good microphones that are in the
in in a
expensive but not too expensive range
but very the right price for the quality
if that makes sense
like you can go mental i've got
colleagues who have bought slr
cameras and don't get as good picture
quality as the camera i'm using right
now which was not 1500 pounds for an slr
yes i have an elgato uh face cam
um i don't have an elgato microphone but
i do recommend it over this one this one
is overly expensive for what it does uh
if i'd known that elgato existed i would
have gotten that
um
i really rate the elgato stuff so i've
got i've got elgato lights
um
a little elgato
boom
thing
um and various other elgato thing and an
elgato um green screen for when i need a
green screen which is not just now
because
you guys are friendly so i don't need a
green screen
uh so let's have a look at the the the
invest
circuit here that i've got let's start
with um independent
uh so
what are
what's the value
of of
stories or requirements or items that
are on your backlog what's what's the
value of them being independent
um it's a small task so um you can
teleport within the day
at the same time
concurrent development maybe yeah
well i like that idea
it prevents too many blockers
yeah prevents blockers that's a good one
also looks good when you start taking
them off
um
i'm actually going to put the
like checking there's a lot of power in
checking things off we've
i've done that thing awesome i feel good
right let's move on to the next thing
i i totally agree with that um
psychologically it is very very
important
yeah good for morale
um
well these are these are quite good uh
let's go let's let's go to
negotiable
what's the value in things being
i was going to mention another point
there's always easy to
push back on smaller requirements in
your i mean
you've got loads of users so it's easier
to just
you know
push back on a couple of them because
it's not it's not a huge chunk of it
i agree and and
pushing back on it is
this one negotiable right prioritization
what what was that
it helps that way with prior
prioritization
i'm going to use ordering okay
and david you need to go look up
prioritization in the dictionary
does not mean what you think it means
but let's not go there
prioritization is a singular
you can only have one
when you prioritize something you make
it the most important thing
but it's the one most important thing
whereas if you had three things that's
not prioritized
yeah it's one of those weird words that
is just
a bad spat word bad word
i don't know who invented that crap but
it was bad
it's probably one of shakespeare's words
you're pretty much
25 25 of all words in the english
language were invented
by shakespeare and therefore it's kind
of
25 reasonably accurate to say probably
shakespeare's fault
did anybody else know that
50 000 words
in the english language shakespeare just
made up
that's what it makes the english
language so difficult to learn it's not
your first language i i agree but you
can kind of ignore a lot of those
words
and i think the thing that makes it
difficult is
in a lot of other languages the
adjective comes before the noun whereas
here the noun comes before the adjective
is that the way it works
no yes the other way around so
a green kettle
right whereas in spanish it's kettle
green that really confuses my wife's
uh first language is spanish so
um
i have a lot of fun with some of those
things for sure
so what's the volume things being
negotiable actually my my mom's language
is the same as english like you do
being kept would be a green girl what
what's what what language is it
okay
yeah yeah
well see that's a sensible language then
that's the way i think about it does it
have gender
like does is a table feminine for no
reason whatsoever
cool i like i like that language
southern european languages all have
gender and they suck whereas germanic
germanic and uh celtic languages do not
have gender in in the words do you know
what's really funny the the the word in
spanish for gender neutral is masculine
isn't that hilarious
they've got they've got genders as well
yeah yeah
but it probably there's probably a
filter there from arabic and
greek
through to
that part the rest of the world yeah
it's either the greeks fault the romans
fault or
arabic's fault that's that's the way i
look at it
oh or shakespeare or shakespeare yeah
yeah they're all the culprits
um
i always find it funny that in
saudi arabia they don't use arabic
numerals they use indian numerals
you will know that the first when you
land and you're walking up to the
immigration test desk and the person
says go to desk four and you're like
what the hell one's desk four because
those numbers do not
relate to
uh arabic numerals it was very confusing
it's like lines and hash marks and stuff
i'm not familiar with indian numerals
oh that's true
it's a bit mental
back to negotiable
why is it important for things to be
negotiable
right oh flexibility
is going to be
especially when it comes to solutions
and deliverables you have to be flexible
otherwise
you're asking for trouble
you're always going to get what you want
yeah so things kind of need to be
negotiable so we can be flexible
next one's valuable
why is it important for things to be
valuable i mean it sounds like that's a
no-brainer
yeah
no but if you have a thousand user
stories
and you try to give that to
you know your project team they're gonna
they're gonna laugh at you like
100 user stories for one requirement
for whatever it is so you're gonna
you're gonna
you know only pick the ones that you
actually need because otherwise you're
delivering too far out
selecting things we need
um
any other good good
reasons why things should be valuable
well you know the benefits it can help
you with the ordering of deliverables
well why would you even bother ordering
it at all if it wasn't valuable yeah
yeah yeah that's good
these are good
estimatable
why why what's the value in things being
estimated
you covered yesterday yesterday but
about
you know running analytics if you've got
loads of
broken down user stories you're able to
estimate okay look
given that the rate we're closing these
user stories you know how
how far off you will be
and complete the rest of it so planning
right planning planning just planning
yeah for planning and um
and sheddling as well you know which
sprint you can put it into and stuff
like that
i'm going to put understanding in there
if we can't estimate it
if if you look at that thing and go
ah that i don't i don't understand that
enough
to estimate it
can you take it into the sprint
no no because you don't understand it so
what the hell are you doing why are you
not refining that item
so estimating that to um
because if you've got a simple task
that'll take too long that means you
haven't got enough resources to complete
the smaller tasks
if a task you take one day he's taking
five days i missed that developers pc so
i've got a little tip it's a little bug
bearer of mine let's call them people
instead of resources
let's do that
uh
so it helps with people
right although you can't say peopling
but you can say resourcing yeah whatever
well
it could be
you're 25 likely to be too true um but
that
resources are replaceable
people are not
if you get another person to do the same
job they don't have the same knowledge
they don't have the same skills and they
don't have the same background
resources are something that that you
can easily replace like i have 500 backs
of bags of grain that's my resources
they're all roughly the same
um
but if i have two software developers i
can't necessarily swap one for the other
because one might be a net developer and
the other might be a java developer
that's that's a
poor example but
that's an easy to quantify example but
there are lots of not easy to quantify
examples
make sense
maybe some of you don't like working
with each other
right and it's you're not going to have
the same
investment in the in the story in the
thing you're building
so estimatable
why should things be small
i think we mentioned it before well we
mentioned ordering before
ordering is important for being small
what else
easy to come i'm quick to complete also
easy oh yeah uh
i'll put fast feedback that's probably
the phrase i like there
do you notice i have to look at my
keyboard when i'm tight typing anybody
else
shows how much i type
juicy's rest so this is good things
being small
how small should things be
small enough so that there's no major
overhead
small enough sometimes
i i like just small enough is probably
small a good one but so there's not
major overhead so there's a balance to
be had yeah
between making things too small
and the overhead is too high
like
um
[Music]
there's no point in taking five thousand
one minute
stories into the sprint
yeah right because you'll spend more
time
updating the work items and you will
actually doing the work
um
but the the the that they can be really
small
like i i would expect
in general i would expect a team to do
to do more than one story per day
that's what i would like to see as a
floor cadence
more than one thing per day being
delivered that's what i'd like to see
but yeah can't always get what you want
but the rule of thumb there is half the
length
of an iteration and that's from xp
extreme programming
oh here's a good one testable
why should things be testable
so you know if they
work
right that was uh because you you said
two things there done them and right
so that's if they're done and they work
right that's maybe maybe
[Music]
um so you can sign and sign off
okay
sign off
uh
validate business value
[Music]
well these are quite good we've got a
few things on there
what is how do you currently visualize
your work
how do you how do you do you get a
whiteboard
and draw pictures of what it is you want
to make and then collaborate on those
pictures
the larger tasks we do yeah
the nice thing about user interfaces
is every single person here speaks ux
and ui
right we all we all
think about products
in that way or we can all think about
products in that way and our customers
can as well
because that's how we interact with most
products
is ui
so user stories
were specifically designed
to describe
behaviors of users interacting with
products
they are not useful for non-functional
requirements
they are not useful for developing apis
they're useful for developing
things
that your users interact with
does that make sense
yeah
it is okay
to have both user stories
and use cases
and non-functional requirements on the
same backlog
everything on your backlog doesn't have
to be in the same format okay
yeah okay i just want to make make sure
because let's people try and fit weird
stuff into
into user stories
uh like like as a product owner i want
to support 30 000 simultaneous users so
that
i can have lots of business right
that's the most nonsensical user story
ever when you could just write must
support 50 000 simultaneous users
and you get the ideas and the intent
across with that simple statement
without having to do any thought
all right so this is a a little we're
going to do
we're going to talk about a few things
around
uh at this example here
so if if we had a whole day to do a
workshop i would do a bunch of examples
and have you
draw
your product
right or a page from your product or a
box from your product
uh but
since we don't have a day we've only got
90 minutes
and here's one i prepared earlier
it's not i stole it from somewhere
um but it's a
a system to hold recipes
right does anybody here cook anybody
cook
have you ever cooked your folder recipe
once in a while once in a while yeah
yeah
sometimes we just make it up as we go
along and see if it works yeah that's
the best way to do it
it's not always the best way
i'm gonna
i
don't don't try and make a sponge cake
that way because it will not work out
okay you want to follow a recipe till
you know what you're doing sometimes
following a recipe till you know what
you're doing is a good idea
how do you make bread well i need to be
able to make bread and then i can change
the recipe to suit my flavor and taste
so in this in this example we are
storing uh
a recipe with ingredients
right and then uh a notes for cooking
right so we've got a system that just
stores recipes and presents them to
users does that kind of make sense
yeah yeah
that's so that's that's that's our
that's our that's our context
um
so let let's
look at the anatomy
of a user story i know uh
jo jabel is that how you say your name
jabel yep cool
awesome i'm getting better at this
um
so jabel you mentioned i think it was
you that mentioned uh as a
some role i want
so that
format of a user story is this familiar
to you guys
yes
let me summon so we're looking at the
same thing on the mural
so that as a role
what might you have in that space where
it says roll
can you just
what you call
the person that's requesting your
business person
you might have a named business person
yeah as as bob from accounting
right i want yeah that's good because
it's incredibly specific
but you could you could just you could
generalize a little bit and say
um as a a
a year-end accounting user
right as opposed to as a monthly
accounting user
yeah so that that's okay too
but it needs to be much more specific
than user
i see a lot of user stories that just
say as a user i want and it's like no
that's you being lazy
let's figure out what user why user
yeah because the user stories i've used
in the past it always says as a user
yeah
because it it's it's too generic
right anybody's a user there's no
there's no intent there's no
understanding of who you're building it
for and that part of the user story is
supposed to tell us who we're building
it for
of course we're building it for users
everything's for users but which users
what are they trying to achieve
so we're going to have some examples for
this recipe uh system i think i've got
them below yes i do
uh in fact let's while we're talking
about aza
here i've got
recipe recorder
right somebody entering recipes into the
system
a chef who's following the recipe i
don't know if chef's probably a good
idea cooker might be better but um
as a chef recipe seeker
right so i'm looking for recipes
i i
an individual person david
you could be any of these
user roles couldn't you
yeah
in using the
system so it doesn't have to represent a
person it can represent
an intent
what is the intent of this user so
recipe recorder chef recipe seeker and
cook with existing ingredients
right why is cook with existing
ingredients important what does that
make you think of
i've seen it before and i know roughly
what i what i need to cook it but i've
forgotten a part of the recipe
or
here's the stuff i've got in my fridge
what can i make with it
oh yes
yeah
how often have you gone to the fridge
and opened it and gone what the hell can
i make
pop it in and pop it into the the system
search based on
ingredients you have
right questions
yeah
yes david
your microphone is horrendous you're
fading in and out
let me talk about it
yeah yeah yeah that works sometimes it's
awesome and sometimes it's just not very
good
like at the start of your question it's
awesome and then it kind of fades out i
don't know what
what's happening with your
did everybody else hear the same thing
as me
yeah
as well yeah it's not not just me then
that works
it's always the thing when you're in one
of these meetings is it just me or is it
everybody yeah yeah
that's why i can't move out i can't move
house
i can't move house i'm in one of the few
houses in my area that have virgin media
and i get uh i get gigabit internet here
everywhere else it's 80 megabit on bt
and i am not willing to suffer through
that
uh
do you compile the draft user list
before creating stories
i think it's a good idea
the first time you start to think about
users yeah i i potentially would create
this list
i would say what what are the
the high level activities
that users are going to do in this
category um so
entering entering recipes following
recipes
finding recipes and that extra one there
is cooked with existing ingredients i
would have that list first before i
started creating
we might find more as we go
but i want to start with
um with some kind of list
it's kind of how you know who you're
building your product for
um and then the second part is i want a
feature
right
what is the user trying to achieve
what's their goal
right
and then the third part is what do they
get out of it why do they want this
so a good example of that
is uh many years ago when i worked for
merrill lynch i had to build um a
crm system
for for for a group of people
and as
as a
um
[Music]
call center
member
i want
a list of
people
right
so you as a developer
go off and create
a list of people first name surname
address
right that sounds pretty good doesn't it
mortgage company first name surname
address
value of local properties i don't know
something like that
but
i did that and i completely missed the
point and they came back and said
what we want to easily call people
we want to phone them
so having the phone number in the first
list is probably a good idea
right so this
why do they want to use it what are they
trying to achieve i want to call people
okay what are you going to talk about on
this call we're going to talk about
renewing their mortgage okay maybe you
want to surface some of that information
on that that that view
does that make sense
yes
so i have three
uh
three user stories here
as a recipe seeker
i want to search by tag values
so that i can find recipes via ad hoc
tags i like uh
i like
jolof rice
right
so i want to to to see all recipes
tagged
uh with jill off that particular flavor
of the rice um so that i can see what
are all the different things that i can
make the meals that i can make that go
with go with that item
right that could be a thing that i want
to search for
and maybe maybe stretching the
determination of tag there
as a recipe recorder i want to tag my
recipes so that i can find them
via ad hoc tags
right so there's there's a searcher and
a recorder both want tags
right so we may implement both of those
stories as a single thing might we
but they have different intent different
activity
so one is uh um
searching
by tags the other one is adding recipes
and adding tags so adding tags
and then as a recipe seeker
i want to search by recipe ingredient so
that i can find recipes for things i
have
those all sound pretty reasonable don't
they
sorry i think your audio is dropping in
and out there miners
yeah i don't know just me or for other
people
sorry it was just me
was it for everybody or just me or just
i'm not sure if the headset disconnected
reconnecting or yeah he keeps cutting
out of it
i i just changed my
settings
so let's see if it uh it perseveres
let me let me check that again
yeah
nice oppression is off
i'm on crisp
how am i signing now
okay you said you sound good now yeah
your video is fine but that's another
thing that's weird you get a whole drop
out but it's just it was just the audio
for a little bit there then it's
probably it was probably my my system
but i have um
i've tweaked it so hopefully it'll um
it'll just work
cheers
so
yeah yeah i need an elgato mic instead
of my my crappy blue yeti
x pro thing
um it's actually my second one
because the other one kept crashing
imagine the microphone crashing how
complicated is it
so let's look at uh we'll probably just
do one of these
um so i have
i perhaps gonna gonna gonna draw
um
my my
ui
and then
we need to have a conversation
right and part of those things that
allow us
to see the behaviors that we have on
this ui if you were looking at this ui
you might have a conversation with your
your product owner or with your team or
with your stakeholders right some users
um and say well what happens when you
click on the home link
right what happens
uh
can we sort this data grid would you
like to be able to sort it
what happens when the cancel button is
clicked
what about if no ingredients are entered
if there are no ingredients entered what
what happens well we want the the add
button to be disabled okay so you can't
add a recipe with no ingredients
that make sense
part of that conversation
so where's me uh
um
[Music]
uh seeker
search
recorder add tags let's do this one
what questions
might you have i'm gonna be your product
owner
i don't have my hat here but i'm gonna
be your product owner
um
so the the user store we want to discuss
is as a recipe recorder i want to tag my
recipes so that i can find them
via ad hoc tags
what questions do you have
what form do you want that tagging to
take is it a flag is it a text now is it
uh
so are we selecting tags or
text entering is that what you're asking
yes
so
um
also generated from
other information you've input
okay
there's some more low-level things that
are are i think more important here
right you're going to be adding tags
what questions might you have for the
product tour
how about the tanks think about the tags
what form the tags take okay what does
that mean
uh
do you is it like a are you
is the tag the form of a flag did it
like fight did you write it out five
stars is it just text do you try and
capture text it's it's a it's like a tag
with words
sorry my headset keeps muting me
keywords
yes
it's keywords
so it is keywords
so now you know its keywords would you
want to ask me
david
david they'll get to dave the other dave
is gone it's just you
answer the question
uh we are
on as a recipe recorder i want to tag my
recipes so that i can find them via
tags so we're adding new recipes
do you want a list of tags provided to
you already existing tags
uh
we can add that when it's enough
different
um
[Music]
should we
right so i think that goes with these
these three
right
but if we know that the recipes are
keywords
if you've got to type something what are
the important questions to ask
it's the input method
the keyboards probably
what do you mean by what's the input
method
um i suppose it's been how how people
are doing what they're doing computer so
they've got a nice big keyboard or are
they on a phone so they might also
use voice recognition
both uh phone and
uh um and we're gonna leave voice
recognition and stuff that's up to
that's the platform issue that's not our
problem
you're building a web page allows people
to enter recipes
they add tags
do you want it to
what's it
um
to autofill when you're typing so once
you start typing it starts to kill you
okay such as suggestions i think it
doesn't suggestion
um i i would like that but not for the
first version
okay okay
do you want it to like auto spell
at the end for the for the for the next
version
okay
it's way more important low level stuff
again we're not doing searching we're
doing adding
so i have here's some pre-prepared
questions
what really big tags can i have a tag
that's super color fragilistic
expialidocious is that okay
yeah so length of the tags how many
characters do you want do you want your
characters in there is a two letter tag
okay
or does that add no value
probably adds no value
what what if somebody enters a space
are we comma delimiting the tags are we
space delimiting the tags can we have a
tag that's two words or are they all one
words can they use a dash in those tags
special characters special character
yeah what do we do with special
characters
is it all english are the numbers is it
can you have
are we going to support other languages
these are these are the questions that
are business decisions
that matter
from an engineer's perspective i've got
to go implement this in the system
so what questions do i need answered
because if they're not there just now
i might just i might just make a
decision
later if you're if you're an engineer
and somebody asks you to add tags you'll
just go well this is how i like tags to
work so i'll build it that way
but these are business decisions
this is this is behavioral decisions
these are not technical decisions
restrictions on who can add taxes
can everyone add tags or only admins can
people select tags can they add new ones
right who can add new yeah all of those
questions
we should be generating as we're
thinking about and talking about and
discussing that that user story
what what do we do with all of this
information that we've just collected
what could we do with it
i hope
you're writing it down
right you need to write down the answer
somewhere don't you
it's been recorded it needs to be
recorded somewhere
right because if it's not recorded
somewhere what's going to happen
you'll come back again
i i but you're gonna you're gonna show
the product owner you're gonna show the
stakeholders at the end of the sprint
and what are they gonna say
that's not what i want it's not what i
wanted we talked about this
we talked about it
yeah
so we we we need to remember to ask
questions
dive into the details and it doesn't
matter
how pedantic those details are
right if the if the product owner says
it doesn't matter you can literally
write
length of the tag doesn't matter
on the user story right
but because you wrote it on the user
story
what's your product owner gonna think
well [__] maybe it does matter right if
you're gonna write it down
maybe i do need to have an answer for
that okay well let's let's
what are my choices right because maybe
the product owner doesn't understand the
question
yeah right and you can say well if
er er you as an engineer might say well
if the tags are if the words are really
long
how are we going to fit them on the ui
how much space do we have on the ui
how many tags are we going to display
you know all of those kind of things you
can you can talk through it you can draw
it
on the screen
right i need to jump off now um thanks
so much martin you you're very very very
uh welcome
remember to ask questions and to write
them down
yeah
i'll i'll join you on the other session
later on anything
okay cool all right cheers there bye
everyone
bye-bye
uh uh me me hi was talking about i'm
doing a a free public workshop on
definition of done
uh this afternoon pretty much straight
after this but not quite 4 30 till
[Music]
4 30 till 6.
um
so if we're going to write them down
how are we going to write them down
who here is familiar with scenarios
have you heard the term scenarios
yeah
have you used them david
not recently and and sort of at a higher
level
so here's
taking that uh that discussions with a
discussion and we ended up with three
character minimum and no spaces right
that might have been the answers that we
got
so then we need to look at what does
what does that actually
look like what's the behavior of the
application because behaviors of the
application are business requirements
not engineering decisions
okay
so given a tag value of less than three
characters
when it is entered then it is not saved
and the user is alerted about the tag
length
does that make sense
yeah
because
your next question after tags can only
be three characters in length is
what if i enter a tag of two characters
what happens then
yeah how many how many times have you
ever been on in an application
and you've filled out the form exactly
like it says and you hit submit and it
doesn't work and it doesn't give you a
warning for anything
because somebody didn't have this
conversation
they didn't think about that option
my favorite one is i
my surname is quite long
right henshaw wood
luckily my daughter's first name is long
so it's evangelina
hinchelwood right so that makes it even
longer but i used to work for a company
called the graduate network
and my and it was in the uk so my email
address was martin.hinchellwood
at the graduate network dot co uk
yes what happened when i went to try and
fill out my email address on forms all
over the internet
what oh i can't have any more characters
halfway through the graduate network no
more characters
bad
right is there any reason to restrict
the length of email address
nope
there's no reason to restrict it
what's the
let me know what the what the maximum
length of an email address is
basically though
max of an email address is 320
characters
that is the official
um and it's
so the first part i think is a maximum
of 64 characters before the act
that might be true
not 100 sure that's true
um
oh well okay maybe
yeah
64.
and so those of you that are geeks well
we'll know why
64 characters before the act 255 after
the act
number two
bits isn't it
binary
yeah yeah it's because of it's it's
because of madness
um
so
that that restriction is is is not good
and then it just pops up a warning
saying you've entered an invalid email
address and i'm like no [__] i've rented
a valid email address i can't fill out
my email address how many times have you
had that happen on forms not that
particular circumstance but
you can't fill out the correct answer
yeah yeah and then they say at the
bottom if you have answered any of these
questions incorrectly
right you may be prosecuted under blah
blah blah like but you wouldn't allow me
to answer them correctly i've actually
had to do that with a form recently i
had to fill out a government
um
procurement
form and it didn't give me any of the
options that were correct
so i had to fill out the form in the way
that it wanted it because it was an erp
system
in order to submit it
and then i had to email the people that
i was dealing with and say here's the
answers i had to fill out
here's the truth
here's why i couldn't fill it out
correctly
and they're like yeah whatever right but
now i've told them i'm off the hook
yeah yeah right
but i couldn't fill out the form
it didn't have the options that
i needed so there's no spaces given a
tag with spaces is entered when it is
saved then the spaces are removed and
the tag is camel cased right there's a
decision made
that's quite a complex decision isn't it
that's probably the result of a bunch of
conversations
but they are all at business decisions
so what does that that look like
um well you would maybe have a title to
your user story and the the the
conversation
right the three c's of a user story are
a card
a conversation and confirmation
right that's the three c's of user
stories
so we've got a title a description and
then some acceptance criteria and in
this case we're writing it as scenarios
right scenarios are a really good way to
to to caveat that because if you think
about that one where the user is alerted
about the tag length um
what actually happens if it's not true
right have those conversations and then
you would take this
ux this picture
and break it down into
a bunch of user stories and then each
story breaks down into a bunch of
scenarios we've had some conversations
so pragmatic point then
yep
oh you went you went on mute
keeps dropping me onto mute annoyingly
i'm not sure why um
pragmatic conversation does people's
time is valuable and it is presumably
plausible to have a very very large
number of scenarios yep what's the where
do you place the threshold of value
because you could just go into sort of
the
infinitesimal level of detail and you
never actually get around to building
anything because you've just documented
out
either scenarios that would never
you went on mute again halfway through
that again yeah
you either end up documenting like
really niche edge scenarios that will
never happen or things that are so
common that
it's not worth capturing them
i i disagree that they're so common it's
not worth capturing them but you might
not have to go into any level of detail
right
you should you should maybe it's just a
sentence that says yeah and obviously
this doesn't happen and obviously that
doesn't happen
right would you would you use
you went on mute again after would you
right um but would you
well so would you capture there that you
know i want the system to use
uh english
as in people to type and use ascii
english
or is that just a given or is that one
of those things that's so common
it's so obvious but it's still worth
capturing in a sentence in the user's
story oh i i might have that captured at
a higher level
right okay so when we're talking about
the system
we will have some things that are true
for everything
like
uh and and the system supports english
okay yes
does it so the event if somebody says
and the system supports english an
engineer's going to ask you
does it support any other languages
you were like no
what about welsh aren't we required to
support welsh and gaelic and
in in in the uk for systems oh oh yeah
maybe we are
let me get back to you on that right so
you've asked the question you've
potentially got an answer because that
is a business decision
yeah yeah um our
questions at that level
are also things around at myopias
right are we are we
how does our system handle people with
various disabilities
are we going to handle that or are we
not going to handle that are we going to
support tax readers or are we not going
to support tax readers
so these are more non-functional
requirements though yeah these these are
i'm supporting english or or or support
supporting klingon are
yeah non-functional that's an actual
language don't laugh
um
you can get a university degree in that
that stuff
um
it is yeah these are these are
potentially potentially some of our
non-functional requirements that just
exist at a high level and then once
they're noted down once they're part of
that story
right your your your overall
understanding and context no you don't
need them in every story
so everything nests
beneath those and therefore inherits
from them yeah so you might have some of
those things end up on your definition
of done because because they're a
quality issue
and some of those things must might be
on
you can have an entry on your definition
of done uh in the must must meet
organizational graphic design standards
right yeah so there you've just there
might be a whole bunch of things that
need to be true to do with icons and
graphics and placement and order of
buttons and
uh you know if you're following what's
the the new
uh microsoft's new is it called flow
fluid design they're the fluid design
model
right so all new products at microsoft
regardless of what platform you're
building where
every new product of microsoft must meet
the fluid design guidelines
right
do the old products meet it no
but if they have to they they have to
all have a plan on
are they going to are they choosing to
update it or not is that a retiring
product that we're not going to fix or
is it a product we're keeping moving
forward which means then we need a plan
to move to the fluid design
yes right so that i mean the
these are things that do need to be
discussed they're business decisions
they cost money
um
and there might be organizational
standards and definitions that we have
to meet
so yes we have that conversation but we
don't need to have it here because it's
probably already been had sure yeah
but
deciding how long the tags are what
happens if people input incorrect data
that's all business decisions
and i guess it gets more complicated
when if you're building a data systems
like you're analyzing data you might
have to clean that data so knowing
what's valid data and what's invalid
data is a business decision
it's not an engineering decision
right the engineers might say here's a
list of [__] that we've got that we
don't know what to do with
business you need to make a decision on
what we do with it and the business goes
well delete that one uh that one's
really supposed to be this so map it to
this value this one's that okay and then
you just go through that list and ask
those questions
[Music]
so let's
who is familiar with gherkin
anybody
david might be
that's in the food or is this something
else no not the food no no no
so gherkin is uh a set of tooling
which in the dot net world you might use
spec flow
um where it allows you to create
executable specifications
uh this might be a task where you turn
these given when thens
into unit tests and those unit tests
validate whether you've met the the
business requirements
um
they're they're very powerful tools you
maybe don't want everything to go that
way but it is certainly a a good option
the more
criteria that you have for acceptance
criteria the more likely you are to want
to to to have an
you know what i mean by an executable
specification
no
so
are our
oh can i i don't know if i could even
add hawker a demo for you um but
effectively you you would have three
methods that are run a given method of
when method and a then method
um and the the system actually takes the
text that you would enter in the
acceptance
criteria box in azure devops
and converts it into code
and then your engineers have to go fill
in the code in between so for example if
you're saying
given a tag value of less than three
characters
right when it is entered
then it is not saved and the user is
alerted you can create a unit test for
that
you can create a test
that tries to send the system a two
character
tag
and it rejects it with the correct
message so you can do something about it
in the ui
i see can you and can you generate those
directly from the user story so you only
effectively
you know you create once used many times
the the
writing yes so let me
i'm just going to share my moment
that one
oh awesome they've got a cookie monster
on their page
oh look at that they've even written
their data privacy as a as a spec flow
scenario
right
so given an unknown user access expect
flow when this user accepts spec flow
cookie by clicking accept all then splat
4 will show the content based on the
user's interest except all right
so um
this is a way for you to
there's a there's a good example let's
see
right i'm not going to dive into that
let's do the right
so there's a a a bit of a spec flow
right you have a feature which is a
calculator
let me zoom in for you
there we go
oh it's either really big or not really
big
um
so the scenario
add two numbers given i've entered 50
into the calculator and i have entered
70 when i press add then the result was
120 on the screen right
so that that
that is a business problem a business
statement is business readable
and then that is turned into code
that is basically a method
um there'll be a method called
uh given i have entered 50 into the
calculator
right they'll effectively be a method
called that
so the engineer will go fill in the
content of the method to add 50 to the
calculator
right
but if you have another scenario
that uses
i have entered 50 into the calculator
it's going to use the same method so yes
you can build up a library of
this yeah of all of this um and it's a
very very
powerful
um
it's a very powerful tool um it
interfaces with lots of different
platforms
uh so you can i mean the the the the
you can set them up
uh so there's libraries like fluid
assertions
uh that allow you to
to to write those statements in code
in an easy way i was just looking first
for for examples uh
maybe that's the intention
uh there we go
so um
should start with
actual so there's the string
should start with a b and end with high
and contained ef and have length nine
right there's an assertion that you can
put in your
uh um
in your unit testing framework
that is human readable
right even if you're not an engineer
you can you can parse that and see what
it's doing
um yeah and and and you could do that
with with tags with other other tools
um
[Music]
and there's just different examples of
of how you would set that up
so that it's easier for people to
understand and then once you've got it i
think there's a way
there's different ways of doing it okay
but if i go back to
spec flow
and
i think spec flow runner is it just spec
flow they have different
tools
but in the the spec flow runner
it basically you can have it integrate
with azure devops load the text
out of the acceptance criteria and use
that as as as the foundation for
building unit tests
sure yeah i understand yeah thank you
um so that's that's a really good uh
tool that is certainly
more advanced right i don't think
uh oh i've gone off the mural
i don't think everybody's going to take
advantage of that
um
but i think
that's that is a powerful way to do it
i've used it with a lot of teams
is what i'm saying
uh
so i guess the question is uh what
questions do you have now on
user stories and scenarios
i can i can
give you a workshop
that you can run with your teams okay
um and it it's super super super easy
i've run it with tons of organizations
you effectively get them to draw on a on
a whiteboard either virtual with mural
or a physical whiteboard and a user
interface that they have already created
in the system
and then create the user stories you
would have and scenarios that you would
have liked to have
not what you did have but what you would
have liked to have to build it because
you know everything about the choices
you made yeah
not only do you know everything about
the choices you made but you know
that oh we tested that and it didn't
didn't pass the tests because it didn't
work like this so then we had to go
change it again
so what could we have had in our user
story and acceptance criteria to not
have to rework that
functionality
because that's waste right that's wasted
time and effort and money
how could we have had a short
conversation that would have resulted in
an answer that allowed us to to build it
the right way the first time
and build out all of the user stories or
as many as you can for that ui breaking
them down and i usually when i'm working
with teams you get together everybody
who cares right so you could have the
the scrum team so so developers plus
product owner plus scrum master and but
you might also invite subject matter
experts uh maybe you have other people
in product management that matter maybe
you have not users but maybe key
stakeholders that you can bring into
that conversation and just
see what it takes to break down and
create user stories in a format
that helps everybody understand
that feature
right
and this is so something you've built
before that make sense
so you can use hindsight
and then the second part of the exercise
that can take like you can spend two
hours doing that easy
okay
and then the second part of the exercise
is take something off your backlog and
do the same thing with it
so now you're not working with hindsight
you're thinking about the future but now
you're thinking about the level of
detail that you need
to not build things wrong
and have to rework it because rework is
hugely expensive you've got the engineer
had to build it then you had to test it
it wasn't right so then you had to
rebuild it and then you had to retest it
that's twice as much work isn't it
yeah
i'd rather do it once right what's the
what's the what's the expression for
joiners
uh measure twice
and cut once at once yep
so agile is not about just making it up
as you go along and then changing it
later
you still need to minimize waste because
everything has a cost
there's a cost like that i think
david you were you were concerned about
about how how much detail should you go
into right
that has a cost the more time you spend
up front has a cost
but you want to minimize you want to
spend enough time up front that you
minimize
the amount of rework that you have to do
yes
and that that exercise that i'm talking
about where you do it once with a ui
that already exists with hindsight we
all worked on that system we know what
questions had to be answered after and
even you might find that you'd built it
put it in front of stakeholders and
they're like no that's not what we
thought it was and then you have to
change it again
right what could you have asked up front
to not have to make those changes
you're not going to know everything but
we need to minimize that rework
was this what you were expecting me to
talk about
yeah i think so yeah okay
yeah it's been a very quite insightful
it is it's um
it's one of these things that sort of
you
you do approach anyway but see it's
structured and put more formally it's
really useful really eye opening to
that's definitely something you'd use
going forwards
but they're not as a part of a larger
methodology it's just
yeah it just makes you really think
about and really separate out
different like different user stories
different journeys it's
yeah it's really valuable so i i i i
have a uh a one day agile requirements
workshop
that covers this in in more depth right
we can only do so much in in 90 90
minutes plus there's only there's only
four of you here so that's you know i'm
gonna
do that as well but if
ultimately the the agile requirements
workshop and the two main exercises in
there are the the the
hindsight and not hindsight exercise and
then there's just some discussion about
these things around it
so that they have a a frame of reference
for building user stories and then as
they're building them out especially the
first time um i go around and
poke at bad user stories
like as a user right i think you can do
better than that or
that you know you've got a user story
and you end up with 20 scenarios and
you're like
guys i think you should break that down
that seems like a very big thing
yeah yeah so so those those are
that that
what you end up with
that level of detail
that you as a team so i'm not going to
tell you what level of detail you need
because it's very specific to you your
team your organization and your your
subject matter matter um so that
exercise the first part brings it down
to here's the level of detail we would
have liked to have to build to minimize
our costs
and then you look at your backlog and go
oh
you know we don't have that level of
detail
we have too many open-ended questions
maybe this is not ready maybe we need to
spend more time in refinement maybe we
need to ask some of those questions
because as you as you found it's really
hard to get to some of those questions
yeah right you gotta that's why a a
picture
really really helps how how are you
visualizing
what it is that you're you're you're
building
right should should those that table be
able to be ordered or not
right if it's ingredients maybe not
maybe it shouldn't be ordered
right because you want them to be in a
specific order
yeah yeah
yeah yeah it's it's super
there's lots of conversations you could
have and in fact i don't like that ui i
want a different one
right might be the first conversation
you have and actually i don't like that
ui
i want the cooking notes and the recipe
ingredients to be integrated
right because you follow a set of step
you need to know what you need to have
up front and then you follow the set of
steps but i don't want stuff twice
so how do i integrate the two yeah yeah
i i get really complicated with these
things for sure
but your your product owner has the
option to sit there and say
we don't need to go in like i did yeah
we don't need to worry about that just
now all right let's we'll think about
that later that's for a future future
story let's just focus on this
but did you notice how hard it was for
me to keep that focus
yeah yeah so your product owner
one of their jobs
is to help the team understand what they
need to build which means during
refinement they have to keep that focus
no this is the context that we're
talking about
and as soon as the team strays outside
of that context
right yes
let's put a note for later
but this is what we're talking about
just now because you can get into a lot
of tangents
right well i think that was your worry
wasn't it uh
mcsee
um was was
get getting getting too far into the
weeds and not focusing on what what it
is we actually need to build just now
yeah i think
uh this is no reflection of my
colleagues but i can see a scenario
where people start to become
[Music]
um
risk-averse and combative and i think if
i haven't listed it this may be my one
opportunity to get it and if i don't
list it it gives them latitude and they
may go off and do something that i don't
want but then you
you ultimately the whole effort is
doesn't achieve its maximum potential
because you spent
filling out forms yes but that will only
happen once
right or or a limited number of times
because
you you i i'm gonna want
your team to have that conversation if
you had to do that right if the if you
get to the sprint review and the
customer's like what is this bollocks
that's not what i asked for right yeah
that's the first conversation you're
having at your retrospective
how how
why were we so far off what the customer
wanted well they wanted this and they
wanted that and the other thing and they
didn't tell us that it's like well okay
why didn't they tell us that did we not
ask
what could we have asked
to find out that information
right yeah so your trip your trip that
that
the the the questioning
that a team needs to be able to do to
interact with customers and stakeholders
and find out what they need to help the
product owner build that better backlog
is a skill that you need to learn
so yeah how do we
figure that out
so i'm saying that
the problems i've got to go shortly but
there's as you move forward through time
this becomes not just easier but also
better because you develop that ability
and experience of what questions to ask
so you don't repeat the mistakes of the
past but also presumably you build up a
set of fairly generic use cases you
build up a library of use cases you
reuse so you know i'm building one of
these it's very similar to that thing we
did two years ago let me just pull in
80 of the use cases which gives you that
head start yeah well and do do you have
uh um documents that are our standards
of the way things
should work in your organization right
you you should definitely have those you
should have a ux guidelines document
that may be a wiki that you constantly
update right you should have a
definition of done
and what is what is this particular
what's our our coding guidelines
right what's the level of quality that
we expect in the naming convention for
our methods in the
uh length of our methods what are what
are our rules that we have as an
organization around that so that we have
readable supportable maintainable
products and that fits within our brand
fits within
our organizational expectation because
users
you don't actually want to build stuff
out with the expectation of users right
so you might have some cool innovative
way of solving a problem that a
developer's like oh that's cool i'll try
and you know i want to try and implement
it that way because i think it will be
cool
right but if it creates
a difficulty for users a friction for
users using it because everything else
in your system works click click slide
and this new feature works
at click click slide slide click
then
you've got a discrepancy in usage and is
that's not within the bounds of your
expectation your users expectations
so so once you've decided what those ux
ui and ux guidelines are although you're
going to iterate on them over time you
will need to quantify them
uh ux guidelines ui guidelines coding
standards right these should all be
documented clearly for everybody in your
organization and part of every team's
definition i've done
just to make you feel bad about your
definition of done if it doesn't have
that
sorry
yes yeah
dave's gone so i think that's
yeah i think i need to go as well so
yeah yeah we're we're we're we're
definitely at time so hopefully that was
useful
yeah
um i didn't run all of the exercises
that i wanted to just because we didn't
have the people to run it so
um it was it was better just to talk
about stuff
i feel like there's sort of a few less
people in the class as well because you
can sort of
talk more directly and it's less lost in
the crowds yeah i i agree both are
valuable both are valuable
i i just i always i always prepare for
like maybe 20 people who turn up i don't
know
yeah so yeah
so you're welcome in an hour um i'm
doing
a a public
definition of done workshop with uh
a colleague so you're welcome to that as
i don't well on your website
uh yeah it's on um
i'll get us i'll pop the link in the
in the chat oh if i can find it
um
so that you've got got that as well if
you want to obviously you don't have to
and it will be recorded so
but you know what it's like sometimes
you if if you don't watch it live
yes
you have to quite find the motivation to
come back to watch it later so i just
put it in the introduction to definition
i've done it will be similar to the
workshop that i'll do with you guys i
think i've got it later in
our set of sessions
um
so it'll get you a little bit of a heads
up and maybe you get to ask different
questions as well
cool okay cool thank you cheers very
welcome okay
speaking
you